Episode 115 will start after 12:07 min.
What do you want?
Step aside.
We need to talk to the Sultan.
What do you mean?
What would the Sultan be doing
among our tribe?
Traitors!
God is good!
I hope nothing is wrong.
Who are they, Artuk Bey?
God is good!
What's going on, Artuk Bey?
I have a bad feeling
about this, my Sultan.
-They will kill my son.
-Lady Mahperi.
-Stop.
-I can't.
He is pointing his sword
at my son. I can't stop.
Do you know what I see
when I look at you, Ertuğrul Bey?
A liar disguised as a valiant man.
Now surrender yourself.
Ask for the mercy of Vizier Sadettin
as they go on their raid.
We only surrender ourselves
to God, Günalp Bey.
Then...
you came of your own will
to meet your death, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll be your executioner.
This will be a holy day for many brave men
who sacrificed their lives
for the state.
I pray to God
to give you a little bit of sense.
Just know that,
I won't stop
until that bastard Sadettin dies.
Now...
Give me your best shot.
Then it's the end of the road for you.
You fools! How dare you raid
the tent of the Sultan!
You will die now.
-Attack!
-God is good!
Lady Mahperi, we need to defend
this place.
Mother, bring us the swords.
If they try to come here,
we will protect the babies.
Give me a sword too, Lady Hayme.
Give me any weapon.
I'll do my best to defend this place.
God is good!
Artuk Bey!
I know you very well, Ertuğrul Bey.
I knew you wouldn't stop
chasing Vizier Sadettin.
Günalp Bey.
Blessed Vizier.
Günalp. Why did you use
the secret passage to the tent?
Ertuğrul is coming after you.
Günalp Bey. He can't possibly come
to a military headquarter
with thousands of soldiers in it.
He will surely come.
Günalp is right.
Then, we should double the precautions.
No, we won't.
We will leave them as they are.
Let Ertuğrul come to kill me.
It won't be possible for him to kill you
if you go for the raid tomorrow.
But he will find a way to infiltrate
the tent tonight.
He won't even wait for the night.
He will come at an unexpected time.
Blessed Vizier...
I have unfinished business with him.
Let me be the one to welcome him.
I'm proud of your loyalty
and determination, Günalp.
Come on, my Bey.
Kill that bastard already.
Ertuğrul will come out once he is done.
We should get him
out of here safe and sound.
Husamettin, who will take over
once Sadettin dies, will handle the rest.
God willing.
What's going on?
Why are the soldiers here?
Bring them to me!
Who sent you?
Who?
He handed over his weapon
before entering the tent.
Blessed Vizier...
Günalp Bey should have already been out
with Ertuğrul's head in his hand.
You still don't know much
about Ertuğrul, Kayraldi.
Ertuğrul's persistence is his weapon.
Surrender, Ertuğrul!
Surrender.
And ask for my mercy.
Surrender, Ertuğrul Bey.
It's the end of the road.
There is no way out.
Stay there!
Move back!
Artuk Bey!
You shall die!
My Sultan!
I will rip you apart.
I will rip you apart!
I'd love to see you try!
Now...
Where is your owner to save you?
Who will save you from me, now?
Ertuğrul! Surrender!
You are in my headquarters,
surrounded by my army!
There is no escape!
Stop!
Stop.
Ertuğrul is trapped. Only we can save him.
They won't let my Bey live.
They will kill us too if we are spotted.
The duty to kill Sadettin will be ours
if anything happens to Ertuğrul.
There will be no one to kill that dog
if we are spotted.
It's me or Köpek...
It's justice or cruelty, Günalp Bey.
Your point of view...
will be the cause of your death.
They ambushed Ertuğrul Bey.
That bastard should die
before anything happens to Ertuğrul Bey.
Turgut Bey and Sancar Bey are still here.
We still have hope.
Finally, I have him in my grasp.
Thank God.
You will have his head
before you go on the raid.
All right, that's enough.
Prepare yourselves.
We'll attack.
Go ahead, Günalp Bey.
Let's see how much Sadettin,
whom you love as a father
and whom you'd die for,
likes you.
Go on!
-God damn you!
-He has Günalp.
There is still hope, Turgut.
There will always be hope
as long as Ertuğrul lives.
For sure!
I will kill you.
Get ready!
We will attack.
Are you going to sacrifice Günalp Bey,
blessed Vizier?
I'd even sacrifice
my own son for the sake of our state.
For sure!
Son. Are you okay?
I'm fine, mother. Don't worry.
You should patch that up, Artuk Bey.
As you order, my Sultan.
Raiding the tent, huh?
Trying to assassinate the sultan, huh?
Your master is scum
and you are a scumbag!
My Sultan...
Let me behead this bastard
in front of you.
Not now, Bamsi Alp.
Why are you sparing someone
who tried to kill you, my Sultan?
This bastard must die at once.
Mother!
I said not now.
Don't make me
repeat myself again.
Ertuğrul...
Did you really think
you could save yourself
if you had Günalp, huh?
Don't you know
I'd even sacrifice Günalp,
whom I love as a son, to get you?
Surrender and ask for my mercy.
Or die together with Günalp!
This is my last warning.
Archers!
So, you've seen the true face
of a man whom you love as a father.
Sooner or later, you'll realize
how wretched he is.
If I die...
the duty to kill him is yours.
I promise you that, Günalp Bey.
Now...
I will surrender...
so that you can live.
Get him.
Let me behead him right here
and right now, blessed Vizier!
No.
He is mine.
But wait...
I have to find out his accomplices first.
How did he enter my headquarters?
Who were the two commanders...
who let him in here?
Who was behind this scheme?
I will find out.
And your death won't be that easy.
I heard that the coward Sultan,
whom you respect dearly,
held his mother's hand
and took her to your tribe.
For them,
there is no one else to trust but you.
None but you.
Now tell me.
How did you enter my headquarters?
You'll stay silent, huh?
Let's see if you are able
to be silent after I'm done with you.
Kayraldi.
Take him to my tent.
How did he...
find the courage to enter my headquarters
with those two commanders?
I'll find out.
I'm sure the emperor will also
like these plans, Ares.
That's what I thought, Kritos.
The emperor will be pleased, too.
What is it, Marya?
What is it you want to discuss with me?
Sir, I've brought important information
about the Kayis.
What is it, Marya?
I heard that
Sultan Giyaseddin left Konya,
and is currently residing
with the Kayi Tribe.
Are you sure?
Yes, sir.
I told you.
I have sources to gather information
about them.
How did you get this information, Marya?
A woman from the Cavdar Tribe.
Sadettin Köpek
is very powerful within the state.
The sultan is aware of this situation.
He must have thought he'd be bested
so he took refuge in Ertuğrul's tribe.
It's a great opportunity to create chaos
among the Turks, Ares.
We should use it wisely.
We will kill the sultan
in the place where he took refuge.
Thus, Ertuğrul's reputation
will be devastated.
You will have this great honor, Ares.
Yes, Kritos.
I truly have the Turks
in my claws this time.
Then, lose no time.
Take your men and go to attack him.
The sultan will not leave there alive.
I knew you'd say that, Kritos.
So you wanted to raid the village
and attempt to kill me in broad day.
And you disguised yourself as a soldier
of my state with no shame.
Tell me whose dog you are.
My sultan.
He's the helper of Günalp Bey.
Günalp Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey said
Günalp Bey was loyal to his state.
How could a traitor like him
be his helper?
He doesn't act on his own, my sultan.
Who has your leash?
Sadettin Köpek?
Whose dog are you?
Traitor.
You're the real traitor.
You and your mother betrayed the state
by killing the sultan.
You'll pay for this.
How dare you talk to our sultan like this?
Majesty Emir will toll
the death knell for you all.
You'll all die in pain.
Let him go, Bamsi Alp.
Seems like Sadettin poisoned this jackal.
My sultan.
What are you going to do?
Bamsi.
To forgive jackals like him would be...
a cruelty to justice.
First, your pathetic life.
And then Sadettin Köpek's.
My sultan.
Who let you enter my camp, Ertuğrul?
Who were those...
two commanders?
No one knows those two commanders,
Majesty Emir.
If we find out
who those commanders were...
we'll find out who let Ertuğrul Bey
enter my pavilion.
They were brave men loyal to their states,
and who wanted to kill a degenerate
that has the ambition to be the sultan.
You should know that
there are many more of them, Sadettin.
Sooner or later,
one of them will cut
your sinister head off.
I'll cut your head off personally
in front of my commanders, Ertuğrul.
I will parade it all over the land.
I'll display it until it decays.
However, first, you'll tell me the names
of those commanders.
-They told us to be ready.
-Hurry up.
It's surrounded everywhere.
It's not possible to save Ertuğrul
from that camp.
They'll try to torture my bey
and make him talk.
Ertuğrul won't talk.
Köpek knows that too.
Now, we'll have to think it through.
Our first goal is to find a way
to rescue Ertuğrul.
What will we do?
Togan Bey showed us a tent.
We'll sneak in and talk to him.
We'll put our heads together and discuss.
Good idea.
Let's go then.
Thank you, Halime Hatun.
May God bless you.
-How have you been, Artuk Bey?
-There's nothing
to worry about, my sultan.
Thank God, I'm fine.
Can I come in, my sultan?
Come in.
My sultan, Ertuğrul Bey rescued
Emir Kamyeri, he's alive and well.
After that, he set off
with Hüsamettin Karaca
to raid Sadettin Köpek's camp.
My brave man.
Thank God.
Good.
I had no doubt
that Ertuğrul Bey would succeed.
My sultan, Emir Kamyeri's army is ready.
They are on their way to outer Konya.
If something goes wrong,
Emir Kamyeri's army will attack
Sadettin Köpek's army.
Good.
They should wait for my command.
I'll lead the army personally.
Your wish is my command.
My sultan.
Emir Sadettin and his jackals found out
that you're here.
If you'll allow me,
I'd like to invite the tribe beys
who are loyal to Ertuğrul Bey.
Having them here would leverage
our unity and strength.
It's also important for you to be safe,
my sultan.
Good idea, Artuk Bey.
But what if they get afraid
of Emir Sadettin and fail to show up?
Still, we should invite them here,
my sultan.
Fine.
Send a messenger to the beys, then.
They should be here
if they love their state.
Your wish is my command.
Tell me.
From whom were
those two commanders getting orders?
Who did they obey...
and who brought you into my pavilion?
They were serving justice.
There's only one type of justice
in this pavilion, Ertuğrul.
And that's my bloody justice.
You've got time until the steel thickens,
Ertuğrul.
And I've got plenty of time.
Now, I'm asking you again.
Who were the two commanders?
Who did you ally with to get in here?
They were brave men,
loyal to Sultan Gıyaseddin
and their state.
That's a lie.
If you try to harm our sultan...
who ran away from your cruelty
and took shelter in our village...
you'll be crushed under the throne
that you're dying to sit on.
Majesty Emir.
Is His Majesty The Sultan
in the Kayi Village?
Günalp Bey.
I don't doubt a bit
that your helper Aydoğmuş
is on his way to kill our sultan
under this scumbag's order.
However, he'll pay for this with his life.
Majesty Emir.
What is he saying?
What would our sultan do
in this dog's village, Günalp Bey?
You still trust his words
that are full of betrayal.
Günalp Bey.
You either trust my words,
or Prince Sadettin's.
What are you saying?
Prince?
This scumbag Sadettin
has been lying about being the son
of our late sultan, haven't you heard?
In his greed to be the sultan,
he poisoned our late
Sultan Alaeddin Keykubat.
Sultan Gıyaseddin left the palace
to find me because of his treachery.
So I sent him to my village
to make sure he was safe.
Silence.
I'll kill this degenerate right away
and leave with my army
for our state and our sultan.
Kayraldı.
The execution shall be performed
right away.
I'll cut his head off myself
in the middle of my camp.
Take him.
Günalp Bey.
Why would I go through so much trouble
when I could kiss this dog's skirt
and solidify my rule over my land?
Open your eyes.
Open them!
Ertuğrul.
It's your time, huh?
Come on, my brave men.
It's your turn now.
Günalp.
Günalp!
Go now.
If God permits, we'll save our state
and our sultan from this traitor.
We survived many hardships.
We struggled
with many enemies and traitors.
However, we've never gone through
something like this.
Our state has never been
in such difficulty
and surrounded by jackals.
May God protect our children.
May God protect our state.
Amen.
God forbid, if something goes wrong,
I have no doubt that my Gıyaseddin
will take the lead of his army
and finish that degenerate.
However, I hope Ertuğrul Bey succeeds,
so that won't be necessary.
God willing, Mahperi Hatun.
God willing.
My Ertuğrul Bey will deal
with Emir Sadettin
just like he did
with his wildest enemies and traitors.
Our state will revive, if God permits.
God willing.
However, Mahperi Hatun,
I wish such things never happened.
I know you're angry with me.
And you have the right to be.
That traitor Emir Sadettin poisoned me
like he poisoned everyone around him.
You have no idea how much
my conscience suffers from what I did.
If we eventually succeed...
maybe my son and I will drift apart.
I know very well that he won't forgive me.
But that's okay.
As long as our state,
Ertuğrul Bey and my son
are alive and well.
No one else should get hurt.
I'll harden my heart, if necessary.
I'll pray to God...
ask for forgiveness.
Mahperi Hatun.
The important thing is not to be perfect.
The important thing is
learning from your mistakes.
A good scare is worth more
than a good advice.
Maybe...
to see the mistake you made...
you had to have a scare.
Let's pray
that God lets us reach safety...
before anyone else gets hurt.
God willing.
If we can capture Sadettin Köpek,
we may trade him for Ertuğrul Bey.
That's the only way.
We have to find the best time.
We can only do that
before he gets out in the yard.
It's almost impossible
to enter his pavilion.
So we'll finish that business
in the only place we can.
Where is that?
In front of his pavilion.
Turgut Bey is right.
-What happened, Togan?
-They took Ertuğrul Bey out
to execute him.
What are you saying?
It's time.
Be very specific about the time you act.
If you are late by even one second,
Sadettin Köpek will get away.
Show us the way where we can get
to the pavilion without anyone seeing us.
Let's go.
My God.
You handed over the state
to this dog, Günalp Bey.
Many more people...
will die,
like your mother and father.
Stop!
Stop.
Ertuğrul Bey...
belongs to Emir Sadettin.
You were the one to trap our sultan
in the Hanlı Bazaar,
the one to set me and my Alps up,
and the one who sent the letter to Ares,
Emir Sadettin.
I relieve you of all your duties,
Sadettin.
You prevented me from serving my state
with your lies.
Your defamation,
your crossing of the line,
and insulting me in front
of the palace seniors.
Did you think I'd forget that, Ertuğrul?
Just like you disgraced me
in front of the palace seniors,
I'll make your death painful and shameful.
Even though I couldn't deal with you
as an emir,
I'll defeat you as the sultan, Ertuğrul.
Die, Sadettin.
Die so the world can be a better place.
Aslıhan.
Sultan Alaeddin gifted me this sword
for saving his life in a battle.
Now...
Now you'll die with the sword
of the sultan that you crushed me for.
Your death won't be so easy.
I won't let you die with the single blow
of a sharp sword.
I'll take over the throne
of the Seljuk Dynasty...
with your head.
A blunt sword like this is suitable
for your ominous head.
Don't get close.
Or I'll cut his throat.
Soldiers, step back!
Now you're in my hands, Köpek.
I would cut your head off right here,
and give it to the coyotes.
But be grateful to my Ertuğrul Bey.
Now you'll release Ertuğrul Bey.
-Or else...
-Günalp.
Do what he says.
They don't have anywhere to run.
Günalp Bey.
Bring three horses
to the exit of the camp.
Only two men will bring Ertuğrul Bey.
The soldiers will step back.
Otherwise Sadettin dies.
Do what he says, Günalp.
Come on!
Governor Kritos found out about the sultan
being in the Kayi Village.
He found out?
How did he find out?
Marya.
She was a spy for Sadettin Köpek.
He got the information from Köpek's men,
and let Governor Kritos know.
Brother,
the horses and the dogs got mixed up.
I won't rest until I get rid of the dogs.
Bamsi.
Governor Kritos knows
that the sultan is in the Kayi Village
because of Emir Sadettin.
He wants me take advantage
of the commotion and raid the village.
I can prevent that.
But I have to find a way.
Brother Ahmet.
Don't you worry.
There's a way.
The Oghuz beys loyal to my Ertuğrul Bey
will be by our sultan's side.
Alps will secure the village.
Now go and tell that to the Governor.
Tell him that it's not possible to raid
the village when the Oghuz beys are there.
I'm glad you said that, Bamsi.
Governor Kritos might give up
on raiding the village
when the Oghuz beys are there
with their alps.
But we have a bigger problem.
What's that, Brother?
The big army from Nicaea.
It's almost ready and about to leave.
I can't stop them.
Ahmet, my brother.
Do whatever you can.
We'll start the preparations.
First, my Ertuğrul Bey will get back
alive and well,
after that, we'll destroy
the governor and the army.
God willing, Bamsi.
I'll go back to Bilecik right away
and let Governor Kritos know.
Thank you, Brother.
Thank you.
Come on.
Go.
Untie Ertuğrul Bey's hands.
Do what he says, Günalp.
Now, let Ertuğrul Bey go.
When you let Ertuğrul Bey go,
we'll let Sadettin go.
Do as he says, Kayraldı.
Go, Ertuğrul.
Let's see how far you can go.
Your death is upon you, you should know.
I'll come after you, Ertuğrul.
I'll kill you...
your tribe...
and your family.
I'll slaughter Gündoğdu Bey's tribe
as well.
Just wait, Sadettin.
You'll get your share of justice's sword.
I'll make everyone pay
for what you did.
My rage won't cool down until...
I kill all of the Kayis.
Your rage will be buried with you.
I'll cut off your head
before you can hurt anyone.
Giddy up!
We'll go after them.
Don't worry, Majesty Emir.
They won't get far.
I removed their horseshoes.
That's a great idea, Kayraldı.
We're leaving now.
Do you hear me, Günalp?
We'll find them, Majesty Emir.
I know where they are going, Karaca.
Something's wrong with the horses.
They removed my horseshoes.
Mine too.
They must be after us.
We have to get to the cave
where we're meeting Togan Bey.
Whatever they do,
we won't go back
before we have Sadettin's head.
First, let's get to the cave
and treat your wounds.
Gather your strength.
Come on.
You're a disgrace!
You have no skill!
Two alps...
come up to my pavilion,
and no one knows about it.
They took me hostage
in front of my pavilion.
In front of my soldiers.
We can't even catch a traitor.
And we're supposed to
take over Samsat Castle?
Is this how we'll do it?
As for you...
I put you in charge of a big camp.
You said it was secured everywhere.
Where did those two alps come from?
Forgive me, Majesty Emir.
-Believe--
-I can't forgive.
"Forgive me."
If you can't do your duty,
why should you even live?
Kayraldı.
Throw his body to the ravens.
Hüsamettin.
What's the situation?
The soldiers are deployed on high hills.
They can't get away.
Majesty Emir.
The only place they can run to
is the creek bed.
Fine, the creek bed it is.
I'll personally go that direction
with my soldiers.
Majesty Emir.
I'd like to go look for them now.
I've done night searches many times.
Fine.
Take big units with you.
Everyone should search
the area they are responsible for.
Nothing will pass.
You've seen what happens to those
who fail their duties.
Come on.
Everybody, get back to work.
May I enter, my Sultan?
Come in, Ibn Al Arabi.
-Greetings.
Sit down, please.
I heard what happened, my Sultan.
I'm sorry.
Thank God you were able
to overcome these dark forces.
God protected you.
God bless you, Ibn Al Arabi.
The enemy pursues us relentlessly.
But thanks to God
and the bravery of the alps,
we were able to overcome them.
This war is clearly destined
to continue until one of us is dead.
This is a struggle between
good and evil, my Sultan.
This struggle
began when the world began,
and will go on until the apocalypse.
Everything has its opposite.
Good cannot exist without evil.
Sweetness cannot exist without bitterness.
Our duty is to sustain that which is good,
and prevent that which is evil.
He whose intention is good...
is strengthened when exposed to evil.
He can destroy its cruelty and treachery
with the power of an erupting volcano.
Don't be afraid of their numbers
and power, my Sultan.
Abraha led an army
of elephants against the Ka'ba.
But God destroyed them
with the Ababil birds.
If we stand with God,
God will stand with us.
Holy God says this in the Qur'an,
"So, do not weaken, and do not grieve,
and you will be superior,
if you are true believers."
There is something which worries me,
which I'd like to talk to you about.
Of course, my Sultan.
My own mother was involved...
in these calamities.
She shows regret now.
But... I don't know how I should react.
You are not one of the people,
you are responsible for the people.
You are the sultan.
The people will obey whatever you command.
You can't ever go to extremes.
In matters of justice,
of mercy, of affection,
you must show restraint
and stay on the path of righteousness.
For you set an example to the people
with the decisions you make.
Holy God says in the Qur'an,
"If you show good or conceal it,
or pardon an offense,
know that God is ever Pardoning.
He is ever Competent."
Punishment serves to
better the wrong-doer.
If she regrets what she's done...
and if you're convinced
she won't repeat it...
you must decide justly,
taking all that into consideration.
In times of trouble your guidance
has helped me to act justly.
Now, in these troubled times,
your words are a source
of great comfort to me
and will, I hope,
help me establish true justice.
God willing.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-Come, Togan Bey.
I thank God you're all right,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
Any news?
Sadettin's soldiers are everywhere.
He's somewhere among them.
He's leading the search himself.
And Günalp Bey?
He's involved in the search too,
in another direction.
He's operating separately
from Sadettin's army.
While he's looking for us...
we'll catch him off guard.
Together with Hüsamettin Karaca
we'll gather our loyal soldiers
and catch up with you.
Thank you, Togan Bey.
What now, my Bey?
We're going to lure Köpek, Turgut.
We're going to get him where we want him.
Then the hunt can begin.
God help you, Ertuğrul Bey.
-God help us all, Togan Bey.
-Amen.
Sadettin Köpek is prey
that will come to us.
We'll surround him like a pack of wolves.
When he's trapped, we'll strike,
then finish him with our claws and swords.
The time for talking is over.
We'll speak our last words to Köpek
with our swords and claws.
Governor Kritos learned that you
and Mahperi Hatun were here
through Sadettin, my Sultan.
How?
Köpek has a female spy
near to Governor Kritos, Marya.
Köpek's guard told Marya that you
were here. And Marya told the Governor.
Köpek.
That bastard is prepared to work
with the governor if it helps him.
This state has never
known a traitor like him.
Even the infidels know we're here.
-We must act.
-May I enter, my Sultan?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
My Sultan, if you'll permit it,
the Oğuz beys wish to see you.
Show them in, Artuk Bey. Show them in.
Come in, beys.
Welcome, my beys.
-Thank you, my Sultan.
It pleases me greatly to see you here.
My Sultan, we came as soon
as we heard you were here.
The traitors' attempt on your life
has angered us all.
Our alps will protect the Kayi tribe.
Not even the emperor,
let alone the governor,
will be able to harm you.
Once again you have proven your worth.
As long as there are
loyal men such as yourselves
our state will always prevail.
-Thank you, my Sultan.
Sit down, my beys.
There's no need to stand.
You'll be rewarded for bringing me
such important news, Marya.
Governor Kritos.
I went to the Kayi tribe.
But we can't possibly attack them now.
-Why not?
-The beys of the tribes
have joined together there
to protect the sultan.
Attacking the tribe now
would be an act of madness.
What then?
Do we just abandon this opportunity?
Kritos, whatever we do,
we must do it right.
If we don't, we'll pay a heavy price.
There must be a way, Ares!
-We can't just give up.
-We'll never give up, Kritos.
But if we make a move
before the army gets here
they'll massacre
every single one of our men.
You're right.
We must wait for the army.
Trust me on this, Kritos. Don't worry.
Even if the sultan
manages to leave the tribe alive,
I'll finish him off on the road to Konya.
This is of crucial importance to us, Ares.
I have work to do now.
We'll discuss this later.
As you wish, Kritos.
Door.
You weren't this afraid
of the Turks before, Ares.
What changed?
Are your days of being
a great warrior behind--
What do you know of war, Marya?
Don't provoke me.
Unless you want to join your brother,
don't push me.
Understand?
I'll find out what you're up to, Ares.
I'll have my revenge
for my brother's death.
You'll curse the day you were born.
Begin, my beys.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My beys, I intend to stay away
from the palace for a while.
My absence from the palace will end
when the traitors have been purged.
-God willing.
Be assured I'm doing everything
in my power to save our state.
If I am to die,
I will die fighting alongside
my beys and alps.
My Sultan, has there been
any news from Ertuğrul Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey is hunting down
our enemy, Sadettin Köpek.
And if he can't kill
Sadettin Köpek, my Sultan?
Then I will take command
of Emir Kamyeri's army myself.
Defeating Sadettin Köpek
is a cause I am prepared to die for.
I wanted to see for myself
that my beys were with me.
We're with you, my Sultan.
And not just here.
Wherever you go,
we'll be with you with our alps.
We live to serve God,
our state and our country.
If we need to unite today, we will unite.
If we must die, we'll die together.
I, Giyaseddin Keyhüsrev,
son of Sultan Alaeddin,
swear that I'll fight
to the death for my state.
We swear loyalty
to our state and our sultan.
They're gone.
They ran away?
They escaped.
They still intend to kill Emir Sadettin.
How could they, my Bey?
They left their horses here
to create a diversion.
They're still after Emir Sadettin.
This is madness.
What can three men do
among all those soldiers, my Bey?
Ertuğrul led us here deliberately,
to reduce the number of soldiers
Emir Sadettin has around him.
But how could they know
where His Eminence is, my Bey?
Ertuğrul is not alone.
His allies will have told him.
If that's the case, they'll have
no trouble locating Emir Sadettin.
We must go now.
I'm going to make my way up
the river. Catch up with me there.
As you command, my Bey.
You either listen to me or...
to Prince Sadettin.
What are you talking about, Ertuğrul Bey?
What prince?
The dog Sadettin
likes to spread the lie that he's the late
Sultan's son, or didn't you know that?
Commander?
Have you ever heard it said
that Emir Sadettin's father was
Sultan Alaeddin,
father of Sultan Keyhüsrev?
Tell me, commander.
I have, my Bey.
From whom?
From... Emir Sadettin himself.
Come on, Emir Sadettin.
My Bey.
-Are you all right?
-I'm fine, brother.
I'm fine.
God willing
we won't rest until Köpek is dead.
Agreed.
My Sultan.
-Are you training, Gündüz Alp?
-I am, my Sultan.
I didn't know you were there.
Come and sit down, Gündüz Alp.
You are a fine swordsman.
Thank you, my Sultan.
My father left me to guard the tribe.
It's my duty to protect it
while he's away.
-That's why I train all the time.
-Well said.
To protect the legacy of our fathers,
and keep their memory alive,
is a son's most important duty.
My father taught me how to use a sword.
Did Sultan Alaeddin teach you too?
Yes. He did.
When I was a child
he would take us on hunts.
Sahbaz would teach me
to ride and shoot arrows.
"The son will replace his father.
One of his two eyes.
A son is everything to the ruler.
A father leaves something to the son,
but what good comes of that
if there is no state?"
That's what my father always said.
You are protecting his legacy, my Sultan.
You defeated all the traitors.
Thank you, Gündüz Alp.
My father has gone
to fight the traitors, too.
It's been a long time since he left.
I miss him.
But I know his duty is more important.
So, I try to stay strong.
Good for you, Gündüz Alp.
As long as brave men
father such brave sons,
I know the state shall prevail.
It will, my Sultan.
Take a good look round.
Stop!
Your Eminence.
They've withdrawn into the forest.
I'm going to find and kill them
even if they're in hell.
Commander, cover our backs.
As you command, Your Eminence.
You're responsible for covering our front.
Search everywhere.
Leave no stone unturned.
Ertuğrul is not to leave
this forest alive. Got it?
-Yes, sir.
-Good.
Right. Time to show ourselves.
Ertuğrul!
Come on, brothers.
For our state, for our country,
for our late Sultan Alaeddin.
For Aslihan Hatun.
For every one of our fallen brothers.
Attack!
For God!
-For God!
Kayraldi!
We're here, Ertuğrul Bey.
Traitors!
Ertuğrul!
Köpek's running away!
My Bey, Aslihan Hatun's dagger!
Kill Köpek with it.
My goodness, Mother!
What a nice cap. Did you make it?
Yes.
For Bamsi and Hafsa's baby.
My dear Hafsa.
I wonder what she's doing now?
Do you think she's all right?
Do you think she's better?
I'm sure she is, dear. I'm sure she is.
There isn't anything we can do
except pray for her.
God willing, she'll return
to our tribe soon with her baby.
God willing, Mother.
Aslihan's death, Hafsa leaving...
It all came at once.
And Ertuğrul.
It's been a long time, Mother.
I know, his is a difficult task.
But bearing the longing
in my heart is difficult too.
My dear daughter.
A long time ago...
my husband, Suleyman Shah...
would leave on perilous missions
and I'd feel just the same as you.
And now I wait like that once more...
whenever Ertuğrul is gone.
What keeps us going...
is the just cause of those who are gone.
True, Mother.
I hope that Ertuğrul destroys
the tyrants with his own sword
and disperses the dark clouds above us.
The sun will rise over our country again.
I hope Ertuğrul brings light
to our tribe and tent again soon, Mother.
I hope so too, dear. I hope so too.
May Ertuğrul return victorious to us.
I hope the sun comes with your baby.
I hope so too, Mother.
I hope so.
May God protect Ertuğrul for our state,
our country and our children.
Amen, dear. Amen.
Ertuğrul...
Look at yourself.
My path I walk will be soaked
with your blood.
Stubborn. Always so stubborn.
Your stubbornness brought you to this.
Was it worth it?
Was it? Tell me.
If you'd obeyed me we could
have united to save the state.
The state will be saved...
when you die, Sadettin.
I've only ever loved two things.
My state...
and Aslihan.
You made Aslihan my enemy.
You took her from me.
You made me spill my beloved's blood.
But it's over.
I've dedicated my life
to ascending the Seljuk throne,
I won't let you take it from me.
I'm going to kill you with
the dagger of the woman you murdered.
Günalp.
My son, Günalp!
Kill him!
Kill him, finish this!
Emir Sadettin...
Did you kill Sultan Alaeddin?
Tell me, now!
Do you lie that you are a prince
so that you can be sultan?
Can you hear the words
coming out of your mouth?
Don't lie to me!
You declared yourself to be a prince.
So I did!
You... are obliged to obey my command!
Yes, I killed the sultan!
Because that throne is my right.
My right!
Now, you will obey me
and kill Ertuğrul. Do it!
You are a liar!
Everything you've said
up to now has been a lie!
I won't allow you to poison
anyone else with your lies.
Ertuğrul Bey.
This dog deserves to feel your sword.
Bastard!
Your father didn't obey me either.
Your father rebelled against me.
Your parents got what they deserved.
I raised you...
And you disobeyed me.
Just like them... you have to die.
The path of migration...
is so perilous.
Shelter...
so far away.
There is no road that doesn't end.
Do not feel remorse, Sultan Sadettin.
Aslıhan...
No more dark words, Köpek.
It's time dark blood ran down dark steel.
Time the dark soil is drenched in blood.
Time the dark clouds dispersed...
before the brightness of the new day.
As with our other gallants...
your death was not in vain, Aslıhan.
My loyal castle commander, Günalp Bey.
Leave us now and resume your duties.
I entrust Karacahisar to you.
Aslıhan was avenged, my bey.
She was, Turgut.
Thank you, my bey.
Ertuğrul.
Brother.
By command of our sultan...
the head of the traitor has been severed,
Husamettin Karaca.
We have done our duty.
I will take command of the army.
-Rest easy now.
-Thank you.
May God bless you.
May God bless you too, Ertuğrul Bey.
We will display that dog Sadettin's
head for the people to see...
just as he planned to do to you.
May the traitors among us,
and the enemies which covet our land,
know of Köpek's end.
May they know it so
that they can have no doubt...
that our state will be eternal.
May they come to know with certainty
that no one can destroy the Turkish state.
Allahu akbar!
Köpek will be on the road to Samsat soon.
My sultan,
Ertuğrul Bey will have dealt with that
bastard before he has a chance to move.
I'm sure we'll hear
from Ertuğrul Bey soon.
I hope they signal good news.
At this time of night...
It is unusual for someone
to approach the tribe so late.
My sultan, if you will allow it,
let us go check who it is.
-May I enter, my sultan?
-Come in.
My sultan.
My sultan, good news,
Ertuğrul Bey has returned.
Ertuğrul Bey?
Thank you, God.
My sultan.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-I'm glad to be back, my sultan.
-I hope you bring good news.
With God's permission, the duty you
gave us has been fulfilled, my sultan.
The menace that was Sadettin Köpek
has been dealt with.
The road we embarked upon
to secure the future of our state...
led either to martyrdom or victory.
Thank God, with his help...
it led to our victory.
The traitors among us,
and the enemies who supported them,
have been disappointed, my sultan.
Justice prevailed
and the evil-doers punished.
You have avenged our late sultan,
Alaeddin Kayqubad...
Turgut Bey's wife, Aslıhan Hatun...
and all those suffering
oppression, Ertuğrul Bey.
The sun of the state
rises once more over our land.
Stories of your heroism
will be told and retold for centuries.
"No matter how big the snake's head...
our swords will suffice
to sever its head."
That's what you said, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God gaze upon your heart,
your wrist and your sword.
I came to understand that a state grows
not only with the might of its reign...
but with the loyalty and skill...
of the brave men who
offer their lives in its service.
May God not deprive our state
of brave men like yourselves.
Thank you, Mahperi Hatun.
This is my command...
Ertuğrul Bey, the title
of frontier bey is once again yours.
These lands shall be under
your command and rule.
May the Seljuk banner be raised
once more at the tribe and the castle.
I shall ride back to Konya
and resume my duties.
My mother will no longer
involve herself with matters of state
and will remain at the Alaiye Palace.
As you wish, my sultan.
I am content as long as you
and our state prosper.
With your permission, my sultan...
Mother.
My son.
As you said...
I proved myself worthy of both my
ancestors' blood and your milk, Mother.
My brave son.
May God keep you with us always, my son.
-Amen.
-May God keep you with us always, Mother.
My Ertuğrul Bey.
My brave son.
You rid our state and our lands
of a great evil, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God bless you.
May God bless us all, Halime Hatun.
My brave boy.
May your victory be blessed, my bey.
I hope God bestows
many victories upon you.
-Amen.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
I will leave tomorrow, God willing.
Is there anything you wish of me
before I go, Ertuğrul Bey?
My sultan, my only wish is
that you fare well...
and that your reign
furthers the power of our state.
And we will begin the preparations
that will see Sogut become our home.
A new era has begun for us all.
My sultan...
we founded this state with our
pure faith, our honorable blood,
and our unwavering courage.
As long as these continue undiminished
nobody's power will be such that
they can harm the state of the Turks.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net