Episode 112 will start after 12:05 min.
The corpses have been gathered.
Taceddin Kayraldi.
Find that traitor and bring him to me.
His wife's brother works for us.
He's there now. It's not far.
I'll be back with him soon.
Good. Reach out to Günalp Bey.
Tell him to come here.
I have an important mission for him.
As you command, Eminence.
You've escaped a deadly plot, Sadettin.
And you saved me from a dagger.
You fought with me against my enemies.
You're welcome.
As I said, I came here
to make a deal with you.
Not a deal with Governor Kritos,
but one with you.
Stay with Governor Kritos.
When the time comes, I'll help you
and give you back your title.
But first, we must finish off
Ertuğrul and the Kayis.
Your reputation and vengeance...
along with my dynasty,
will rise above Ertuğrul's blood.
Ertuğrul's blood? Deal.
From now on, your bey is nothing.
Neither are you!
His rage has cost him his title.
Tomorrow I take back Söğüt.
You little--
Stop!
What are you doing?
Where will violence get you?
I'll show you violence!
Bamsi!
You'll be held accountable
for this, Aydoğmus.
Your bey is no longer the frontier bey.
Know your place.
Otherwise, we won't let you live.
Soldiers! Untie Governor Kritos.
Our frontier bey, Günalp Bey,
will see him in his chamber.
Now I have to let Governor Kritos go
so he can sign the peace agreement.
That is what the state commands.
Ertuğrul Bey?
I had no idea the Sultan
was going to issue this decree.
Nor do I know why he's done it.
But that is what the state commands.
I have to abide by it.
As much as I know
your intentions are pure...
I also know that Emir Sadettin has drawn
a veil across your eyes, Günalp Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey.
I knew that this would happen
sooner or later, Günalp Bey.
Emir Sadettin,
through one mischief or another,
has forced our Sultan
into signing this decree.
Don't, Ertuğrul Bey.
You don't know Emir Sadettin.
You don't know
what he's done for the state.
He has stood beside our Sultan
through many a battle.
I know his heart best, Günalp Bey.
Sadettin is not for the good of the state,
the state is for the good of Sadettin.
Choose your side.
I earned the right to this castle
and the frontier bey title with my sword.
I surrender them to you now
in the name of my state
so that blood need not be shed.
I am consoled by the fact
that I surrender it
to a valiant castle commander
who will defend Karacahisar
until his last breath.
Thank you.
I will go to Söğüt with my tribe.
But that dog, Governor Kritos,
will not leave you be there.
We have no fear of anyone, thank God.
Keep your eyes open.
Emir Sadettin has taken control
of the state. Don’t fall for his tricks.
He has no loyalties, Günalp Bey.
Just as he did for our Sultan,
if you should someday stand in his way...
know that he won't hesitate
to destroy you too.
May God be with you and aid you.
Ertuğrul Bey.
If the day comes when you find yourself
in a bad situation in Söğüt...
know that you have a friend
at Karacahisar Castle.
Thank you.
If Ertuğrul manages to evade Kritos' trap
it'll leave him even angrier
with you and him.
There's nothing he can do.
I relieved him of the title
of frontier bey with the Sultan's decree.
What?
How?
How did you persuade
the Sultan to do that?
It is useful to know when to use the power
at your disposal.
I persuaded him with that power.
However...
he gave Söğüt to Ertuğrul
so that he can settle there.
You isolated Ertuğrul.
You left him alone
with Governor Kritos at Söğüt.
With Governor Kritos
and with you, Ares, right?
I've laid Ertuğrul out before you.
Now it's your turn. Finish him off.
You will be the one
who profits most out of this, Ares.
Kill Ertuğrul, and be governor once again.
Not even becoming emperor could compare
to getting revenge on Ertuğrul.
Don't worry about Ertuğrul.
Leave him to me. I'll deal with him.
But now I have to get back to Bilecik.
I will expect good news from you, Ares.
My bey. My bey.
My bey.
Are we to leave the castle
that we conquered, just like that, my bey?
This is not the time for us to rise up,
even if what has befallen us
is a great injustice, Bamsi.
Justice has yet to be served.
Sadettin Köpek has gotten what he wanted
by forcing our Sultan into a tight spot.
The situation our Sultan
finds himself in...
shows that our state
is at greater risk than I had thought.
Know that this is my most important
command to you as your bey.
It's not only our duty to defend
our castle and our tribe...
but every land which makes up our state.
Wherever a fire might burn
in our homeland...
we will be there.
Let Günalp Bey be the frontier bey.
But the castle in which he is to remain
will be forever protected by our lineage.
We will not forget the blood
of our martyr's in its soil.
Our glorious banner
will always fly over Karacahisar.
-As you say, my bey.
May God never take you from us, my bey.
-Amen.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
You've made a sound decision, my bey.
There would have been
no stopping the bloodshed otherwise.
Now...
it's time we saw
our banner flying over Söğüt.
We know what Köpek's intentions are.
He knows I won't leave Söğüt.
He wants to feed us to Kritos.
We'll send that jackal
to lie next to his son, my bey.
Thank you, Bamsi.
I have no doubt you will.
We'll let them think
they've turned us into bait.
We'll be the ones doing the hunting.
Next...
we light a fire in Söğüt.
The Turk tribes, the Turk beys...
will come together around that fire.
We have but one other mission.
We're going to kill Emir Sadettin.
You summoned me, my bey.
Gunkut,
get this letter to our Sultan right away.
This isn't just a letter
I'm entrusting to you.
It is the honor of the Kayi tribe
and our state.
This letter is to be read by no one
but the Sultan, understand?
As you command, my bey.
Show me what you're made of.
Come on, men.
Door.
I'm begging you,
please let me out of here.
You'll get out.
They were cruel to you.
But Emir Sadettin showed you mercy.
You know who it is
you should work for, right?
I will show Artuk Bey.
They will all suffer at my hands.
Good.
-I have your first task.
-I'll do whatever you want.
You will go to Governor Kritos at Bilecik.
We want to know everything
that goes on there.
It would be my pleasure.
I'm indebted to you.
Don't doubt
that I will pay you back in full.
If you try to escape,
know that you will suffer
the full force of Emir Sadettin's fury.
You can be sure that I will do my duty.
Very good.
We will await news from you.
Leave without being seen once Ertuğrul
and his alps have left the castle.
God!
My bey.
Is what they're saying true?
My alps.
The castle that we took
with the blood of many martyrs,
we now entrust back to the state.
No one should despair over this.
No one should blame
the state nor feel anger towards it.
We conquered this castle for our state
and we surrender it to the state.
Our arms are strong, our swords are sharp.
Our swords will
be raised yet again in battle
and conquer other castles.
-As you say, my bey.
What makes a state is the obedience
of its people, Günalp Bey.
Your loyalty to Emir Sadettin
will strengthen both you and the state.
And bring peace and tranquility to us.
I'm glad to have brought peace
to this land with a man such as yourself.
The peace that Ertuğrul
would have denied us...
we will enjoy together.
The time of reckoning will come, Ertuğrul.
It will come.
I will deal with you
when you get to Söğüt.
Ertuğrul Bey got knocked down to size,
turned tail and ran.
If Ertuğrul Bey
wasn't so loyal to his state,
he would have executed you on the spot.
And after what you did, Governor,
I would have let him.
Günalp Bey, the peace treaty
has been rewritten as per your orders.
Leave it.
If...
you make any attempt to harm Ertuğrul
when he reaches Söğüt, I will crush you.
Don't forget that.
That dagger mark will remind you of it.
Think carefully before you sign it.
Know well what will happen
if you don't keep your word.
May God render our
peace treaty everlasting.
Aydoğmus,
escort Governor Kritos out of the castle.
As you command.
What's going on?
Come on, let's go see.
-Don't take the flag down.
-Why are they doing this?
-Why are you taking it down?
-Look! He's taking it down.
-What are you doing?
-This isn't right.
What are you doing? What is this?
What are you doing, son?
Why are you taking down our banner?
Our Sultan commands it.
Ertuğrul Bey is no longer
the frontier bey.
-What does that mean?
-What did he say?
-How could this be?
-What are you talking about?
The new frontier bey is Günalp Bey.
That's why we're taking down the banners.
This was sure to happen.
We told you it would, Aslıhan Hatun.
This is not the time.
We said we shouldn't stand against
the state. Ertuğrul Bey didn't listen.
We can't migrate to Söğüt now.
Beys.
Is this the time to say such things?
Say what you will to Ertuğrul Bey
when he gets back.
-She's right.
We should wait for Ertuğrul Bey.
What do you think you're doing?
Mother. What do we do now?
Are we just going to stand here?
We need to be patient, my girl.
Ertuğrul Bey will return to us soon.
We'll deal with this
as we've dealt with trouble before.
We will!
May I come in, my bey?
Come.
Ertuğrul and all his alps
have left the castle, my bey.
God Almighty commands in the Qur'an,
"We fulfilled Our promise to them
in the end:
We saved them and those
We wished to save,
and We destroyed those who
exceeded all bounds."
Do you think you're overstepping, my bey?
Do you doubt you did the right thing?
I have fought shoulder
to shoulder with Ertuğrul Bey.
I saw for myself
that his strength, his resolve
and his courage come from his faith.
When you stand side by side
with such a man...
how can doubt not eat you up inside?
So, you doubt not only yourself,
but Emir Sadettin as well.
I won't let the death of your father,
your mother
or these valiant men be in vain.
I will put an end
to this damn war of princes.
I will make an honorable soldier,
an honorable castle commander, out of you.
Emir Sadettin is like a father to me.
But I fear he may be on the wrong path.
May I enter, my bey?
Come.
Emir Sadettin has sent
a pigeon with a message.
Our sultan and state are at risk.
I await you at the caravansary.
Make haste. Emir Sadettin Köpek.
Emir Sadettin awaits.
Prepare my horse!
Send the scouts to the Kayi tribe.
I want to be kept informed
of Ertuğrul's every move.
Yes, my bey.
Come, Marya, sit.
I'm here to help you
get revenge on the Turks, sir.
You don't need to do anything, Marya.
You have served me
well enough all this time.
You can live as you wish from now on.
I stayed with the Turks
for a long time, sir.
I know a great deal about Ertuğrul Bey
and the rest of his kin.
I can point out
their many weaknesses to you.
All I want is to serve our holy cause.
Ertuğrul has to die.
Only you are capable of doing it.
I will do anything to achieve it.
Wonderful.
And...
what have you heard about Ares?
Nothing, sir.
Last I knew, he'd been taken to Konya.
Ares...
has managed to escape
Ertuğrul and now serves me.
How could this be, sir?
He killed my brother.
I know.
If you want to stay here...
you will have to resolve
your dispute with Ares, Marya.
You will have to reconcile
if you are both to serve our cause.
I want you to get close
to him and earn his trust.
You will bring me news of him.
Ares... may use me
to recover his reputation
so that he can become governor again.
He's not one of us, but we can use him.
As you wish, sir.
Hayme Hatun, Ertuğrul Bey has been
relieved of his position as frontier bey.
You cannot stand up to the state.
If we migrate to Söğüt,
they'll never leave us be there.
Let go of this ambition.
It is our responsibility to stay here
and protect our tribe.
Migrating to Söğüt makes no sense.
What is this, beys?
Why are your voices raised?
What makes no sense? Tell me.
Ertuğrul Bey,
they've got us in a corner.
You're no longer the frontier bey.
Give up on the migration.
Don't throw us into the fire.
Titles come and go, beys.
What lasts forever is the will of God.
Our path is clear.
It is a hard one. Rough.
But there is light at the end of it.
It's for the best.
Söğüt was entrusted to us
by Sultan Alaeddin.
It falls on us to protect
that which was entrusted to us.
We won't leave Söğüt to anyone else.
Those who lack the strength to ride
this path have no place among us.
We follow this path with the brave,
with those who do
not fear for their lives.
The ones who aspire to this path
are welcome to come with us.
Those who don't can stay here in peace.
Excuse us, Ertuğrul Bey.
Don't let anyone despair.
Don't think that we were crushed
and forced to retreat.
We are like a bow pulled tight.
When the times comes,
we will let loose like an arrow.
If the Cavdars leave us now
it will be to their disadvantage.
We should not let that happen.
My bey, what if the Cavdar beys
insist on staying where they are?
I've said all I will, Aslıhan Hatun.
Those who have the strength
will come with us.
Those who don't can stay here in peace.
Turgut.
If the Cavdars don't come,
you must remain at the head of your tribe.
You must stay with the Cavdars,
even if we go to Söğüt.
Stay as their bey.
I...
How can I stay if you leave, my bey?
Turgut.
The bey of a tribe is its mast.
If a tribe loses its leader,
it will sway and bend
like a leaf in the wind.
As you command, my bey.
Traitors! Scum! Let go!
-Let go of me!
-Get down!
What's the meaning of this, Sadettin?
Revenge, Taceddin Pervane.
Let go!
Revenge.
So...
So you thought
you could go behind my back?
Did you think I wouldn't make you
and the ones behind you pay?
Did you think I wouldn't
exact my retribution?
You think that your betrayal
and plotting will go unpunished? Scum!
Bastard!
Everyone will see who the scum is.
Do you think I don't know
what an immoral man you are?
Did you think I didn't know about
your affair with that singer from Akşehir?
-Lies! Slander!
-It's true.
I have the witnesses to prove it.
The punishment for your immoral behavior
is death by stoning.
I will put the wheels of justice in motion
and have you stoned, Taceddin Pervane.
Your reputation will be destroyed.
Liar! Slanderer! Bastard!
Sadettin Köpek!
You won't get your hands on this state!
You have killed innocent people,
just like you are about to do to me.
A hero will rise and put an end to you,
count on it!
This state is mine!
Understand? It's mine!
Nobody can stop me!
Let go of me! Let go!
Bastards!
The state is mine!
I'll kill every one of you!
The whole world will know
who Sadettin Köpek is!
Take him away.
Bury him up to his waist
and have him stoned in the morning.
Yes, Eminence.
-Here, Brother.
-Thank you.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-Here, love.
-Thank you.
Both Cavdar beys...
and our people look like
they want to stay.
As things currently stand,
on the orders of my bey, I'll stay here.
I can't bring myself to do it.
However, I can't cross my bey either.
Things will work out, Turgut.
Don't you worry.
They may decide to come with us,
and we can go all together.
Even if you stay here,
Söğüt is just around the corner.
We'll fight many more battles together.
Of course, Brother.
We'll go from battle to battle together.
I hope so, Brother.
Come on, stop sulking everyone.
It's not the end of the world.
Just as Ertuğrul Bey earned
his status as Margrave with his efforts,
he'll get it again.
We need to stand strong beside him.
They are trying to intimidate us
with all kinds of plotting.
However, we will never yield.
We won't give in to their cruelty.
So long as Emir Sadettin is alive,
this won't stop.
That bastard needs to die.
We'll never be at peace
as long as he's alive.
His time will come, too, Aslıhan Hatun.
There's time for that.
Rest easy.
He'll keep getting stronger as we wait.
That bastard has to die.
However, many more will die.
Many more.
What was that, Aslıhan Hatun?
What do you mean?
Emir Sadettin is a man
blinded by ambition.
I fear many innocents will die
because of his ambition and hatred.
God protect us from his evil.
Ertuğrul Bey wants us to wait.
There must be a reason.
Let that bastard think...
that he's won this time.
These lands will be awash
with his blood at the end of all this.
I hope so, Turgut.
I hope no more innocents die.
May I enter?
Come in, son.
-As-Salaam-Alaikum.
-Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Those seeking peace
find anguish instead, son.
This world is a burden on the believers.
Tell me, what makes you so sad?
What are you burdened with?
We beat our enemies one by one.
However, we're troubled
by the traps of the traitors
struck at the heart of our country
like a rusty dagger.
I'm putting up with this cruelty
so that our country may not be tarnished,
and the innocent don't die.
However, it's hard on my people.
Bigger troubles find those
with higher authority, son.
You are responsible for the people.
That's why it's heavy on you.
However, you have God's help.
That's because you don't act with greed.
You do what's right in the name of God.
Sometimes, what may look like a loss
is actually a victory.
I was just reading Surah Al-Fath.
I was amazed by God's wisdom once again.
Prophet Muhammad once had a dream,
and had his followers prepare...
for umrah based upon it.
His companions were overjoyed...
because some had to leave their families,
others their jobs
and houses in Mecca due to Hegira.
They took to the road
with their burning sense
of seeing Mecca years later,
and with the hopes
of seeing Kaaba once again.
However, those practicing idolatry,
who found out about their visit,
tried to obstruct the Muslims
upon learning that the Muslims would visit
even when they'd let even the enemy in.
At last, a messenger was sent
and they made a deal.
This deal was seemingly
against the Muslims.
They would return without being able
to see Kaaba as per the deal.
The Muslims were upset.
It was heavy on their hearts
not being able to see Kaaba,
which they had been waiting
to see for so long.
However, as it says in Surah Inshirah,
surely, ease comes along with the trouble.
God's wisdom manifests itself.
Surah Al-Fath was sent
on the way back to Madinah.
Our Prophet was announced
with the good news of conquest.
God said thus in Surah Al-Fath:
"Indeed, we've given you a clear conquest.
That God may forgive what preceded
of your sin and what will follow.
And complete his favor upon you,
and guide you to a straight path.
And God may aid you
with a mighty victory."
Good and wisdom is hidden
in what we see as bad.
May God let us see that good.
Amen, son.
Now, you must bear with
the bellowing people.
They are like fire now.
And if that fire spreads to the country,
it'd hurt everyone.
Your path is full of hardships now.
It's dark.
However, light awaits at the end.
Keep walking that path, son.
I'll pray for you.
Thank you.
You wanted to see me, Your Highness?
The men Taceddin Pervane
sent to kill Sadettin...
they failed, Mother.
Köpek got away from the ambush.
They killed Taceddin's men.
Now, he'll be even more cautious.
What about Taceddin Pervane?
Nobody knows where he is.
But I'm sure Köpek
will find him right away.
Köpek will kill him.
He'll kill him like he did Altun Aba.
Today, he'll be stronger
and more frantic than before.
Grant his wishes until your authority
allows you to kill him, Your Highness.
You must do this for the well-being
of our country.
Enough of that!
Enough!
This all happened because of you.
Because of your greed!
And now, you want me to serve
under that dog.
You have to, son.
That's not true.
-That's not true, Mother!
-Then, what will you do?
If he knows that you are against him,
he'll kill you.
And he'll give the throne
to one of his children.
Köpek has a grasp on all the officials
in our government.
He is the government.
Control your anger.
First, get me out of the room
you locked me in.
Once you get back from Amid with victory,
everyone will see who the real
ruler of our country is.
And it will mean Sadettin's end.
We will go along with it
if patience is what it takes
for the throne.
We will make him pay, soon.
So,
they killed yet another young prince.
I can't bear it, Ertuğrul.
The country that my forefathers strived
so hard to build is in tatters now.
And now, it's our turn.
We won't shun
our country because of traitors.
We won't turn our backs on it.
They will perish sooner or later.
But our duty is to strive
to keep our country straight.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Our people may lose hope
now that you are no longer a margrave.
If they lose their hope,
it's our job to give them hope.
If they collapse, it's our job
to build them back up.
Talk to the women, Halime.
Tell them to stay resolute
and strong.
Spring always comes after winter.
And all nights store dawn in its wake.
May I enter, sir?
What could it be?
I hope nothing bad.
Come in, Artuk Bey.
Sir.
I shall excuse myself.
I'll go see Aslıhan Hatun.
All right, love.
What is it, Artuk Bey?
There's a letter
from the White Beards, sir.
"The Oghuz beys will revolt.
The country and Turkmen tribes
will fall out with each other."
It seems they are sick of the doings
of Sadettin Köpek.
We can't let our country and those tribes
fall out with each other because of him.
The White Beards want us
to stop this revolt.
If we can't stop it fast,
it'll be the end of our country.
Abdur Rahman!
-Yes, sir.
-Send for my brother, Sungur,
Turgut Bey and Commander Bamsi.
Have them ready their men.
Prepare the horses,
we'll depart right away.
As you wish, sir.
So, I saved my country
from an immoral and greedy man
like Taceddin Pervane.
We will now rid our country
of all these cancerous men.
Ertuğrul included.
I know you would do anything
for the good of our country.
However, Ertuğrul...
I doubt he'd go against
the traditions of our country.
What do you mean, Günalp?
Ertuğrul Bey would have done anything
to protect the castle
and his status, if he so wanted.
However, he gave up
what was rightfully his
so that he wouldn't go
against the country.
Günalp...
Son.
You still haven't realized
Ertuğrul's true motives.
Ertuğrul gave up on what was
rightfully his not because of that,
but because of the fact that
his power couldn't match mine.
If it was any other emir,
he wouldn't even pay heed to Sultan.
I traveled with Ertuğrul Bey.
I fought back-to-back with him.
He's a brave man.
I didn't see greed for power,
not in his words, nor his eyes.
But you know best.
Günalp.
My brave son.
You, too, will one day see
the kind of man Ertuğrul really is.
You will have no doubts
about his treachery, either.
However, never mind that now.
There's something more important.
I called you here for that.
Yes, sir.
Some Turkish beys will try
to unite and revolt.
Revolt? But why?
They lost control after
Sultan Alaeddin’s passing away.
And since Sultan Gıyaseddin is still
a child to them, they want to revolt.
They think they can
steal whatever they want
from the country and bring forth disorder.
But our country would never yield
to some marauders.
Would it?
Never.
The well-being of our country
depends on you, Günalp.
You must put an end to this mutiny.
Make an example of them
so they can never forget.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Go now.
Excuse me.
You may leave.
It was obvious
Emir Sadettin wouldn't stop.
I knew it.
But nobody listened to me.
Nobody. We'll be in even more
trouble if we go to Söğüt.
We will fall apart because of
that bastard Sadettin Köpek.
He'll cause bigger troubles
if nobody stops him.
It's all my fault.
What did you say, Aslıhan?
What does it have to do with you?
Ever since I became Turgut's wife,
he treats both of us as his enemy.
He hurts me and those around me.
He's blinded by the thirst of revenge.
He won't leave us be
as long as he lives.
Aslıhan Hatun.
We must leave this matter to the men.
All we can do is be patient.
This matter affects
both men and women alike.
We must kill that bastard
where and when
he least expects it
so he can't run away.
Aslıhan Hatun.
You will see.
Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut Bey
will beat him.
Emir Sadettin has the whole country
backing him.
It will be hard for Turgut
and Ertuğrul Bey
to deal with him now.
If they cross Sadettin Köpek,
innocents will die.
It's better for one person to die...
to save thousands,
instead of thousands of innocents dying.
Aslıhan...
Sister.
He was a bey to you,
and a brother to me.
He was a terrific man
that put up with me and supported me.
He has now passed from this world.
He rests in peace here.
Now, it's our turn to stand up for him.
We will stand erect.
We will protect our tribe, traditions
and our unity in his path.
Let it be known
that our tribe will not
be left without a leader.
Until a new bey is elected,
I will shoulder my brother's legacy.
I swore to protect our tribe, Brother.
I promised that I would not let
our tribe fall apart,
and that I'd protect it.
I gave up on my life
for our tribes,
for my Turgut and Ertuğrul Bey.
It's now time to take revenge
on that bastard Sadettin Köpek.
You will die by my hands, Köpek!
What's he doing here?
Isn't he one of Günalp's dogs?
Who are you to stop me in my tracks?
You shall not pass, Ertuğrul Bey.
And who is stopping me? You?
I will!
I see. You are one of Köpek's dogs,
and you owe this boldness to him.
Watch your mouth, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'm a soldier of this country.
If you go against a soldier
of your country,
you will pay for it dearly.
You heard him, everyone.
Don't draw your swords.
Attack!
Ertuğrul Bey.
I'm a soldier of your government.
You are lucky that I'm in a hurry,
or I'd have beaten you to a pulp.
If you attempt something like this again,
I'll crush you under the shoes
of my horse.
Tell this to the one holding your leash.
Come on, everyone.
Everyone.
Begin the preparations.
Prepare the ox carts.
Collect up your things.
Have the shepherds
take our herds to the highlands.
Prepare dried meat to eat
during the migration.
Halime. Personally guide everyone.
Make sure everything is prepared orderly.
Yes, Mother.
-May I enter, Mother Hayme?
-Come in, dear.
Aslıhan Hatun wasn't at her tent,
Mother Hayme.
I looked everywhere, asked everyone.
-Nobody saw her.
-What did you say, Bürçe?
Where could she have gone?
I don't know. She took some of her things.
Her horse wasn't there, either.
I was worried and wanted
to let you know, Mother Hayme.
Well done, dear.
Halime, let's go look for her.
Dear, let the men know.
Tell them to look for Aslıhan Hatun.
Yes, Mother Hayme.
Come on, everyone. Back to work.
Let's go, dear.
He had Taceddin Pervane
stoned to death, Mother.
Who is next?
You? Or maybe it's me.
The murderer of my father is killing
your bastards, Mother. You are next.
Should I be happy or worried?
Since one bastard kills another.
Tell me, Mother, how should I feel?
Forgive me, Son.
Forgive me.
What use is crying now?
Would God forgive you?
We will all pay the price for your sin.
I wish it was that easy
to pay for killing my father.
You left our country to that dog.
As long as Sadettin Köpek is alive,
he'll have control over our country.
Emir Taceddin.
He sent his men to kill Sadettin Köpek.
But they are all dead.
I had to fight against them.
I gained Köpek's trust.
Well done.
The fact that you gained
the trust of both Emir Sadettin
and Commander Kritos
will benefit not just them,
but it'll help us against
the emperor, as well.
Köpek will definitely want
to get back at him.
They must know Taceddin's location.
He's already sent his men after him.
No doubt, they'll kill him.
Emir Taceddin had always crossed him.
He killed yet another who opposed him.
He's gained more power in the government.
Even more than the Sultan.
Köpek wants to use me to beat
Governor Kritos as well.
He offered to make me a governor.
He thinks he can make me his ally.
He said he removed you
from your position as Margrave.
For now.
But justice will be served, Ahmet.
Köpek will let you settle in Söğüt.
However, he'll have thrown you
at the feet of Governor Kritos.
His goal...
is to destroy your tribe
by having me and Kritos join hands.
If the governor can't do it...
Günalp will try to end us.
I trust Günalp in that respect.
For now, it's good
that Günalp is the margrave.
If Emir Sadettin tries
to attack us violently,
Günalp will try to stop it.
He thinks Söğüt will be our grave.
Let them think it's going to be
our grave, Bamsi.
However...
Nobody will be able to stop
the holy plane tree
that will be born in Söğüt.
Allah!
Stay with the governor, Ahmet.
Keep your connection with Köpek.
The intel you gather
from both Köpek and the governor
is very important.
As you wish, sir.
We're going through harsh times, Ahmet.
I know what you are doing is not easy.
However, bear with me a bit longer.
It will all pass.
And you will come to live
with us in our tribe.
Thank you, sir. I hope so.
Where is that girl?
If you had to go somewhere,
why didn't you tell anyone?
This is unacceptable.
May I enter?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
What happened?
Could you find Aslıhan Hatun?
We looked everywhere.
But we couldn't find her.
Nobody saw her, either.
Did she tell you anything?
Where could she have gone?
She didn't tell me anything.
I don't understand why she'd do this.
Emir Sadettin has the whole country
backing him up.
It's hard for Turgut and Ertuğrul Bey
to deal with him now.
If they cross Sadettin Köpek,
innocents will die.
It's better for one person to die...
to save thousands,
instead of thousands of innocents dying.
Mother!
Artuk Bey!
I'm afraid Aslıhan Hatun
went to Emir Sadettin.
What did you say?
Why would she go there?
I was with Aslıhan Hatun yesterday.
She keeps blaming herself
for what Emir Sadettin has done.
She said it's better for one person
to die if it saves thousands.
I'm afraid he went to Emir Sadettin
to kill him.
She's sacrificing herself to save us.
That's not possible.
Oh, Aslıhan, my dear.
May God protect her.
Amen.
Then, let me send our alps
to check all the roads to Konya.
That'd be good, Artuk Bey.
Go in peace.
We haven't been able to live peacefully
since Sultan Alaeddin passed away.
That devil, so called Sadettin Kopek,
wants to remove us from our own homeland.
We'll show both Kopek and the state
who we are
We will!
Everyone swear an oath on their swords.
Ertuğrul Bey, son of Suleyman Shah
and the leader of the Kayis, is here.
Ertuğrul Bey is here.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey?
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, glorious beys of Oguz.
Please take a seat.
Thanks.
Here you go, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
What brings you here, Ertuğrul Bey?
Are you here to support us?
Put your swords,
on which you were going to swear,
back in their sheaths, beys.
I'm not here to support you,
I'm here to stop you.
We all know you for your bravery
and your honesty, Ertuğrul Bey.
We respect you.
But the issue is different.
We can't take it anymore.
There is no turning back from this path.
Right, there is no turning back.
I know about Sadettin Kopek's cruelty
better than any one of you.
But rebellion is not the way
to stop him and to warn the state.
What else can we do, Ertuğrul Bey?
Should we just sit
and watch his massacres?
Beys...
Mongols in the eastern borders,
Byzantium in the western borders,
they are all waiting for a weakness.
They will bite, the moment
our state shows any weakness.
A rebellion will weaken the state.
We can't risk our state
just to get rid of Kopek.
Don't burn your home
to frighten the mouse away.
We can't risk our homes and the state
just because of Kopek.
Surely Kopek will be destroyed.
We are glorious beys of Oguz.
Instead of rebelling,
we should be thinking seriously.
Let's not stigmatize our reputation
and let's not leave a tainted legacy.
Being silent won't help us, Ertuğrul Bey.
We will get rid of this state
and establish a new one if necessary.
But we won't turn back from this path.
We will not!
Lady Mahperi...
Welcome, Vizier Sadettin.
Thank you, Lady Mahperi.
I see that
as soon as you arrived, you suspended
some officials in the palace.
And replaced them
with those who are loyal to you.
After the deplorable incident
I went through,
it's true that to protect our Sultan
and our state,
I've made anyone
who is loyal to Taceddin Pervane
disappear. That's correct.
What was Taceddin's fault?
I found out he had an illegitimate affair
with a songstress in Aksehir.
Of course, we couldn't possibly
let such indecency slide.
Right?
I hope you have proof to show
when our Sultan asks about it,
Vizier Sadettin.
Of course I do, Lady Mahperi.
Don't worry.
Maybe you heard about it.
A couple of bandits tried
to assassinate me
when I went to the caravansary
to meet with the governor Kritos.
I see God has spared you for us.
I hope you are not harmed.
I'm fine.
I'm very well.
But when I figure out
those who are behind the attack...
I will not leave their heads
attached to their bodies,
and their eyes inside their heads.
First, I'll remove their eyes,
which are looking down on our state.
And then I'll chop off their heads.
I'll do my best to help you
find out who is behind the attack.
I see you are no longer confined
to your chambers.
Thank God,
our Sultan realized his mistake.
Thank God.
May God protect our Sultan.
Lady Mahperi...
Hopefully, we'll make
our state everlasting.
We'll crush our enemies under our boots.
They are taking back the lands
which were given to us by our late Sultan.
They are increasing the taxes.
And they are crushing anyone
who has close relations with us.
We've had enough
of their cruelty, Ertuğrul Bey!
If...
the solution was to rebel,
I would be the first one to rebel.
There have been many bastards
like Sadettin.
Yet, they were all beaten
before they reached their goals.
But,
the state has been always there.
And so it will be.
Now,
if you love your state and your home,
put your swords back in their sheaths.
Otherwise,
you'll be standing against me.
Swords don't go back to their sheaths
once they are drawn, Beys!
Kutlu Bey, don't you know...
that a misguided sword
ends up cutting its owner?
The beys did the right thing.
You talk like you are supporting
Sadettin Kopek, Ertuğrul Bey.
Did he send you here?
There are some words...
which can end wars.
And there are words
that make you lose your head.
Watch your words, Kutlu Bey.
Everyone knows about my fight
against Sadettin Kopek.
Both your sword
and your words are misguided.
Then draw your sword and join us.
And lead us on this path.
Let's deal
with Sadettin Kopek altogether.
The fight you're talking about
is against the state, not Sadettin.
I don't fight against the state!
And I don't let anyone to do so!
When there is cruelty,
the cruel must bleed!
It's about our traditions, Ertuğrul Bey!
And shame on you all.
My tribe will teach a lesson to Sadettin
and to the state if necessary.
Everyone can go their own ways.
I appreciate this, Beys.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Well done, Ares.
You've regained Sadettin's trust
after all those things.
I admire your wit.
Thank you, Kritos.
But...
how did Ertuğrul escape from your trap?
He was prepared.
He ambushed us instead.
I told you, it's not easy
to deal with this Turk,
Kritos.
You must be patient.
You must be strong.
Or he will kill you
just like he killed your son.
Then he will conquer the Bilecik Castle.
He captured me and took me to the castle.
But you should've seen his face.
They all went mad when they learned
he was no longer Margrave.
Sadettin Kopek...
strikes again.
Now, it's up to us.
So, what will you do?
Will you wait for him to come to Sogut?
I'll be fully prepared when he comes.
Once he is here,
he'll beg me to kill him.
What about the peace?
It's not possible while Ertuğrul
and Kopek are alive.
Anyway, we'll talk later.
I have a surprising gift for you.
A gift, for me...
I wonder what that is.
The door!
Marya...
Governor Ares...
Beys...
Ertuğrul Bey is right.
I hope Kutlu Bey stops
insisting on the revolt.
Hopefully.
What's going on? Who are you?
Protectors of the state
against which you try to rebel!
In the name
of Vizier Sadettin, surrender!
Or none of you will leave here alive.
Did you say Vizier Sadettin?
We'll die before we surrender.
We won't surrender!
Vizier Sadettin ordered to kill them all,
my Bey.
Why are we waiting?
Know your place, Commander.
Mind your own business.
Beys.
I don't want to spill blood here.
This is my last warning.
Surrender.
We don't want to spill blood either.
But instead of surrendering to Sadettin
we'd create a blood bath.
A blood bath, you say.
Well then, as you wish.
There are seven of you here.
But there are nine mugs here.
Who were the other two people?
Kutlu Bey...
and...
And?
Ertuğrul Bey...
Ertuğrul Bey?
Vizier Sadettin was right.
Where are they now?
Where did they go?
Speak up!
Commander! We're going after
Ertuğrul Bey, at once.
Move.
What do you mean by blocking my way?
You either give up on the revolt,
or I will not let you pass, Kutlu Bey.
I said my final words.
Now get out of my way!
So that no harm will come to you or us.
I'm not here to spill blood, Kutlu Bey.
But I will turn this place
into a blood bath if necessary,
instead of letting you rebel
against the state.
That Kopek will make us all bleed
if we don't revolt.
What should we do?
Leave our own homeland?
No one is leaving.
If the tribes and the state clash
then the winner will be the enemy.
I won't let that happen.
We'll deal with this situation
without a revolt.
Dogs won't be barking
in the world of the wolves, Kutlu Bey.
That's my promise to you.
All the Turkish tribes will be wasted
if there is a revolt.
I won't let that happen.
And I won't let you make
such a grave mistake.
-Who is this woman?
-She wants to see Vizier Sadettin.
Why do you think you can do that?
Escort her out.
Take her to the dungeons
if she comes again.
Stay back!
Or I'll kill him and then kill you.
Let Vizier Sadettin know
that Lady Aslıhan is here.
He knows me. He'll want to see me.
I'll let him know.
But if he refuses to see you,
then you are dead.
You won't leave the palace alive.
Now let my soldier go.
Vizier Sadettin is having
a council meeting with the Sultan.
You are going to wait.
And you two watch this woman.
If she tries to do anything
do whatever is necessary.
The enemies are getting bolder
and bolder, my Sultan.
That's mostly because
of your young age, my Sultan.
They see your lack of experience
and they get bolder, my Sultan.
That's why, your and the army's reputation
will be affected badly if you go to fight
for Amid,
without conquering
the Samsat Castle first.
Vizier Sadettin is right.
That's right. It's not the time
to fight for Amid.
That's the reason why
we, as your subjects in the council,
don't think going to fight for Amid
is the right thing for you to do.
Then,
get my army ready so that I can conquer
the Samsat Castle first.
The army still needs some time
to trust your leadership, my Sultan.
What do you mean, Vizier Sadettin?
I mean I'll be in command.
Of course, if you excuse me.
Once I have conquered the Samsat Castle,
you can go with the army to fight
and save us from the trouble of Amid.
It's a great happiness for me
to have such considerate officials.
If it wasn't for your help
I wouldn't be able
to manage the state properly.
I'd like you to know
I'm grateful to you, Vizier Sadettin.
You have a point.
Go to Samsat Castle and defeat the enemy.
Then, with you
and the other precious officials
I will go to fight for Amid.
May God help you, Sadettin.
May God protect you, my Sultan.
Vizier Sadettin killed my father,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Do you know why?
He wanted my father
to kill Bektas Bey
because Bektas Bey didn't obey
Sadettin's orders.
My father chose to protect him
instead of killing him.
And for that reason,
Sadettin murdered my father.
Sadettin also tried to make my father
kill his blood brother, Kurtoglu.
He managed to make the leader of Cavdars
kill his own son.
And he got our sultan killed
by his chef, Nasuriddin Ali.
What are you saying, my Ertuğrul Bey?
Wasn't it a natural death?
His own son, Sultan Giyaseddin, said so.
At first, Sadettin tried to accuse me
of the killing of our late Sultan.
He wanted to get rid of me and my alps.
His intention was to hang me
but the Sultan saw the truth.
Then, he managed to release you
of your duties as Margrave.
Thank God, brother.
You finally understand.
What a dishonorable man he is,
Ertuğrul Bey!
He is the biggest problem
our state is facing right now.
Also know that,
he surrounded our Sultan
with officials who are loyal to himself.
The Sultan?
Our Sultan is a prisoner of Sadettin
in his own palace.
We all need to unite
to get rid of this bastard.
The question is when to kill the bastard,
not if.
That's what we are discussing, Kutlu Bey.
We would be wasted if the tribes
which have problems with Sadettin
joined a rebellion.
There would be too much blood, Kutlu Bey.
And Mongols would take the opportunity
to get rid of our state.
We, the Turkish tribes,
would be the ones that suffer, again.
Now, do you understand
our Ertuğrul Bey, Kutlu Bey?
My rage clouded my judgment.
I have to tell you
that you have a solid point, Ertuğrul Bey.
If you are available
I'd like to invite you to my tribe
to talk with my uncle, Garkin Bey.
We'd be happy to be your guests
in your tribe.
Thank you.
We're being attacked!
Protect yourselves!
Come on brother!
-This way!
-Protect yourselves, brothers!
How could you give up
on the fight for Amid
just because that bastard, Sadettin,
said so, my Sultan?
Don't you know that demon's intentions?
How could you do that?
I know he is frightened
to see me victorious
and for my reputation to grow
in the eyes of the officials, Mother.
That's why he wants
to increase his influence
by conquering Samsat Castle,
and thus controlling me.
Then why did you allow him
to do what he wanted?
You taught me how to be a sultan, mother.
You taught me to be the hunter
instead of the hunted.
What do you mean, son?
Vizier Sadettin won't come
back to Konya ever again,
whether he conquers the Samsat Castle
or not.
No one can hear us here, Mother.
Don't worry.
What are you saying, son?
For the first time,
I decided a sentence with my own will.
The death sentence of Vizier Sadettin.
What are you saying, son?
Goodness gracious.
I told you.
You'll be begging me.
Here you are, Aslıhan.
Any gem I carve...
shines only when a beautiful woman
who deserves it, wears it.
This necklace will shine on your neck.
I've made it for you.
I'd be sorry if you refused.
I'd love to see you wearing it.
Thank you, blessed Vizier.
I've made a necklace...
using my late mother's precious gems
for you.
I put it on your tender...
elegant neck...
after you swore
to be my wife forever.
And what did you do?
You married a lowly alp.
I should kill you, Aslıhan.
I should make Ertuğrul and Turgut
grieve for you
before I kill them.
Or should I...
make you the wife
of Sultan Sadettin, huh?
Or should I...
feed birds with your skin?
What should I do?
Tell me, Aslıhan. What should I do?
Tell me, huh?
May I come in?
Blessed Vizier, may I come in?
Yes.
Thank you for agreeing to see me.
What about me, Aslıhan?
Should I also be grateful to you
after all the pain you put me through?
I came to you just like you said.
Now, the past has passed.
I wish...
But the past affects the present, Aslıhan.
I can't forget the past...
neither can it desert me.
I'm here to beg you.
So you came to beg.
Is everyone alright?
-Yes, my Bey.
Who are they, Ertuğrul Bey?
Sadettin must've learned
about your meeting.
How? It's not possible.
He must have a spy in one of the tribes.
Just like he has everywhere.
If you had attempted to revolt
anyone in your tribe, including women
and children, would have been murdered.
They killed my alps.
I'll kill them all.
Just be patient, Kutlu Bey.
We are outnumbered.
We need to find a way
to get out of here first.
Our horses are far away, my Bey.
We can't make it there if we leave here.
For now, we are safe here, Turgut.
Ertuğrul Bey!
In the name
of Vizier Sadettin, surrender.
Or you'll have a bloody death
just like the other beys at the meeting.
They killed them all.
Who has authority, Commander?
I do, Ertuğrul Bey!
Günalp Bey...
Sadettin's death warrant.
We'll either revive
the legacy of my father, Selcuk Bey,
and that of my grandfather, Kutalmisoglu,
my glorious Sultan Alaeddin,
or we'll die like insects under
the tiles of this cursed palace, Mother.
This game will end here.
What kind of order is this, son?
We'll lose everything.
What do we have to lose, Mother?
What will we lose?
Our rotten bodies?
Will we lose our souls,
the ones we sold to a degenerate?
Can't you see that he will
bring us down eventually?
We have no choice.
But how would it work?
Do you think they'll let you
kill that bastard Sadettin openly?
Not openly, Mother. Not openly.
He'll go into the Samsat battle
a victorious commander.
But only his corpse will come back.
Who could you possibly trust to do this
when it endangers not only yourself
but also the state?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Why would you trust him, my Sultan?
Mother, open your eyes.
Ertuğrul Bey was always loyal
to his state and my father.
If my brother had lived,
he'd have fought for him to be Sultan
with the last breath in his body.
But you killed my brother.
So Ertuğrul Bey will be loyal to me
to ensure our state will survive.
And I have not the smallest doubt in him.
Now, you either help me
and Ertuğrul Bey kill Sadettin,
or Sadettin kills us and sweeps
through our state like a plague.
It's your decision, Mother.
So tell me, Mother.
Will you trust Ertuğrul Bey as I do?
Do we have any other choice?
Ertuğrul Bey sent me this letter.
Read it, Mother.
My Sultan, your decree has stripped me
of the Beylic your father gave to me.
Even though you were the one to seal it,
I know it was written
at the direction of Emir Sadettin.
It's obvious that he rules
the state in your name.
It's time you made a decision, my Sultan.
Either Sadettin dies,
or our state collapses.
Either our state lives or we die.
If you ally yourself with me,
I promise to serve you faithfully
and bring the traitor to account.
Otherwise, I will finish this myself.
It's your decision.
Suleyman Shah's son, Ertuğrul.
How can Ertuğrul overcome
the Emir by himself, son?
I'll be right there with him, Mother.
As will Governor Husamettin Karaca
of Sivas,
who I trust completely
and Emir Sadettin avoids.
After I read Ertuğrul Bey's letter,
I sent word to Karaca.
When Sadettin returns from battle
and is resting at Sivas,
he and Ertuğrul Bey will kill the Emir.
That's why you changed
your mind about Amid.
That's why you sent Sadettin to Samsat,
to keep him away from Konya.
Forgive me, son.
I killed your father without trusting you.
Now I understand that I made
a terrible mistake.
You should know, until my last breath,
I will never betray you.
May God help us.
What's he doing here, Bey?
Obviously,
Sadettin Kopek has assigned his best man
to stop the rebellion against him.
Ertuğrul.
Can you still trust this man
to do the right thing?
He's either a soldier blinded by loyalty
or nothing more than
Sadettin Kopek's puppet.
If he keeps acting this way,
I'll kill him with my own two hands,
however good his intentions are.
There's only eight of you there.
Resistance is pointless.
Ertuğrul Bey,
I intend to take your life myself.
Surrender now.
Forget his intentions, my Bey.
Let's kill them all.
-I'm going to talk to him.
-Don't do it, Ertuğrul.
He thinks you're working
with the traitors.
There's no way he'll believe you.
I have to, brother.
Let's talk, Günalp Bey.
I'm not interested
in anything you have to say.
I've seen what type of a man you are.
What are you doing, my Bey?
I'm looking for a way to stall them
so we can get out of here, Turgut.
Take care of yourselves.
Listen to me, Günalp Bey.
If you still want to kill me after that,
I'll give you your chance.
I was right.
So, I was right.
But it's not that simple, Aslihan.
I was prepared to do anything for you.
Do you know who the
stones in this necklace belonged to?
My late mother.
I wanted...
this to adorn your beautiful neck...
and honor her memory with you.
I loved you that much.
I wanted you...
to be my wife and raise
sons and daughters who would
keep my legacy alive.
What did you do?
You walked all over me, Aslihan.
You... crushed me.
You married Turgut.
Turgut! For what reason?
Because of your loyalty to Ertuğrul.
You destroyed
the strongest Emir of Seljuk, Aslihan.
So, I was right.
Right, right.
But does it matter, Aslihan?
Does it matter?
Seeing that I was right...
tell me,
why did you come here?
To throw yourself at my feet
and beg for my forgiveness?
To seek refuge,
and ask me to forgive Turgut and Ertuğrul?
Why are you here, Aslihan?
So that you may save my tribe from
Ertuğrul's never-ending ambition.
So that you may stop him and Turgut taking
us to Sogut and letting us die there.
I beg you, Your Eminence.
Give me my tribe back.
Was it worth it?
How could it be?
My father, my brothers,
many of our alps, all sacrificed
to satisfy Ertuğrul's greed.
How could it be?
Here I am...
begging...
for your forgiveness.
A desperate and helpless woman...
and someone who you loved
not so very long ago.
You are the most powerful Emir
in our state.
I'm begging you, Emir Sadettin.
Save my tribe from his malice.
I'm begging you.
May I enter, Your Eminence?
Come in.
Eminence.
I have important news.
Fine, get out.
Your Eminence, Emir Sadettin,
the traitorous Beys rebelled against me.
I killed them all.
However, I then discovered
that Ertuğrul has joined a secret
council of disgraced beys.
They were involved in the rebellion.
I followed them but they got away.
I'll do everything I can to kill
Ertuğrul for rebelling against his state.
Frontier Bey Yakup Günalp Bey.
I've got you, Ertuğrul.
You can't escape me now.
I'll give you what you want,
Aslihan Hatun.
Turgut and Ertuğrul
have sealed their own death warrants.
No one can save them now.
What... have you done, Aslihan?
That's for my brother Aliyar.
I believed your lies.
I even doubted Emir Sadettin,
the man I think of as a father.
Moreover, I risked
my own life fighting Kritos.
I know that you joined
that traitorous council.
You can't fool me anymore, Ertuğrul Bey.
Did Emir Sadettin tell you about
the council of beys?
Yes.
Seems like Sadettin
not only keeps his dogs in the palace
but one in each village too.
He has already established
his own state, Günalp Bey.
He's deceived so many innocent people.
-He'll pay for what he's done.
-Enough!
I had no idea about the council.
When I heard about it,
I went there to stop them
betraying our state.
You're still able to look me in the eye
and lie to me, Ertuğrul Bey.
Damn a traitor like you.
There's nothing I can do
but pity you, Günalp Bey.
You're too weak to see the truth.
I know only too well
what the truth is, Ertuğrul Bey.
You want to establish
your own Beylic in Sogut
by weakening the state.
Kopek took control of the state
by killing our Sultan.
You can't believe that
but you can believe I would try
to establish my own Beylic in a tiny land?
Enough, Ertuğrul Bey.
Do you still disparage me?
Your loyalty puts me in
a difficult position, Günalp Bey.
If you cross the line...
and try to harm my men...
understand that I'll kill
you myself, Günalp Bey.
What are you waiting for?
Here I am.
Let my alps go.
Let's you and I settle this.
Your alps...
and you...
will die here!
If so...
may God forgive your sins, Günalp Bey.
Go to hell, Ertuğrul Bey.
My God.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net