Episode 114 will start after 12:30 min.
What is this arrow?
Ertuğrul Bey!
Who are you?
I bring greetings from Husamettin Karaca.
Husamettin Karaca?
Alps, be cautious.
-Whose blood is our right?
-The dog, Sadettin.
At ease, alps.
Where is Husamettin Karaca?
He's waiting for you in a cave
on Kargi Hill. It's important.
What could it be, Ertuğrul?
It must be important for Husamettin Karaca
to stop us in our tracks like this.
We should make our way there at once.
When we lay siege to the castle
we will pound the walls with catapults.
At night, our soldiers will howl
like wolves at the base of the walls,
beat drums and blow horns.
We will deprive them of their sleep
and their peace of mind.
They won't dare poke their heads
over the walls out of fear.
We will hold all the roads
that lead to the castle.
Not so much as a grain
of wheat will go in.
Hunger and fear will force them
to surrender the castle to us.
What if they resist, Your Eminence?
If they resist, we will march
on them with all our might
and raze the castle to the ground.
Now go back to your troops.
Know that I won't tolerate
any mistakes before our victory.
-Yes, Your Eminence.
May I enter, Your Eminence?
Come Kayraldi, come.
Your Eminence.
I hope nothing's wrong at the camp.
Everything is in order
at the camp, Your Eminence.
However, I have important news from Konya.
What?
Sultan Giyaseddin
and his mother Mahperi Hatun...
have left the palace.
Left the palace? Where have they gone?
Unfortunately, nobody knows,
Your Eminence.
What do you mean, "Nobody knows"?
What about you?
Did I not say I wanted to be
kept informed of everything?
The sultan and his mother
leave the palace,
and you come here and tell me
you don't know where they went!
-Your Eminence--
-Silence!
Leaving the palace
without anyone knowing?
This does not bode well. Not at all.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-I'm glad to see you, Husamettin.
What made you turn us from our road?
Come now.
My Sultan?
Mahperi Hatun.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-I'm glad to see you, my Sultan.
Come, sit down.
You've disguised yourself, my Sultan.
Has something happened in Konya?
Not yet, Ertuğrul Bey. But it will, soon.
Sadettin Köpek has had everyone
who opposed him killed.
He has taken control
of all positions of state,
from the army to the justice chamber.
We can't take a step in the castle without
him knowing. Everyone works for him.
Everyone's eyes are on us.
They look at us like executioners,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We had to leave in disguise
so that we could talk to you.
If you don't crush the snake
growing beside you...
you'll be the first one it bites.
Unfortunately, no one
recognizes a snake for what it is...
until it poisons you.
If Sadettin is victorious at Samsat,
we'll be done for
before he reaches Konya.
We can't wait for Emir Sadettin
to get his victory at Samsat.
We need to finish him off
before he gets there.
It doesn't matter how big
that snake has become...
with God's permission, our swords
will be able to sever its head.
I don't doubt that, Ertuğrul Bey.
However, there's an important matter
you must take care of beforehand.
Command me, my Sultan. What is it?
Sadettin Köpek has taken
Emir Kamyeri captive.
Emir Kamyeri is extremely
important to the state.
If he has captured him,
he won't let him live.
He intends to kill the last
Emir still standing against him.
After he kills the powerful Emir Kamyeri,
no one will dare oppose him.
You know, Emir Kamyeri
has a formidable army loyal to him.
I know, Husamettin Bey, I know.
If Emir Kamyeri dies,
Köpek will get a hold of his army.
His military forces will be unstoppable
and his power in the state absolute.
Emir Kamyeri must be saved before Köpek
has a chance to get his hands on him.
We must move at once.
That sultan and his mother...
have set out to kill me.
Nothing can stand in the way...
of the glorious victory that awaits me!
Look here, Kayraldi.
Send your men out far and wide.
The sultan and his mother must be found.
If they return to the palace,
don't let them go anywhere
until I'm back in Konya.
Should we keep them prisoner
in the palace, Your Eminence?
Yes, we should.
I cannot have them disturbing
my thoughts while I am out on campaign.
And when I get back,
I'll uproot this problem once and for all.
Any word on Emir Kamyeri?
He was caught and arrested,
Your Eminence.
They're bringing him to you.
He'll be here tomorrow.
Good.
Let him come.
I will behead him myself.
He must be dealt with
before I set out for Samsat.
so that I can take his army.
Have his possessions confiscated
and added to my treasure.
As you wish, Your Eminence.
A famous conquest awaits us, Kayraldi.
A great one.
When I take Samsat Castle...
I'll pile the heads of my enemies high...
and sit my throne atop them.
My scouts tell me that the soldiers
escorting Emir Kamyeri
have passed Yilanli Mountain.
That means they'll reach Köpek's
camp tomorrow evening.
We have to get going at once.
We'll carry out the raid at first light
and rescue Emir Kamyeri, God willing.
And we should get back to Konya.
My Sultan, they'll know by now
that you left the palace.
It's too dangerous for you
to go back to Konya.
They won't let you leave the palace again.
What should we do then, Ertuğrul Bey?
It would be best if you
didn't return for the time being.
My Sultan, Sultan Alaeddin
was poisoned right in front of my eyes.
Shahzade Kilicarslan died in my arms.
I can't let you return
to what would be certain death.
So what do we do?
If you will consider it,
I'd like you to go to my tribe.
-Your tribe?
-My tribe, my Sultan.
You will be safer with my tribe
than at the palace.
You will be the guests of my tribe
until the Köpek threat is dealt with.
You are right, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Bamsı.
-Yes, my Bey.
Take Dumrul, Meliksah,
Abdurrahman and Oguz with you.
Get our Sultan
and Mahperi Hatun to the tribe.
You know the shortcuts and hidden paths.
Take those roads.
I know them, my Bey. As you command.
I'll get the horses ready.
-God speed.
-Thank you.
This is a wise move, Ertuğrul Bey.
But I am uneasy
at leaving my palace behind.
My Sultan, traitors lurk
in the palace like ghouls.
That place is a prison for you now.
When we do away with the traitors...
you will once again
shine in your palace like the sun.
I too left my tribe and my family
behind when I embarked on this mission.
We all have to shoulder our duty
until we rid our state of these traitors.
Be reassured by the knowledge that
you're doing this
for the good of our state.
All right, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
May your sword be sharp.
Godspeed, my Sultan.
Come on, my brave men.
It's time for us to move.
Battle awaits us at daybreak.
May your work be easy.
-Thank you, Halime Hatun.
-May your work be easy.
-Thank you.
Good luck.
Look at what she's carrying.
Alçiçek, take those jars off her.
-Let me, Hafsa Hatun.
-Alçiçek, I'm fine. Thank you.
Here.
How many times have I told you
not to carry heavy things?
You could hurt the child in your belly.
You keep working as if you don't already
have enough of a burden to carry!
Come here, come and sit down.
Alçiçek, bring Hafsa some water.
She needs to rest.
Halime Hatun, I'm not able to help you
in the rug house because of the baby,
at least let me help you
by bringing you water.
Hafsa, if I told Mother about this
she'd be furious.
She'd say, "Are you trying
to harm my grandson?"
Here, Hafsa Hatun.
Thank you, Alçiçek.
Thank you.
Why is that rug not finished?
It was Aslıhan Hatun's.
Half-finished.
Whenever I try to complete it,
my hands shake...
and my heart aches.
It will remain unfinished,
like her life, like her happiness.
But our beys will exact revenge
on the one who did this to her, Hafsa.
The one who cut her down
in the spring of her life will perish.
We should think of our children.
I have two in my tent
and one growing inside me.
And yours will be here soon.
God willing,
our beys will come back safe to us.
I beg God that they get the chance
to kiss and embrace their children.
God willing, Hafsa. God willing.
They travel a difficult path
not just for their own children,
but for the children of all our kin,
and for those who will come after.
May god grant them speed.
Amen.
I'm going to check the rugs.
Hafsa Hatun!
Hafsa!
Halime!
Bring water, Alçiçek!
Hafsa? Sister?
Hafsa!
Hafsa, wake up.
Bring water!
-God save her.
-Sister!
Hafsa? Hafsa, my sister?
My God, my God, help her. Hafsa!
Wake up, Hafsa Hatun.
Hafsa? Sister! Hafsa!
-May I enter, my bey?
-Come.
Any word on Ertuğrul?
We've been watching the tribe closely.
But there's no sign of Ertuğrul.
Where are you, Ertuğrul?
We should confront them, my bey.
Frighten him into returning.
We could even take Hanlı Bazaar from them.
What's stopping us?
-They'd be so scared they'd obey.
-How many times must I say this, Aydoğmus?
Ertuğrul took Hanlı Bazaar
by the right of his sword.
It would go against our laws
to usurp that right.
It belongs to the Kayi.
It provides them with a living.
-Then the tribe--
-We'll not touch the tribe, either.
The innocent should not be made
to suffer because of Ertuğrul.
You think this is the way to treat an emir
who has dedicated his life to his state?
You'll pay a heavy price for this.
Be silent!
You'll be free of this torture
once you're put to death.
God, give me patience!
Emir Kamyeri.
We'll take down the two men
on either side of him first.
Then we'll draw our swords
and tear them apart.
We're being attacked!
God is infinite!
-Will you tell me your name?
-Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
So, you're the bey of the Kayi.
May God bless you.
You're welcome.
The life of any man who is loyal
to the state is important to us.
And at times like this,
when there are traitors everywhere,
we can't allow
a single good man to be lost.
Husamettin Karaca.
If you hadn't arrived,
those bastards would've killed me.
As long as that traitor Sadettin Köpek
is around to pull their strings,
-we must stand united.
-You're right.
First, we must get you free
of these chains.
My loyal friend, Ares.
-Welcome.
-Governor Kritos.
-Thank you.
-Sit down.
It's good to see you again.
I hope you've brought
good news from Nicaea.
It happened exactly
as I thought it would, Kritos.
The emperor agreed to give you an army.
As soon as the army is ready,
it will depart.
God save the emperor!
We'll finally be able to throw
the Turks out of this land.
Ares, with this army, we can take
not only Söğüt but Karacahisar as well.
Sir, if you'll excuse me.
Meet Emir Sadettin on his way to Samsat
and persuade him to settle his
cantonment in Sivas, Husamettin Bey.
As Emir Sadettin's guest,
you can then pass us
information about his army.
Then we'll move.
When Sadettin is with you in his tent,
we'll attack and bring him down.
Husamettin, you know
Sadettin doesn't trust you or Togan Bey.
Husamettin Karaca
will tell Sadettin that he killed you.
And that he'll obey him.
How can I, Ertuğrul Bey?
You'll tell him Emir Kamyeri sought refuge
with you after escaping, Husamettin Bey.
You'll tell him you carried
out the execution personally,
fulfilling the death warrant
Emir Sadettin had issued.
How will I prove it?
You'll give Emir Sadettin
Emir Kamyeri's cap and ring.
Good thinking, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sadettin will certainly recognize my ring.
It'll be easy for Husamettin
to convince him.
Once you've won Köpek's trust,
you'll pass on to us
what you've discovered.
I'll do whatever's necessary,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
Our enemy is wicked
and your task difficult.
May God help you, brave men.
-Thank you.
It's a war between the tyrannical
and the oppressed, God and superstition,
treachery and loyalty.
May God help us all.
-Amen.
Your Eminence,
Günalp Bey has disobeyed your orders
and refuses to take any action
against the Kayi tribe.
As a result, we have found
no trace of Ertuğrul Bey.
If I advance on the Kayi,
I may learn Ertuğrul's location.
But Günalp Bey will not allow this.
To find Ertuğrul, you will have
to put Günalp Bey out of action.
I look forward to receiving your orders.
Your loyal servant, Aydoğmus.
Your Eminence.
You thought our Seljuk state...
was weak just because...
a young sultan had ascended the throne.
You rebelled against our state.
Well...
you never stopped to consider
the wrath of Sadettin Köpek, did you?
Did you really think
you could get away with it?
You were as good
as dead the moment you did.
-Your Eminence, I have news.
-What is it?
Kamyeri managed to escape before
he was taken to the castle to be hanged.
What the hell are you saying?
How many lives did we sacrifice
to find Kamyeri?
How could this happen?
The men escorting him were killed.
You're doomed, Sadettin! You're doomed!
You'll never succeed in this!
Is that so?
You'll be hanged for this treason!
Kayraldı.
Send a messenger to
Gurcuoglu Zahireddin immediately.
Tell him he is to find that traitor
Emir Kamyeri and kill him.
Confiscate his goods
and seize his property.
If any of his family object,
put them to the sword,
and that includes his female slaves.
As you command, Eminence.
The Sultan and his mother are behind this.
I'll hold them accountable.
Your Eminence.
Well, a Seljuk soldier.
Take this to Aydoğmus immediately.
I came without anyone seeing.
So, you work for Sadettin Köpek.
That message is of vital importance.
Give Aydoğmus
and Emir Sadettin my regards.
They also send their regards.
Marya.
You vile woman. You think you have
the intelligence to play us as fools?
I'll reveal your little game.
My darling Hafsa.
She just collapsed,
right in front of me.
God, you're the only one who can
save her and the baby inside her.
May I come in?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
-How is she, Artuk Bey?
-Did Hafsa wake up?
Hafsa Hatun is sleeping.
Alçiçek Hatun is with her.
She's clearly exhausted herself.
She needs complete rest.
I can't say much now, but...
her condition is not good.
God help her.
What would Bamsi do if anything
happened to her or the baby?
Mother, I'll stay with her,
if you'll allow it.
May I come in?
Is that Bamsi's voice?
It is. Come in, Bamsi.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun, Bamsi.
What are you doing here?
Ertuğrul Bey sent me.
I've brought important guests with me.
-Guests?
-Who?
Mother.
My Sultan!
Mahperi Hatun!
We overcame many obstacles,
many challenges, much darkness,
so that we might
reach this blessed night, Aslıhan.
From now on,
we will illuminate the darkness together.
We will overcome
any difficulties together, Turgut.
I swear, Aslıhan.
I swear, those who destroyed
our happiness and stole our peace...
will never find peace
of their own in this world.
This dagger...
that you gave me before I went to war...
I swear...
I'll avenge you with this dagger.
That's the situation.
We'll be guests in your tribe
until we have set our state free
from Sadettin Köpek.
What do you mean by "guest"?
Our tent, our tribe, are yours, my Sultan.
I hope you'll be as comfortable here
as you are in the palace, my Sultan.
My father, Sultan Alaeddin,
used to take me
and my late brother,
Kılıç Arslan, to the Oghuz tents.
The days we spent hunting, joining
their councils, sleeping in Khagan tents,
were the best days of my life.
I don't know of a more comfortable place
than right here, Artuk Bey.
Rest easy.
My Sultan,
we suffered the loss of many lives
as the princes fought over the throne.
Their greed put us in this situation.
But it is our duty to protect you,
even if it costs us our lives.
Ertuğrul Bey has gone after Köpek.
We all stand ready
to do whatever you ask of us.
Thank you.
God willing, we'll overcome
these troubles together.
God willing.
We, our state, our homeland,
are grateful to you.
My Sultan...
if you'll excuse me, I would like
to go to my tent to see my wife.
You can go, Chief Alp Bamsi.
My Sultan.
-Bamsi?
-What is it, Artuk Bey?
Hafsa Hatun has worsened a bit today.
Hafsa? Worsened?
What's wrong, Artuk Bey?
She's pregnant, son.
She's due soon. All this is normal.
Try to stay calm.
Artuk Bey, Mother Hayme.
Hafsa is all right, isn't she?
Tell me, my child will live.
Bamsi, calm down. Alçiçek is with her.
Now, go and see your wife. Go.
I'll go and see her right now.
My Sultan.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Hafsa? Can I come in, Hafsa?
Bamsi? Bamsi! Bamsi, come in!
My dear! My dear Hafsa!
Hafsa, light of my life, what happened?
God, help her. Help her.
Alçiçek Hatun.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hafsa, that's better.
You're all right, aren't you?
Bamsi!
I'm scared that I might not live
to hold our child,
I'm scared I won't be a mother to it.
Don't speak like that,
don't speak like that.
God has granted us this child.
Don't be downhearted.
The baby will arrive safe and sound.
I'm so glad you're here.
I'm so glad you're here, Bamsi. Thank God.
What would I do without you?
What are you saying?
Of course I'll always be with you!
Hafsa, I'm going to feed you myself.
I'm going to get you some hot soup.
That'll help you get your strength back.
Our child will be born healthy and happy.
Hafsa, we're going to fill our tent
and our tribe with lots of children!
Don't you worry.
God willing. God willing, Bamsi.
May God intend us to see those days.
He will, Hafsa. He will.
Hold on to that thought.
Now, you must get some rest.
Get some sleep. Come on.
Come on, get some rest.
Relax, comrade.
Relax.
Turgut.
You look so unhappy.
I know... you are thinking
of Aslıhan Hatun.
I think about her all the time, my Bey.
The pain cuts my heart
like the blade of a dagger.
Until I have avenged Aslıhan,
even breathing is forbidden to me.
I know, my brave man. I know.
It is hard to bear.
Be patient a little while longer.
We will avenge her, I swear that we will.
We must, my bey. We must.
I'd gladly give my life
to see that bastard dead.
My bey...
I have a request of you.
Anything, friend. Anything.
If...
I die for this cause...
bury me next to my Aslıhan.
God willing...
none of us will fall as martyrs
before we can take that bastard's head.
Rely upon it, Turgut.
God willing, bey.
God willing.
Sayyid of the frontier.
Glorious Sultan.
Sultan of the two seas...
and of the two lands.
Sultan of the Greeks...
of Damascus...
of Armenia...
and of the Franks.
I am Sadettin Köpek. I walked
this path adorned with blood and fire.
But every step I took,
took me a step closer to my reign.
I clawed my way to the top
of the mountain by the force of my will.
My place is not a low one,
it is high above, where the eagles nest.
Now I have risen...
and reached my throne.
Sultan of the lands, the seas, the Greeks,
of Damascus, Armenia and the Franks,
His Highness Sadettin Köpek.
Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul!
-May I come in, Your Eminence?
-Come.
Your Eminence.
Is there any news?
We discovered where the Sultan is,
Eminence.
Where?
He and Mahperi Hatun
are with the Kayi tribe.
I knew it!
And Ertuğrul? Where is he?
He's not with his tribe.
No one knows where he is.
My men are looking for him.
Also, this letter arrived from Aydoğmus.
All this time, they couldn't find
a trace of Ertuğrul either.
Günalp has been far too tolerant
of the Kayis' insolence!
Günalp!
What will you do, Your Eminence?
Get a message to Aydoğmus immediately.
Tell him to infiltrate the Kayi tribe...
and kill the Sultan.
Then the entire Kayi tribe
must be put to the sword.
And Günalp Bey?
Summon him here, to Sivas.
That way we'll prevent him
hindering Aydoğmus.
If you do this,
Ertuğrul will be sure to come after you.
I'll be ready when he comes...
and I will finally take his life.
Alps!
Station yourselves all around the camp.
Sadettin's dogs may attack
our village anytime.
Gunkut, Melikshah,
you go out to the hills.
Dumrul, Oguz, stay close to the well.
Abdurrahman.
You stay close to the marquee.
Yes, Commander Bamsi.
Alps!
Know that all we want to do
is protect our sultan and our tribe.
If those heinous hyenas
try to attack our tribe,
we will kill them like the wolves we are!
Hurrah!
Now, take your positions and keep alert.
-Yes, Commander Bamsi.
-Let's go!
God help us.
Amen.
Someone is coming.
With God's permission.
Your Highness.
What is it, Husamettin Karaca?
May your victories...
be everlasting, Your Highness.
Have you so forgotten your hostility to me
that you would grovel before me?
And how about you...
emir of the whole world, Togan?
You defied my orders two years ago
and informed on me to the Sultan Alaeddin.
Sir.
We take refuge in the shade
of your greatness.
You are not only a victorious commander,
but also the emir of all emirs.
We...
are here to ask for your forgiveness.
Is that so?
Before you begin the siege
on the great Samsat Castle,
we'd be honored
if you would rest in Sivas.
I have no time to rest, Husamettin Karaca.
The traitor Kamyeri got away.
I can't rest when my country
is under threat
from traitors and enemies.
After Kamyeri got away,
he asked me to give him refuge.
Because he had gone against our country
and your orders,
we welcomed him warmly.
Soldier!
And then...
along with the soldiers
that had saved him,
we killed him.
This is his ring.
-Yes, Your Highness.
-This cap belonged to Kamyeri as well.
He wore this cap on his head
when I beheaded him, Your Highness.
Good.
This is a great service to our country.
You will be repaid in kind.
As a reward for this,
we would like you to honor us
by setting up your camp at Sivas.
Now, please.
Rest a bit with your army
before you head for Samsat, sir.
Fine.
Kayraldi?
Yes, sir?
Let my army know...
that we will rest a while in Sivas.
As you wish, Your Highness.
We were hunters,
but we have now become prey.
There are people inside
our borders, everywhere,
who hate the success of our state.
And now those damned Mongols
are preparing to attack.
If something happens to me,
I want to make sure my country
will be in safe hands, Gıyaseddin.
Your legacy, this great country,
is being swarmed by hyenas, Father.
They even deny us our own palace.
God, give me the strength
to bear this pain.
May I enter, Your Highness?
Come in.
Selamunaleykum.
Aleykumselamun.
I heard you were here, Your Highness.
I wanted to pay you a visit.
I'm happy to hear that. I'm honored.
The honor is mine, Your Highness.
Come, sit.
My dear İbn Arabi.
First of all, I'd like you to know
how thankful I am to you.
I almost killed Ertuğrul
because of the traitors
swarming my country.
Thank God that with your guidance,
I came to release him.
Now, I come all the way here
to seek his protection.
Whenever you receive a helping hand,
know that God is ultimately
behind it, Your Highness.
No one makes decisions but him,
and no one is stronger than him.
If I helped bring about something good,
that was God's will.
What a nice explanation.
Ertuğrul Bey is on a harsh path
to rid our country of traitors
and save it from great disaster.
And here I am, doing nothing but waiting.
Every moment I spend here
is like another stab in my heart.
I feel like my country
is melting before my eyes,
and I'm just lounging about.
The night is at its darkest
right before the dawn.
Treasure the hardships you go through
to protect our country.
For those bearing great hardship
in striving for God's cause...
God's grace awaits them.
However, you must be patient.
Surely, God's wrath will fall upon
the cruel and traitorous like lightning.
I hope so.
I hope we get to see that day.
Because being away from Konya,
from my palace,
brings heaviness to my heart.
There is a spring after every winter.
Every separation ends with
a coming together, God willing.
I hope so.
When Muhammad...
declared that he was the prophet,
the polytheists did cruel things to him
and his followers.
They laid down thorns in his path.
They threw dirt on him.
They called him a magician, a sophist,
and tried to deter him.
They mocked him.
The cruelty was so harsh that in the end,
our prophet was compelled
to migrate to Medina
from his hometown, Mecca.
The situation caused him great grief.
However, the wisdom of God
was hidden beneath it.
And he saw the fruit of his faith
and patience while he was alive.
He was thrown out of Mecca...
but returned as a great commander
and conquered his hometown.
The number of followers
who attended his farewell sermon
was as high as 124 thousand.
And almost every surrounding country
converted to Islam.
Those with patience always win.
Patience is hard,
but it is fruitful, Your Highness.
You want to advance
the whole Muslim community
and protect our country.
You are a soldier to a holy cause.
Now, rest at ease.
Before long, the efforts of Ertuğrul Bey
and yourself will prove fruitful.
And with God's help,
our country will be rid of traitors.
You will be welcomed back to Konya
with a great parade, with God's help.
I hope so.
Your words enlighten me.
They give me peace.
God bless you.
May God help our land.
May He keep us on this holy path.
Amen.
Come, dear.
Sniff this, Hafsa Hatun.
Sniff.
It will refresh you.
Artuk Bey.
Will I be able to hold my baby?
I'll do my best to ensure that,
Hafsa Hatun. Don't you worry.
Hafsa.
Don't exhaust yourself.
My dear.
Please, God...
help my daughter.
Amen.
I heard Hafsa Hatun was feeling bad.
I came to see how she is doing.
Thank you.
Hafsa is okay. She will be better soon.
Mahperi Hatun.
Bamsi...
Commander Bamsi.
Our Hafsa isn't feeling well.
You are right, Mahperi Hatun.
We need to take Hafsa Hatun somewhere
where we can treat her better.
But I don't know where that could be.
What about Konya?
The late Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad
had a hospital built there
called Hospital Alaeddin.
Its facilities are quite good.
Hafsa can be treated there.
What can I say? I just don't know.
Would that be good for Hafsa and our baby?
Many seemingly hopeless cases
became healthy again there.
With God's help,
Hafsa will get better as well.
Mahperi Hatun is right.
I agree with her.
It's likely that Hafsa Hatun will receive
proper treatment at the hospital.
Artuk Bey, how can we possibly do this?
How can we take her? I...
My duty is to protect our sultan.
I can't leave the camp.
Plus, I'm a fugitive.
They will arrest me
the moment they see me.
What would my Hafsa do then?
Don't worry, Bamsi.
I will send her with the bravest
alps and women we have.
I'll write a letter personally.
We have loyal, trusted doctors there.
Once they get my letter,
they will treat her properly.
The Sultan is at the Kayi Tribe.
I called on Günalp to come to Sivas.
Once he leaves the castle,
you have absolute authority.
First of all, take our best soldiers
and sneak into the Kayi Tribe.
Kill the Sultan and his mother
for the well-being of our country.
Then, find out where Ertuğrul is
and finish him off.
If nobody will tell you where he is,
kill everyone at the Kayi Tribe.
Yours, Emir Sadettin Köpek.
The moment I've waited for is here.
So, the Sultan is at the Kayi Tribe.
There is news for you
from Emir Sadettin, sir.
From Emir Sadettin?
What is it, sir?
Emir expects me at Sivas.
Sivas?
But why, sir?
We'll see once we get there.
He ordered me to leave you here
as my representative.
When do you depart, sir?
Right away.
I will take the guards closest to me.
Yes, sir.
Aydoğmus.
I want to find everything
just as I left it.
Understand?
You will not touch the Kayi Tribe,
nor the market.
Our traditions demand that,
and you know what happens to those
who dare break tradition.
As you wish, sir.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun, Ertuğrul Bey.
What's the situation, Husamettin Bey?
Your plan was a success, Ertuğrul Bey.
Once he saw Emir Kamyeri's
cap and sealed ring,
Köpek trusted us.
Well done.
What about their camp?
I told them about
where to set up their camp...
in great detail.
They will set up their camp
in a safe place.
I will take over the army
once Sadettin dies.
Then, I will protect you.
You will be guided by Togan Bey
once you get inside the camp.
They will increase security measures
around the camp and marquee at night.
We will sneak in the camp where
and when they least expect it.
We will finish off Köpek
on the day he least expects it.
Once Köpek dies,
you'll be responsible for the camp.
That way, we leave the camp safely.
I'll be ready.
I'll move if anything goes wrong.
And I'll fight to the death
for the final time, Ertuğrul Bey.
Don't do that, Husamettin Bey.
Köpek will slaughter you
and Togan Bey alike.
The Sultan needs the two of you alive.
Even if we die,
act as though you are allies of Köpek
so that the Sultan is not left alone.
Our nation will be eternal thanks to
self-sacrificing, brave men like you.
-You have my absolute faith.
-We'll do this together, Husamettin Bey.
The time we've been waiting for has come.
Now, our swords shall do the talking.
We'll make Köpek regret
celebrating his victory.
May God help us.
Amen.
Hafsa.
Know that...
it's best for you...
and our baby to be treated
at the hospital.
They have everything there.
The best physicians
in our country reside there.
Plus, Mahperi Hatun will write a letter.
The doctors will treat you well.
How can I stop worrying?
What will I do in that strange place?
Please.
Do you think I'll leave you alone
when you go?
Do you think I'd do that?
Hafsa.
I'll come to you as soon as I can.
What if I lose our baby
while you are gone?
Hafsa.
Don't talk like that.
You will both return to our tribe
safe and sound.
I hope so.
I hope so, Bamsi.
Hafsa.
You will see. It will be all right.
We will live to see
happy, bright days with our baby.
God will help us.
He'll help us, Hafsa.
Okay.
Fine, Bamsi. I'll go.
That's my Hafsa
Hafsa.
The apple of my eye.
Just as I was preparing
for the Samsat conquest,
look what happened.
I was almost assassinated.
The bastard.
He's so treacherous, he would kill
an emir who would die for his country.
This is nothing, Günalp. This is nothing.
Who knows what else he will do,
unless we kill him?
I know him the best, Günalp Bey.
Sadettin doesn't work for our nation,
but for his own power.
You must choose your side now.
I secured both the margraveship
and this castle by myself.
And now, I'm handing them over to you
to prevent bloodshed.
I have no reservations,
as I'm leaving Karacahisar
to a brave man who I know will protect it
until he dies.
Is it Ertuğrul Bey,
or is it the man who taught me
to rule a castle,
the man I love and respect like a father,
Emir Sadettin, who is lying?
What if Ertuğrul Bey is right?
I will find out.
I must find out.
Come on, everyone.
Let us go.
Today,
your country needs your service.
This is the greatest service of all time.
The son of a traitor, Gıyaseddin,
who killed Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad
and his mother,
will be executed.
They are at the marquee of Ertuğrul,
who aided and abetted them.
Death to the traitors!
Emir Sadettin will bring
stability and peace to our country.
And you all
are honorable soldiers
who lay down your lives for this cause.
If we went in with our army,
the Sultan would escape.
However...
we will present ourselves to the Sultan
as soldiers of his...
and then leave death in our wake.
It is your duty...
to slaughter...
the Sultan, his mother,
and whoever else is at the marquee,
along with Ertuğrul and the Sultan's
entire lineage, men and children alike!
Long live Emir Sadettin!
Let us go.
Open!
We are ready, sir.
We're ready to fight for our cause
as always, Turgut.
May God help us.
Amen, brother.
Give me your blessings, sir.
God bless you, Turgut.
And now it's your turn.
God bless you, sir.
Give me your blessings, brother.
God bless you, brother.
We have already laid down
our lives for our nation, Ertuğrul.
May God help us.
Amen.
For those who we see first thing
in the morning. For our loved ones.
For our tribes, who had to sacrifice
many brave men and women.
For our nation.
This is the day, everyone.
May God help us.
-Amen.
Let us go.
Come on!
Welcome, Your Highness.
-Welcome, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Please, sit.
Husamettin.
Where is Togan Bey?
He excused himself so he could see
if your army needed anything.
He should be here soon, Your Highness.
Good.
I'm happy to be here with
Husamettin Karaca and my valuable emirs.
As you already know,
I am about to head into a war
which is important to our nation.
May God grant you victory.
May God never take you from us.
-Amen.
Amen.
We will bury our enemies' thirst for power
alongside their bodies
and alongside Samsat Castle.
Of course. May God grant you victory.
Amen.
However, I must tell you that there is
something even more important
than this victory.
-Who deserves to die?
-That bastard Sadettin.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
How is the situation, Togan Bey?
Sadettin Köpek is at the marquee
with his most trusted men.
Since Husamettin Karaca trusts nobody,
only the two of us know
of the plan to kill Sadettin.
These two brave commanders, too.
All right. When I catch
that bastard alone in his tent,
his army won't be there to save him.
I hope we can get rid of
that nuisance, Ertuğrul Bey.
If this doesn't clean up nicely,
a civil war will await us.
We'll deal with that dog.
-May God give you all strength.
-Amen.
Now, I must go back to the marquee.
Sadettin Köpek will want to see me.
Wear these uniforms.
Our commanders will get you in the camp
and Sadettin's marquee.
Thank you.
-May God help you.
-Amen.
As you already know,
I prevented the death of our Sultan
and the destruction of our army
by not sending them to Amid.
Once we achieve victory over Samsat,
Amid will hopefully be next.
But I don't think our Sultan
is fit to lead this attack, either.
This is the truth.
We can't allow our Sultan
to command our army into destruction.
When the whole world is our enemy,
the weakest army could end us.
Husamettin.
What do you think?
If you lead the Amid campaign,
I'm sure you will secure yet another
victory for our army, Your Highness.
And so, the Mongols will keep
their distance from our mighty nation.
I will personally stay by your side.
I have already...
laid down my life for you.
-May I enter, Your Highness?
-Come in, Togan.
I was just announcing
some important decisions
to those gathered here.
Let our Sultan entertain himself
at his palace.
We, the soldiers, will be the ones
to keep our nation strong.
Hush.
Ladies, may I come in?
Yes, Lady Mahperi.
Hello, ladies. Please don't be disturbed.
We haven't had the chance
to talk to each other since we arrived.
I wanted to say a couple of words to you
in private.
Good boy.
What a sweet baby that is.
What is his name?
His name is Savci.
Lady Halime, do you mind if I hold him?
Aw...
Good boy.
Savci...
Here, Lady Mahperi. Have a seat.
This reminds me of Giyaseddin's infancy.
I used to forget everything else
when I held him, just like this.
I would forget about the palace,
the internal issues, everything.
Giyaseddin was the only thing
I could think about.
I've done everything for him.
So that he can be the sultan.
I know I'm the one responsible
for the current situation,
of me, of him and of the state.
I don't care about my own life.
I just pray for God to save our state
and my son.
We all think about our state
before all else, Lady Mahperi.
Our sons, warriors, have gone
to chase down the traitors.
You left your palace and came here
for the sake of our state.
Once our state is liberated
from all the dangers,
the rest is up to God.
And I upset you so many times,
Lady Halime.
What's done is done, Lady Mahperi.
It's not the time
to hold each other accountable.
We can't argue about our egos
while our state and home are in danger.
From now on, we should do all we can
for the good of our state.
There's nothing more important to us.
God, who makes the sun shine
after every night,
will surely let the sun shine
after this dark period.
That's all we can say.
My Savci, Come on.
Hush.
It's all right.
May God help Ertuğrul Bey and the others.
Amen, my Sultan.
May God deliver our state
from evil people like Sadettin Köpek.
But...
going into a military quarter
with so many soldiers in it...
Don't worry, Artuk Bey.
If Sadettin dies,
Husamettin Karaca will have
the authority over the army.
Then, it'll be up to him
to protect Ertuğrul Bey and his warriors.
And I'm sure he will protect them.
All they need to do is to get that dog
Sadettin's head.
Oh, my Hafsa. Where could you be now?
What are you doing on your own
with the baby, my Hafsa?
It's the Head Alp, Bamsi.
-Hello, men.
-Hello, Head Alp Bamsi.
Good men.
Someone is coming.
Why are these bastards here?
Let's find out.
Come on.
I hope it's something good.
Who are they, Artuk Bey?
Step aside.
We need to talk to the Sultan.
What do you mean? What would the Sultan
be doing among our tribe?
Everything is for the crucial interests
of our state.
I know no one has any doubts about that.
Husamettin Karaca, governor of Sivas,
and his banner man Togan,
they did something great
and got rid of the biggest enemy
of our state, Kamyeri,
thus giving us the chance
to have a moment of peace.
I'm grateful to them.
May God protect our state
from the extremists.
We will not be beaten as long as we have
talented viziers like you, for sure.
It is our primary duty...
to make this state,
which was entrusted to us
by my late father, Sultan Keyhusrev,
live forever.
Long Live Prince Sadettin!
-Long Live Prince Sadettin!
-Oh God, please protect our state.
Long Live Prince Sadettin!
Now go and rest.
Tomorrow we will leave for a long,
hard journey.
We'll have a glorious victory
and make our state proud,
God willing.
May God bless our endeavor.
Amen.
Köpek must be alone in his tent.
We'll find out now.
Köpek is in his tent, Ertuğrul Bey.
Kayraldi is with him.
Wait for him to come out.
He is out.
May God help you.
Amen.
Come on, men.
Brother Sungur.
Turgut...
Stay sharp.
I'll go in alone with two commanders.
My Bey. Let me go in with you.
I don't want you to go in alone.
I'll go in as a messenger, Turgut.
They only accept one person.
You'll make a move if things go awry.
As you order, my Bey.
Don't worry about us.
We'll do whatever is necessary.
My brother. May God help you.
Amen, brother.
May God help you, my Bey.
Hopefully, this will be the last day
for that bastard.
Hopefully, my Turgut.
Very well, men.
-Very well.
-Let's move.
What's going on, Artuk Bey?
I have a bad feeling
about this, my sultan.
A messenger from Samsat is here
to see the blessed Vizier.
-It's important.
-The blessed Vizier is resting.
It's important, soldier. Let him know.
The blessed Vizier is waiting
for the messenger.
Give me your weapon.
May God help our Bey.
Amen.
So, you are finally here, Ertuğrul Bey.
You've taken your first step into hell.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net