Episode 93 will start after 12:40 min.
Brother, do you miss our father?
I miss him a lot.
Brother...
This smells like my father.
I smell it whenever I miss him.
Here, you should smell it too.
Don't you be sad, okay?
Big brothers don't get sad.
Look at me.
Mother, why are you crying?
I'm not crying, my Gündüz.
Don't cry, mother.
Don't be afraid.
I'll protect you and my brother.
I know, my Gündüz.
You can protect me and your brother.
You are a great Alp commander.
My father entrusted you to me
when he was leaving for the battle.
That's right, my Gündüz.
He did.
The horses can rest here, Ertuğrul Bey.
We can stay the night in the village.
I know some people there.
We'll be comfortable.
Ho!
Hush!
Ertuğrul Bey...
Antheus took care of you well.
I wasn't expecting you to be this healthy.
You said we had a long way to go.
But as you can see, it wasn't that long.
As caravansaries are raided,
the merchants are running away.
Kayıs can't deal with the bandits.
They don't know what to do.
Neither my people nor Turks can find
what they are looking for in the bazaar.
I kept my promise, Tekfur Ares.
Now it's your turn.
A big caravansary that left from Iran
should be here soon.
From Mosul, Aleppo and even China...
All caravansaries that pass by here
have to pass through Hanlı Bazaar
by my command.
Before gold starts accumulating
in Hanlı Bazaar,
the bazaar has to be
taken away from the Kayıs.
Or I'll burn that bazaar down
with my own hands.
Be at ease, Tekfur Ares.
Dündar will ask for my help
when he gets in trouble.
And I'll encourage him to sell the bazaar.
And I'll make a man that I trust
buy the bazaar.
By then, everything will have changed.
So...
We'll run this bazaar together
through this man, huh?
Yes, you'll pay for the bazaar's value.
If you'll buy the bazaar with my gold,
Emir Sadettin,
then I'd like my own man
to run the bazaar.
I want to bury my gold in the bazaar,
not in the soil.
I'll get one of the most skillful
merchants from Nicaea to run the bazaar.
That's my only condition.
If the merchants from the east are
in your pocket,
Greek and French merchants are in mine,
Emir Sadettin.
If you want partnership, this is it.
Simfono!
Ne. Simfono, Ares.
Emir Sadettin, I'll introduce you
to my favorite woman.
Welcome, sir.
I'm honored.
You know how to own beautiful things.
I like it.
I've eaten enough.
I'll leave you alone with your beauties.
Don't waste any time, go see Dündar,
press him.
While the fire is burning,
we should add more fuel to it.
Now surrender to your new owner Simko
who found you and helped you
recover and escape death.
From now on, I own your life.
I'd rather die than be a slave
for you rascals.
So...
If that's what you want...
Get him!
The sparkle in your eye is a sign
of the new order that you've established.
To reestablish the order
that he demolished
is the binding duty
of any great statesman.
You have proven that once again,
Majesty Emir.
Moreover, you laid the entire burden
upon your biggest enemy, Ares.
Already, his mercenary soldiers are
creating trouble for Dündar Bey.
My biggest enemy was Ertuğrul.
I'll build my reign out of his ashes.
What about Ares, Majesty Emir?
He'll eventually figure out
that he was tricked.
After our Sultan's victory,
it'll be Karacahisar's turn.
Don't worry.
I'll bury Ares in the same land
that I buried Ertuğrul.
What about Bahadır Bey?
He should be here soon.
Good.
Let him come.
Let him.
I'll buy the bazaar with Ares' gold
and I'll make sure
Bahadır Bey becomes powerful
and becomes a frontiersman
under my command.
What matters is our state.
That'll be the thing to last, Göktuğ.
I'll always kneel before our state,
Majesty Emir.
I had my biggest victory today, Marya.
I bought this necklace for you
so we'll never forget this day.
The biggest gift I can receive is
your victory, Tekfur Ares.
What? What do you want?
Sir...
Mihalis is here.
Let him come in.
Go to our room, wait for me.
I'll be there soon.
You called for me, Tekfur Ares.
I want bigger raids, Mihalis.
Get more men. Don't think about the gold.
I'll take care of it.
Just make sure the terror you'll spread
is enough to suffocate the Turks.
As you wish, Tekfur Ares.
Lukas!
Double the men we have on the border.
Have them spread out.
Have them kill all the wandering Turks.
I want them to be scared
of leaving their villages, got it?
Yes, Tekfur Ares.
We're so close to breaking the back
of the Turks, Lukas.
I don't want any mistakes.
Hah!
Send a message to Dündar Bey.
-I'll see him in Hanlı Bazaar.
-Yes, sir.
It's time to upset Ares.
The pigeon in the castle should start
moving too.
This way Ares will find out Ertuğrul
is still alive
and that he's not safe
even in his own castle.
What if Ares doesn't pay
the gold we demand for Ertuğrul?
Then Sultan Alaeddin will find out
that his frontiersman was trapped
by Ares.
Ares will be scared, not us.
Now go and wait inside the cave.
Oh, wow, Ertuğrul Bey...
Look at you!
Haven't you understood how much
compassion I have for you yet?
Why did you resist my men?
Don't think I surrendered, Simko.
Even if you tie me up...
I'd rip you apart with my teeth.
Well, I'll rip your teeth out then.
A merchant like you wouldn't waste
his time with a slave.
Tell me.
What do you want from me?
You're a smart man.
I know very well that you are too valuable
to be a galley slave.
I have no desire to sell you
in the slave market like those hangdogs.
We know who your owner is.
You know who set me up.
And you want to sell me to them?
Ah...
You're so smart, Ertuğrul Bey.
So smart. But don't worry,
you'll figure everything out
when I sell you to him.
Get up! We're leaving!
Come on!
Get up! We're leaving! Come on!
Quick!
-Good luck with that.
-Thank you, Bey.
How is your business, Merchant?
How could it be, Bey? It's been really bad
since the bandits started to raid.
How long will this go on for, Bey?
When will security be established?
Don't worry.
We'll try with God's help.
The bazaar will go back
to its former order as soon as possible.
-Have a good day.
-Thank you, Bey.
My Bey, don't you worry.
Merchants think their worlds turn
upside down when business is bad.
With God's help,
everything will get better.
You say that, Artuk Bey...
They're not wrong.
We can't stop the bandits.
Day by day, it's getting more and more
difficult for us to stop it.
Dündar Bey is right.
The bandit incident has shaken up
the revenue of the bazaar.
Everyone's income has decreased.
Both the merchants
and the customers are uneasy.
-I don't know what to do.
-Every cloud has a silver lining.
Our duty is to maintain the peace.
Greek merchants have started
to run away from the bazaar.
-They can't earn much.
-The bread doesn't come from them.
God is the one to provide the bread.
If God closes one door,
he'll open another one.
We just have to carry out
our responsibilities.
Dündar Bey...
Tekfur Ares sent a message.
He wants to talk to you
if you're available.
It's okay. He can come.
I wonder what happened.
We'll see, Artuk Bey.
We'll see.
Your wound is so deep.
The enemies who did this to you
must be very strong.
But you're stronger than them.
That wound has started to heal
ever since you touched it, Marya.
Those hands must belong to a saint.
I'm getting shy.
You saved me from being a slave
and took me into your paradise.
You are the saint.
Not yet.
But I stomped out our biggest enemy...
I'll be the great knight saint
who kicked the Turks...
out of Anatolia.
So he was a Turk.
I'm curious about this strong enemy
who made you this furious.
It must have been so painful
for him to die in your hands.
I never look back
at the people I destroy, Marya.
I never mention them.
I care about the future.
I'm dreaming of the great knight, Ares,
who kicked out the Turks from our lands.
Now you're a part of that dream.
Think about the future, Marya.
Whatever you want.
Now I have to go.
But when I come back,
we'll both be closer to that dream.
Come on!
Come on! Walk, you fools, walk!
You useless men!
Hurry up! Quick!
Your eyes are on the keys.
Simko said you're a very smart man.
He was right.
I can tell from the way you fight
and your eyes.
My name is Pito.
I was a miserable thief.
It's clean, sir!
I'm a sinner.
I thought God was punishing me,
but I met you.
Come on, you hangdogs!
What are you waiting for?
Don't stall!
We're all trying to run away
from the slave trader, Turk.
We've all seen that you are too brave
to accept being a slave.
If you want to escape, you're not alone.
We have all accepted the risk of death.
If you were a thief,
show your skills once more.
Take those keys.
I'll take those keys
to save you and us from these chains.
But we are entrusting our lives to you,
you should know that.
Look at me, you thief!
What did I tell you?
I told you not to speak to that man.
You haven't behaved yourself
ever since I bought you.
Mavro!
Take that man and whip him
the rest of the way so he'll behave!
You low scumbag!
Hah!
Don't deprive me of the strength
to crush the cruel.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
I want my hunt on my dinner table.
Serve it with almond rice and raisins.
Yes, Majesty Emir.
Majesty Emir, Bahadır Bey is here.
He's going to the Cavdar Village.
Good.
Let him see Aslıhan Hatun for a while.
Let him settle down in the pavilion.
We've got a lot of important stuff to do.
With Bahadır Bey's arrival,
the Anatolian people
will change just as we want them to, sir.
We call the shots now, Göktuğ.
Dündar will ask for help eventually,
and he'll be at our mercy.
Then we'll start digging the Kayıs graves.
And Aslıhan will see...
who is stronger.
Aslıhan Hatun, praise be.
Your hair is just like silk.
The brush flows by itself.
Thank you, Esma Hatun.
You and Turgut Alp look perfect together.
When is your wedding?
I just want him to come back
alive and well.
We can have our wedding after that,
if God permits.
May God let him come alive and well,
quickly.
Amen.
What's the drum for?
Am I allowed to come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
No, Kırca.
Tell me.
Bahadır Bey is approaching the village
with his son Sancar Bey.
I hope he's got good intentions.
I don't think so.
Only evil spawns
where Bahadır comes from.
May God turn this into a blessing.
Our Bahadır Bey is coming.
Welcome, Bey!
The one who storms
through the battlefield.
The one who makes the enemy spit blood.
The one who cuts 40 hands
with a dark weapon.
Bahadır Bey with a speedy horse
and the life of a lion.
Welcome, Bahadır Bey. Welcome.
You cheered up our village, Bey.
Welcome, Bahadır Bey.
You brought joy!
You brought joy! You brought victory!
You brought honor to our village!
Your victory overflows your majesty, Bey.
Welcome.
First of all, the victory is God's.
I hope we never go through a separation
again.
God willing, my Bey.
Fortunately, I was lucky enough
to come back to my village years later,
and with a battle victory.
I know you've been missing the honor
of a victory for years.
I came here to share my victory
with the Cavdars
and to earn new victories
and to hang the enemy's heads
on the village entrance.
So that every passerby
can see Cavdars have gained
the honor of a battle.
Your wish is our command, Bahadır Bey.
Hand out the battle treasures
to all the Cavdars.
Long live Bahadır Bey!
May your victory be blessed, Bey!
May your treasure be blessed, Bey!
Long live Bahadır Bey!
Welcome, Bahadır Bey.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
The purpose of our lives is to claim lives
on the battlefield and become glorious.
I was swaddled in a lion's coat.
I grew up destroying eagles' nests.
Valor comes from the womb.
You know Karaca Hatun.
She became my wife.
May God make you happy.
May God bless you.
I heard that you are taking care
of my late brother Candar Bey's legacy.
That's right.
Thank God, I take care of his legacy
perfectly.
Come into my pavilion.
You've been traveling. Rest a little.
Kırca, ask the Hatuns
to bring some sherbet.
Our guests have come a long way.
They are tired.
Please go ahead.
What is the purpose
of your visit, Governor Ares?
It's about the situation with the bazaar.
You aren't able to protect it
from the bandits.
Our alps are on guard everywhere here.
With God's permission,
the bandits will be destroyed
and the bazaar will be back to normal.
I think we all know that is not possible,
Dündar Bey.
Greek traders are also suffering losses
because of this situation.
You know, I'm responsible for the safety
of them and their properties.
What are you trying to imply, governor?
If you can't ensure security and order
then, maybe the best idea is
to sell the bazaar to someone
who can ensure security.
Or else I'll have to forbid Greek traders
from coming to the bazaar.
Do you think it's that easy
to sell the bazaar just like that,
knowing that we paid a high price
in blood, Governor Ares?
This inn and the bazaar are the relics
of our Ertuğrul Bey.
They were acquired with blood,
they can only be given with blood.
Ertuğrul Bey promised
to ensure the safety of the people.
You are not able to fulfill his promise.
Soon, even the Muslims won't come here
to trade.
You and the other traders
will suffer even greater losses.
You can save the traders and yourselves
from greater losses by selling the bazaar.
If you find it acceptable
and want to sell it,
I'd like to purchase the bazaar.
The bazaar is not for sale.
Thanks for your advice, Governor Ares.
Then, I'll be waiting
to hear from you, Dündar Bey.
Do you intend to punish
or to kill him, you bastard?
I've had enough of you!
What's going on?
He held my hand
while I was whipping that thief.
He took the whip from my hand
and hit me with it.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Didn't I tell you to behave?
No vile man can tame brave men.
For God's sake, I won't behave.
It's understood.
I'll punish you to teach you a lesson.
Listen here, there's a deserted place
on our way.
We'll rest and spend the night there.
And I'll punish you there, Ertuğrul Bey.
Lady Esma.
Yes, Lady Aslıhan.
Prepare our guests' tents.
Be sure to make them feel at home.
Lady Aslıhan.
I'm not here as a guest.
According to our traditions,
strangers can be guests.
Not those who share the same blood.
You're most welcome, Lady Karaca.
My tribe and my tent are also yours.
My niece Aslıhan...
With the order of Vizier Sadettin,
I came here to reunite the Çavdars.
And our people will be here
in a couple of days, Lady Aslıhan.
Welcome.
You are very welcome.
But know this.
The Çavdars are already united.
Our unity will last forever
as long as I'm the leader of this tribe.
Very well, my niece.
Seeing you like this has made me happy.
You did your task very well.
But...
now it's up to a man from the Çavdars
to be the leader.
My Halime, whenever you send me to fight
with tears in your eyes,
I can't think straight.
My sword becomes useless.
I'm proud and I believe in you, Ertuğrul.
Don't you know I love you?
I miss you.
I cry for you.
I wait for you.
Yet I stand patient.
May my tears be your companion.
May my love be your shield.
Dear God...
This is too much to endure.
I can't take this anymore.
I can't take this any longer.
God...
I wish I was the one who died.
So that I wouldn't have to suffer
because I failed to save my bey.
So that I wouldn't have to see a child
suffering like that.
I wish I was the one you took, God.
Mother, Aktolgali is coming.
Aktolgali.
Welcome.
My Gündüz.
Come on, pet him.
Aktolgali.
If you were someone else,
I'd already have killed you.
You have cost me a lot, Ertuğrul.
I have taken good care of you.
We both have to be patient
until I'm paid for my troubles.
If it's the gold you are after
then I can give you more than you want.
I will give you more than you want
if you let me and these slaves go.
I'm touched
by your mercifulness, Ertuğrul.
It gives me goosebumps
to see you still thinking
about the slaves.
But even your wealth won't be enough
to pay me how much I want.
So the man who tricked me is very rich.
You can't even imagine.
Is he as rich as an emperor?
As rich as a vizier?
As rich as a governor?
That's enough, Ertuğrul.
You'll be in chains till morning.
If you behave and ask for my forgiveness
then maybe I'll reconsider
your punishment.
Do you think you can tame me
by putting me in chains?
What are you going to do? Huh?
Will you rip this tree from its roots?
We are the descendants
of those who melted iron mountains.
Nothing can stop us.
We will see, Ertuğrul Bey.
We will see.
Look, Mavro.
This man is so bold,
he can wrestle with an elephant.
He is insane, a maniac!
He is chained to the tree
but keep your eyes on him,
just in case.
Aktolgali is coming, Aktolgali!
The horse of our bey is coming.
Aktolgali is coming!
Aktolgali is here!
Aktolgali.
My God.
Grandmother! Aktolgali is back!
Aktolgali.
Companion of my son.
Our blessed prophet says
that horses bring good news
along with their saddles.
I hope you bring good news
to our troubled tribe.
Hopefully, Mother.
He is a beacon of hope for us.
Horses are the companions of the warriors.
As per our traditions
let's cut his beautiful tail
and tie it to his companion's tombstone.
Yes, Mother.
We shall do that.
My Aktolgali.
Blessed vizier.
Dündar Bey wants to see you.
I wasn't expecting him so soon.
So, Ares stung him deep.
Let him come.
-Welcome Dündar Bey.
-Thank you, blessed vizier.
Come on, take a seat.
What's up? What is troubling you?
Is there a problem with the tribe?
We've been having a hard time
since my brother's death.
It's getting worse every day.
And the bazaar...
The situation with the bazaar
also troubles me.
Even the traders don't visit there
anymore, let alone the customers.
You know, our Sultan believes
that trading is vital.
I know.
I know, blessed vizier.
Our business is getting worse and worse.
Governor Ares came to the bazaar today.
Interesting.
What did he want?
He said this couldn't go on.
He said someone capable should
buy the bazaar.
And he himself proposed to buy it.
I wanted to discuss it with you first.
Well, well, well.
So he wants to buy the bazaar?
So, what do you think about it?
I need to discuss it with my tribe, first.
I'm not sure they'd be okay
with selling the bazaar to Ares.
Yet there is no reason
to insist on suffering losses.
I intend to sell the bazaar,
one way or another.
Well thought.
You need to sell it
if it causes you to suffer losses.
A leader is someone
who can make hard decisions
in times of need.
Don't worry.
I'll be with you.
Now go and discuss the topic
with your mother and your tribe.
And I'll also think about it.
As you order, blessed vizier.
Dear God, who watches over his people.
Dear God, who helps those in need.
Dear God, who makes the sun shine
after a long period of darkness.
Please relieve me of this pain
which makes my heart burn in flames.
Please ease my sufferings.
Take this unbearable burden away from me.
Give me strength
so that I can watch over my tribe
and my children.
Amen.
Dear God,
you are the one
who protected his prophet in dark caves
with a spiderweb.
You are omnipotent.
Help this subject of yours
to escape from these chains.
Strengthen my hands.
Empower my spirit with your grace.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Oh, God!
You took responsibility
for the tribe
after my nephews and brother
passed away.
That's right.
I took good care of my tribe.
Thank God.
Very well.
But you can't continue to do so
as a woman.
There will be some changes
in the border lands.
Çavdars will have to make
great contributions.
Now,
it's inevitable
that we choose a male leader.
There is no such need now.
I'll take good care of my tribe
just like I've been doing
up to this point.
For sure.
You as a woman
did all you could for the tribe.
But all these years
of recession is enough.
A male Çavdar should take the lead.
So that our tribe outgrows the tents!
So that our alps build
castles made of heads
and swim in pools of gold.
So that we can take the lion's share
of the loots from the heathens.
Bahadir Bey.
Lady Aslıhan knows our traditions
very well.
She will do the right thing for sure.
It's not that easy, Bahadir Bey!
You should know that!
It's not appropriate for a lady
to be in a position of leadership
while there is a glorious bey
like Bahadir Bey.
Sancar!
Now,
I'll discuss the matter
with the other beys.
I'll ask for a council meeting at once.
And you should do your part...
instead of resisting against the flow.
Why are you smirking, filthy thief?
Look at you.
The strong Turk even took your sleep
away from you.
So, you still want some more whipping!
Yes, I do.
Seeing the Turk taking the whip
out of your hands was quite a scene.
You can't do anything to me.
Simko would make you pay for it.
And do you know how much gold I'm worth?
Don't worry.
Simko's only concern is the Turk.
He wouldn't care about the death
of a filthy thief like you.
I'll bury you all in the darkness,
for all the innocent people you killed.
Unchain the slaves, too.
We'll leave here at once, Pito.
Be quiet.
What is it, son?
Is there a problem?
Yes, Mother.
You all know about the bazaar.
It has gradually become
a deserted place.
It's obvious
that it can't go on like this.
We need to find a way out
before it gets even worse.
We know, son.
There are black clouds upon us.
What do you think?
I say we sell the bazaar, Mother.
This is not a way out, Dündar Bey.
The bazaar is more precious to us
than any treasure in the world.
You know that very well.
I do, Artuk Bey.
I do.
Yet it becomes a burden
if it doesn't make a profit.
It'll be even harder for us to go on
if we lose our reputation.
If we want a way out
then we should consider fixing the problem
instead of selling the bazaar.
The bazaar is a relic of Ertuğrul Bey.
There is no need
to make him feel disturbed in his grave.
This is a place of discussions.
And there is an important matter
to discuss.
Everyone wants what's best for the tribe.
It's appropriate for everyone
to speak their minds.
Ertuğrul Bey took the bazaar
with his sword, Mother.
How can we even discuss selling it?
The appropriate thing to do is
to sharpen your words like a sword
and say no to them.
My girl.
We are in a critical situation.
Sharp words
won't do any good
in a matter like this.
Lady Hayme.
You are right.
The issue is very important.
However, selling the bazaar
is not the solution.
Also, the one who offered it...
was Governor Ares.
What is this, Dündar Bey?
Do you intend to sell the bazaar,
which was taken with a fight,
to the heathens in return for gold?
Mother, don't you have anything
to say to that?
-The slaves are escaping!
-Get up!
Get up, the slaves are escaping! Run!
Damn it! Get them!
Pito! You run away!
I will catch up with you! Go!
May God protect you, Turk.
Is that so, Dündar?
Yes, Mother.
But I didn't say yes to the governor.
The bazaar can't be sold to a heathen
even if it does need to be sold.
A heathen can't buy
the Muslims' blood with gold.
This is our red line.
I'm not suggesting selling it
to the governor!
I'd like this matter to be discussed
without any bad intentions.
The matter started
with a bad intention, Dündar Bey.
No matter who the buyer is
this bazaar can't be sold for gold,
as it wasn't acquired with gold.
Artuk Bey is right.
Whatever I do,
I do for the good of my tribe, Artuk Bey!
We can't even prevent the bandits
from attacking.
The bazaar needs to be sold
before it becomes a greater burden!
It will cause losses
as long as we have it.
It's no time for conflict.
What we need to do is
to stand united and find a solution
instead of arguing.
Dündar Bey has found
his own solution.
And you spoke your minds.
The bazaar is not personal property.
It belongs to the tribe.
Discussing the matter with the council
is the appropriate thing to do.
Dündar Bey should gather the council
as soon as possible.
And we should abide by the decision
of the council.
No! I need him alive!
Get him! Run!
-Run!
-Catch them all!
You should've seen Dündar's face.
I saw it.
He came to me after you spoke to him.
He mentioned your offer.
They won't sell the bazaar to you.
But Dündar still intends to sell it.
He was going to discuss it with his tribe.
Everything is going smoothly,
Vizier Sadettin.
You have the advantage, now.
Bahadir Bey,
a bey of the Çavdars, arrived today.
He is the uncle of Aslıhan.
He will make this place
home for his tribe.
Also,
he will buy the bazaar for us.
I envy your wit, Vizier Sadettin.
So...
Now, it's your turn, Ares.
Here is the shiny glow of our victory,
Vizier Sadettin.
That bazaar is ours now.
No one can stop us,
neither Ertuğrul, nor the Kayi tribe.
I have no doubt about it,
Vizier Sadettin.
No one can stop us
as long as we stand together.
Not even the Sultan.
Not even the emperor.
Come on!
Thank God!
I will reunite with my family!
After all, I'll get to see my children!
We are grateful for everything.
We wouldn't have been able to escape
from them if it weren't for you.
It's not over yet. We may come across them
at any moment.
There is no need to worry now.
Simko will never be able to catch us.
That pack of bastards is unpredictable.
Come on, be quick.
Come on!
We were very fortunate today, again.
We raided yet another caravan
going to the bazaar.
-Thanks to our friend Ares.
-Mihalis!
-Is there another caravan?
-It's something far more precious.
-What is it?
-I saw Ertuğrul, the bey of the Kayi.
Are you delusional, you fool?
Ertuğrul is dead!
No, Mihalis, he is not.
I'm sure I saw him.
Come on!
The star of richness is shining upon us.
We'll get the real prize now.
Simko the slave trader. So, you have
Ertuğrul in your possession.
Send word to Ares.
Let him know we saw Ertuğrul,
that Simko the slave trader had him
and that we were chasing after them.
All right, Mihalis.
Oh, Aktolgali!
Somehow, I can't accept the death
of Ertuğrul Bey.
And you arrived at such a time
that you became a beacon of hope for me.
Perhaps they will call me crazy
and they will mock me.
But I don't care what they say.
You are back, along with a beacon of hope.
No one can extinguish this hope
inside my heart now.
My God,
you placed this hope in my heart.
You wouldn't do that if there wasn't
something planned.
Either set this hope ablaze
or extinguish it once and for all.
I can't take it anymore.
Come on!
They went this way. They can't be too far.
Quickly! Come on.
I need to speak with the blessed vizier.
Your Eminence, Bahadir Bey is asking
for permission to talk to you.
Let him come.
Your Eminence.
Bahadir Bey, victorious commander
of the battlefields.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
Go on, take a seat.
We've heard of your bravery.
You left a trail of dead enemies
in your wake, again.
Praise be, no enemy who fell into my claws
was able to escape.
Excellent.
You deserve a reward after all this glory.
From now on, you'll settle in these lands
with your tribe.
With your arrival, the divided Cavdars
will be reunited and made stronger.
Hopefully so, Your Eminence.
May God protect you and the state.
Did you talk to Lady Aslıhan?
I did. I said I wanted a council meeting.
She didn't like the idea.
But the Cavdar beys are what is important.
I'll talk to them one by one
and convince them about the meeting.
Be quick about it.
We have important things to do with you.
I'm very curious. What is it?
The bey of the Kayi, Dündar,
wants to sell the bazaar.
And you'll make a proposal to buy it,
which will increase your reputation.
Excuse me, Your Eminence.
But even if I wanted to buy the bazaar,
I couldn't possibly afford it.
Don't worry. I've gotten everything
ready for you.
This is yours.
You'll make your proposal
with these golds.
I'll talk to Dündar for you.
And he won't be able to refuse
when he sees this gold.
But I have some conditions.
You need only to command, Your Eminence.
You'll reunite the Cavdars
and become their leader.
Then, you'll do whatever it takes
to become the margrave.
Now, we are in this together.
So, you won't take a step
without my knowledge.
Furthermore, whatever it takes,
you'll prevent the marriage
of Turgut and Lady Aslıhan.
That marriage won't take place.
You understand, don't you?
I do, Your Eminence.
Excellent.
So, go back and do whatever is necessary
to gather the council.
And wait to hear from me.
Get ready, Goktug.
We are going to the bazaar.
As you order, Your Eminence.
Move!
What is that?
It's addressed to Commander Ares.
These are the Turkish tribes
which surround us.
The grand operation will start
once the army comes from Nicaea,
and we'll destroy them all.
You dealt a debilitating blow to the Turks
by destroying Ertuğrul.
We'll burn their tribes,
herds and bazaars.
We won't stop until we rip
their hearts out.
We will hit them so hard
that there will never be another Ertuğrul.
Come in!
What is it?
Governor Ares,
I found this letter nailed on the door
of your chamber with a dagger.
We have Ertuğrul, he is alive.
We healed his wounds and we know
that you killed his alps.
I didn't reveal your identity to Ertuğrul.
If you don't do what I demand
he and the sultan will find out
it's you who ambushed him.
Wait to hear from me.
How is it possible
that Ertuğrul is alive? He is dead!
Sir, calm down.
You saw his burial with your own eyes.
Then who wrote this letter?
Who infiltrated us and nailed this letter
on the door of my chamber with a dagger?
Sir, whoever they are, they are lying.
No one would dare do that.
Ertuğrul is alive. He lives.
Find whoever did this at once.
Find him right now, I said.
Get the hell out of here!
I murdered him.
I murdered Ertuğrul!
Ertuğrul!
Water!
We are so tired. Let us rest.
I can't go on like this.
We can't stop here. It's too dangerous.
Come on, just a little more.
We'll die of fatigue.
Come on.
-Take it easy.
-Thanks.
Where are you headed?
To the Red Apple.
-What is your destination?
-Martyrdom.
Where will you end up?
With the homeland.
Where is the homeland?
It's the whole world.
Ilbey wanted me to deliver this letter
to you.
May God help you.
Artuk Bey, we heard about Ertuğrul Bey.
We've revealed important information.
We are shadowing those lands.
Take care of the Kayi tribe.
Don't let it disintegrate.
I'll visit there as soon as possible.
Wait to hear from me.
Ilbey wouldn't visit here
if it wasn't important.
Dear God, both good and bad
are your doing.
Please do good this time.
So, Dündar,
did you find the chance to discuss
the issue about the bazaar?
-Yes, Your Eminence.
-Very well.
They don't want it to be sold to Ares.
And they are right.
But we decided to gather the council
to discuss the topic.
Of course, the property of Muslims
can't be sold to the heathens.
But there will be other buyers.
I mean, if you are determined
to be the bey...
I am.
But I'm thinking what we'd do here
if we sold the bazaar.
Dündar,
is it absolutely necessary
for you to stay here?
Why don't you go be with your brothers
Sungur Tekin and Gündoğdu?
Look, you were with your brother Ertuğrul.
But now you are all alone.
It may be hard for you
in these border lands.
You can revive your tribe with the gold
you'll receive for the selling.
Then, you can migrate
to where your brothers are...
and restore the power
of the Kayi tribe again.
Additionally, I know someone who can pay
the amount of gold you want.
Who is it?
Bahadir Bey, the brother of Candar Bey.
He has just come back from battle.
I know his plunder was substantial.
You can sell it to him if you like.
Also, he is a Muslim, so it's appropriate.
Accept his gold and relieve yourself
and your tribe from this misery.
Also, migrate to where your brothers are
and restore the power of Kayi.
You are right, Your Eminence.
But first, the beys need to be convinced
at council.
Well, you will show your skills.
Convincing is your duty.
Dündar,
you are not Dündar the Rookie anymore.
You are Dündar the Bey.
Sir. Mihalis sent a letter.
Didn't I tell him to hide somewhere?
He was hiding, sir.
But there is some terrible news.
Mihalis...
Mihalis saw Ertuğrul, sir.
Is that fool sure he saw him?
Not only Mihalis, sir.
His men also saw Ertuğrul.
-I killed him!
-Mihalis is after him, sir.
-Where did he see him?
-Simko the slave trader had him.
Get him to me dead or alive at once.
I said at once. Get lost!
Door!
So, Simko has him.
Maria.
That scum! Maria!
Door!
With the 99 names of the holy God,
who makes it happen
when he says "Let there be,"
bismillahirahmanirahim.
Honorable and brave beys of the Kayi,
you all know about the situation
the bazaar is in.
Neither caravans nor traders
are visiting anymore.
-Dündar Bey is right.
-The situation is bad.
There will be a shortage of food soon.
-Yes, soon.
It's impossible to deal with the bandits
who hit the caravans.
And it's obvious this can't go on.
So, that's why...
I decided to sell the bazaar.
What will we do if we sell the bazaar?
How can you sell the bazaar, my bey?
The bazaar is our source of income.
-We don't have any other source.
-But Dündar Bey is also right.
-What, should we suffer a food shortage?
-Beys.
-What will we do if we sell the bazaar?
-My beys!
My beys.
As you know, this bazaar
was acquired with the blood of martyrs.
So, think accordingly.
Artuk Bey is right. He is.
Selling the bazaar means turning our backs
on the legacy of Ertuğrul Bey.
It means turning back on his cause.
Whatever I do,
I do for the good of the tribe.
My brother would do the same.
Watch what you are saying.
These words are not appropriate...
in a council meeting opened with prayers.
With the gold we'll get
in return for selling the bazaar,
our tribe will revive itself
and be relieved of the shortages.
Hopefully so.
We listened to everyone. But your thoughts
are important, Mother Hayme.
What do you think?
It's true that the bazaar is the legacy
of my son and the martyrs,
yet it's also true it has become a burden.
They conquered the bazaar
for the sake of our tribe.
Now,
for the sake of our tribe,
it can be sold if it needs to be.
It is the beys' decision.
How come? It's a tough decision.
There will be nothing left once the bazaar
is sold. What will we do here then?
We don't have to stay here.
Where will we go, my bey?
This is our homeland.
Where can we go?
It's time for the Kayi
to reunite and become one again.
He is right.
Having sold the bazaar,
I say it's appropriate for us to migrate
where my brothers live.
It's not appropriate.
How can we leave our lands?
We can't leave these lands.
Come on. Just a little more.
Come on.
Did you think you could escape
from me, Ertuğrul Bey, huh?
You are my most precious slave.
I don't want to hurt you.
So, surrender.
I won't become a captive
to you or anyone else.
Get him.
-Run! Leave here!
-We can't leave you.
Don't you hurt the Turk. I need him alive.
My beys!
The issue has become
about the cause of Ertuğrul Bey.
Selling the bazaar and leaving the land
for which we shed our blood
means turning our backs on the cause
of Ertuğrul Bey.
-He is right.
-We can't give up on the cause.
Artuk Bey is right.
If that's the case, another council
meeting is necessary.
For what, Artuk Bey?
For the election of a new bey, Lady Hayme.
We chose Dündar Bey as the leader
so that he could follow the cause,
but he intends to turn his back
on the cause.
Given the circumstances,
his leadership is not legitimate.
What do you say, Artuk Bey?
Are you defying your bey's decision?
Dündar Bey, you are the defiant one.
You are not defiant against a single man
but against a whole cause.
-He is right. Yes.
-He speaks the truth.
Let's say we gathered the council.
Is there anyone asking to be the leader
other than Dündar Bey?
There is, Lady Hayme.
To follow the path and the cause
of Ertuğrul Bey,
I'm a candidate.
-Artuk Bey, what are you saying?
-How?
Who the hell are they?
Don't let Ertuğrul get away.