Episode 118 will start after 12:10 min.
My dear son.
Eat your food
and be a glorious alp.
Come, Gündüz.
Come, sit.
Father.
Will you take care of us
when Mother is gone?
Will you feed Savcı?
I will, son.
I will.
I'll help you, Father.
I shall feed both my brothers.
I shall protect them.
I'm proud of you.
Go on.
Father, my brother is full.
He is, son.
He is.
I'm proud of you.
A brave brother like you,
feeds his brother with his own hands.
I'm proud of you.
And I'm proud of you as well.
My Sultan.
It's not good that Ögeday sent Noyan
as a messenger.
Their wish is clear,
Hüsamettin Karaca.
We already pay our taxes, my Sultan.
What else?
The Mongols are at the Danube.
Desht-i Kipchak and
the Black sea are theirs.
They're pressuring us.
That scum is trying to take advantage
of this
to try to create chaos in the Seljuk lands
every day.
Ögeday will consider all this
and raise his demands.
May God protect us from them.
Alps, brothers.
Be cautious.
These are treacherous times.
We must be ever vigilant.
Is this the next problem
the Emperor has for us?
We'll see, brother.
We'll see.
-Be careful, alps.
-As you order.
Just in case.
I'm the new commander
of Bilecik Castle.
My name is Romanos.
Welcome.
Thank you.
I heard that Ertuğrul Bey lost his wife.
I've come to offer condolences
and for peace talks.
Huh.
What peace?
Our Emperor specifically tasked me
with this.
I wish to see Ertuğrul Bey, if possible.
Wait here.
I'll tell Ertuğrul Bey.
My Sultan,
Noyan asks to see you.
Let him in.
Do you not know
how to respect a Sultan, Noyan?
I'm the messenger of Ögeday Khan,
the Khan of Khans.
If I am to respect someone,
he must be mightier than my Khan.
I don't see anyone like that.
What does your...
Ögeday Khan want?
My Khan's demands
are in this letter.
Let me see.
God created you so beautifully.
My little lion.
My brave son.
Permission to enter, my Bey?
Come, Turgut.
-Speak.
-My Bey.
A man named Commander Romanos came.
For you.
What does he want?
To offer his condolences...
and to discuss peace.
Wait, son, don't cry.
My Osman.
Don't cry.
Turgut, you and Bamsı speak with him.
You'll tell me about it after.
As you order.
Excuse me.
My son.
Look,
I'm here, I didn't go.
I'm with you.
Don't cry, my son.
Don't cry.
The tributes your khan demands
would weaken my state.
It wouldn't do you any good,
even if you were strong,
Sultan Giyaseddin.
Power is not important when you are
under Ogedei Khan's rule...
obedience is.
I agree to... Ogedei Khan's request.
I will double the tributes
I have paid up to now.
But of course you will, Sultan Giyaseddin.
The future of your state
and your throne depends on it.
However... I have a request of my own
for your khan.
What is it?
When you ride to deliver my answer
to your khan,
my emissary will accompany you.
There are important matters
I wish to communicate to Ogedei Khan.
I pity that emissary already.
Who will this emissary be?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul?
Husamettin Karaca will give you my decree.
No one will stand in the way
of you leaving.
You may go now.
I would be honored to have
Ertuğrul Bey's company on the journey.
But be careful you don't
provoke Ogedei Khan's anger.
It would break my heart if Ogedei got to
take Ertuğrul's head instead of me.
I bring our emperor's greetings
and condolences to Ertuğrul Bey.
He sends his deepest regrets
over the loss of his dear wife.
Thank you, Commander Romanos.
Our emperor also sends this letter
of friendship to Ertuğrul Bey.
We wish to make a strong
and lasting peace with you.
Your emperor has frequently made
promises of peace to our bey and sultan.
But... each time he breaks it
with some new act of treachery.
The hand of peace you extend to us
comes dripping with betrayal and blood.
How can you expect us to believe you
after everything that's happened?
The Mongols.
What do the Mongols have to do with peace?
The Mongols have taken Crimea.
The Black Sea is now under their rule.
They will soon reach Baghdad.
They will surround Anatolia
on three sides.
Look, it's just you and us out here.
We have to make peace in order to protect
Anatolia from a Mongolian invasion.
We are aware of everything you speak of.
We too are taking precautions as a state.
However, none of that
is enough for us to trust you.
In exchange for peace,
our emperor will not challenge
your right to settle in Söğüt.
You can settle there whenever you want.
Just agree to unite with us
against the Mongols.
Don't try to suggest your emperor
is bestowing anything on us.
Söğüt is ours to take.
It's not in our interest
to turn away the hand of peace.
We won't let you down.
But, Commander Romanos, if you do
let us down, we will destroy you.
If you betray us one more time...
know that we will trample you
under our horses hooves.
We both want peace.
Then...
good day to you.
Osman, you are such a beautiful child.
I just got him to sleep. Don't touch him.
What's with the temper?
Why do you protect the child so?
Its own mother wouldn't be so cautious.
Do you not trust me?
You brought the head
of Ertuğrul Bey's enemy to the tent.
Ertuğrul Bey trusts you.
However...
even though I didn't
bear Osman, I do feed him.
I look after him
as if he was my own child.
What harm do you see in me caressing him
that causes you to intervene?
Osman didn't eat for a long time.
He has my milk now
but he needs to rest to grow stronger.
What's going on, ladies?
We are tending to Osman, Hayme Hatun.
God bless him.
He is like a ray of light, praise be.
It's obvious he will be a wonderful child.
Sugay, my girl.
Are you all right? You look so tired.
I hope nothing is wrong.
As you said,
I am a little tired, Hayme Hatun.
I will rest as soon as Osman
recovers a little more of his strength.
All right, my girl.
Ertuğrul Bey is inside. You may see him.
Your brother fell asleep at last.
Father, you've taken care of us
since my mother left.
You feed us, give us water,
dress us, and put us to sleep.
Of course I do, son.
But you also have your duty to do.
How is it you're always looking after us?
Maybe you should think about
getting us a new mother, Father.
-May I enter, Ertuğrul Bey?
-Come, Almila Hatun.
My condolences, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
-What is it?
-I came about a matter of trade.
But I can see you are busy.
Come, sit down.
Talk to me, Almila Hatun.
Our hides have proved
popular with the people.
I spoke to the Rum notables.
They too liked our hides very much.
They want to buy a great number from us.
Our earnings will increase and it will
provide work for the people here.
And you will make earnings
through the tax due to you.
I want authority from you
to agree the deal and set it in
motion with the Rum merchants.
With the honesty
you've shown at Hanli bazaar
you helped us establish
a more just system, Almila Hatun.
On top of that, by bringing me
the head of Kritos after the tannery raid,
you gained my trust.
I would like to receive you
at my tent this evening.
We can talk about
this matter in more detail.
As you wish, Ertuğrul Bey. Thank you.
May God allow you to see the day
your sons wield swords, Ertuğrul Bey.
Amen.
The Mongols killed my mother and father.
My brother and I grew up alone.
Your sons are very fortunate
to have a father like you
and a grandmother like
Mother Hayme to take care of them.
You tend to your sons
despite your other responsibilities.
May God always keep you with them.
Amen, Almila Hatun.
-Excuse me.
-You may go.
Gündüz, see to the bed
so I can put your brother down.
Men, this is the way to Söğüt.
Those in the vanguard will take measures
to establish where the tribe will be set.
A unit is to be positioned at stages
along the road to ensure safe passage.
Two units, one at the front and one
at the rear, will escort the convoy.
-May I enter, my Bey?
-Come.
My bey, a commander
has arrived from Konya.
He says he brings an important
letter from the sultan.
A letter from the sultan? Show him in.
-Begin preparations.
-As you command, my Bey.
What's this about a letter
from our sultan, commander?
Our sultan commands Ertuğrul Bey act
as envoy to the Mongol Khan Ogedei.
Envoy to Ogedei?
This is the sealed order, my Bey.
And these are to be
entrusted to Ertuğrul Bey.
-Is there a situation, Commander?
-I don't know, my Bey.
The sultan's personal demands
are contained in these documents.
They need to be given
to Ertuğrul Bey immediately.
All right.
Then let's get them
to Ertuğrul Bey right now.
Can I come in?
My Osman.
My brave son who came as a gift.
May God render you fortunate.
I thank God for sending you to me.
Sugay Hatun.
May God bless you too.
You came at my darkest hour...
and what you brought kept my Osman alive.
You provided hope... for Osman and for me.
In his mother's absence...
you took him as your own.
It was very hard to bear
the loss of my own child.
But... Osman has come
into my life like the sun.
God has allowed me
to nurse this beautiful child.
I would like to bring him up
worthy of God.
You and I are being tested
severely, Sugay Hatun.
What God sends...
we must accept without question.
From now on...
my home is your home.
And Osman...
will always be a son of yours.
That would please me greatly,
Ertuğrul Bey.
My dear mother. My doe-eyed mother.
If only you knew
how much I missed you already.
If you came back now...
I'd hug you so tight.
If you would say once more to me,
"My Gündüz, my valiant son",
I'd never upset you again
and I'd always do what you said.
If only you knew how
much I missed you, Mother.
My brothers are so small.
My father does everything he can
to tend to our every need.
But how can he carry
this burden on his own?
What will we do without you, Mother?
Son.
Ibnu'l Arabi, sir.
Were you pouring water
over your mother's grave and praying, son?
Yes, sir.
Good for you.
He who visits his mother's grave
to pray and pour water over it...
is a very dutiful child.
Thank you, sir.
However, I'm very upset
my mother went away.
I want to stand tall. But it is very hard.
Come now.
Come and sit.
I want to tell you about someone.
When this boy was still
in his mother's womb
he lost his father.
He was born fatherless.
He lost his mother as a small child
and soon after that his grandfather too,
the man who had taken him under his wing.
Cruel men who saw he had no one...
pursued him without mercy.
They wanted to turn him from his cause.
They tortured and tormented him.
They despised him and poured dirt
over his head... while he was praying.
He sought to enlighten their dark souls...
but those cruel men just made fun of him.
If that wasn't enough,
they had him stoned.
But even as he was being stoned...
he did not pray ill
of those who had ordered it.
He prayed they should be saved.
He then saw the loss of his precious wife,
his beloved and his source of comfort...
and also his uncle,
who had protected him.
These losses weighed
so heavily on his heart
the year was deemed "the year of sorrow".
He buried his young children
with his own hands.
Do you know what he did
in the face of all this pain, son?
What did he do, sir?
He showed no sign of despair.
He spoke not a word
of defiance against his fate.
With determination...
and with loyalty to his cause...
he continued on his path.
Who is this blessed person, sir?
Why did he have to endure so much?
The master of the universe...
he who was sent
as a blessing to the realms...
our great prophet
Muhammed Mustafa, my son.
Our Prophet was steadfast
and compassionate.
He was patient in the face
of so many trials.
My father tells us
to follow our Prophet's path
and let him guide us.
I guess that's why.
My son, this world is full
of things which will test us.
God demands the most
of the ones he loves the most.
Because if God loves a person...
he strengthens them and helps them rise
by making them endure such ordeals.
You know, the further back
an arrow is pulled...
the further it flies when released.
It falls on you now
to take care of your brothers.
To support your father.
If you make the effort...
God will reward you with the patience
and resilience to see it through.
God willing, sir.
Come now, let us pray
for the souls of our Prophet...
and of Halime Sultan.
I told them,
"If you ever betray this peace...
we will trample you
under our horses hooves," my Bey.
Good, Turgut.
We need to be cautious.
Keep your eyes and ears open.
Byzantium has ten tongues
and every one of them lies.
The doors to Söğüt
are now open to us, my Bey.
Söğüt...
Halime and I...
would often talk about
the home we would create there.
We were going to further our tribe...
and our lineage there.
My Bey...
That blessed home will still
be built there, thanks to you.
We will further our tribe and lineage.
My father...
died in my arms.
I've lost so many loved ones, Bamsı.
But the pain of losing Halime...
cuts into my heart like a knife.
With every passing moment,
it cuts me deeper.
I know, my Bey, I know.
I know only too well
how that pain takes root in your heart.
It seems...
we only truly understand...
the value of our loved ones
when they are gone.
I wish I'd given her more of my time
while she was alive.
I would give the world
to have her here by my side
so that I may look
into her eyes one more time.
When a man buries his beloved,
he buries half his heart
beside her, my Bey.
That is true, Turgut.
And what's left of our heart
belongs to our children...
and our cause.
If not this way...
the pain of our loss
would make the world unendurable.
We...
need to collect ourselves.
We should not...
make an extravagant display
of either our pain or our love.
-You're right, my Bey.
Come now, my brave men.
Can I come in?
Welcome, my son.
Praise be...
Osman is growing stronger, Mother.
Thank God.
Thank God for sending
Sugay Hatun to you, my son.
She treats Osman as if he were her own.
If it hadn't been for her...
where would our Osman be now?
Thank God, Mother.
Sugay Hatun is a part of our family now.
As you ordered...
a tent is being prepared for her.
It will be ready soon, God willing.
God willing, Mother.
What would I have done
if I'd not had you here with me, Mother?
May God always keep you with us.
My valiant boy.
You have survived many ordeals.
You have walked fiery paths.
But you never gave up.
I know.
The pain of losing Halime
lies heavy on your heart.
But even in your saddest moments...
you still thought of your children,
of your family, of your tribe.
May God always keep you with us, my son.
My Gündüz, my Savci, my Osman...
they are all my sons.
They are a piece of me.
Be comforted by that.
Mother.
What could those drums herald?
I hope all is well.
The alps are outside, Mother.
They'll come and tell us soon.
He burned everything down!
Alps! Alps!
Return your swords to their scabbards!
We need to find out first what has given
this bastard the audacity to come here.
I come in peace.
What peace?
We've no time for your lies, Noyan!
How dare you come here?
I come here at the order of Ogedei,
Khan of Khans...
and at the request
of your sultan, Giyaseddin.
What did the dog say?
Here is your sultan's decree.
He burned everything we had!
What are you doing, woman?
-Murderer!
-Punish him!
This bastard put my tribe to the sword.
Let go of me!
-I'm going to kill this dog, let go!
-Calm down, woman.
Are you going to allow...
a half-crazed woman
to attack Ogedei's envoy?
Oguz Alp, get Almila Hatun out of here.
If you don't punish the greatest devil
this world has ever known,
tell Ertuğrul Bey I will torment him
in this world and the next!
-Oguz Alp.
-Let go! Let go of me!
Let go!
Tell Ertuğrul Bey I am here.
Abdurrahman.
Go to Ertuğrul Bey immediately.
-Kill him!
-Take his head!
Kill him!
Get rid of him!
-May I enter, my Bey?
-Come, Abdurrahman.
-My Bey.
-What's all the noise, Abdurrahman?
Noyan.
He has come here to see you
at the request of our sultan.
-What are you saying, Abdurrahman?
-My God.
My God, give me strength.
Our sultan's decree, my Bey.
Tell Artuk Bey, Turgut Bey and Bamsı
to go to my tent and wait for me there.
-Let Noyan wait.
-As you command, my Bey.
What does this dog want from us, son?
What is he doing here?
Our Sultan entrusts Noyan's life
to me in his decree, Mother.
He wants us to treat him as our guest.
But he is to say why...
with his own messengers.
What is it, Almila Hatun?
I come from the tribe, Günalp Bey.
Noyan just turned up there.
-Noyan?
-Noyan.
He was one of the bastards
who murdered my family.
I'd have killed him
but the alps stopped me.
All right. We ride to the tribe too.
Let's hurry. God speed.
God speed, Günalp Bey.
Why do you show yourself
like this, brother, why?
That woman rides
just like the Mongols do, my Bey.
Her horse is like theirs, too.
I noticed. Come on.
My Bey, we don't know
if he's telling the truth or not.
Let me kill him for you right here.
If we were to kill an envoy of Ögedei
who was here at the orders of our Sultan,
we'd give him the excuse
he wants to attack our land, Bamsi.
Ögedei Khan would call
our Sultan to account for Noyan,
knowing his army is a stone's
throw away from us in Şimal.
What if he's lying?
What if this is a ploy, my Bey?
The only way we'll find out for sure
is to have Noyan address
Ertuğrul Bey directly.
Abdur Rahman.
-Show Noyan in.
-Your wish is my command, my Bey.
May God steer us safely through this.
Gok Tengri...
rotates the world around the sun
on and on, never stopping.
He turns it...
to keep our eagerness...
to stand up and fight
constant and undiminished.
Here I am again, Ertuğrul.
The spirits didn't want me to die.
The spirits...
know the account between
you and me is not yet settled.
You wanted to bury me in the ground.
But mother earth didn't take me.
Mother earth would have vomited
a bastard like you out of her soil, Noyan.
Your tongue is
as sharp as your sword, Ertuğrul.
I'm grateful to the spirits,
for granting me a wise
and brave enemy like you.
Tell me, what is it you want, Noyan?
First, my condolences.
I heard that Halime Sultan died.
She was a courageous woman.
At one time, she gave me
as hard a time as you did.
What do Ögedei Khan
and our sultan want with me?
You probably heard
the khan of the khans, Ögedei Khan,
and I won a famous victory
in a great battle recently.
We took Kiev.
The Black Sea, just like the Caspian
and the Aral seas, is our sea now.
We rule half the world, Ertuğrul.
Now we're impatient
to take the other half.
Get to the point.
Why are you here, Noyan?
I am here as Ögedei Khan's envoy, bringing
his orders to your Sultan Giyaseddin.
As you'll have surmised, your sultan...
swore to follow the orders of my Khan.
But your young sultan has made
a request to Ögedei Khan.
And the envoy he chose
to convey this request, is you.
So you see, you and I have
a long journey ahead of us, Ertuğrul.
My Bey, you can't trust a word he says.
-May I enter, my Bey?
-Come, Günalp Bey.
Orders from our sultan, my Bey.
Read it aloud so everyone knows
this heathen speaks the truth.
Our sultan...
orders me to be his envoy...
to Ögedei Khan.
Our sultan wants you
to take this bag with you.
Sugay, daughter,
put this thick blanket on too.
It's going to be frosty tonight.
Mother Hayme...
we had our share of trouble
from those bastard Mongols too.
They used to raid our tents.
They never got tired of harassing us.
They showed no mercy
when they slaughtered my family.
I've hated them my whole life.
May God save us from their malice.
I see you have suffered
a great deal, daughter.
May God ensure your parents rest in peace.
It's not easy to bear
what you've been through.
Amen. Our struggle against
the Mongols is very hard.
May God help Ertuğrul Bey and our state.
Amen, my girl. Amen.
As soon as we rid ourselves
of one trouble, another rears its head.
We only just dealt with that evil Kopek...
and now it is this bastard Noyan
who haunts us.
May God help us.
A new plague has reached our door.
We have to be careful.
If we stand united against the enemy,
no one can defeat us.
I hope so, my girl. I hope so.
God help us.
Bamsi,
take Abdur Rahman and Oğuz and five alps.
Noyan will stay
at the Hanlı Bazaar tonight.
Your wish is my command, my Bey.
You won't have me stay here
as your guest, Ertuğrul?
We don't turn anyone
away from our tent, Noyan.
You'll be my guest at the Hanlı Bazaar.
When do we set forth?
You'll find out in the morning, Noyan.
What are you saying, Ertuğrul?
Will you refuse
to be your sultan's envoy?
Bamsi.
Get Noyan away from here
before something happens to him.
That's all I'll say now.
Alps.
What have they been up to?
All they've done in eat, like bears
that've just woken up, Chief Alp Bamsi.
They eat more than me.
Watch they don't choke on it and die.
Whatever Ertuğrul Bey's orders are,
death will come
to this heathen by our hands.
You said it, Chief Alp Bamsi. God willing.
God willing. God willing.
Come over, iron man.
Come and share my table.
I wouldn't even share my sin
with someone like you, Noyan.
But if you can't share my dinner now...
how will you share your stinking state
and these glorious lands,
and even those rosy-cheeked women
of yours, when the time comes?
What's wrong, iron man? Why hold back?
Or do you want to keep that grudge
you nurture all to yourself too?
Its time will come, Noyan.
Its time will come.
And when it does,
I'll cut out your snake's tongue.
I'll tell you what will happen
when the time comes, iron man.
When the time comes,
the spirits hidden in the beech trees
will appear one by one.
The screams of these spirits
will drown out the sound of your horses.
While your Sultan Giyaseddin
washes his father's blood off his hands,
he'll keep on making mistakes,
keep on making terrible mistakes,
so that first, he'll have to share
his palace with me and then his harem.
Then I'll come back here.
I'll destroy the regime
Ertuğrul has maintained.
He'll be scorched by my fire
under the shade of his tent.
Along with all his family.
Comrades!
The Avsars, the Kiniks...
the Dodurgas and the Cavdars,
will have no place to run.
They'll surrender to the fate laid out
for them
on the slopes of Khan Tengri mountain.
They'll stand in front of me
with bent necks and kiss my boots.
As for the Kayi, they won't get away
just with kissing my boots.
I'll make them taste a less happy fate.
I'll skin Ertuğrul's whole family
and sew myself a great tent out of them.
Skin your bastards first, Noyan,
to patch the holes in your rotten flesh
that my Bey made with his sword.
Your foul-smelling, rotten flesh
which I wouldn't even use
to line the soles of my boots.
Laugh, Noyan. Laugh.
When the cool dawn wind blows, Noyan!
When the northern goshawk
with the grey beard sings;
when the Bedouin horses
see their master and neigh;
when the long-bearded stranger shouts;
when white becomes black;
when the bride and daughter
of the numerous Oghuz
is decked out for battle, for freedom;
when the sun hits the beautifully
breasted rough mountains;
when the brave men, the heroes,
come together;
the wrath of God, Noyan, will be on you!
God is the greatest!
You keep taking shelter
behind the tales of your ancestors.
I came here not to retell tales,
I came here to make history.
God is the greatest!
Our sultan wants to send you
into the Mongolian hell, my Bey.
But as long as Noyan remains with us,
we won't be safe.
Our sultan knows that you and Noyan are
at daggers drawn, my Bey.
So why does he take the risk
of sending you with him?
-There, there, Savci.
-Give him to me.
Keep on growing, my lion.
You're going to be a fine man.
You'll travel these lands
on the back of your horse.
Everyone will know you
when you put on your sword.
Wolf-eyed like my ancestor Oghuz,
my heavenly son.
Son, what is this about
our sultan wanting you to be his envoy?
It's important, Mother.
I've never seen Ertuğrul Bey
look so worried before.
More pain comes before the last
has receded, Günalp Bey.
His alps, brave men, all martyred.
The grief of losing
Halime Hatun still consumes him.
He's not being given a chance
to mourn his woman.
First brother Ahmet,
and now this devil Noyan turns up.
His children...
Those three little boys left motherless.
Our bey will make his decision.
And when he does,
he will fulfil his promise,
even if it kills him.
-God protect him.
Do you remember Mother,
when I first brought Halime to the tent...
I was an envoy then too.
Now Halime is gone,
and I have the duties
of an envoy once again.
It is fate, Mother.
I remember. How could I forget?
Duty is important son,
but going to the Mongol Khan
with this evil Noyan...
We can't know what will happen,
what troubles you'll face.
Father, are you going to leave us again?
What will we do when you're gone?
I'm big now, but what about Savci?
And Osman?
Look how quiet Osman is when
you hold him in your arms.
What if he cries again and wants you?
My Gündüz, my lion.
You said it was important.
What if you don't come back?
My mother's gone.
How are we to manage if you go too?
What will we do if
you leave this world too?
I've been waiting for you, Alangoya.
Is what I heard true, brother?
Ertuğrul will accompany me
to see Ögedei as an envoy.
And you'll kill him on the way.
That depends on what Ertuğrul decides.
What do you mean?
Whether my grudge remains or not
depends on what Ertuğrul decides.
What do you want from him, brother?
Victory, Alangoya.
Victory.
A bloodless victory.
Ögedei asked me to persuade
the brave Turk beys to obey him.
Beginning with Ertuğrul.
Now, as Ertuğrul is due to
come before Ögedei as an envoy...
Ögedei will hear Ertuğrul's
decision himself.
We'll win this battle without
our swords being soaked in blood.
As for you, Alangoya...
you are to remain
as my eyes and ears in these lands.
Rouse the broody hen inside you.
Endear yourself...
to the hearts of Ertuğrul's children
and his mother.
Neither Ertuğrul nor his family
should learn who you are.
Until we have achieved
our purpose, that is.
What if Ertuğrul refuses to obey Ögedei ?
Then they all die,
including Osman in his cradle.
Keep your sword sharp
and your heart as soft
as the snow on the slopes
of Khan Tengri mountain, Alangoya.
Apparently, the fate of the state
depends once more upon us doing our duty.
We need to fulfill this duty
if we are going to ensure
no lives are lost.
We'll set forth tomorrow morning
for Ögedei Khan.
Turgut, Bamsi and some
of the alps will accompany me.
Of course, my Bey.
The castle is entrusted
to you, Günalp Bey.
Very good, my Bey.
Artuk Bey, you will be responsible
for the tribe and the Hanlı Bazaar.
As you command, my Bey.
All of you, keep your eyes
and ears open.
Monitor who comes and goes
and check them all thoroughly.
Be sure they are who they say they are.
If Noyan has returned...
I've no doubt he's placed his spies
in every corner.
After the dark days we've experienced,
we head into our toughest mission yet.
May God help us all, my Bey.
Amen, Turgut.
For the sake of our state,
we will endure our darkest hour
by turning our hearts as hard as stone
as we set out on the road again.
In this blessed cause, we will be
separated from the people of our tribe.
If the need arises, we must be prepared
to be separated
from our loved ones and our home.
If the state isn't everlasting...
if our homeland isn't prosperous...
our tents, our children,
what does any of it matter?
Only that the state exists.
Only that our homeland survives.
Only that we are free.
It is an honor for us to commit our hearts
and our lives to this blessed cause.
My Savci.
My Osman.
My Gündüz.
I thank God for giving you to me.
Son, you only just buried your wife...
Your tiny son is still in his cradle.
And now this parting...
When the order comes from the sultan,
we must surrender to our fate.
You know that, Mother.
Our way is one of sacrifice...
not just our lives,
but in leaving loved ones behind.
Go, son. Go.
The decree comes from the state.
You've remained patient
through a grueling ordeal...
God willing, you'll come through this.
God willing, Mother.
Father?
You're going too, now?
What will I do with my brothers?
Can't you stay?
I can't do that.
How could we refuse our sultan's order?
Grandmother will stay with you.
Sugay Hatun, too.
Osman is so much stronger
now thanks to her.
And tell you what...
Aren't you the bey of this tent?
Do beys ever show fear?
As you command, Father.
You're setting forth
on a difficult mission.
My duty is to take care of my brothers.
Yes, just like that, my brave son.
I entrust all of you first to God,
and then to grandmother and Sugay Hatun.
Now, it's time for you to show
what a brave bey you are, Gündüz.
In my absence, I entrust your brothers
and the tent to your care.
You are the bey of this tent
when I'm gone.
As you command, my Bey!
God bless you, my brave son.
Don't you worry, my lion.
Sugay Hatun and I will do our best.
Thank you, Mother.
We could have no more important work
than taking care of them for you.
Rest assured of that, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Sugay Hatun.
I should go, Mother.
God bless you.
Ertuğrul...
Be careful.
That bastard Noyan is unpredictable.
I will, Mother.
Until I'm sure he's dead,
I'll be sure to watch my back.
I won't give him his chance.
Very good, son.
We've had our fair share of misfortune.
Make sure you come back to us safe,
God willing.
With God's permission I will, Mother.
You must start preparing
for our migration.
No more obstacles stand in our way.
I hope not, my brave son.
The women and I will
make sure everything is ready.
-Sir, your messenger is here.
-Bring him now.
I hope for good news.
Noyan is at Ertuğrul's inn, sir.
They'll probably set off together
with Ertuğrul.
Now that's good news.
Noyan is both Ögedei's best commander
and his messenger.
If Noyan dies, Ögedei will destroy
the Seljuks.
We'll start such a fire that it will
consume the Seljuks,
Ertuğrul and all the Turks in Anatolia.
Gather the men, we'll set off now.
I will personally come.
My love.
My brave wife.
Death took you to the afterlife.
I know that nobody dies before their time,
and that those who go don't return.
But your absence is hard, Halime.
I speak but...
I can't explain the fire inside me.
Only God and I know how my heart burns.
Our Prophet said,
"Humans are split in two,
and they are complete when married."
You completed me.
Now I'm missing a half.
Now I have a difficult
and fiery path ahead.
You always said farewell...
and prayed for me.
My heart is longing for your sweet words.
There's a reunion after each separation.
I hope that...
God will bring us together
in the afterlife,
just like he did in this one.
Turgut, you've removed the traces
of the past from your heart.
I see a tense bow in front of me.
The suffering you caused to our tribe
and our loved ones...
sharpens our swords, Noyan.
-Just like old days, huh, Ertuğrul?
-Nothing is like the old days, Noyan.
True.
You're not the crybaby running after
Gündoğdu and Sungur...
and I'm not the Noyan
who has come to torture Erzurum.
Now, I'm a friend of your state, for which
you've risked your life many times.
I see a poor Mongol dog who I beat
many times with my sword, Noyan.
I await the moment that I take your head
like the others who threatened my state.
You mean like Emir Sadettin,
whom I had put on a leash some time ago?
Do you not know that I hold
Sultan Gıyaseddin's leash now?
You'll never enslave the Turks, Noyan.
Ah, Ertuğrul!
When you're in the presence
of Ögedei Khan,
you'll see the gates
of the world opening for you.
You and your dogs listen to me, Noyan.
You'll be under my protection on the road.
It's my duty to bring you to Ögedei Khan
safely and soundly.
Know that I'll give my life to do that.
But...
know that...
if you try anything against my alps
on the road,
I'll make you vomit blood.
Even a single drop
of my blood on these lands
is an invitation to Ögedei's army.
If trouble is coming,
we'll face it and crush it, Noyan.
I've got my eye on you.
If you're protecting me, very well.
Let's go.
We can't make Ögedei,
the Khan of Khans, wait.
Come on, alps!
What's the matter, Almıla Hatun?
What are those for?
For Ertuğrul Bey's children
and for any children in the tribe
who might need them, Sugay Hatun.
They should be happy.
So thoughtful.
They should surely be happy.
Why do you hate the Mongols so much,
Almıla Hatun?
The Mongols massacred my children.
So, I try to make children happy
and consider them my own children,
Sugay Hatun.
You don't know my pain.
I had no idea, Almıla Hatun.
I know what it means to lose a child.
It's hard.
Osman helps me dull my pain.
Those Mongol scum...
killed all my family.
Many children in my village were orphaned.
I long to become a mother again.
You have no idea how much it hurts,
Sugay Hatun.
Don't worry.
Keep praying.
God will answer sooner or later.
What are you doing, Sugay Hatun?
Almıla Hatun...
brought hats and leather clothes
for the children.
-So thoughtful, Almıla Hatun.
-Let's try them.
Looks good, right?
Anything looks good on Gündüz Alp.
Thanks, Almıla Hatun.
Thank you, Almıla Hatun.
I just want the kids to be happy,
Hayme Hatun.
Can I hold Osman?
Almıla Hatun.
Oh, my dear.
What's your tribe? Where are you from?
I'm from the Taurus Mountains.
I came to Ertuğrul Bey's rich lands
to graze and sell my herd.
With my tribe.
All right, welcome.
Now, go. Have the bazaar scribe write down
your name, tribe, et cetera.
Then start trading. Go!
Thank you.
All right.
-Good day, Artuk Bey.
-Welcome, Günalp Bey.
-Sit down.
-Thanks.
-Are you speaking to the newcomers?
-Yes.
Ertuğrul Bey wants all incoming tribes
and merchants investigated.
So, I'm investigating them.
A new tribe is coming soon,
I'll investigate them.
They might have Noyan's spies among them.
The woman rides like the Mongols, my bey.
Her horse looks like a Mongol horse too.
He's right, Artuk Bey.
We must dig deeper into this.
I'll see what I can find
about Almıla and her men.
Almıla and her men?
Why investigate her, Günalp Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey gave them a spot
in the bazaar.
But we don't really know who they are
and where they come from.
Foxes dressed as sheep, Artuk Bey.
Anyone might be a threat.
-Anyone.
-All right.
The horses will rest here.
We'll be at the caravansary before dark.
Great Tengri! Give me strength!
I'll burn your flesh like this, Ertuğrul!
I'll send all your family to the Red Tamu.
You'll suffer what I suffered
one-thousand-fold!
May your sword never be broken.
May your red flag never fall.
May your white crowned mother
rest in heaven.
May you never lose the hope
God gave you.
May you never lose faith.
May these prayers be accepted.
God bless you, dear.
You got used to us quickly.
And we got used to you.
I consider you my mother.
My dear.
Tell me now.
What's your problem?
If you let me,
I wish to visit my son's grave.
Of course, my dear.
Go.
See your child.
-The alps will escort you.
-Thank you, Mother Hayme.
I won't be late.
If you'd bent the knee to Ögedei,
instead of bringing the begging words
of your sultan to Ögedei now,
we'd be riding together to Danube,
Ertuğrul.
The Syr Darya and Amu Darya,
Euphrates and Tigris, we took them all.
We would tame the great Danube.
If I obeyed Ögedei,
I would have been crushed, Noyan.
We'd fight together, ride together.
The sky would be the limit.
But if you continue like this,
following a boy sultan
who killed his father,
neither your family nor your tribe
will ever see peace.
What does that mean, Noyan?
I mean, instead of being
the sultan's messenger,
you'd lead Ögedei Khan's armies.
We'll surround them from three directions.
We'll kill them all.
But our main target is Noyan.
We must kill him, no matter what.
Noyan can't leave this place alive.
-Understood?
-Yes, sir.
Incoming!
-Who is that?
-Günalp Bey, the castellan.
What is he doing here?
Don't break character.
Good day, Almıla Hatun.
Thank you, Günalp Bey. Welcome.
Thank you.
Well done, you're really working hard.
We try to do our best.
I hope there aren't any problems with us.
No, don't worry.
I wanted to see the tannery
and ask if you were okay.
We never talked about...
where you're from
and what you did before.
Then come in, drink our ayran.
Thank you.
You've been rolling like a snowball
towards an abyss, Ertuğrul.
Nowhere to escape, now.
You're about to fall.
Both your state and your tribes
will surrender.
Instead of surrendering with blood,
honorably obeying Ögedei with your swords
will make you rulers of the world,
not slaves.
Don't you see that?
To hell with you and your global empire!
Scum!
You lost many lives.
Why? For nothing.
Not for nothing, Noyan.
To be free.
Do you think you're free,
Abdur Rahman Alp?
Have patience.
You'll soon be our slaves...
or you'll die.
Abdur Rahman!
Noyan.
So?
Where were you before coming here?
Around Kayseri.
We would hunt in the mountain
and produce leather products to sell.
Kayseri?
There are Ahis in Kayseri.
All tanners are united.
You're not Ahis.
How did you work there?
We didn't stay long.
We came here when we couldn't stay there.
Thanks to Ertuğrul Bey,
we're making money.
Bless him.
You were a hunter, right?
I am.
I've hunted since childhood.
-I'm a good archer.
-I see that.
Your bow shows that.
Made from a birch tree.
Sheep bone at both ends.
This has twice the range of a normal bow.
I bought it from a trader.
You had to have been an archer
since childhood to be able to use this.
Because this is a Mongol bow.
But you mastered it right after buying it.
Well done.
Well, enough talk.
The castle waits.
Have a good day.
I told you to hide your bow and arrows,
didn't I?
I said nobody was to use Mongol goods,
Alangoya, the man was smart.
So what if he saw Mergen's bow?
He was suspicious even when he came,
didn't you see?
You're right, Bergütay.
He was suspicious.
He came here to be sure.
And we gave him a reason.
How can we eliminate his doubts?
By eliminating him.
There's no other choice.
Mergen, go kill Günalp!
The Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit help us.
Come on.
Attack!
Who shot my comrade?
Attack, my heroic knights!
-Kill them all!
-Commander Romanos!
Romanos? Who is that?
Treacherous scum!
The scum show their filth again!
Unleash hell!
We'll use their skulls to drink
our victory sherbet!
That's them!
Bring Sugay Hatun alive.
Sugay Hatun, run!
Catch her! The woman is getting away!
You're wasting our time, woman.
Drop the sword and surrender.
I won't let you take me again, you scum!
You tortured me.
I buried my own baby.
I'd rather go to hell!
Well, we tried.
Cover Bamsi!
Here I am, brother!
-Bamsi, are you okay?
-Yes, brother!
Noyan!
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net