episode 104 will start after 12:35 min.
It's possible to conquer everything
by the sword.
But what matters is to be able
to call it home.
We must make this place our home
and ensure peace for the Christians.
You're absolutely right, sir.
First, we must build a mosque
as the symbol of being owned by Islam.
Get it done, Bamsı.
Have the best artisans do it.
Buy whatever we need.
As you wish, sir.
Sir, from now on,
scholars will be visiting our home.
We need to build a place
for them, a madrasah.
Good thinking, Artuk Bey.
Education is the basis
for a prosperous home.
We must attract scholars,
and make sure they stay here,
if need be.
Sir, we can use the artisans we brought
to build an almshouse for the poor
and infirmaries for the sick.
The biggest concern
of the Christians is tax.
They've been crushed
under the harsh Byzantine tax for a while.
And now they are afraid
of what taxes we'll ask of them.
What do you think about this, Artuk Bey?
Sir, our tradition dictates
that a bey is the one who gives,
and the brave are those who are strong.
Based on this, their bellies must be full
and their sacks filled with coins,
to live in peace.
If the people live in peace,
then they will be loyal to their ruler
and comply with him.
I thought so, Artuk Bey.
That's why we must keep
the taxes we'll be taking
from the Christian tradesmen to a minimum.
Abdur Rahman.
Go out and gather the Greek.
Let them know that the taxes
are going to be minimal.
As you wish, sir.
Artuk Bey.
Before all else, check the documents
we found here.
Surely, something that connects
Emir Sadettin and Ares will show up.
Check everything in detail.
This is important.
As you wish, sir.
I shall go to the cellar now.
Ares' confidential documents are there.
All right.
Take Marya with you.
She'll help you read
the documents in Greek.
As you wish, sir.
Come in.
This is the last room.
This room has the best scenery
in the fortress.
So, it was used mostly to rest
or to host our guests overnight.
This great fortress belongs to you now.
You can arrange everything to your liking.
Oh, Suleyman Shah.
I wish you were alive...
to see this great day.
Oh my God!
-Mother?
-Mother Hayme?
What's wrong?
-Help her!
-Give us a hand.
Mother, are you okay?
Hafsa Hatun, call Artuk Bey.
Come, my dear.
Wait. Don't go.
I'm okay.
It's passed.
What do you mean you are okay?
You were out of breath.
Let Artuk Bey check on you.
There's no need, dear.
See, I'm okay.
It's just... old age.
This much is normal.
-Halime.
-Yes, Mother?
This is an ephemeral world.
If something happens to me...
make sure that Dündar comes back
to your brother.
Keep your brothers together.
Don't let them be hostile to each other.
Look out for them.
Don't say that, Mother.
You will stay with us.
Don't speak like that.
Dear.
Fate will knock on my door as well.
Tomorrow, if not today.
Marya Hatun.
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to check documents
in the cellar with Artuk Bey.
Excuse me.
Take care of yourself, Mother Hayme.
Thanks, dear.
God bless you.
Come on.
We have much to do.
Let's go.
Here, Mother.
It's okay.
I'm all right.
Ares.
Titan.
Ertuğrul appeared
as I was waiting for you.
We lost the fortress
due to your foolishness.
If your men holding the secret passage
had been alert,
we wouldn’t have ended up like this.
Don't you try to blame others
for your mistake.
We ended up like this because of you.
You are wounded.
My wound is unimportant.
To hell with my wound.
I was betrayed by the woman I love.
My fortress fell!
The war is not over just yet.
Let's treat your wound.
The war is not over.
The war is not over just yet.
Not yet.
It's not over yet.
What's wrong, Abdur Rahman?
Ertuğrul Bey told me
not to allow anyone in.
Not even me? Let me pass.
Halime Sultan, his orders are absolute.
Don't put me in a difficult position.
I'd lay my life down for you,
but I can't let you inside.
What's going on in there?
I can't say.
O almighty God.
You are just and merciful.
I'm forlorn.
I'm helpless.
I'm poor.
Don't leave me alone
in this mortal life, God.
Look out for me.
Grace me with your mercy.
Help me.
Don't let my heart be
a slave to this throne.
Don't let me be one of your subjects,
whose heart is stricken with ambition.
I only ask for your mercy
and bow down only to you.
Don't let me lose
to the trickeries of evil.
Don't let me be blinded by this world
and forget about the afterlife.
I know.
Only you grant victory.
Only you grant power.
I know that only you grant glory.
Don't let me be one of those
who don't know.
Don't let me be an ungrateful believer.
Don't let me fall prey to gracelessness.
I lay down my life for you.
My people fight for your cause.
All I ask is for you
never to leave us alone.
Amen.
Al-Haqq.
What happened, Marya Hatun?
Did you find an important document?
Sorry, not yet. They are
just ordinary scribbles.
Artuk Bey.
You're looking at them very intently.
Are you looking for something specific?
If so, I'll be on the lookout for it.
We are not looking
for a specific document, Marya Hatun.
Just keep looking.
Read it to me if you find
an important document.
Of course.
Men!
Question.
Is this fortress of stone
safer than our tents?
Of course, the stone is safer,
Commander Bamsı.
What's a tent, anyway?
What about you, everybody?
-Günkut is right.
-Yes.
Then...
Then, pity me.
Pity.
I'll have to break a sweat
to nail maturity in you.
Men!
First of all, an alp's safehouse
is his heart.
His sword is his mind.
Mere stone won't keep you safe
without your heart.
And what good is a sword for a fool?
You asked if stone was sturdier
than a tent, Commander Bamsı.
Your question and your explanation
have nothing in common.
We already know what you mean.
Of course, stone is sturdier
than some rags.
However,
those living in those tents made of rags
prevailed over those
hiding behind this fortress.
Then, the might of stone
blew up in their face.
And you said stone was
stronger than rags?
Everyone!
It all depends on the situation.
An alp must be able
to read between the lines.
He must feel it.
He must see the intent
hidden behind faces.
Why do you think we went through
all this trouble?
Why was our bey's son Gündüz kidnapped?
Why did we lose Doğan Alp?
And Samsa Alp...
Why was he killed?
It's because we couldn't read the enemy.
We couldn't realize
the schemes of the traitors.
That's why you mustn't shake things off
as being just questions.
Try to understand
the hidden meaning underneath.
I need soldiers that can see
through what is hidden.
And read the enemy.
Men!
If we show weakness,
we will just be a burden for Ertuğrul Bey.
We know how to take orders,
but we also need to know how to think.
Now, every morning and evening
I'll teach you how to shake off
the dust on your minds.
-Have I made myself clear?
-Yes, Commander Bamsı.
Good.
What's your plan?
We need to take the fortress back first.
I sent a message
to the Governor of Bilecik.
He'll send a messenger.
He'll make a generous offer.
Do you still think you can fool
Ertuğrul with your offers?
Of course, not.
But I'll corner him so badly
that he might be tempted...
to take the offer during our bargain.
Are you ready?
Sir, we couldn't find Ares, unfortunately.
So, it's not his time
to die yet, Atsız Bey.
It seems so.
This is amazing.
We were once slaves.
And now, we own this fortress, Atsız.
May God give you abundance.
May you conquer many others.
May you might be everlasting,
Ertuğrul Bey.
-Amen.
-Thank you.
May you live a long life.
We couldn't have done this
without your help, Atsız.
Our country wouldn't support you without
your persistence, passion, and dreams.
God bless you.
God bless us all.
Thank you.
Open the gate!
Commander Bamsı.
There's a Byzantine messenger.
Good, good.
Take away his weapons.
-They shall wait.
-As you wish, Commander.
Take off your weapons.
Welcome to the fortress of Ertuğrul Bey,
bey of the Kayis.
I came to tell Ertuğrul Bey
about the Governor of Bilecik's offer.
Who are you?
-Angelos, Governor of Bilecik's commander.
-I see.
Well, then.
You shall wait here.
When Ertuğrul Bey is available,
and would like to see you,
I'll let you see him.
Dumrul.
Help our guests with some sherbet.
As you wish, Commander.
Come on, then.
Ertuğrul Bey, with this,
my mission is over. I'll excuse myself.
Ilbey is waiting for me.
All right, Atsız.
Sir.
What is it Bamsı?
There's a messenger from Bilecik.
Here comes our new enemy, sir.
All right.
Let him in at once.
We shall see his stature
and sharpen our blades accordingly.
As you wish, sir.
What kind of enemy
would you like to have, Turgut?
I just hope they don't take me captive.
That's all I want.
I'm tired of being captured and rescued.
What about you, Bamsı?
Honestly, sir,
I don't want an enemy
that sows discord among us, anymore.
-Right.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
What about you?
What kind of enemy do you want?
We've had many enemies,
and many traitors.
This is my verdict on the nature
of our enemies after all this struggle.
Some enemies back-stabbed us
disguised as friends.
Emir Sadettin, for one.
Such people are usually very destructive.
It has proved hard to defend
against their schemes.
Some enemies are the heathens.
You know what to expect from them.
Their schemes show up in time.
The most dangerous kind of enemy is...
the one that allies with the heathens
disguised as a friend.
It's tricky to deal with them.
It's painful.
Thank God we got rid of such enemies.
However, we lost many men.
Now, we'll learn from all this pain.
We'll face our weaknesses.
-Am I clear?
-Yes, sir.
Now, let him in, Bamsı.
Right on, sir.
That barbaric Turk called Ertuğrul
fights with not his mind
but his faith, Titan.
We must fight with our faith, as well.
If we really want to take revenge,
we must finish Ertuğrul in one fell swoop.
Yes.
With just one move, but how?
We must get him to think we retreated
and disappeared.
And we'll prepare to hit him
when he's vulnerable.
We can't sneak into the fortress.
Ertuğrul must have taken all kinds
of measures against our attack.
There's only one place we can use
to sneak in and ambush Ertuğrul.
The Hanlı Bazaar.
I'm Commander Angelos.
I brought you greetings
from the Governor of Bilecik.
As the token of his good will,
he sent you this white flag.
Why would he send you
when the war has just ended?
This is a great victory for you,
no doubt, Ertuğrul Bey.
You are a great warrior.
But I came here to talk about peace,
and not war.
The governors here said the same thing.
-I hope yours doesn't end up like them.
-I'll get straight to the point.
I want you to hand over
Karacahisar Fortress to us.
In return, we're offering you
something more valuable.
I'll give you the taxes
from Karacahisar and Bilecik,
as well as Governor Ares' head.
This fortress you're in,
and all the lands
up to the Bilecik border,
have been taken with the blood
of our people.
If you want to take what's ours,
you must risk taking up arms against us,
and shed blood.
Ertuğrul Bey.
I came here with good intentions.
We can find a middle ground.
Consider it well.
You don't know me, so I'll forgive
such an insolent offer.
Do you think I'd trust men
that would sell out
the governor that sought refuge with them?
I'll take Ares' head sooner or later.
You just need to stop supporting Ares,
if you want your head intact.
Now, go back.
Tell your governor to think long and hard.
Make him realize he is playing with fire
by protecting Ares.
I'll pretend you didn't make this offer.
Your attitude will cause yet another war.
The honest war I fight is more honorable
than your treacherous peace.
I came to these lands
to collapse the nest of evil around you.
You may go now.
Ertuğrul Bey.
I said the man that'll take us
to Ares would come to our doorstep.
I'll track Ares down, if I may.
That shall be my last mission.
Thank you.
Take some men with you, Atsız.
Follow that commander.
See where they are hiding Ares.
Let me know.
Yes, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sir. Atsız went after him.
What should we do?
They'll do their best to wear us out
until an army from Nicaea arrives, Bamsı.
We must all take measure
to destroy their schemes.
Tomorrow, I'll explain what measures
to the Oghuz beys at the meeting.
We'll deal with our own problems.
Did you tell the merchants
at the Hanlı Bazaar
that we'd come after the meeting?
We did, sir.
Good.
They should know what
they must do in this new order.
How are things in your tribe, Turgut?
Bahadir's tribe has come
and they want to see me, sir.
Well then.
Go back to your tribe.
Invite them to your marquee
and tell them the state of things.
If they comply with you,
they may live in your tribe.
If they don't comply,
and want to be left alone,
then they should know
what will happen to them.
As you wish, sir.
Thank you.
He won't leave me be.
What is it now, Göktuğ?
Why did he send for me?
I spoke to the men close to him.
There's no sign of anything, sir.
It's just...
Just what?
They say a messenger
from Karacahisar has arrived.
Is it from Ertuğrul?
Emir, sir.
His Highness is waiting for you.
The well-being of Turkmen tribes...
means the well-being of our country.
Is that why you ordered
an attack on the east, Your Highness?
Yes.
I want them to see that
we are strong and agile enough to fight
against the Mongols
with the Turkmen tribes at all times.
Make preparations at once.
As you wish, Your Highness.
You sent for me, Your Highness?
Sadettin, Ertuğrul Bey sent a messenger.
Is that so?
And what does he say?
Ertuğrul Bey conquered
the Karacahisar Fortress.
Are you so surprised?
It's happiness, Your Highness.
I'm tongue-tied with happiness.
I hope that Ertuğrul Bey managed
to hang the head of that dog Ares
on the gates.
That dog Ares managed to escape.
Artuk Bey.
I found an important letter.
What does it say?
It says that they gave Bahadir Bey
money to buy the Hanlı Bazaar
upon a request from an emir
of the Seljuks.
Are you sure, Marya?
I'm sure.
You keep looking.
I need to see Ertuğrul Bey.
Sadettin, I want you to write a letter
to Ertuğrul Bey, saying that
I shall award him
the Karacahisar Fortress,
plus Söğüt and Domaniç.
Your Highness.
Ertuğrul Bey deserves the best
of everything
for his loyalty and bravery.
That's for sure.
However, I'd like to remind you
that you haven't given such a privilege
to any other beys.
I'm afraid it may cause a falling out
between the beys.
No.
On the contrary.
They will all learn to be unflinching
just like Ertuğrul Bey.
Not just the beys that are subject to me,
but also the servants at my palace.
When our country is fighting
on both sides, trying to survive,
what we need the most
is courage and loyalty.
Just like Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey says
he wants to see me
and come to Konya personally to give me
one fifth of the spoils from the conquest.
Your Highness.
I thought you were going to make
for Erzurum and Ahlat with our armies
to check our borders, and then spend
the summer at Alaiye
with your wife Hunat Hatun.
I'll postpone the attack for a while
to see Ertuğrul.
Do you have any evidence
on the traps that were set
for me and Ertuğrul Bey, Sadettin?
Soon, Your Highness.
There is not much time left.
You'll find out about everything soon.
Same for you, Sadettin.
There's not much time left for you.
I was just talking about you, Artuk Bey.
Right, sir.
We found something important.
What is it?
Sir, it'd be in our best interest to talk
about this alone when you're available.
All right.
Let the Greek people know what I said.
You may leave.
God bless you.
Sir, Marya found an important letter.
She said it says Bahadir Bey received
some money to buy the Hanlı Bazaar
on the orders of an emir of the Seljuks.
On the orders
of an emir of the Seljuks, huh?
Emir Sadettin.
Your schemes are over.
The jackals that have spread
in our country showed themselves.
What will you do now, sir?
I'll take this letter with me
when I go to see the Sultan.
This letter will be a death sentence
for Emir Sadettin.
Watch out.
Must be Commander Angelos.
Why are these infidels here?
Must be a secret location.
We'll spend the night to find out
what happens inside.
Commander Angelos.
I'm sure Ertuğrul welcomed you with joy.
He crushed me with his words.
He wanted war, I wanted peace.
He wanted blood and profit.
What did you expect?
For him to just hand over the castle?
Like you, Ares?
What are you doing?
Do you want to grant a victory to
the enemy with your own hands? Ares!
Be grateful that the Emperor hasn't
given up on you, Ares.
Otherwise, I'd make you pay for
what you've done.
I'll make you eat your words, Angelos.
Don't forget.
The Emperor will not tolerate
another failure.
Don't forget it.
Don't worry.
I'll bring his head to the Emperor myself.
How will you do this
when Ertuğrul has taken precautions?
You can't even come close.
He'll be defenseless at the Hanlı Bazaar.
I'll infiltrate the Hanlı Bazaar
and kill him.
Since you wish to kill him
at the Hanlı Bazaar,
I have some information for you.
One of my spies there has said
that Ertuğrul was going
to hold a meeting at the castle.
He and his beys would go
to the Hanlı Bazaar afterwards.
Ertuğrul will be defenseless near
the merchants.
I need men for this, Angelos.
This great victory is not only for me,
but for the Emperor.
All right.
I'll give you men for our Emperor.
But if you fail...
there'll be hell to pay, Ares.
We don't have many men there.
Even if we kill Ertuğrul,
it would be hard to leave.
You're right.
While I infiltrate the Hanlı Bazaar
with the men,
you and Commander Angelos must go
to Bilecik and get reinforcements.
Don't forget, Titan, you're the key
to get us out of the Hanlı Bazaar.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Thank you, all.
Thanks.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Good day.
-Eat well.
-Thank you.
Thank you, sit.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
-Thanks, my Bey.
-Thanks.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
-Welcome, my bey.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Welcome, my bey.
We heard what you said about us.
You saved us from Ares.
Scum.
They're licking his boots.
Now we have food.
God bless you, Ertuğrul Bey.
That's our last chance.
We either kill him now or never.
We either die with honor or we live
as slaves under the Turk's sword.
You are our neighbors,
our people.
Sometimes we share our sadness,
and sometimes our happiness with you.
As we try to be just for the sake
of our faith,
you must try to be the same
with your money and balances.
Do the same,
so that we can respect you.
Trader, how much for this?
The bag for my mother,
and this for my grandmother.
You're Ertuğrul Bey's son,
we won't take your gold.
No, you'll get your money.
Then I'll lower the price for two bags.
All right then, Gündüz Bey.
Bargaining is a good thing.
-God bless you.
-Thanks.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
-What is it, Gündüz?
-If you allow, Father,
I'll buy this bag for Mother
and this one for Grandmother.
I'm glad you thought about them.
All right then.
-How much for them?
-My bey, please.
You helped everyone.
I can't take your money.
I must pay you your time's worth.
-How much?
-Your son said the same.
You raised him well.
Three gold coins for them, Ertuğrul Bey.
All right.
Forgive me, my bey.
Forgiving the evil is condemning the good.
Good boy, come here.
Well done.
Abdur Rahman.
Gather the bodies.
As you order.
Bahadır Bey has overstepped his bounds.
Ertuğrul Bey and I attempted to reconcile
with him. He refused.
He got what he deserved.
Turgut Bey has become
the Çavdar Tribe's bey,
by the frontier bey Ertuğrul's order.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
We heard about Bahadır Bey's doings.
They have disappointed us.
We didn't think this would happen.
We set off to unite our tribes.
We won't make anyone suffer.
If you wish to unite,
we can live together in peace.
We'd be glad.
If you wish to live together
in the village,
you must obey Turgut Bey first.
I wish you a good reign.
Thank you.
Tomorrow, Ertuğrul Bey holds a council
at the castle.
-You should attend too.
-As you order.
Oğuz.
Leave.
As you order.
Who is the bey, Aslıhan Hatun?
You are, Turgut.
Then, don't speak after me.
Turgut.
From now on,
don't get involved in tribal matters.
You won't attend councils.
You're responsible
for the women and the tailors.
In this village, I have the last word.
I have the only sword, I rule alone.
Did you understand?
You're my husband.
You're my love.
My honor.
My pride.
How are the preparations going?
Everything is set, my bey.
Tomorrow, we'll have a council
worthy of our victory.
Don't worry.
Both mother and I are taking care
of everything.
Thank you.
Hand out food for the elderly and homeless
at the market.
As you order.
I'll take care of it personally.
How is Marya?
She's fine.
She works to do her duty.
She and Artuk Bey search the documents.
Good.
-What is this?
-A letter from the Emperor for you.
Our Emperor gave Ares a last chance.
If he fails again, you'll kill him...
and become commander.
You'll fight Ertuğrul under my orders.
I'll take care of all your needs
including reinforcements.
I'll never betray Ares.
Titan.
Nobody knows your bravery and loyalty
like I do.
Didn't you see Ares?
Ertuğrul has poisoned his soul.
We lost hundreds of men
for his rage and pride.
The Turks have taken
our most important castle.
And more importantly,
we lost our prestige.
Nicaea is worried.
So are the people.
A civil war might even erupt.
If Nicaea falls,
think about what will happen.
Father.
We only had one village.
Now, we have a castle.
How did we become so strong?
Look Gündüz, do you see?
Small sparks have united
to become a big fire.
Union makes strength.
We became a big fire by uniting ourselves
just like these sparks.
We gave warmth to our friends,
we burned away our enemies.
Look, son.
We endured many difficulties on this path.
Our tribe was hungry.
Our animals died.
We lost many brave men.
We settled on barren lands.
What brought us here from those places
was our loyalty
to God's cause and tradition
and to each other.
Father, if I have difficulties
when I grow up, what should I do?
Always mention God's name, son.
If you fall into a dark hole someday,
hold God's hand so you can live.
If you take up God's cause,
he won't leave you alone.
Your people and your friends
will support you.
If you don't leave the right path,
the followers of God will be your friends.
Father, how will I find them?
If you follow the path,
they will find you, son.
You have an important guest.
Who, Abdur Rahman?
Just a poor fellow on the road.
Good to see you.
Selamunaleykum.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, son.
Mashallah.
Thank you, brave warrior.
Come along.
Come, son.
Peace and mercy of God be upon you.
Amen.
Oh, God.
You granted me many things
in this mortal world.
You let me raise my kids
and see my grandchildren.
You granted me and Suleyman Shah
many conquests.
You helped us endure
many troubles and evil men,
and conquer castles
with my son Ertuğrul.
All the glory to you, oh God.
When it's time to die,
give me faith and strength, oh God.
Reunite me with Suleyman Shah
in Heaven.
Protect my tribe and my children.
Keep me near our Prophet.
I only ask your help,
I only seek your refuge.
Amen.
Oh, God.
Help us.
We've been waiting for you
for a long time.
We really missed your wise words.
I was in the Holy Land.
The land of our Prophet.
As soon as I arrived,
I heard the news and came to visit.
You honored us.
Hallelujah.
You conquered this castle,
now it belongs to Islam.
You opened the way for many good things.
A good conquest.
May it allow you to conquer hearts
as well.
Amen. Amen.
Ertuğrul Bey,
your conquest reminds me of Umar
who took Jerusalem from non-Muslims
and made it an Islamic city.
Jerusalem was conquered
by the armies of Islam.
The former administrators said
they would only give the keys
of the city to the Caliph.
Therefore, Umar and his slave
set off with a camel.
Umar and his slave took turns
riding the camel.
At last they arrive...
and they see Jerusalem from a hill.
Then, it was the slave's turn
to ride the camel.
The slave forfeits his turn and says,
"Oh, Leader of the Faithful,
it would be more appropriate for you
to ride the camel."
Umar refuses.
"He whose turn has come,
shall go riding" he says.
So, he holds the camel
while the slave rides
and they enter the city.
Those who waited thought
the slave was the Caliph
and showed him respect.
He was ashamed.
He says he's not the Caliph,
that the Caliph is the one walking.
Everyone is shocked.
"How can that Caliph,
who makes the world tremble,
enter the city holding the camel
which carries a slave?"
They ask this to Umar.
He replies,
"Before God,
there's no difference between us.
The superiority is about loyalty to God.
We took turns on the camel.
It was his turn, so, he was riding it."
The people were shocked.
Umar's act helped him conquer
the hearts of many non-Muslims.
Ertuğrul Bey,
you did a great duty conquering this place
in the name of Islam.
But your real duty has not yet begun.
For greater conquests,
you must raise men of merit.
For it is men who keep a country running.
If you don't have any men of merit...
your conquests won't last.
That's why you must rule with justice.
Conquer hearts with justice.
Make the world tremble with your glory.
Your duty is harder,
your load is heavier.
But don't forget,
as long as you follow the path...
God's mercy will always be upon you.
Thank you.
Marya Hatun, mashallah.
You're talented.
And you have a good heart.
We love you a lot.
Therefore,
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to have a family
and raise children like yourself,
instead of being alone.
Does Ertuğrul Bey want me married?
Yes.
Ertuğrul Bey found you a suitor as well.
I don't know what to say.
But how?
If Ertuğrul Bey found someone for you,
he won't force you.
We don't do that here.
What's important is your desire.
Can I adapt to your customs?
I'm a Christian, too.
Would one of you marry me?
Marya Hatun...
You being Christian poses
no religious problems to us.
In our religion,
a Christian woman can marry a Muslim man.
Don't feel under pressure, okay?
What's important is your desire.
Marya.
I was a Christian
just before I married Bamsı.
But the hospitality of these people
has really affected me.
And I converted to Islam of my own will.
Also, the suitor Ertuğrul Bey has found
for you
is also a good and a talented person.
It's Artuk Bey.
-Artuk Bey?
-Yeah, Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey,
he's a good and talented man...
like you said.
He is.
If Artuk Bey wants it,
then I want it too.
Marya, you'll have the time of your life.
You won't regret it.
Thank you.
Thank you as well.
-Thanks.
-You too.
Despite his failures,
I asked the Emperor to give
Ares another chance.
Without me, he would be dead.
If Ares succeeds,
we'll stand by him until the end.
Both of us.
But if he fails again...
Then the duty awaits you, Titan.
If you won't,
I have the authority to send you away.
The Emperor prepares his army.
We'll both lead the army.
I spoke with the soldiers outside.
They can't wait to attack the Hanlı Bazaar
and avenge their fallen friends.
They're all ready to die.
Good luck, Commander Ares.
May God forgive our sins.
Are you okay, Halime?
You look sad.
No, I'm fine.
Tell me Halime, what happened?
I know you well.
I was going to see you today, Ertuğrul.
Abdur Rahman Alp didn't let me in.
It annoyed me.
I wonder if these stones will make us
grow distant.
My Halime...
My Halime.
What do you mean?
Our love will overcome even steel fences,
let alone walls of stone.
Your place is where I am.
Then why wasn't I allowed in, Ertuğrul?
I looked behind and saw
how our lives changed.
A person might forget that it was God
who brought him where he is.
I'm afraid of making the same mistake
if I don't paying attention.
That's why I wanted to be alone
and think.
My Halime.
You're my love,
the throne of my heart.
Your place is always my side.
May God never let me
out of your heart and mind, Ertuğrul.
We spoke with Marya Hatun today.
She wants to marry Artuk Bey.
All right.
And I told Bamsı Alp.
Asked him to talk to Artuk Bey.
I hope they'll be happily married.
So do I.
I have another thing to say, my bey.
Tell me.
It's about Mother.
What happened to Mother, Halime?
Her heart had a problem this morning.
She was in pain.
She told me she was all right,
but I'm worried.
Go see your mother tomorrow.
Don't tell her I told you,
she'll be angry.
Okay.
I'll see her before the Friday prayers.
Bamsı.
Don't play with them.
All right.
I'll go anyway.
It's late.
Hafsa waits for me.
Artuk Bey,
marriage is such a good thing.
What do you say?
Don't you think about it?
I never thought about marriage
all these years.
I chose science.
Look, you work so hard
all the time.
Would it be so bad to have a wife
and babies in your tent?
Bamsı. Enough. I'm working.
Artuk Bey.
Marriage is the real science.
Wise is the man who can get along
with a woman and raise kids.
Artuk Bey,
talking about the babies,
if there were many little Artuks,
lots of little Artuks,
you could teach them.
You should get married, Artuk Bey.
If you dedicated yourself to science,
you must raise educated kids.
Alps.
Bamsı Alp will leave now.
When he leaves, don't let anyone in.
As you order.
Good.
I'll go.
Keep working Artuk Bey. Work hard.
And when you want some soup,
these papers will bring it to you
right away.
Alps.
Ares and Titan.
At last.
They're with the Tekfur's commander.
Those who wish to die at the battle
of the Hanlı Bazaar, take a step forward.
As long as I have such brave men,
killing Ertuğrul or driving the Turks away
will be easy.
Ertuğrul will go to the Hanlı Bazaar
tomorrow to meet the traders.
Yanis and you three,
you'll go there tonight dressed
as merchants.
Spend the night there
and hide your swords under the tables.
Me and the other soldiers will go in
when Ertuğrul comes, using the chaos.
Scum.
They'll ambush Ertuğrul Bey.
When we go to the Hanlı Bazaar,
Titan will bring men from Bilecik.
When it starts, our soldiers will surround
the Hanlı Bazaar.
At last, we'll take our revenge from
Ertuğrul who killed many of our heroes.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
Mother.
Come, my brave son.
Come, the light of my eye.
How are you, Mother?
Is there anything you need?
Thank God for this day.
What is it, Mother?
Is something the matter?
No, my son.
No, I'm fine.
I'm fine. I know you worry.
But don't you worry.
Well,
I have grown old.
It is almost time...
for me to ride...
the horse of fate to the other side.
Don't say that, Mother.
May God keep you with us.
It is so, my son.
In this world,
I have seen my share of hardship.
Thanks to your father, Suleyman Shah,
and thanks to you,
I have been proud many times.
I finally saw you conquer
this castle, too.
If I am to have one last wish,
it would be to see my sons together.
Let me see us...
celebrate our victory altogether.
My Sungur Tekin,
my Gündoğdu,
my Dündar.
Let them come here.
Still, you know what's best, my son.
However,
that is my wish.
Mother,
Just be all right.
I will send a messenger
to my brothers right away.
May God look upon you.
May God take from my life
and give to you, my son.
Don't say that, Mother.
Don't say that.
Come on, brave men.
We need to tell Ertuğrul Bey. Come on.
Spies!
Spies! Don't let them get away,
go after them.
Commanders, stay here.
Come on.
Everybody look around.
Come on, no time to rest.
We need to get to Ertuğrul Bey
to prevent the infidels' plan.
Damn.
Titan!
We can't let him get away.
Ertuğrul will find out everything.
We need to get him, dead or alive.
Knights, to your horses.
Are the documents done, Artuk Bey?
Almost, my bey.
We are arranging them all with great care.
Marya Hatun is of great help, praise her.
Good.
Marya Hatun is a clever woman.
She quickly integrated with us.
She did, my bey.
She is eager to learn.
She doesn't have any family.
I wish she would have a home.
Bear children, have a family.
I wish to hand her over
to a competent man.
That would be wise, my bey.
Is there someone on your mind?
Yes, Artuk Bey.
You are on my mind.
Me?
Well, my bey,
I don't know what to say.
Artuk Bey,
your home, too, should be filled
with your children.
My bey,
all these years, I never thought
of getting married.
I dedicated myself to knowledge.
I don't know how this will work.
It will do good. It will be for the best.
Our prophet ordered his ummah
to marry and reproduce.
Marya too has knowledge.
You are the best match for each other.
My bey,
will Marya accept?
She has, Artuk Bey.
Halime Hatun has spoken with Marya Hatun.
If you accept too,
after the celebration,
I wish to...
honor our victory
with your engagement.
Well, if Marya accepts, too...
As you wish, my bey.
Thank you.
May it be for the best then, Artuk Bey.
I am very pleased.
Grandmother,
when will my uncles come?
Your father sent the fastest messengers.
Your uncles will hit the road
as soon as they receive the invite.
God willing.
Grandmother,
I never knew my grandfather.
Tell me about him a little.
I wouldn't know how to tell you.
The roads he rode,
the mountains he passed,
should tell you about him.
He didn't give in to the cruel...
and he helped the oppressed.
Those who saw his shadow
would pay respect...
and his enemies would search
for a place to hide.
He roared like a lion,
walked like a wolf...
and had the eyes of an eagle.
In the field of battle,
he was unrivaled...
and he brought the backs
of many a wrestler to the ground.
That which Suleyman Shah said...
wasn't possible...
has never been proven possible
by a single soul.
He gave me sons as valiant
as your father...
and grandsons like you.
May God bless him, my dear.
Amen.
How many sons do you have, Grandmother?
I had six sons.
Two were killed in the war
against the Mongols.
How many grandsons do you have?
Your uncle Gündoğdu...
has two sons.
And you uncle Sungur Tekin has one son.
Me, one and Savcı...
Then you have five grandsons, Grandmother.
Right.
I have five grandsons,
smart like you, my dear.
I hope they come soon.
I've never seen them.
I wish to know them.
God willing, my boy.
What's wrong, Grandmother?
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
I'm fine, my dear.
You go,
be with your brother.
Let me rest a little, eh?
Okay.
Okay, Grandmother.
Oh!
Oh, I'd die for you.
I'd die for you.
Come on.
Go.
Go on.
Stop.
Go.
On this sacred Friday,
at this time that prayers are heard,
we thank God that with your effort,
believers who have come together,
and the help of our God,
it has befallen us to perform
Friday prayers here.
God willing, all your generations
may perform Friday prayers here forever.
Amen.
As our great prophet says...
Peace be upon him.
"Islam is good morality.
A Muslim is someone...
whose word and work is true.
Conquering a castle is important business.
But the important thing
is to conquer the castle of hearts."
Our prophet says...
Peace be upon him.
"If people look at your conduct
and do not aspire to Islam,
review your faith."
Just as you raised our glorious banner
and made this place an Islamic land,
you are required to make people feel...
the encompassing warmth of Islam
with your just and merciful behavior.
Our Lord says in the Surah Ali Imran:
"If you had been mean and cold-hearted,
it is with no doubt that they would
leave you."
Venerable believers,
as God commands, we shall...
be kind towards the oppressed.
However, against the cruel,
we shall always be resolute.
To live in harmony with unity
and prosperity,
we will firmly embrace this line
from the Quran...
and walk a righteous path
with the guidance of our prophet.
May God bless your Friday prayer.
Amen.
-May your conquest be blessed.
-Amen.
Merchant Niko.
I caught you at last.
Not Niko,
Atsız.
You still haven't learned.
You won't be able
to tell Ertuğrul this time.
Bastards.
You only know how to fight dirty.
You truly are a great spy,
a spy good enough to get near me.
But don't forget...
that I am a great warrior.
And I won this game.
Who knows how upset Ertuğrul will be
when he loses such a spy.
No matter what traps you set,
Ertuğrul Bey...
will do away with you all.
Your rule of these lands is over.
Keep on resisting.
I will have you beg for your life.
Do what you will.
But the last breath of a Turk...
will not be for mercy...
but the proud smile...
of martyrdom.
Our margrave, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
Welcome, my beys.
Glad to be here, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sit.
In the 99 names...
of God,
who makes things happen
and fills our hearts with faith,
may our celebration be...
for the best and for good fortune.
Amen.
When you broke the infidels
on our doorstep,
our tribes and families
were filled with joy.
Ertuğrul Bey, may God...
further your victories and your name.
-Thank you.
-May your victories be lasting.
Thank you.
Victory...
is God's, my beys.
Name and reputation...
are transient matters of the world.
Our fight...
and our conquests...
are for the grace of God.
And we gather here today to share this...
and to consult on the new order.
Yes, Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey,
Sultan Alaeddin's lieutenant has arrived.
Bring him in, Abdur Rahman.
Welcome.
You are most welcome.
Glad to be here.
May your celebration be blessed,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
I bring you Sultan Alaeddin's...
conquest gifts and edict.
If it would please you, I'd like to read
our sultan's edict...
to the beys.
Please do.
"Ertuğrul Bey, Bey of the Kayi,
son of Suleyman Shah.
May God render your sword sharp,
your victories perpetual,
your life fruitful.
The conquest of Karacahisar,
through the gallantry of you
and your alps,
has increased the power of our state.
Following this conquest,
henceforth,
I give you Domaniç for the summer
and Söğüt for the winter.
The rule and the protection of these lands
are under your command.
Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad the Victorious."
-May it be for the best, my bey.
-Thank you.
May God bless you, my bey.
May God give you the strength
to do what you wish.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
May our offspring be wolves...
and everywhere we set foot be our land.
Thank you, brother.
You are our state's protector,
the pride of the Turk tribes,
Ertuğrul Bey.
May God render you always victorious.
-Amen.
-May God bless you, my bey.
Thank you, my beys.
Thank you.
May our state stand tall.
As our sultan commanded,
from now on,
Söğüt and Domaniç...
are our lands.
We will start working on the improvement
of these places right away.
And I shall soon ride to Konya
to surrender our sultan's
right to the spoils.
Soon.
Now, let us eat.
Come, sit.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
Look at the bride
She has henna on her hands
Don't say anything to her
She'll be offended and go back home
Henna on her door
She is an angel
-May your bridal henna be merry
-Bismillahirahmanirahim.
May your prosperity be sweet
Look at the bride
She has henna on her hand
Who are you?
We are merchants. We wish to spend
the night.
Where do you come from?
We come to Hanli Bazaar
from Söğüt to trade.
We heard that Ertuğrul Bey will
accept merchants here tomorrow.
We would like to stay here
and meet him in person.
All right, then. Surrender your swords
and daggers.
Then you may come inside.
Henna on her door
She is an angel
-May your bridal henna be merry
-God willing, may you have
armies of sons and tribes of daughters.
May your home be prosperous.
She has henna on her hand
This...
is our wedding gift to you.
Her door has henna
-Halime.
-I'll put it on, Mother.
May your bridal henna be merry
May your prosperity be sweet
Look at the bride
-She has henna on her hand
-I don't know what to say.
You've made me so happy.
You are so beautiful, Marya.
May God protect you from evil eyes.
-Amen.
Thank you.
You've helped me so much.
I appreciate it.
I wish...
my brother was here...
to see this day.
Marya Hatun,
don't be sad.
And don't feel alone.
You lost your brother.
But if we may,
we would like to be your sisters.
Look at the bride
-She has henna on her hand
-You are such good people.
I thank God that he led me to you.
Sit here.
Eat something. I will get
your quarters ready.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Bring some food to this table.
Let's sneak down at night
and place the swords under the tables.
We will take our place inside
before Ertuğrul comes tomorrow.
Everybody knows what to do.
The emperor...
will do everything he can...
to take back...
Karacahisar Castle from us.
Ares...
and the governor of Bilecik...
will always threaten us.
That's why we have to get rid of Ares...
and conquer Bilecik.
The war between us will go on
until we end...
Nicaea's rule...
over these lands.
We await your command
and are always ready to fight,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you.
This is a symbol of our endless allegiance
to you.
The moment you send this,
I will come under your command
with all my alps.
Thank you.
The basis of prosperity...
is unity.
I have no doubt that the Oğuz Beys
who have not rejected...
unity so far will not do so going forth.
I'd like to know...
what the newly arrived Cavdar beys
think of this matter.
We too are under your command,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We have come to accept Turgut Bey
as our bey.
Thank you.
Bamsi.
Give me an arrow.
He who...
isn't united...
and acts alone...
will break as easily as this.
However,
if we are one,
nobody can break us.
I would like...
to add joy to this day that we celebrate
our prosperity...
and unity with a wedding.
In front of all the beys,
we shall wed Artuk Bey and Marya.
Congratulations, Artuk Bey.
May it be for the best.
May you have armies of sons...
and tribes of daughters, Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Turgut Bey.
Thank you, my beys.
Thank you, my bey.
God bless you.
Bamsi.
Tell the women to bring Marya Hatun.
Yes, my bey.
This room is for two.
You have water.
If you need anything else,
there's an alp on guard.
-Call for him.
-You've hosted us well.
Thank you.
-Good night.
-You're welcome.
Good night.
I have wed you in front of the witnesses
and the people here.
May God bless your covenant.
Amen.
Oh, God.
We are witness to this wedding covenant.
You witness it too.
My God, bless this wedding covenant.
Amen.
Help this couple get along,
give them love
-and patience in marriage.
-Amen.
My God,
grant this couple...
the friendship, peace and happiness
that was among the prophet Adam...
and our mother, Eve,
among our prophet Muhammed,
may peace be upon him,
and our mother, Hatice,
-and among Ali and Fatima.
-Amen.
My God,
grant this couple suitable children,
-long life and plenty of livelihood.
-Amen.
Our God, grant us, in this world
and the next, blessed wellness
-and beauty.
-Amen.
-Protect us from hell fire.
Al-Fatiha.
After everyone settles in,
we will hide the swords
beneath the tables tonight.
When Ertuğrul comes tomorrow,
Ares will be here to finish him off.
Come in.
We risked everything coming here.
Ertuğrul must be celebrating victory
at the castle with his beys.
But tomorrow, this inn...
will be his grave.
May God render your union perpetual,
Artuk Bey.
May he soon give you valiant sons.
God bless you, my bey.
Thank you.
Artuk Bey,
may God further your lineage
and give you many children.
May God protect you from all evil.
Thank you, Turgut Alp.
Thank you.
May it be for the good.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God bless you, Artuk Bey.
May you have armies of sons...
and tribes of daughters. God willing.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Thank you.
-May you be happy, Artuk Bey.
-Hayme Ana.
God bless you, Halime Sultan.
Thanks to you, I have found happiness.
Thank you.
Be happy, my girl.
May you always be happy, Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun, thank you.
May you have little children, Artuk Bey.
Bring pride to our tribe.
Bamsi.
Come on, let's hug and celebrate.
Marya Hatun.
Mother.
-Mother!
-Hayme Ana.
-Wake up.
-Mother.
Mother.
Grandmother.
I'd die...
for you.
Mother, come to.
Mother.
-Speak, Mother.
-Ertuğrul.
Son...
Son.
Give me...
Don't say that, Mother.
Don't.
Give me your...
Mother!
Ble...
Bless...
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net
Subtitle translation by Yurdakul Gündoğdu