episode 102 start after 12:43 min.
Betrayal, ever worse than the enemy,
you have no place in these lands.
Get the bodies away from the fire.
-Quick, put the fire out.
-Come on, everyone.
Yagiz Alp.
-Find Bahadir.
-As you wish, sir.
Samsa...
Samsa.
One of our martyrs is here.
-Brother.
-Samsa.
Samsa...
Samsa, my brave brother.
Samsa.
How could they do this to you, brother?
How could those scum do this?
Unless we take your revenge,
there will be no peace...
for you nor for us in this land, Samsa.
I promise we will.
I promise.
Bastards.
They slaughtered them all, sir.
We have all the bodies, sir.
Prepare to get them back to camp.
Find Bahadir.
Bahadir Bey isn't here, sir.
We couldn't find his body.
What do you mean, "You couldn't," Yagiz?
Did you check the bodies?
Yes, sir. He wasn't there.
Bamsi Alp.
We know who was stationed here.
Identify all the bodies at once.
See if it's just Bahadir missing.
Let me know.
Yes, sir.
Hurry up.
I need to find another way
to get out of here and see Ertuğrul Bey.
Sir.
All our soldiers stationed here are dead.
Only Bahadir is missing.
Do you think those heathens
took him captive?
Those bastards killed all my men.
Why would they take him prisoner, Bamsi?
Those that are trying to deter us
could have killed Bahadir easily.
Bahadir is neither dead
nor captive.
Looking at all our dead comrades,
and burned catapults,
I believe he got away.
Traitor scum!
And he boasts how well he fights.
Did he run away from battle like a coward?
We will find out...
if he ran due to fear or due
to betrayal, Bamsi.
Turgut.
Head to the camp.
Bahadir is probably there.
Bring him to me fast.
When all these men were killed,
he'll tell me how he could
run back to the camp.
This might be a plot...
by Bahadir and Ares.
Be careful.
As you wish, sir.
Go on.
Let us take our dead back to the camp.
People might lose hope...
once they see that the catapults...
were burned to a crisp.
I shall be there,
so that people don't lose hope...
and that they may be tenacious.
They need to know that the war...
has just begun. We haven't lost.
As you wish, sir.
Yagiz Alp.
Send news to all the beys.
They shall stay put.
Günküt, Dumrul, Abdur Rahman.
They shall find people to look after
their units and come back to the camp.
As you wish, sir.
Sir, we could have conquered
the fortress
with the catapults.
Our soldiers were stationed
accordingly, too.
It's all burned down.
What do we do now?
We will keep the order, Bamsi.
We will give it our all
and make new catapults.
Yes, sir.
And they shall see that this
won't deter us.
Be careful, everyone.
Titan succeeded again, sir.
The catapults were burned down.
Ertuğrul's men are dead as well.
Titan is an army by himself, Kostas.
He has proven it once again.
With this loss,
Ertuğrul should be crippled.
I made him lose face in the eyes
of the Turkmen tribes.
Now, I'll make him suffer defeat
again and again.
I'll not let him breathe.
Divide et Impera.
Divide and conquer.
Ertuğrul must be mad with anger.
And he will attack the walls in fury.
If he makes such a stupid mistake,
it'll mean the end for him.
Don't be so sure, Kostas.
Ertuğrul isn't so stupid as to
charge at the walls out of anger.
He'll grieve for his dead men
and try to find a way out.
That's exactly when I'm going to
deal the killing blow to him.
How so, sir?
Bahadir Bey.
He should have attacked
his tribe by now.
It's time to make use of him.
What are you going to do?
I'll use Bahadir to lure Ertuğrul
into a trap, Kostas.
Find me a brave soldier.
He'll go to Cavdar tribe.
Have him take my letter to Bahadir Bey
through the secret path.
Bahadir Bey, who united and gave
strength to the Cavdars.
Congratulations and all the best.
Congratulations, Bahadir Bey.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
I, Bahadir Bey, son of Kara Cavli,
swear on the Quran,
our flag, and my sword.
If I ever sway from our faith,
our traditions,
and my brother Candar's path,
I shall perish by my razor-sharp sword
in honor of the Quran and our flag.
I shall unite the Cavdars...
and resurrect and advance our tribe.
I swear never to stray from my brother
Candar Bey's path.
Bring Aslıhan Hatun here.
Let me go!
Pledge your allegiance to Bahadir Bey,
Aslıhan Hatun.
I'd rather die a thousand deaths
than obey him.
You're all cowards.
You have betrayed the margrave
while we are at war.
You murdered my beys and my soldiers.
You'll regret it.
I'm giving you one last chance, Aslıhan.
Don't waste it.
Otherwise, your husband Turgut
will die because of your obstinacy.
Obey me,
and I shall let both of you live.
You and your beys at this
blood-stained marquee
have no more chances, Bahadir Bey.
You'll pay with your blood
for forming this assembly
on the blood of my soldiers,
and pretending to be a bey.
Ertuğrul Bey will make you pay
for what you have done, sooner or later.
Quiet!
Quiet, you impudent wench!
You still dare to hide behind Ertuğrul Bey
and preach to me?
Isn't it Ertuğrul that caused the death...
of your very own father,
and deceived your brother Ural?
And here you are, shamelessly wishing
to keep chasing behind Ertuğrul.
You will die before you even get
a chance...
to beg for forgiveness in this marquee
that you have covered with our blood.
Enough is enough! Know your place!
Are you looking for trouble?
Then,
you and Turgut Alp...
may very well dig your own graves.
Burn in hell!
Sir.
Ertuğrul Bey's men were attacked
before the siege.
All the catapults burned down,
and all his men were killed.
Fool.
He lost the war before it even began.
He won't find the strength...
to fight, let alone conquer the fortress.
So, he couldn't protect the catapults
that I labored to make.
He let his men...
be wiped out...
in a treacherous ambush.
And he's supposed to be margrave.
I'll make you bow before me, Ertuğrul.
There, Aslıhan.
This is your Ertuğrul,
who you trusted and to whom
you gifted our tribe.
Ertuğrul, who let his men get ambushed,
and who once let himself be taken captive,
has become the food of Ares' soldiers.
God surely has a reason for this...
ill fate.
As you don't know the will of God,
you still have yet to see
Ertuğrul Bey's wrath.
You'll get what you deserve.
Bey.
What happened?
They attacked the catapult camp, Halime.
They were already dead when we arrived.
They burned the catapults, too.
Oh, my God.
Cruel bastards!
My boys.
My brave boys.
God bless you.
My son.
Devoted mothers and brave men...
of the Kayi.
I know well...
that it tears your heart out
to see your sons...
and husbands die.
But they fought and died for God.
God says thus:
"Don't call those who died for me dead."
"As they are alive."
"But you can't comprehend it."
The souls of our men
will give us moral support.
Each drop of their blood
will help us flourish in these lands.
Our enemies want to stop us in our tracks
with ambushes and traps.
However,
we'll flow like a wild river
and flood them all.
Don't let this deter you.
As long as it's for our country
and our rippling flag,
we are all ready to fight in this war.
I already lost a son for God's cause.
I'm ready to give the other three, sir.
Thank you.
-God bless you all.
-Amen.
Amen.
Artuk Bey, come with me.
Who are these guards?
They are not our soldiers.
I wonder what happened.
Something is amiss.
Turgut.
Sancar.
What are you doing here?
We came with my father to take back
our tribe that you took violently.
Now neither your chief...
nor Aslıhan Hatun has any power here.
Where is Aslıhan Hatun?
We put her where she belongs.
Get him.
Take her away.
Turgut.
Aslıhan.
Bastards!
Sir.
How did Ares's soldiers manage
to get close to the catapults?
How could no one notice them?
We'll find out, Artuk Bey.
Once the men I stationed before the walls
come, I'll ask them.
Then we'll find out how they came.
Could it be Bahadir's doing, sir?
I sent Turgut Alp.
He'll bring him to me for sure.
If it's Bahadir's doing,
he'll suffer my wrath this time,
Artuk Bey.
Yes, sir.
We organized our men for using catapults.
We need new catapults to keep the order.
Gather the men at the camp.
As you wish, sir.
But what are we going to do?
Who knows how to make them?
I do, Artuk Bey.
As you wish, sir. Excuse me now.
Thank you.
Surrender, Turgut.
Tell your men to drop their weapons.
Or Aslıhan Hatun dies with you.
My father doesn't want to kill you.
He wants to deal with your bey.
He wants to put an end to this hostility.
He doesn't want to shed more blood.
Surrender, so that this ends here.
Stop the bloodshed between our tribes.
Surrender.
Lowly bastards.
You have no power in this tribe.
You will obey.
We obey only God.
And we destroy those
who would stray from God.
Take these two to the captives' tent.
-Are you okay, Aslıhan?
-Turgut.
I'm okay, don't worry about me.
They took advantage of the situation
since our men were under siege.
Bahadir sent his own men beforehand
with Sancar.
They invaded the camp.
Lowly bastards.
Turgut, this is our fate.
We must endure until our last breath.
-These dogs can't stop us, Aslıhan.
-Stop talking and walk.
Walk.
I had these catapults done myself.
They can...
throw rocks weighing ten kantar.
I brought these for you to examine.
I'll level the castle to the ground.
Even if you set a thousand traps for me,
you will not avoid your end.
I've seen our people's resiliency
and strength.
I am convinced that those cruel people
cannot break us, Mother.
Our people are so devoted, so generous.
Thank God.
You are right, my dear.
They suffer
because of the deaths of their loved ones.
But they showed resilience.
Now our job is
to be with them,
and try to
ease their suffering.
Halime, my dear.
We should set up
a tent for our sisters to mourn.
We should be with them
to increase their resiliency,
and strength.
Okay, Mother.
Hafsa, my dear.
You should help the women of our tribe
with the funerals.
Be with them.
Take supplies to them
for their funeral dinner.
Yes, Mother Hayme.
What should I do, Grandmother?
Come with us to the mourning tent.
The martyrs had children.
They are your siblings now.
Brotherhood and friendship
are important at times like these.
You should be with them now,
and they will never forget this
for their entire lifetime.
-Okay, young man?
-Okay, Grandmother.
Let's go, then.
We should go set up the mourning tent.
And we will have someone read the Quran
for our martyrs.
-Let's go.
-In the name of God.
Alçiçek, you should stay with Savcı.
Yes, Halime Sultan.
Come with me.
Get out.
You still look rebellious.
My patience is wearing thin,
I am warning you.
Obey me,
and I will spare your lives.
You are wasting your breath, Bahadir Bey.
We won't obey you, even if we die.
Then...
you will sign your own death warrants,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Do you think
that Ertuğrul Bey
will not take our revenge?
Do you think that
the Sultan won't make you pay for this,
when he learns what you did?
You are the one
who signs his own death warrant.
I have never...
revolted against
my state or my margrave.
Ertuğrul Bey said, "We're going to war."
and I said "Okay."
I said I will put my alps under his order.
I made those catapults myself.
And then what?
Huh?
Then what?
Ertuğrul Bey
couldn't protect the catapults
and his alps from Ares's soldiers.
And I took
the seigniory that I deserve
the right way.
You are lying!
Where were you when our alps were dying?
Where were you?
My duty
was making the catapults.
Ensuring security
was Ertuğrul Bey's duty.
I did my duty perfectly.
But,
Ertuğrul Bey...
couldn't ensure the security.
You are full of lies.
You took advantage of our alps absence
when they were at war,
and invaded my tribe.
Enough.
Enough with your nonsense.
How long
were you going to
try to prevent my leadership?
I was going to take
what I deserve one day.
And it is today.
Ertuğrul Bey will bring you to account.
Turgut.
If I had bad intentions,
wouldn't I kill both of you?
Ertuğrul Bey
will accept my leadership.
Otherwise,
you will all die.
He wants to use us as leverage
to convince Ertuğrul Bey.
We need to find a way out of here.
Aslıhan.
Come near me.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
Bey,
is that a catapult?
Yes, it is, Bamsi.
Magnificent.
Look at these drawings.
Bey drew how to make one.
It looks like a monster.
Bey,
they look better
than the ones Bahadir Bey drew.
Our catapults will not only throw stones.
They will also throw oil barrels,
and we will burn our enemies.
Since they are not handing over
the castle to me,
I will burn it to the ground.
They deserved it a long time ago, Bey.
We will start making
these catapults without delay.
Time is pressing,
and it's a difficult job.
However,
we have the power to overcome
every obstacle, with God's help.
They will see
that their traps and dirty tricks
cannot dissuade us from our holy victory.
May God
help us all.
Amen!
Amen.
You will deal with this personally,
Artuk Bey.
I drew everything in detail.
You should start right away.
As you wish, Bey.
Bey, they will not escape from us.
Bey, we will use these catapults
against the heathen.
And if you allow me
I would like to throw the first one.
I want to be the first one who burns them.
You will, Bamsi.
You will, God willing.
We are looking forward to it.
Come on, then.
Go and do your duty.
Eûzu billahi mineş-şeytânirracîm.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahîm.
Yâsîn.
VeI Kur’ân-iI hakîm.
İnneke IemineI mürseIîn.
AIâ sırâtın müstakîm.
TenzîIeI azîzirrahîm.
Litünzira kavmen mâ
ünzire âbâühüm fehüm gâfiIûn.
Lekad hakkaIkavIü aIâ
ekserihim fehüm Iâ yü’minûn.
İnnâ ceaInâ fî
a’nâkihim agIâIen
fehiye iIeI ezkâni fehüm mukmehûn.
Ve ceaInâ min beyni eydîhim
sedden ve min haIfihim sedden
feağşeynâhüm fehüm Iâ yübsirûn.
Ve sevâün aIeyhim
eenzertehüm em Iem tünzirhüm Iâ yü’minûn
innemâ tünzirü menittebazzikra
ve haşiyerrahmâne biIgaybi
febeşşirhü bimağfiretiv
ve ecrin kerîm.
İnnâ nahnü nuhyiI mevtâ ve nektübü mâ
kaddemû ve âsârehüm
ve küIIe şey’in ahsaynâhü
fî imâmin mübîn.
Vadrib Iehüm
meseIen ashâbeI karyeh.
İz câeheI mürseIûn.
Titan the Hero.
With your victory,
you have honored our castle,
our land and our empire.
Welcome, Titan the Hero.
Welcome, my friend Titan.
Ertuğrul took the first blow
in this arena of war.
Now it is time to throw him to the lions.
I am going to play a trick on him,
and Ertuğrul will be finished.
What's on your mind, Ares?
I sent a letter to Bahadir.
He will lure Ertuğrul
into a trap that you will set.
Soldiers, out.
Tekfur Ares
has sent a letter.
Let's see what he says.
What does sneaky Ares say?
He said
he will save me
from the trouble of Ertuğrul.
How?
He wants me to invite Ertuğrul
to my tent to talk to him
as the Cavdar Bey,
and obey him.
What does that mean?
Why does that heathen meddle
in your business?
That means, son...
Ertuğrul
will come here to reach an agreement,
and to save...
Aslıhan and Turgut's lives,
one way or another.
Ertuğrul cannot afford a conflict
in a time of war,
he wouldn't want to shed more blood.
And then what?
But...
Ertuğrul will never arrive here.
They will
set a trap on the road
and kill Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul will never forgive Bahadir.
He will try to find a way
to kill him eventually.
But what is important for us is
to make Ertuğrul to go to Cavdar Tribe.
Will he, sir?
He will.
He will go there when he learns
Bahadir overtook the tribe.
And I will set a trap for him on the road.
Yes.
When Ertuğrul gets the invitation,
he will use this road
to go to Cavdar Tribe.
And you will set your trap here.
I am very grateful to you for giving me
the honor of killing Ertuğrul.
I can't leave my castle, Titan.
That's why I am giving this honor to you.
Take a troop with you,
full of your best soldiers.
That would be too many.
Ertuğrul is not easy picking, Titan.
I have witnessed that before,
and I won't leave it to chance.
It's not that I don't trust you,
but you will do as I say
to break the jinx this time, Titan.
As you wish.
I will bring Ertuğrul's head to you.
Nobiscum deus.
May God be with us, Titan.
These bastards want to
set a trap for Ertuğrul Bey.
I cannot leave him alone.
Sancar and Bahadir
are so blinded by anger.
We must save ourselves
before Ertuğrul Bey comes.
There will be a lot of blood,
if we can't stop them.
Almost done, Aslıhan.
We'll escape from the ropes.
In the name of God.
-Turgut.
-Aslıhan, go there.
You were like lions in your tent.
Now,
you look like a couple of sheep.
We will kill you,
and your leader, and then...
cut your heads off,
and display them in front of the tent,
then you will see
who is the lion, and who is the sheep.
What is it, Son?
You look upset.
We should be the ones
who kill that bastard, Father.
Don't you understand that
Ares saved us a lot of trouble?
Our hands will be free
of the margrave's blood.
We will not attract the Sultan's anger.
Your mother is right.
Ertuğrul isn't worth
getting our hands dirty,
and coming into conflict with our state.
You will
content yourself with Turgut's head.
As you wish, Bey.
Kaya Tekin!
-Yes, Bey.
-Now,
go to Kayi Tribe.
Tell Ertuğrul Bey that
I have become the bey of Cavdar Tribe
by gaining approval from all the beys',
and I invite him over to my tent
to talk to him tomorrow.
As you wish, Bey.
How is it going at the armory, Artuk Bey?
Everybody is working hard, Bey.
And I stand over them,
and do whatever it takes
to complete them quickly.
-Thank you.
-We are all working hard.
We are doing our best, Bey.
We will finish them in time.
Don't you worry.
Thank you, brother.
-Any news on Turgut Alp?
-No news, Bey. He hasn't come yet.
I hope he is all right.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Dumrul.
You summoned us, Bey.
I've charged you with the duty of watching
the castle's gates,
and the road of Nicaea.
Have you seen anybody
going in and out?
We always have our eyes
on the gates, Bey.
Nobody has come in or out.
There was no one, Bey.
It is the same at our post, Bey.
Since no one has come out from the gates,
there must be a secret door.
They used that door to go out and attack.
Otherwise,
they couldn't have
come near the catapults.
What's on your mind, Bey?
Atsız must have learned something.
If he can,
he will tell us where this secret door is.
But we won't stand idle.
Bamsi.
You will deploy the alps.
They will search for the secret door
without letting anybody know.
As you wish, Bey.
If we find it,
all of Ares's hopes will perish.
And then,
he cannot do anything
but wait for us to attack.
What do you want, Merchant Niko?
Sir, I am here
to talk about Hanlı Bazaar.
I know, Niko,
you are confined to my castle.
You came here for trading, and gold,
but Ertuğrul wanted a war.
I know that
victory will be ours, sir.
I have no doubt about it.
That's why I want to go to Nicaea,
and make arrangements
for the new order you will put in place.
I can't afford for you to leave, Niko.
I need you here.
And you are responsible
for the castle's gold.
-Sir, we don't know how long--
-Enough!
I said I need you here.
Ertuğrul will die tomorrow.
And you will be my side when he dies.
Then you will become
the head of Hanlı Bazaar.
You summoned me, sir.
Pray for us, Niko.
May this war end soon.
My prayers...
are always with you,
-sir.
-The door!
Gregoryus.
Use the secret door,
don't let any alps see you.
Send this letter to the Emperor.
Thank God.
Hurry.
So, you are trying to escape.
-Aslıhan, watch out.
-Alps!
You corrupt...
Aslıhan!
Turgut.
Let go of me!
Ertuğrul Bey will bring you
and your father to your knees again.
But, no one will save your heads this time
when you are down.
Do you think your Ertuğrul Bey
can come here and save you?
He is already defeated.
Get out of here, Sancar.
Get out!
Don't you say anything!
You got in way over your head!
You set people against each other!
All of this happened
because of your stubbornness,
your ambition for leadership!
Turgut!
No, you will not die easily.
I will torment you so badly...
you will beg me to kill you.
Alps!
Chain them up.
Put a guard to watch over them.
You corrupt...
You will get what you deserve!
Let go of me!
Son.
Mother.
As you command,
we are doing everything we can
for our martyrs' funerals.
Thank you, Mother.
Hereafter, our martyrs' children
are my own children.
They will wear the same as my children.
They will eat the same as my children.
We will bring up our children well,
Mother.
May God bless you for that, Son.
May God give you a long life.
Thank you, Mother.
Son...
I know you have a heavy burden.
There will be many obstacles on your path.
But our Lord says,
"On no soul does God
place a burden greater than it can bear."
I am walking God's path, Mother.
When I say, "Help me, God",
all my troubles
just go away.
And I pray to God for a way out now.
I believe in him.
God will open that door for me.
Our Lord says,
"With every difficulty,
there is relief."
Your intentions are good.
Your way is God's way.
God will surely show you a way
out of this, Son.
Mother.
If you excuse me,
I will go and pray now.
May God accept it.
Amen, Mother.
Merchant Niko.
What are you doing here?
It is not Niko,
it is Atsız.
Good.
This letter will open
all the doors for me.
My Lord,
I seek to live for your justice,
and fight for your justice.
Do not let me be
defeated by the enemy, I don't want to
let down my tribe or my people.
My Lord,
you can do the impossible.
Make me victorious in this holy war.
You have the power to open all the doors.
Show me a way out of this.
Out of respect to Muhammad the Prophet,
accept my prayers.
With Tekfur Ares's order,
I will take this letter to the Emperor.
Tell me your name.
Gregoryus.
Use the secret door,
don't let alps see you.
Send this letter to the Emperor.
Gregoryus.
Okay, you can pass.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Bamsi.
Bey.
Bahadir Bey has sent his alp.
He wants to say something to you.
Bahadir Bey?
Where is Turgut, then?
I don't know, Bey, the alp came alone.
Let him come in.
-We will find out.
-Yes, Bey.
Let him come in!
Speak.
Ertuğrul Bey,
I brought you greetings from Bahadir Bey.
Where is your Bey?
He is at Cavdar Tribe.
Bahadir Bey became the bey of the tribe
by gaining all of the beys' approval.
He invites you to his tent
to talk tomorrow.
He became the bey?
What do you mean?
Where are Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp?
Until Bahadir Bey talks to you
and you reaches an agreement,
he will hold Aslıhan Hatun
and Turgut Alp as captives.
Bey.
Bey, what is he saying?
They hold Turgut
and Aslıhan Hatun as captives.
So... that's why the
bastard that is your bey
abandoned us on the battlefield.
When we were fighting on the battlefield,
he went to the tribe
and took it, didn't he?
He both betrayed us
and rebelled against us.
Go and tell him...
that Ertuğrul bey will come to his tent,
not to make a deal...
but to hold him accountable
for the crimes he has committed.
Tell him... he won't get up
from his knees this time.
Go.
My Bey, my Bey, that dog
is holding Aslihan Hatun
and my brother Turgut prisoner.
We should have held on to him, my Bey.
Even if he is the dog of that bastard,
we won't touch a messenger.
Let him go.
Let him go and tell Bahadir what we said.
Let him speak...
so that Bahadir may appreciate the
power of the storm brewing against him.
What's happened, my son?
That bastard Bahadir, Mother...
He's keeping Turgut and Aslihan
Hatun prisoner at the tribe.
-What?
-Fiend, bastard!
What kind of a treachery is this
while the battlefield still blazes?
He conspired with Ares, Mother.
He betrayed our state to satisfy
his ambition to become bey.
He had a hand
in the burning of the catapults, too.
Treachery runs through
his veins like blood, Mother.
But, I swear, with my sword...
I will make that treachery flow.
-Bamsı, get ready, we ride.
-As you wish, my Bey.
Mother.
Tell Artuk Bey to join
the funeral prayer in my name.
He should accompany
the families of the martyrs.
You will accompany the women.
Don't worry, son. Don't worry.
Let them not feel our absence.
My God, one disaster follows another...
Grant power and strength to Ertuğrul Bey.
This is the best place to set an ambush
on the way to the Cavdar tribe.
When Ertuğrul comes,
we'll surround him quickly.
He is not to get out of this ambush alive.
Everybody take their places!
Come now, Ertuğrul Bey.
My sword will finally shine red
with the blood of a powerful Turk.
Take my horse.
What's this, Atsiz?
I have important intelligence,
Ertuğrul Bey.
There is a secret passage into the castle.
Ares sent a messenger
to the emperor with a letter.
I caught the messenger before he left
the castle and escaped in his clothes.
-And I also have letter.
-Very good.
Everything he was plotting
with Bahadir Bey is written down here.
They planned to ambush you.
Thank God I got here in time, my Bey.
So that's why he sent a messenger
inviting me to come to the tribe.
They were going to
ambush me on my way there.
There's no time to lose, Atsiz.
We have to save Aslihan Hatun
and Turgut Alp from this bastard
as soon as we can.
Then we make him pay.
I know where they set the ambush, my Bey.
-On the road we always use?
-That's right.
There's another route
to the Cavdar tribe up ahead.
Bamsı, Abdurrahman and I
will get to the Cavdar tribe that way.
You will continue on this road
and deal with their ambush, Atsiz.
Don't worry, my Bey.
We'll trap them in their own trap.
Very good.
Günküt, Dumrul!
After you've finished with Ares' men,
get to the Cavdar tribe
as quickly as you can.
Some of you surround the tribe,
the rest of you enter it and be ready.
-As you command, my Bey.
Atsiz, after you've
dealt with the soldiers,
join the alps at the siege.
As soon as we're done
at the Cavdar tribe, we'll join you there.
We'll go through the passage
when night falls.
This will all be over tonight, Atsiz.
Get the alps ready right away.
May God be with us, alps.
Amen, my Bey!
-Come on!
-In the name of God!
In the name of God!
I wish the news of
Ertuğrul's death would come.
The longer we wait, the more tense I feel.
Why are you tense?
One way or the other, Ertuğrul will die.
You say that, my Bey,
but you don't seem that relaxed either.
Something's gnawing at your insides.
If you have something
to say, say it, wife.
Stop beating about the bush.
Just tell me what it is you want to say.
My Bey, Ertuğrul has
the nine lives of a cat.
What if he eludes
the ambush and comes here?
What if he realizes
it was you and Ares who set it up?
What's done is done, woman.
If he escapes the trap Ares has set,
and doesn't recognize my beyhood...
Ertuğrul will meet his death
by my own hand.
Come on then.
You won't be able to
save yourself this time.
Alps are approaching
but Ertuğrul isn't with them.
-What do mean, Ertuğrul isn't with them?
-I'm sure I didn't see him, sir.
We checked everyone.
Ertuğrul isn't with them.
He must have suspected it was a trap.
He sent his alps instead.
He'll go straight to the Cavdar tribe.
-What do we do?
-Kill them all.
Bring my horse.
I'll ride to the Cavdar tribe.
Whatever happens, Ertuğrul dies today.
Come with me.
It's one trouble after another.
Whenever we try to achieve something,
a thousand misfortunes haunt us.
My Ertuğrul cleared the way
for that snake Bahadir,
so that he might walk the right path
instead of a crooked one.
But he closed the door on that himself.
Well, he'll pay for it, of course he will.
But why does he keep
Aslihan Hatun and Turgut Alp captive
and just sit in his tent, Mother?
What despicable work he has done.
But he'll see.
My Ertuğrul Bey will surely
put an end to it this time.
-My Gündüz.
-Mother.
Did you talk to your brothers, Gündüz?
I did, Mother. I consoled them.
I told them to come to me
if anything was wrong.
Good for you, Gündüz. Good job.
Hafsa, my girl, is everything
ready for the funeral meals?
Everything is ready, Mother.
The pots are boiling, the food is ready.
All right then, let us go and give
our condolences to the people.
Come on, Gündüz, come.
Surrender!
Come on then, you bastards!
Come on, alps!
It's time for battle!
No infidel leaves here alive!
In the name of God!
Allahuakbar!
Come on!
Titan isn't among them.
He might close the secret passage.
Bring my horse.
I'll go defend the gate to the passage.
I must stop Titan.
I'll wait for Ertuğrul Bey there.
I hope you finish off Bahadir Bey
and get back in one piece.
-God willing.
Come on!
Ertuğrul Bey still hasn't come.
He'll be here, eventually.
Ertuğrul wanted to destroy our tribe
with his games but you put a stop to that.
God willing...
I'll put a stop to the ones in Konya, too.
It's time our sultan learned
what an ambitious and vindictive man
Ertuğrul really is.
-God willing, my Bey.
My Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey is nearing the tribe
with two of his alps.
Then...
let us welcome our margrave.
After you, Beys.
How did he survive Ares' ambush, Father?
How can this be, my Bey?
We should be welcoming him dead,
not alive and well.
Maybe he saw through the trap.
If that's the case,
he comes here knowing everything.
Let's just invite him into the tent.
Then we'll see.
If he knows everything,
my tent will be his grave.
Sancar, whatever you do,
don't give away our plan.
Keep a tight hold of your anger.
Otherwise, this tent will
be our graves instead.
Understand, Sancar?
-I understand, Father.
-Good.
-Kayatekin.
-Yes, my Bey.
Go keep guard of Aslihan and Turgut.
-Stay alert.
-As you command, my Bey.
Neither Ertuğrul nor his alps are wounded.
They can't have fallen for the trap.
You must find some way
of making him accept you as the bey.
This does not bode well.
If you kill him here,
you'll have to take on the sultan, too
You will have rebelled against the state.
The penalty will be far harsher.
He didn't send his son into exile,
he had him gather the alps to rebel.
He has a death wish, my Bey.
We should grant it.
Just look how he carries himself!
He acts like he has an army
beside him, not two alps.
Thank you for accepting my invitation
and coming to see me, Ertuğrul Bey.
Come in.
We have been preparing for your arrival.
Let's talk and eat a nice meal?
Where are Turgut and Aslihan?
Don't worry about them. They're safe.
Let's have that conversation.
Then we will invite them to eat.
Come in.
Abdurrahman.
-Wait outside.
-As you wish, my Bey.
Stay standing.
Now tell me.
What has happened here...
while I was at war,
despite the Cavdar tribe being
under my protection?
The tribe had an internal issue...
which has now been dealt with.
I took what was rightfully mine.
That's what happened.
Don't worry about Turgut and Aslihan.
After you recognize my beyhood...
I will surrender them to you,
Ertuğrul Bey.
What is this beyhood
you speak of, Bahadir Bey?
The one you tried to claim by spilling
the blood of your own kin?
Did you not know?
Those who come by blood... go by blood!
You didn't even grant us an election
so that I may have taken
what is rightfully mine.
You wanted to make the bey
someone who is not of our blood!
A couple of insolent men
who would not accept my beyhood...
they got what they deserved, that's all.
What about the beys...
loyal to Aslihan Hatun?
Why do you stay silent?
Did Bahadir Bey
tie your tongues with the gold Ares
gave him to buy out Hanli bazaar?
Tell me!
What is this, Ertuğrul Bey?
We can't be bought.
You are for sale,
you violate our rights and customs.
You shame the Cavdar name!
You have violated its honor!
You have sullied Aliyar Bey's
cherished memory!
Ertuğrul Bey!
Ertuğrul Bey.
You are here in my tribe,
sitting on my seat,
and I have had enough!
I intended to put my alps under
your command and fight alongside you.
But you continue to slander me.
What makes you think
my spoils of war are Ares' gold?
I will not allow you to insult my beys.
They have shown how low they have fallen,
by betraying their tribe
and its traditions.
You should have taken better care
of your catapults.
Ares burned them to the ground.
You fell into every single one
of the infidel's traps.
But despite all of that...
we still wish to stand
by our state and by you.
May everyone in my tribe be my witness.
Recognize my beyhood
and we can figure this out peaceably.
First, bring Turgut Alp
and Aslihan Hatun here.
Then...
we can talk again about your betrayal
and your collaboration with Governor Ares.
Your bey...
has finally arrived.
Thank God. Thank God...
-Where is he now?
-In the tent.
He is in council with Bahadir Bey.
In council?
What? Why not?
You should stop guarding us
and think about how you can
save your bey's head.
Don't get your hopes up.
He has no choice
but to recognize Bahadir Bey's beyhood
and both he and you will play nice.
Or the blood that flows...
and the lives that are lost will be yours.
Kayatekin...
We have known many
who have tried to tame us.
But all that's left of them
is a stain on our swords.
We're not like anyone else.
Haven't you learned that yet, Turgut?
To us, all bastards are the same.
Don't worry. We won't do you any favors.
You will share the same end.
You are not to speak anymore! Understand?
-What collaboration?
-You think we're traitors, Ertuğrul Bey?
-We're not traitors.
The gold for Hanli bazaar
has blinded you, beys.
You tried to make a man
who collaborated with Ares...
Bey of the honorable Cavdars.
The man responsible for burning
the catapults I had built for the siege,
and far worse,
for the killing of my alps...
is Bahadir Bey!
He and Ares formed
an alliance of evil against our state.
In this letter I hold before you...
Ares explains to his emperor
everything they've done together!
Liar! You slanderer!
The plots he and Bahadir hatched...
how he would ambush me on my way here,
how he intended to kill me...
it's all here, in this letter.
Know this, neither asking for mercy
nor begging for your lives...
will save you.
Just like Bahadir Bey...
you will pay the price of betrayal.
Lies!
Still you slander me! That letter is fake!
Your denials are for nothing, Bahadir Bey.
I have a spy inside the castle.
The contemptible tricks
you and Ares have played
have been revealed, one by one.
I did not betray my state.
Nor will I ever.
But if you keep this up...
know that I will take your head.
All we want is to further
the lineage of our fathers.
You cannot stop that.
You have desecrated the path
of the honorable Cavdar tribe.
You will pay the price with your lives.
Sancar, stop!
Sancar!
My son.
Ertuğrul keeps the Turk tribes unified.
They are empowered by him.
They are encouraged.
The tribes themselves are weak.
They couldn't survive without Ertuğrul.
When Ertuğrul is dead,
the Turk tribes will disperse.
That will be our chance to throw them
out of these lands once and for all.
What about Hanli bazaar, sir?
It's time we took that over too.
We will attack Hanli bazaar tonight.
We will inflict a second
fatal blow on the Turks.
When we return,
I will hold a great feast for everyone.
Sir, two of our men are missing.
What do you mean? Where could they be?
I don't know, sir.
We couldn't find them anywhere.
I will see to it myself, sir.
You killed my son!
I will kill your family!
I will burn down your tribe!
I will put your sons' heads on stakes
and plant them in the middle of the tribe!
Die!
I warned you that if
you didn't bow to me...
I would take your head, Bahadir Bey.
It's time you paid that price.
My Bey, we surrounded the tribe,
as you commanded.
We have it under our control.
-What are your orders?
-Good, men.
Take Bahadir Bey's alps' weapons.
And tie them up.
-As you command, my Bey!
Bamsı.
Bring Aslihan Hatun and Turgut Alp to me.
Yes, my Bey.
I swore I would...
take the head of anyone
who refused to kneel before me.
One head is already on my sword.
Now, is there anyone else
here who refuses to kneel?
Aslihan, are you all right?
Didn't I tell you not to speak?
Don't open your mouth again!
What do you think you can do?
-Are you going to cut out our tongues?
-You talk too much.
I'm here, brother!
May you accompany your bey to hell.
Brother, hold on. Hold on.
Thank God.
The smell of the bodies led us here, sir.
-We found them like this.
-Who did this, Kostas? Who?
Ertuğrul is behind this, sir.
How so?
Are you telling me
Ertuğrul has a spy in the castle?
-Yes, sir.
-Who is it, Kostas?
Who? Find him!
Question everyone in the castle!
All the new men, everyone! Even
the civilians outside! Find him for me!
Yes, sir.
You didn't leave us to die
at the hands of that bastard.
Thank you, brother.
Brother, your life is my life!
How could I leave you?
Did our bey do away
with that dog, Bahadir?
He did, my brother. Yes, he did.
Free Aslihan Hatun
and let's go to the tent.
Ertuğrul Bey is waiting for you.
Where the hell is that idiot soldier?
What's going on at the tribe?
What did you learn?
Sir, Ertuğrul Bey captured the tribe.
He killed Bahadir Bey and his son
and made the beys kneel.
Bahadir Bey's alps have surrendered.
Damn it.
How could this happen?
Ertuğrul will head to the castle now.
We need to close the secret passage
if we're going to defend the castle.
Everyone to the castle! Now!
That's the entrance to the secret passage.
When Ertuğrul Bey arrives, we'll advance.
We will conquer it tonight, God willing.
-God willing.
When Ares finds out I'm not at the castle
he may well suspect something
and close the entrance.
Titan could show up at any moment.
We'll ambush him here.
Let's pray that Ertuğrul Bey is on time.
According to our laws...
there is but one punishment for traitors.
Death.
This traitor...
paid the price
of his uncontrollable ambition
with his life.
Look at him!
Whoever breaks our laws and betrays us...
for his own benefit
or to satisfy his ambition...
ends up with his head on my sword.
-My Bey.
-Brother.
-May God bless you, my Bey.
-Thank you, Turgut.
God bless you, Ertuğrul Bey.
You were truly sent from God.
You saved my tribe from the traitors.
Thank you.
You're welcome, Aslıhan Hatun.
Until it had a knife through it,
her treacherous heart would
always have been a problem.
Now, leadership is yours, Turgut Bey.
From now on, my tribe is yours to command.
But my Bey...
Henceforth,
the Cavdar tribe is led
by Turgut Bey.
Obey him!
By agreeing to obey, don't think
you've got away with what you've done.
There is still a price
to pay for your actions.
Verdicts...
will be reached after
the battle, Turgut Bey.
As you command, my Bey.
If no traitors are left among us,
the thousand bastards who wait outside
stand no chance of defeating us.
We took the head of the traitor.
Now it is time for us
to take the head of our enemy.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net