Episode 92 will start after 13:03 min.
My God, what is this?
Alps, take precautions!
My God!
Artuk Bey is still breathing.
Artuk Bey.
Hurry!
Alps! Get here now!
-Come on!
-Hurry!
-Bring a stretcher.
Get him up.
Come on, brothers.
Come on.
-Take him back to camp at once.
-Hold him.
Come on.
-Has anyone seen my bey?
-No.
Ertuğrul.
Where are you?
Where are you, Ertuğrul?
Be careful!
Ertuğrul!
Bamsi.
Bamsi, my son.
Dündar.
Get him up.
Bamsi.
My son.
What?
My boy.
Open your eyes, my boy.
Dündar.
-Alps. Alps! Get a stretcher.
-Stretcher.
Come on! Bring the stretcher!
-Mother.
-Get him, quick.
Mother.
Take him back to camp, quickly.
Come on.
-Mother.
-Make haste.
Mother, Ertuğrul isn't here.
-My brave man isn't here, Mother.
-He isn't.
He isn't.
Ertuğrul, where are you, my son?
-Where are you, Ertuğrul?
-We will find my brother.
We will find him
if it's the last thing we do.
-What did they do to you?
-Alps.
You will search every inch of land.
Look in every hollow tree,
leave no stone unturned.
Send word to Aslıhan Hatun.
Get to the Hanlı Bazaar
and tell Emir Sadettin.
Tell them to come help us find
Ertuğrul Bey, come on.
Send word to the sultan also.
Come on!
I'd die for you, my son Ertuğrul.
Where are you Ertuğrul?
Where are you?
No other enemy has given me the pleasure
I got from having Ertuğrul in my grasp.
Killing a foe such as Ertuğrul
could only have been realized
by a renowned knight
such as yourself, my lord.
Ertuğrul's death
will be a lesson to all the Turks.
Either they
get the hell out of Anatolia...
or be put to the sword like Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul's death will no doubt
stir fear among all the Turks, my lord.
They will really be afraid
when they find his body.
My lord, his body hasn't been found yet.
What do you mean?
The Turks are searching
the site of the ambush.
Our men are secretly watching.
By the Turks or by us, Lukas,
that body needs to be found.
My lord, Ertuğrul is already dead.
Why do you want to find his body so badly?
We killed Ertuğrul, who was a great hero
for the Turks, Lukas.
They need to see the body
so they know
that their cause dies with him.
Only then will they lose hope.
Aslıhan Hatun.
What is it, Kirca?
Not good news I'm afraid, Aslıhan Hatun.
Aslıhan Hatun,
they ambushed Ertuğrul Bey
on the road to the campaign.
They martyred the alps that were with him.
Artuk Bey and Bamsi Alp
are heavily wounded.
They took them to camp.
What about Ertuğrul Bey?
He hasn't been found yet.
Hayme Hatun, Halime Hatun and Dündar Bey
continue to search with the alps.
Who would do this?
We don't know, Aslıhan Hatun.
Prepare the horses quickly.
We ride right away.
Yes, Aslıhan Hatun.
Your Eminence...
Dündar Bey of the Kayi camp...
has sent you a messenger, sir.
Well, what does he say?
They heard about the raid.
They went to the site of Ares' ambush.
They found the bodies of the alps.
Bamsi and Artuk Bey were wounded
and taken to the camp.
Ertuğrul?
Speak, man.
What of Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul hasn't been found yet, my Emir.
They're searching for him, dead or alive.
They ask for assistance in the search.
They think Ertuğrul retreated
during a fight.
I don't think
Ertuğrul would have left his alps
and retreated, Göktuğ.
And Ares wouldn't leave him alive.
Send your men.
Have them search for Ertuğrul.
If they find him dead, good,
if he is alive...
you know what to do.
Tell Dündar Bey's alp
to take us to the ambush site right away.
Wait.
Artuk and Bamsi are wounded?
Call for the healer.
Send him to the tribe.
If they know anything...
let him do what is necessary.
Yes, Your Eminence.
What's happening?
Hurry. Come on, quickly.
Move.
Who did this to our beys?
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
How could this be?
-Move.
-How could this be?
Bamsi!
Bamsi! Bamsi, what happened to you?
Bamsi, who did this?
Open your eyes. Bamsi!
Bamsi!
Bamsi! Bamsi, open your eyes!
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
He is missing.
Ishak. Where is Ishak?
Ishak has been martyred.
Who is going to heal them now?
There's nobody left.
Artuk Bey, get up.
Let go!
Let go of me!
-Towel.
-Brothers, some water.
-Bring towels.
-Come on, quick!
Bring towels.
Bamsi, you are my man, my companion.
Don't leave me alone!
God, help us!
Come on brothers, come on.
Ertuğrul Bey!
Bamsi, no, hang on Bamsi.
It won't stop.
We can't stop the bleeding.
We need to cauterize it.
Then do it.
What are you waiting for?
Bamsi!
Bamsi, hang on!
Stop.
Move.
-Move.
-Who are you?
The healer.
The emir commissioned me.
Everybody out.
Thank God.
-You'll be all right, Bamsi.
-I said, everybody out.
I won't leave him. He is my man.
No, woman.
This is my job.
Nobody must come in.
Let me help you.
I'll be right by my man's side.
Or else I won't be at ease.
Fine.
Is he going to live?
Please tell me he will.
Look, you are my only hope.
Please save him.
Thank God, he's alive.
We have to undress him
and cauterize his wounds.
May God help us.
Ertuğrul Bey!
My bey.
Bamsi.
Forgive me, my bey.
My bey.
Bamsi.
He's waking up. Thank God.
Forgive me, my bey.
I couldn't protect you, my bey.
Bamsi, I am here.
Tell me who did this.
What traitors did this to you?
I don't know.
The infidels'...
faces were covered.
My bey!
However,
I wounded...
their leader in the back.
What about Ertuğrul Bey?
Where is he?
He was wounded too.
Kill them!
Don't let them get away!
My bey!
Alps! Take our bey.
Take him, alps! Take him!
Two of our alps...
took our bey away.
-No!
-Brothers!
How could they do this to you?
How could they kill you?
Oh, my God.
There are martyrs everywhere.
Where? Where did they take Ertuğrul Bey?
Tell us so that we may help.
I don't know.
Bamsi.
Bamsi! Bamsi, wake up!
Wake up, Bamsi!
Woman, let's leave the wounded alone
for now.
They need to rest.
I have to tell Halime Hatun
what Bamsi told me.
Their hearts suffer, just like mine.
I have to get to them
before their hope runs out.
Get what I'm about to say
to the emir at once.
Come on.
-Mother!
-Aslıhan.
Mother!
Halime, my sister.
Sister.
How could this be?
Who did this?
We don't know, my girl.
We haven't found my son yet.
Don't worry.
We will, Hayme Ana.
We will find our Ertuğrul Bey.
We searched everywhere.
We looked in every bird nest,
every ant nest.
There is no trail.
Nobody's hand...
or power will suffice
in getting to our Ertuğrul Bey.
We will find him, Halime.
All my alps will look for him.
We will find him.
God bless you, Aslıhan.
Göktuğ, tell the men
to join the alps searching
for Ertuğrul Bey.
Nobody comes back
until our Frontier Bey is found.
Yes, Your Eminence.
I came as soon as I heard.
And I sent my healer
to tend to your wounded at the camp.
My men will continue to search
day and night until Ertuğrul Bey is found.
I fear that
the ones who did this may have
taken Ertuğrul Bey, Your Eminence.
Our state and I...
are behind you to the end.
Rest assured.
May God bless you.
As my men look here for Ertuğrul Bey...
I will personally go
and question the people involved in this.
To whoever dared to attempt this...
let it be known
that it is my duty to find him.
Dündar Bey!
We found Ertuğrul Bey's armor.
Ertuğrul Bey was nowhere near it.
Brother.
Ertuğrul!
I'd die!
Ertuğrul.
We have done away with a fierce enemy.
I raise my wine of victory
in honor of my knights.
I will also hold a great feast
in celebration of this victory.
However...
I would like to show you something first.
What is this sword, my lord?
The sword of our enemy.
A sword is very precious to a Turk.
We sent Ertuğrul to hell.
Now we will stamp
on his most cherished possession.
This is the might of the knights.
Long live Commander Ares!
The might of the knights!
Just like this sword and its master,
we will stamp on the Turks
and destroy them!
We will stamp on the Turks
Ertuğrul Bey!
-Ertuğrul Bey!
-Look under every stone!
Look in every tree hollow!
Ertuğrul Bey!
My son...
We will continue to look until daybreak!
-Ertuğrul Bey!
-We will not return until we find him!
Ertuğrul Bey!
-Mother Hayme!
-Mother!
Mother Hayme!
-Mother, it's Hafsa.
-Mother!
Mother Hayme!
What is it?
Hafsa, what are you doing here, my girl?
I have important news, Mother Hayme.
-Speak, what is it?
-Bamsi opened his eyes.
-Oh, thank God.
-Thank God.
Did he say where Ertuğrul Bey was?
They did not see who attacked them.
Their faces were covered.
Two alps took Ertuğrul Bey away.
Mother...
-The alps we saw.
-No.
-Mother, if they are dead then--
-Halime!
Get a hold of yourself!
Let's pray first, my girl. Pray.
Maybe they died
after they hid their bey.
Do you hear me?
Listen to me!
Mother!
We won't give up.
We'll find my son.
We will!
Come on.
If they hid my brother...
we should search in the vicinity
of where we found them.
-Yes.
-You're right.
Alps!
We will look where we found the two alps.
We will look everywhere!
-Come on!
-Come on, alps!
Ertuğrul Bey!
Your Eminence, the healer you sent
to the Kayi tribe has sent word.
-Well?
-Bamsi said that the assailants
were bandits but didn't see their faces.
He wounded their leader
in the back as he got away.
Good.
So, Ares took care of this silently.
Well?
Any news of Ertuğrul?
He doesn't know where Ertuğrul is.
He saw two alps take him away wounded.
Göktuğ, until Ertuğrul is found,
dead or alive,
we can't rest.
Tell your men to be quick about it.
Yes, Your Eminence.
You summoned me.
Permission to enter, my Sultan.
Come.
An alp brought word from your tribe.
I have no knowledge of this, my Sultan.
Ertuğrul Bey and his alps
were ambushed and raided en route.
They were raided?
By who?
Who ambushed them, my Sultan?
That is not known.
Unfortunately...
many of the alps died.
Only two survived but they are wounded.
Ertuğrul Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey is missing.
There's no sign of him.
The Kayis are looking for him everywhere.
Now, it is my command to you...
Take your alps
and go to your tribe immediately.
Make inquiries.
Find out what happened...
and who set this trap.
As you wish, my Sultan.
Until you return...
I will appoint a head alp in your place.
You do as I say and...
don't come back
without finding Ertuğrul Bey.
This is your mission.
But be careful.
I wouldn't want you to be ambushed too.
As you wish, my Sultan.
Ertuğrul Bey!
Halime.
You've tired yourself out.
I won't stop
until I overturn every rock...
look in every hollow
in these mighty mountains.
Mother Hayme,
we found a burnt body nearby!
Burnt body?
Come on.
This...
isn't Ertuğrul.
It isn't.
It's not my son.
My God...
don't give me more pain than I can bear.
Ertuğrul!
Brother!
Mother! They burnt our heart!
My boy!
How could they do this?
Ertuğrul!
Brother!
My lord, our men sent word.
-Ertuğrul's body was found.
-Found?
Who found it?
The Kayi alps, my lord.
They will take his body to the tribe.
I wonder how they cried out
when they saw his body
choked on his own blood.
My lord, Ertuğrul did not choke on
his own blood, he was burned.
Burned?
Who burned him?
We don't know, my lord.
None of ours did.
But don't worry. It is Ertuğrul for sure.
The Kayi alps are sure
that it is Ertuğrul too.
It doesn't matter who burned him.
That rascal found hell
in this world too.
Prepare a great feast, Lukas.
Let the bells toll for three days.
Invite everyone to the feast.
And make preparations
for Ertuğrul's funeral.
Yes, my lord.
Door!
Your Eminence.
There is word from our men.
They have found Ertuğrul's body at last.
Thank you, God!
I hope that tekfur
wasn't stupid enough to leave a trace.
There are no traces on him, Your Eminence.
The body was burnt when they found him.
Burnt?
Yes, Your Eminence.
They understood that it was Ertuğrul
from his bow ring.
What a monster, that tekfur.
As if it wasn't enough to kill him...
he burned him too.
What should we do, Your Eminence?
The first thing we'll do...
is attend Ertuğrul's funeral.
What we'll actually do...
will begin after the funeral.
Bamsi...
Who is it wrapped in a flagged
this time?
Bamsi, please go inside. Come.
Bamsi, stay with me. Bamsi!
Bamsi. Please stop, stay with me.
Stop!
-Stop!
-Bamsi!
No! Who is it?
Who is it?
-No!
-Bamsi...
-Stop! Bamsi!
-No!
Don't look!
-Mother...
-Don't...
My son!
-Mother Hayme!
-My son!
Mother! Say he isn't.
Say he isn't.
Say no.
Say it is not our bey, Mother.
My son!
Say he isn't.
Say no.
Fire can't burn our bey. Say it.
Say it.
He died in the name of Allah.
Fire doesn't burn a hero of Allah. Say it.
My son!
Bey!
I couldn't shield you as an alp.
I couldn't save you as a brother, Bey.
I wish I had choked on my bread,
I wish my eyes were covered with blood
so I didn't have to see you like this.
Is this how I have to see you
after awaiting your victory?
Mother!
Mother! Mother!
Is this my father?
Bamsi?
Bamsi, who is this?
Who is this Bamsi?
It is Bey!
Turgut!
Turgut.
Turgut! No fire can burn our bey, Brother.
No fire can burn our bey, Brother.
Did they burn my bey?
Alps.
I won't let him go.
My child.
Bey!
My son!
Long live Commander Ares!
Let them have fun until morning, Lukas.
Let them keep on drinking
until Ertuğrul is laying underground.
Today is the happiest day in Karacahisar.
Yes, sir.
Sir,
this is slave trader Simko.
I know him from Nicaea.
He is a very famous trader.
He wants to have
the distinct honor of meeting you.
Greetings, Commander Ares.
I heard that you allow beautiful slaves
to join this wonderful feast of yours.
So, here I am
with all my beautiful slaves.
Because there would be no better chance
for me to meet you.
Why do you want to meet me?
People praise the trade here
and I'm planning to do trade here.
But to do this,
I should meet
a powerful landlord like yourself
and collaborate.
You look like a smart trader.
Thank you, Tekfur Ares.
I have a small present for you
in honor of our meeting.
If you wish,
I would like to present it to you.
Before his forty days have passed,
we have to avenge him!
We have to.
Help me, God!
Looking at the slaves you have Simko,
it is obvious you're a good slave trader.
This beauty is Marya.
We call her, Mermaid.
Immaculate, innocent
and a rosebud.
Mermaid, huh?
Beautiful.
Very beautiful.
As the start of our good collaboration,
I kindly
ask you to accept this beauty
as my present.
Only the wise traders think of presenting
such a precious thing.
It is clear that
you're a good trader Simko.
I like your generosity.
And I always need good traders.
Clearly, we won't have any difficulty
building good relations.
It's a great honor for me, Tekfur Ares.
Lukas!
Settle my present in a comfortable room,
she will rest until tomorrow.
I'll go on feasting tomorrow with Marya,
after Ertuğrul's funeral.
Go, come on.
Where?
Where are you going?
How...
did they throw you into the fire, Bey?
How did they do away with you?
Bey...
We are all burning inside.
And thinking that the bey was burned
by these daemon bastards...
burns us a thousand times.
This happened...
because of me.
You are not to blame, Brother Bamsi.
Turgut Alp is right.
Now,
it is time...
to keep the hand on the sword.
Those who think of anything but revenge,
may they be ruined!
After...
Ertuğrul Bey is buried...
it is time...
to disregard our lives
and to face death!
Yes!
Revenge is honor!
And we owe this honor to our bey
and to our tent!
He who runs from his debt,
may he drown in blood!
Yes!
From now on...
it is your duty...
to look after the tent...
and to avenge your brother.
Therefore...
no later than tomorrow...
gather the beylic council.
Our law orders this.
Gündüz.
Come, Gündüz.
Come, my brother's lion.
Halime.
Halime, don't cry in front of the child.
We've perished, don't let him perish too.
I thought I saw Ertuğrul
when I saw him by the door.
Father, wake up, Father!
Come on, Father!
Gündüz, my nephew.
Let's go to your brother.
I won't!
Father, come on, wake up, Father.
Don't.
Don't, my son.
I'd die for you, don't Gündüz.
Father, wake up.
God, how do I console this little child?
Mercy, God. Mercy.
The Oghuz insignia,
these three arrows and the bow,
would have ruled of the world.
Now they are the insignia
of your funeral, Son.
My condolences.
Did the earth bare its heart
for my son, Turgut?
It did, Mother.
We come and go in this world
and find death in the end.
I envy Mother Earth for taking my man.
How can Earth cover you, Ertuğrul?
How can the earth keep you?
Ertuğrul!
How can death
come for a valiant man like you?
How can the earth hide you?
The mighty world has become lonely.
The mighty universe has become lonely.
Come.
My hero!
The mighty universe has become lonely.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Alps!
Allahu akbar!
I'll avenge you, Father.
I'll avenge you.
I'm giving you the word of an alp.
Allahu akbar!
Come to the salaah for Allah.
Come to the salawat for our Prophet.
Come to pray for the funeral.
And I will follow the imam
intended for a man.
Allahu akbar.
Ertuğrul Bey,
I swear to God...
If we cannot avenge you,
may my sword tear me apart
and be washed with my blood!
Tear me apart, washed with blood!
I came here as your neighbor.
Sorry for your loss.
Ertuğrul Bey...
was a brave warrior,
a glorious commander.
We are all sad about what happened.
I want you to know,
I am always here for you.
Thank you.
Allahu akbar!
After Ertuğrul’s death,
I hope the Seljuk State
follows politics which will ease
the tension in the margraves.
I decide the politics here.
Don't you worry.
From now on, our politics
won't be fed by tension,
but by mutual benefit.
I am very glad to hear that,
Emir Sadettin.
I'd like to reap the reward
of these politics.
Those fruits are not ripe yet.
But soon they will be.
Wait for my word.
Allahu akbar!
Brave beys...
devoted mothers...
children who will be Kayi alps.
We can't break...
from one gust of wind.
We can't perish...
in one hurricane.
We...
can't be defeated by one thunderstorm.
Our tears...
our pain and our sweat...
are soaked into these lands.
We have a cause!
Whoever...
believes in Ertuğrul Bey...
and admires him...
should know that
they are a martyr for their cause.
Whoever...
believes in the cause of mighty Allah,
or admires Allah,
should know that this cause
will live and will continue to live
until the Judgment Day.
Anyone wants to praise
Ertuğrul Bey's soul,
gather yourself
and support this cause.
For...
it is time...
for revenge.
An eye for an eye...
a tooth for a tooth.
-Revenge!
Revenge! Revenge! Revenge!
Revenge! Revenge!
Allahu akbar!
Who are you?
We are the Bozok Tribe...
of Oghuz.
From Otuken, the Mountains of Heaven.
Joy to you, Ertuğrul Bey.
This child shining in your white tent,
is your son Osman.
May his guide be the Quran
and the sunnah of our mighty Prophet.
May his law be the law of my Oghuz father.
We are the Ucok Tribe of Oghuz,
come down from the Altai Mountains,
washed in the Orkhon River.
Joy to you, Ertuğrul Bey.
This child shining in your lovely tent
is your son Osman.
May his sword be strong,
his cause be just.
The nine fringed aigrette
that our...
world-conquering Khagans carried...
may be his destiny...
and may be the insignia
of the World State.
Ertuğrul Bey,
the key to the united state
that will be created by your son
is in your hand.
First of all, stay alive,
have your revenge upon your enemies.
Bring order to the lands.
Then, you will see your son Osman
before you die.
With the oath of my Oghuz father,
armed with bow and shield,
may we be branded with merit.
May our iron spikes be so numerous
that they seem like a forest.
It is in the sea,
it is in the brook.
May the sky be our tent,
the sun be our flag.
Allahu akbar!
Osman.
My Osman.
What will we do?
We buried...
Ertuğrul Bey.
Now,
immediately,
we need to gather together.
The position of bey should be filled
so as not to leave our tent
and our alps unattended.
He is right.
We should designate a new bey.
Therefore, I...
Dündar Bey, son of Suleyman Shah...
seek to be...
bey of the Kayi tribe...
and carry on Ertuğrul Bey's cause...
where he left off.
With God's grace...
avenging him is my duty.
Know that.
You are the only choice to be the bey
in Suleyman Shah's marquee.
Ertuğrul Bey's cause
must be carried on by his own blood.
Agreed.
So the beys are agreed,
beylic insignias
should be worn.
She's right.
On the book,
on the flag,
and on the sword,
I swear.
If I leave
the path of my faith,
my tradition and of my brother,
may I be killed
with my own sword
for the Qur'an and our flag.
Oh, Ertuğrul...
Oh...
You have disobeyed the state
and its powerful emir
for many years.
He tried to undermine every decision
you made, Your Highness.
Yes, and now what?
He filled his own grave.
The Sultan rules us.
But
I rule here. He couldn't understand that.
He won't rest in peace.
I'll send his village
to the place they came.
I'll create a new order in these lands,
where even
his grave will be forgotten.
Ares left smiling, Your Highness.
You'll see how he smiles
when he hears my offer
after the mourning.
No doubt, sir.
Your Highness, the council will end soon.
Dündar Bey is at the tent.
This council is just a charade,
and I'll be the winner.
I'll put such a tight leash
on Dündar that...
whatever Ertuğrul owned,
whatever he took from me,
will be mine again.
But,
our issue is Turgut Alp.
What is he doing?
He stays here
and is provoking the alps
to avenge Ertuğrul, sir.
Send him to me.
We buried Ertuğrul.
He has a grave.
Where I'll send Turgut, he won't
even find soil to be buried under.
What, are you hungry? Here you go.
Is there no water? Give us water.
Water?
Give them water. Here you go. Water.
Please give us water.
Here you go.
Water!
Give us water. Just a little.
Tell me.
Is Ertuğrul going to live?
His anger will keep him alive,
don't worry.
What happened?
Tell me everything.
If you left even the slightest trace
that you were there,
we'll pay with our lives.
Commander Ares ambushed Ertuğrul
and his men
dressed as a bandit.
Lots of blood.
Kill them. Don't let them escape!
When Ares was injured,
I saw his face.
So Ares
wanted to get rid of Ertuğrul Bey
before making peace
with the Turks.
But how did Ertuğrul escape?
Two injured alps took him away.
My bey! Hang on, my bey!
I followed them.
Almost there, hang on.
My bey. Hang on my bey.
Almost there, my Bey. Hang on.
Please hang on!
They're coming!
Hang on.
His alps gave their life
for Ertuğrul.
And so they handed
Ertuğrul to me.
And his body?
How did you convince his family
and the alps that he had died?
I put Ertuğrul's ring
on one of Ares' men
then burned him.
Good.
You weren't seen, were you?
Rest assured,
only we know the truth.
Very well done, Antheus.
Now we have such power that
we can set two countries on each other.
So, what now?
If we want to make a profit,
we'll keep Ertuğrul Bey alive.
We need him alive.
Ares won't fear a dead Ertuğrul
but an alive one will scare him
and he'll give us the gold we want.
Since you gifted a beautiful slave
such as Marya
to Ares...
You'll contact him soon.
Marya will be our eyes in the castle.
Come, let's see Ertuğrul Bey before
before we set off.
May your rage keep you alive,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Feed off your rage...
so we can get rich.
Oh, Allah, you who helped Yusuf
out of the darkest of holes.
Help this poor servant
of yours as well.
Help me.
You asked for me, Your Highness.
Our Sultan...
what did he order you to do?
Find out what happened
and find Ertuğrul.
You know all that you need to know,
and since you found Ertuğrul,
you don't need to stay here anymore.
Ertuğrul Bey has been found.
-But without finding those--
-Those who did it will be found.
The Seljuk Emir is here.
Dündar Bey is here,
you're not needed anymore.
-Your Highness...
-You've done your duty here, Turgut.
Our army is marching.
And
the campaign awaits you.
Take your alps tomorrow morning...
and get going.
Don't worry about here.
May your reign be a successful one.
May your village be happy.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
Thanks, dear.
It means a lot.
When do you join the campaign,
Turgut Alp?
At dawn, we'll set out
with the alps.
Must be hard to leave
while the village mourns.
But you and your alps...
are our hope.
You are an alp.
You'll get through this.
Mourning aside,
leaving without having
avenged Ertuğrul Bey
just doesn’t seem right.
Don't worry.
Ertuğrul Bey will be avenged.
If our state wants you on the campaign,
you have to take your sword
and go to battle.
Turgut.
Don't forget this.
There'll be someone waiting for you.
It soothes my heart
knowing that someone is waiting for me.
We can never accept
the deaths of those we love.
Can't accept burying a loved one.
In my heart
I still can't believe you're gone.
No words will persuade me.
Ertuğrul!
You told me you'd seen me in the eyes of
a scared deer.
You saved me in my darkest hour.
Look!
I need help again.
This time it's not the enemy's sword
that attacks me
but the cold touch of the dark soil.
Mother.
My Gündüz.
Why didn't you tell me you were here?
You were sleeping, son,
I didn't want to wake you up.
You should have.
How will the flowers of his grave bloom
if we don't water them?
Right, they won't.
Good thinking, son.
I have something to say to him.
What is that, Gündüz?
Dad, you wouldn't have let me
have a steel sword,
but you're not here anymore.
It's time.
I took the sky sword.
My Halime.
My Gündüz.
My Gündüz!
Who are you?
Where am I?
You're safe, Ertuğrul.
Save your energy.
I'll get you back to health.
Don't push yourself.
You're still weak.
I made you some soup.
Drink.
Now is not the time for soup.
Where are my alps?
Who are you?
I found you injured.
Consider me a friend.
Come on, eat your food and get well.
Why is my
getting well so important to you?
Not just for me,
but for everyone who loves you.
Your loved ones are waiting for you.
Any news of them?
You push yourself too hard.
If you go on like this,
you'll never get to see them.
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
But I must go.
Come on.
You get well now.
Thank you.
We're ready to go to Karacahisar,
Your Highness.
Good.
Let's not keep our partner waiting.
Forgive me, Your Highness,
I don't understand.
Open your eyes, Göktuğ.
Even the night chases the morning.
Why should we stay idle?
We have to chase our gains.
Look,
every event opens a new door.
If you knock at that door
you win.
This door is Hanlı Bazaar for us.
A new era is beginning.
Oh...
And news from Bahadır Bey?
He's on the road.
He will arrive shortly.
Good. Bahadır Bey is precious to us.
Because
Candar Bey's brother Bahadır Bey
will bring Aslıhan down.
Thanks to him...
I'll marry Aslıhan...
and get the Çavdar Village.
We joined Sultan Alaeddin's army
and destroyed the enemy.
We showed the Çavdar bravery
to everyone.
Our village is behind us.
Our brothers' village
is ahead of us.
Now
it's time to unite
under my rule.
New battles
and new treasures await us.
Yes, my bey.
Traitor.
Go!
I give you this traitor, Father.
Kara Tunga!
Kara Tunga.
You
were one of my village's beys.
You were the brother of my wife, Karaca.
You were
no different to me than
my son Sancar.
But you...
tried to tempt my wife...
kill me...
and take my title, huh?
Shame on you!
You denounced your own brother,
your own blood.
Bahadır Bey is my blood and my life.
I have no brother like you.
That's my wife.
The honor of taking this traitor's head
is all yours.
Whoever
disobeys me
and rebels
against
my rule
pays with their head.
The traitor's blood
is the sweetest revenge.
Not just my brother,
but my entire life is yours.
So long as you're well.
Nothing will happen to me
as long as I
have my brave son,
my brave wife
and my brave warriors.
We're near the Çavdar Village.
That's the village
of my ancestors,
of my brother Candar.
And now it'll be mine.
We have
the great Emir Sadettin behind us.
We'll rule these lands.
Yes, my bey.
My brave alps,
we smashed the enemy in battle.
We made the traitor pay.
Now we'll take our village
and rule these lands.
Whoever stands against us,
whoever resists our might,
will have their heads on our spears.
Long live Bahadır Bey!
Ertuğrul's death changed Karacahisar.
How are the Kayıs?
They couldn't get over
the death of Ertuğrul.
Doesn't look like they will soon.
If they knew what was about to happen
to them, they'd cherish these final days.
When will we move to capture
Hanlı Bazaar, sir?
Very soon.
-Have you sent word to bandit Mihalis?
-Yes, sir.
Good.
He must've missed raiding caravans.
He'll be very happy.
That’s enough fresh air.
Let's get inside.
Our dear guest
Emir Sadettin will arrive soon.
Let's see what he wants.
Emir Sadettin.
Welcome.
Thank you.
We prepared a feast in your honor.
A full table...
means a full heart.
I like sharing.
So do I.
That's why I'm here.
I'm sure a statesman like you will share
even the most precious things.
Let's keep it brief, Ares.
Until now,
I've made all kinds of sacrifices
for my country.
I'm sure you've done the same.
We've ensured plenty of gains for
our respective states.
However,
now it's our turn to win.
I'd be honored to work with you,
Emir Sadettin.
What do you propose?
Hanlı Bazaar.
The first reward of our partnership.
If we administer it together,
we'll both be rich.
If you accept,
I'm here to propose a profitable
partnership.
I'd like that very much.
But there's something I'd like to know.
You're the most powerful Seljuk Emir...
why do you still want more?
When I have the chance,
why shouldn't I want more?
Emir Sadettin.
You only lack being the Sultan.
Do you mean that?
Why not?
I told you to bring food
when you were coming!
What's with this empty horse?
Simko sent that horse for Ertuğrul.
He said he doesn't want
to make Ares wait any longer.
So it's time to be rewarded
for the things I've done for Ertuğrul.
He said he'll wait for you at Monks Hill.
You know what to do.
Simko shouldn't worry.
I'll bring Ertuğrul to him
of his own will.
My God.
Ertuğrul Bey, I told you not to get up.
You haven't recovered yet.
I'm fine, Antheus.
Don't worry.
I want to go back to my village.
I know you burn with vengeance.
But whoever set you up
couldn't find your body.
They must be looking for you everywhere.
And they'll never give up.
There's nothing beyond death, Antheus.
I'll never forget what you've done for me.
Whoever did this to you must be
very powerful.
I can't send you out there like that.
Look, I brought clothes for you
from the village.
And a horse that's waiting outside.
We've got a long journey.
I'll come with you.
Thank you, Antheus.
I don't know how far we have to go.
But the destination is apparent.
The account between those degenerates
and us has to be settled.
Whoever did this to me will pay for it.