Episode 105 start after 12:39 min.
May I enter, Your Highness?
Come in.
You sent for me, Your Highness?
How fares our army?
The soubashi commanders are
at their posts, Your Highness.
The catapults and crossbows
should be ready soon.
We've also got enough horses
and mules for deployment.
Great.
Now, take this letter.
Give it to Mahperi Hatun in Alaiye.
Before I launch this campaign,
have her come to Konya with
my son Ghiyath al-Din.
I'd like to see them.
Ertuğrul Bey will be here soon.
I have important matters
to discuss with them.
As you wish, Your Highness.
The poets and scholars would like
to see you and show their work
before you leave for the campaign.
The famous poet Qol Ghali of the Oghuz
has come to Konya on your orders.
He's waiting to see you.
Good.
Let him come, too.
As we sharpen our swords for battle,
we must keep our spirits up.
We haven't met with the poets in a while.
The poet's meeting is tomorrow.
Have my emirs and commanders be ready.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Mother. Endure it, Mother.
Don't give up.
Please, God.
Give strength to my mother.
Hayme Hatun is in bad shape,
she's having difficulty breathing.
Leave us, please.
Artuk Bey, I brought your sack.
Here, your sack.
God.
You are the one who cures.
You are all knowing.
Mother Hayme's condition is
pretty bad, sir.
Artuk Bey.
We need to find a cure at all costs.
-Get her whatever she needs.
-Bamsı, it's not like that.
You leave now. I'll figure it out.
Don't lose hope, Sister.
Mother Hayme will be all right.
Mother.
Please, God.
There's no doubt that you are all wise.
You are the curer.
Don't take our Mother,
our beloved, from us.
Mother.
Mother!
Artuk Bey.
Bring water, Halime, quick.
Here.
May I enter, Your Highness?
Come in.
Your Highness.
What is it, Göktuğ?
Is what I heard true?
Indeed.
Ertuğrul conquered
the Karacahisar Fortress all by himself.
And now the Sultan has granted him
the lands around Söğüt.
And to top it off...
Ertuğrul is bringing one-fifth
of the spoils to share with us.
If Ertuğrul voices his suspicions
about you to our Sultan...
What suspicions?
Ertuğrul has no doubts, Göktuğ.
I'm damn sure that he knows all about me.
And now, he's coming
to tell our Sultan everything he knows.
Then... what will you do, sir?
It's far too soon for the Sultan
to die, Göktuğ.
I don't have control over
his heir and mother yet.
If the Sultan dies suddenly,
my enemies at the palace
will skin me alive,
and hang me on the gates of the palace.
What about Ertuğrul?
We tried to kill him many times.
If we can't succeed this time,
we'll attract everyone's attention.
And then, the Sultan won't let us live.
In that case, you have no other way
than to clear your name
in the eyes of the Sultan.
The Sultan must have no doubt that
whoever tried to poison him at the inn
got what he deserved.
This will also clear Ertuğrul's suspicions
about me.
So that...
we may keep getting
ever closer to our goal.
We need a scapegoat for this, Göktuğ.
Who is it going to be, sir?
Nizamettin.
Emir Nizamettin.
He sent a gift box to our Sultan,
saying that he won't be able to attend
tomorrow's meeting with the poets.
I heard about it.
You'll change Emir Nizamettin's box
with the box I'll prepare.
The Sultan will take his gift there.
What are you going to gift him, sir?
I'll give him a present he can't forget.
It'll be legendary.
Is the Sultan going to die?
We shall do our part.
The rest depends on the angel of death.
When the Mongols...
murdered...
our mothers and fathers...
we were left all alone in the mountains.
Ertuğrul Bey found us and took us in.
Mother Hayme became...
our mother,
and Suleyman Shah became our father.
Ertuğrul Bey...
was more than a brother.
Turgut, brother.
Brother.
What would we have done without them?
We might have become bandits by now.
We'd be goners for sure.
Brother, they didn't leave us alone.
How can we repay this debt?
Brother.
We must find a way to remedy Mother Hayme.
I can't bear waiting like this...
with nothing I can do.
I can't!
Turgut.
It's tearing me apart.
Mother Hayme will be all right.
She will be okay.
I hope so.
Son.
Who is this boy?
It's my son, Osman.
Osman...
My wonderful boy.
With a searing gaze...
his face shines bright.
He's such a wonderful boy, right?
I hope he becomes a man...
that will carry on our name.
I hope so.
This is a mortal world.
I may be here today...
and gone tomorrow.
Bring him up the way...
we brought you up.
We'll raise him together, Mother.
It was you who raised me,
my brothers, and my sons.
You sang them to sleep with lullabies.
It will be you who'll raise Osman, Mother.
The arms of Mother Hayme are
a lion's cradle.
He'll grow up in your arms.
Osman...
Mother.
Osman.
Thank God, she came to her senses.
Mother.
This is an amazing invention,
Your Highness.
I just hope it doesn't jam
when the Sultan opens it.
Try it then and see if it jams.
As you wish.
And, what is that, Your Highness?
Poison.
The one that was given
to the Sultan before.
The head physician knows about it.
Then, when he examines him,
he'll recognize the poison.
And the poisoning before will be
blamed on Emir Nizamettin.
Take this chest.
Change it with Emir Nizamettin's.
Tomorrow, the meeting of the poets...
will be a feast for the eyes.
As you wish, sir.
Open!
Son.
Ertuğrul.
Mother.
My enduring mother.
Don't wear yourself out, Mother.
Hayme Hatun is all right, sir.
Don't worry.
But she survived a huge crisis.
It'd be best for her to rest.
Thank God.
-Thank God.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Have some rest.
You must be tired.
I'll wait by my mother's side tonight.
Don't worry about me, Halime.
You can leave.
I'll be by her side.
-If that's what you want.
-All right, sir.
Of course.
I'm worried that something's going
to happen Mother Hayme, Artuk Bey.
I love her like my own mother.
You all treated me so kindly...
After so little time,
I loved her and the others so much.
Such sweet words, Marya.
I'm happy to hear that you think this way
and that you're happy here.
You treated me kindly as well, Artuk Bey.
I was so happy to become your wife.
What did I do
to deserve all this goodness?
Your heart is pure, Marya.
You have no ill-will in you.
You took care of Gündüz
and protected him.
This meant a lot to us.
I have never been so happy in my life.
I'm sure with you,
we'll live happily ever after.
I hope so, Marya.
We'll live to see many happy days.
I hope so.
Mother.
Tell me, son.
Why are you so tearful?
Mother...
You suffered a great deal for your sons.
You cried for them so much that crying
my eyes out is nothing compared to that.
You left your sons behind
and joined my cause for me.
How can I ever repay you?
I'm all right, son.
I dreamed about Osman...
last night.
My son, Osman.
He'll change our unfortunate fate.
He'll make sure
the Oghuz take root here.
Suleyman Shah named him.
May he live a long life.
Now, I can die in peace.
I felt him in my arms.
I kissed him.
I breathed in his smell.
See?
I'm okay.
Now,
get back to your duty.
That's what befits the margrave
of our country.
I sent the news to Dündar
and my older brothers, Mother.
I asked them to come at once.
I asked them to join me
and let us live here together.
Your words...
reminded me of the smell of my sons, dear.
God bless you.
May you never fall on your knees.
Come on.
Go back to your duty.
All right, mother.
May God protect you.
May God protect you as well, son.
My brave son.
Before Ertuğrul enters the Hanlı Bazaar,
you will disguise yourselves
as merchants and blend in.
Nobody will recognize you in the crowd.
-What about you, sir?
-Me?
I'll be inside this basket
that we'll gift Ertuğrul.
Once we are in, the rest is easy.
Our men hid swords under the tables
where they'll sit
by disguising themselves the night before.
Once we get inside,
we must kill the guards posted
at the inner door and close it.
We must prevent the alps from entering.
There'll be few men with Ertuğrul.
-He'll be defenseless.
-And then what, sir?
How do we get out?
We will set fire to the Hanlı Bazaar
after we kill Ertuğrul.
Once Titan sees the rising smoke,
he'll know that Ertuğrul is dead.
He'll come to our rescue with his men.
That's enough.
Let's get going.
Keep your eyes open.
This is going to be a cruel battle
for our holy cause,
with no second chances.
Ares will set fire to the inn
once he's dealt with Ertuğrul.
When the smoke rises from the inn,
we'll attack.
Get ready.
Do you have faith that
Ares will succeed this time?
God is with Ares.
His only chance is to succeed this time.
I'm sure that barbaric Turk will get
what he deserves this time.
Don't be so sure.
It's not so easy to defeat Ertuğrul.
Ares is a great warrior, Angelos.
Remember that.
He won't stop unless he kills Ertuğrul.
-What did you bring?
-It's made exclusively for Ertuğrul Bey.
This isn't much, but...
Mother, smell this.
Here, Mother Hayme.
Let me.
May it help you recover.
Thank you, dear.
At last, I'll get to see
all my children before I die.
What more could I ask for?
When Sungur Tekin Bey,
Gündoğdu Bey,
and Dündar's return,
our unity will get even stronger, Mother.
I hope so, dear.
I do hope so.
Now, I must get up
and start the preparations.
-Mother.
-Mother Hayme.
What are you doing?
You need to rest.
We can do it.
We can't let you work
while we are here, Mother Hayme.
That's right.
I can't contain myself.
I can't express how much I miss them.
My heart is burning to see...
my sons.
If they could come in one piece...
I'll cook for them myself.
I'll make them a bowl of soup.
That's all I want.
Mother Hayme.
You need to rest.
We'll handle the preparations ourselves
until they come.
Fine, my girls.
Now then, let me rest a bit.
Mother.
Why didn't my uncles come here
with my father?
What can I say, son?
Your uncles have their own tribes there.
There are enemies there too.
If they left their tribe...
the enemy would attack.
Let's all get together, Grandmother.
I want my uncles.
I'll tell them the story about
how I plucked Ares' eye out.
My boy.
Fine, tell them.
My dear boy.
Your Grandmother loves you.
Aziz Yusuf was 11 years old.
Prophet Jacob was asleep.
He saw Joseph in a strange dream.
And he asked his forefathers
its interpretation.
As the full moon rose,
11 stars bowed down before me in my dream.
I saw this dream for sure.
Pray, tell me what it means now.
What's the meaning of this dream of mine?
How will it end up? Tell me.
Show me the meaning clearly.
Does my dream contain a hidden bliss?
O Muhammad, Joseph saw your dream.
The moon, the sun,
and 11 stars bowed down.
Why did the stars pull the grass?
Now, tell me in detail.
God bless you, Qol Ghali.
May God bless your victory
and give you a long life, Your Highness.
Amen.
Ensure the safety of the inn, Bamsı.
-Tell everyone to be alert.
-Yes, sir.
Men!
Keep your hands at your swords.
Look out for any enemy's attack.
All right. Take your position now.
Go on.
Margrave Ertuğrul Bey.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-I'd like to welcome you all, as well.
-Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
We are happy to see you.
-Aziz.
-Yes, Your Highness.
Why didn't Emir Nizamettin attend?
It was because he was sick, Your Highness.
However, he sent you a gift box.
Nizamettin.
My loyal emir.
He knows best what to gift me.
Bring it over here,
let's see what's inside.
Yes, Your Highness.
With this conquest,
there's a new order in trade.
First of all,
with the peace we will provide,
trades at the inn will be safer
and more fruitful.
We will keep the taxes low.
The Bazaar will grow two-fold.
Every merchant that comes here
must leave with satisfaction,
so that wherever he goes he will preach
just how abundant and peaceful a place
the Hanlı Bazaar is.
That way, people from all over the world
will come here to trade.
If you expand the trade,
our people will prosper and be rich.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
We are happy that you are here.
-Thank you.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
Yes, my tradesman.
We'd like you to accept
this Persian carpet
as thanks for your kindness.
Thank you.
Open it up, Aziz.
Atsız.
Bastards.
This will be your grave, Ertuğrul.
You won't even have a grave, Ares.
O God!
What's this?
What's the meaning of this?
Make way!
It's a poisoned arrow.
It's poisoned.
It's a trap, Your Highness.
Aziz!
Is this chest not the chest
Nizamettin sent me?
That's true, sir.
I brought it myself.
How could emir Nizamettin do this?
Nizamettin is a loyal emir of mine.
I'd expect anyone but him to do this.
-What's all that noise?
-It's coming from inside.
-Let's go in.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
I'm here, sir.
Make way, brothers.
Brothers, push!
They closed this door too.
Come on!
Sir!
My brother!
What if there's something
behind this, Aziz?
I'll start an investigation in the palace
right away.
Find Nizamettin, wherever he is,
and bring him here!
Until we find the ones who did this,
everyone is a suspect.
Everyone should know.
Yes, my sultan.
I'll find whoever stabbed the Great Sultan
of the Seljuks in the back...
in his own palace...
and bring him here for his punishment.
I'll hang him by Konya's door...
so anyone with betrayal on their minds
will see him and give up.
Brother, come on!
With the strength of your faith.
God is one!
Alps, check if he's dead.
He's alive, Bey.
My brave man.
May you rest in peace.
Atsız...
He was such a brave man who sacrificed
so much for our state.
And he carried out so many duties for us.
As long as we have such brave men,
our state will go on forever.
May God send more of them.
Amen.
Atsız's funeral will be held
with our other martyrs in our village.
I'll visit his grave when I'm done
with the scumbag Ares.
The smoke still hasn't risen from
Hanlı Bazaar.
There must be something wrong.
I'll go check what's going on.
Obviously, Ares couldn't manage
to kill Ertuğrul.
If this is the case, we can't help him.
We don't have many men.
To attack while Ertuğrul is still alive
-would be suicide.
-I can't let Ares die there.
And I can't let someone like you die.
We all need a warrior like you.
If he can't make it, they'll either
kill him or take him hostage.
And they know you.
If they see you,
they'd never let you live.
Titan, it's all over.
Just understand that.
Ares couldn't make it.
You'll replace him.
Don't worry, we'll soon find out
about what happened to Ares.
How?
There's someone in the castle
that's very close to Ertuğrul.
He's our eyes and ears in the castle.
He'll let me know what's going on soon.
Who is this person so close to Ertuğrul?
I'll tell you when the time comes.
Now, let's go to the cellar
and wait for the news.
If Ertuğrul takes Ares to the castle,
he'll let us know.
You can grin to the demon you'll befriend
in the place you're going.
You cruel scumbag!
It's time for you to pay for everything,
Tekfur Ares.
Now either tell me everything you know
one by one,
or I'll separate your head from your body.
I won't surrender to you, Ertuğrul.
I'd rather die.
But I won't surrender.
Why are you still talking when
you're in this pathetic position?
My bey, if you'll excuse us,
we'll decapitate this degenerate.
Not now, my Turgut.
Not now.
Keep your swords away for a while.
I know you've been playing games
with that traitor Emir Sadettin
to take over Hanlı Bazaar.
You'll tell me all about it.
So, Bey, we're getting rid of these
two degenerates.
You won't die peacefully, Ares.
You won't die peacefully.
Take this degenerate away.
Once again, poison.
Once again, an ambush.
If it was the enemy, we'd be finished
with them nobly on the battlefield.
When will we see the end of the traitors
who are worse than my enemies?
Can I come in, my sultan?
Come in, Aziz.
We brought Emir Nizamettin, my sultan.
Bring him in right away!
My sultan, we looked everywhere in
his mansion.
We questioned his wives, slaves
and servants.
We found these in his mansion.
These are the letters written
for the emperor and the tekfur
of Bilecik.
They are new. The ink has just dried.
He gave them information...
about my army and my battle route.
Seems like he didn't have a chance to send
them yet, my sultan.
What does it say, my sultan?
The tekfur of Bilecik wrote...
to Emir Nizamettin about where to
find the poison...
that he'd give me.
From the former priest that
Ertuğrul killed.
He made him do everything.
Let Emir Sadettin know right away.
I want him in my presence.
Bring that traitor in as well! Quick!
-Quick!
-Your wish is my command, my sultan.
Little time left.
Soon Sadettin's palace will be built.
-Can I come in, Majesty Emir?
-Come in.
They brought Emir Nizamettin,
Majesty Emir.
Did they find the letters that I placed
in his palace?
We placed it with the help of the slave
you gifted him.
-They must have.
-Good.
When the sultan reads those letters,
he'll go mad.
He won't believe
that Nizamettin is innocent
even if everyone he knows says he is.
Can I come in, Majesty Emir?
Come in.
Our sultan is waiting for you,
Majesty Emir.
The sultan's wish is my command.
Let's go and watch with joy
how Nizamettin gets punished.
From now on, you'll be the emir that
our sultan trusts the most, Majesty Emir.
In the name of God.
Grandmother!
Grandmother would die for you.
-What's this?
-Tell me, Gündüz,
why are you so excited?
I brought molasses, Mother!
-So Grandmother can recover quickly.
-So nice of you, son.
Oh, my brave boy.
You've got such a good heart.
As long as you are such a brave Alp,
nothing will happen to me.
Nothing will happen, Grandmother.
I am Gündüz Alp,
the son of Great Ertuğrul Bey,
-Of course.
-Can I come in, Mother Hayme?
Come on, Mother.
Go ahead.
Ertuğrul Bey caught Ares
and he's bringing him to the castle.
See, I told you
my father would get him
and make him pay for it.
And now my father will
cut his other eye out!
Of course he will, son!
Your brave father would never let
the enemy get away.
Thank God, Mother.
Finally, Ares's head is in the hands
of my bey.
Let's go.
Mother Hayme.
Thank God you're okay.
But you should rest more.
Mother.
You should stay. Don't exhaust yourself.
I can't sit still, daughter.
I want to see how pathetic
that degenerate is.
And I'm good.
I'm so good.
Alçiçek, take care of Savcı.
Yes, Halime Sultan.
Alas!
The kind of business the Great Seljuk Emir
was after is unbelievable.
Turns out he served the enemy.
My sultan, Sul...
My sultan.
The soldiers raided my mansion.
They brought me here without
giving me any information.
You don't even let me kiss your skirt.
I see a rage
in your eyes bigger than
the rage you have for your enemies.
What did I do to deserve this treatment,
my sultan?
Because you've been...
even worse than my enemies, Nizamettin.
-My sultan...
-Your betrayal came out of the chest!
The poisonous arrow that came out of it
missed me
but it killed a soldier of mine
and my trust for you.
I swear to God that I didn't put those
things in the chest, my sultan.
How would I know about those
devils’ inventions?
I sent you the manuscripts
of your favorite poets.
The chest was received
right in front of me.
It was placed in the room
And it was moved out of the room
right in front me.
I'm not a traitor, my sultan.
If you're not a traitor, explain these.
They found these in your mansion!
Letters to the emperor
and the tekfur of Bilecik.
You wrote about the army's condition,
the number of soldiers,
the route of the campaign and everything!
Moreover, they told you where to get
the poison to kill me!
This is an ambush, my sultan.
The letters are an ambush!
The chest is an ambush!
Shame on you, Nizamettin!
I dedicated my life to serve you,
my sultan.
My father served your father,
my grandfather served your grandfather.
When your brother İzzettin...
got you arrested and put you in prison,
I served eight years in prison so
I wouldn't leave you on your own.
I was there with you...
at the Battle of Alaiye,
the Battle of Yassıçemen and many more.
My body is full of the scars of arrow
and sword blows...
I took for you.
This is the doings of the snakes
that hide in the state, my sultan.
I'm not the one who wanted to poison you,
they are.
The state's traditions can
forgive anything...
except betrayal.
For this cause,
fathers disregard their sons,
and brothers disregard each other.
You took advantage of the exceptions
I provided you,
and imagined yourself
in the sultan's position.
But two swords do not fit in one sheath.
I am the only sword in this state!
The reign and the power are mine!
You'll pay for it!
Take him to the dungeon!
He'll rot in the dungeon until...
he gives up the names of his allies.
My sultan, your sword is about to
take the head of the wrong person.
You're throwing your state into the fire!
Every cloud has a silver lining,
my sultan.
Luckily, you exposed the traitors
before they could...
harm you or the state.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Degenerate scumbag.
Finally, you fell into the trap
that you set up.
You got what you deserved.
You have been so evil that...
even if I tore your head off
with my bare hands,
I wouldn't feel better.
I put my feet on...
your head in the castle
that you took shelter in
once upon a time.
All evil people like you
will end up the same.
Kill me, Ertuğrul!
Kill me!
Don't waste your breath!
We've got more stuff to do.
You'll tell me everything you know.
If you resist,
I'll make you talk until you start
bleeding from your mouth.
Take him away.
Maybe the reign will go on
with ingratitude, however,
it'll never go on with cruelty.
Such wise words, Great Vizier Nizamülmülk.
May God protect us from cruelty
and from being cruel.
Can I come in, my sultan?
Come in.
What's going on Aziz? Is something wrong?
Speak!
I'm coming from the dungeon.
Emir Nizamettin.
Emir Nizamettin killed himself, my sultan.
What do you mean he killed himself?
How could this happen?
I'm one of the dungeon guards, my sultan.
He drank poison and killed himself.
The doctor is examining the emir's body.
Tell the doctor and Emir Sadettin
to come here right away!
Now!
Kill me, Ertuğrul. Finish this.
Don't rush it.
I'll give you an opportunity
to escape your death.
I'll take you to Konya.
You'll tell Sultan Alaeddin
about your alliance with Emir Sadettin.
Explain to me, how did this happen?
He had poison in his ring, my sultan.
He mixed the poison with water
and killed himself.
This is the same kind of poison
that killed
your soldier, my sultan.
Traitor!
He must have realized that he was exposed
and there was no way for him
to save himself.
So he killed himself.
There's more, my sultan.
This is the same poison they used when
they wanted to kill you in Hanlı Bazaar.
Nizamettin.
Why would he want to kill me?
Ambition for power blinded him, my sultan.
He wanted to take over the reign
by killing you
and causing a fit between your children.
There's no other explanation.
Traitor!
You worked with Emir Sadettin
on the trap you set up for me and my Alps
while we were on our sultan’s campaign,
and on the sale of Hanlı Bazaar.
If you confess this in the sultan's
presence, I'll let you live.
I am...
a knight that took an oath for my empire,
and our holy cause, Ertuğrul.
I would never do something that serves
you or your state.
I will not say a word.
Neither your empire nor your cause
can save you.
I walked all over your knighthood.
You're nothing now.
You only have your worthless life left.
And if you have some intelligence left,
you'll do as I say and save yourself.
Otherwise, tomorrow morning
I'll execute you in front of your people
and announce the kind of degenerate
that you are.
Your people will spit in your face.
You'll die with the curse of your people.
You can't do that to me, Ertuğrul!
I don't deserve that!
You don't deserve that?
Think about it until sunrise.
If you can't save yourself by morning,
you never will.
I'd die for you.
Karacahisar is conquered.
And the degenerate Ares is captured.
My mother's health is okay.
We'll have much better days, Mother.
God willing, Daughter.
Don't get up, Mother.
How are you? Is everything okay?
I'm fine, Son. You look tired.
I'm okay, Mother.
I was just with the degenerate Ares.
I'm done with him.
But the future of our state is ambiguous.
Why do you say that?
Sit down, Mother.
I've got things to tell you.
It's time for you to hear about them.
The worms of a tree come from within.
And our glorious state is weakened
by traitors within.
Not only is our state under threat,
but also our villages.
When have we lacked traitors?
They either deceive the sultan
or set the Şehzades against each other.
Thank God, the roots of our tree
are solid, my bey.
After today, no one can cause us harm.
This time it's worse, Halime.
Our sultan got poisoned,
my Alps and I were trapped,
Turgut and Aslıhan were poisoned,
and same people were behind all of these:
the emir of our state,
Emir Sadettin Köpek.
Emir Sadettin?
We all know how sinister he is.
However, how could a great emir...
be this corrupt, son?
My bey, you're talking about
the poisoning of our sultan.
That kind of evil is irredeemable.
Do you have a proof?
I have proof, my Halime.
But it's not enough.
The degenerate Ares knows everything.
If he confesses to the sultan
what he knows,
everything will come out.
Our state will get rid
of the traitor Köpek.
But Ares says he won't
confess anything.
So what are you going to do, Son?
I gave him time to think
until the morning.
If he doesn't confess,
I'll give him the necessary punishment
in front of his people.
And then I'll go to Konya to talk
to the sultan about what I know.
Oh, for God's sake, Ertuğrul.
How will you prove it to him
if Ares won't talk?
You know that as much as I do.
The palace is a lion's den.
God knows how many more Emir Sadettins
are there.
If you can't prove it, God forbid,
they will harm you badly.
We will do whatever we can to prevent
Emir Sadettin from succeeding, my Halime.
If we submit to Sadettin's games,
then our state will fail.
If we can't be as brave as the traitors,
shame on us.
To take care of the state is more
important than our own lives.
You'll come to Konya with me, Halime.
Whatever you want, my bey.
Son, you're on a tough journey again.
May God give you the strength...
to pass the deep waters
and cross the grand mountains.
Amen, Mother. Amen.
If we lose the state,
traditions will go astray.
It's time to clean the state of those
who disregard tradition.
If you'll excuse me,
I'll go see Muhyiddin Ibn Al Arabi,
Mother.
Peace be with you.
Peace be upon you. Go ahead, son.
With the help of God,
you defeated the ambushers.
Thank God.
But you couldn't get rid of the ambushers
in your mind.
Sing your heart out so you can feel peace.
The mad horses in my mind
are taking me to faraway lands.
What do you see in those lands?
Giant plane trees, mad stallions.
Sails that tame the waves.
Keys to many cities.
So what worries you?
Those mad stallions whisper in my ear.
What do they say?
They say...
"Plant a seed so it can become a plane
tree when it grows.
And that plane's shade can cover
all over the world.
So your state can exist."
May God grant these kinds
of stallions to everyone.
How can we establish this state?
What kind of qualities does that person
have to have?
Do I have those qualities?
First of all, a state is not a post,
a position, a sultan, a king
nor a khan.
A state is about the mind and the heart.
A clear mind and heart are what makes
a body human,
and what makes a state is the qualities
of its people.
The more qualities people have,
the better the state will be.
That's why they say to keep your people
alive so the state can live.
Brave people and quality people
make powerful nations.
Among them, good viziers, commanders,
scholars and students will come out...
and altogether, you'll have a grand state.
So what kind of qualities should...
their leader have?
The head is the commander
that moves the body.
The head has the eyes,
the ears and the mouth.
For a body to be healthy, the head
should be intact.
He should be merciful.
He should be fair.
He should be decisive and determined.
He'll think about the welfare
of the people before himself.
He'll make his people have new dreams.
His people's problems will be his.
So what destroys a state?
Almighty God commands, in the Quran,
"People! God’s promise is true,
so do not let the present life
deceive you.
Do not let the Deceiver
deceive you about God."
The Devil plays lots of tricks
to destroy a state.
The blind Devil instils unfairness
into the people.
He makes the bribery seem sweet.
He whispers that the inadequacy
is the reality.
Everyone cares only about themselves...
and forgets about the problems
of their people.
By then, the people get so unruly that...
they don't listen to their sultans,
they don't follow traditions...
and they stop following God's orders.
God forbid.
Holy God, I trust you and Titan,
and no one else, to save my life.
I have to look like I've surrendered
to Ertuğrul.
Help my friend Titan to find and save me
before I get to Konya.
It's time, Ares.
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
We'll take you to the bazaar,
before your own people.
You'll see Ertuğrul Bey there, Ares.
Stop.
I wish to see Ertuğrul Bey first.
Tell your bey.
I have something important to say.
The emperor and the governor of Bilecik
will attack from the north
with all their power to take back
the Karacahisar Castle.
They will attack the Kayi
and the Cavdar villages, my bey.
Those are the strongest Turkish tribes.
If we fall, the Turkish tribes
lose their leadership.
That's exactly why I want these two tribes
to unite.
Good. My bey, the Cavdars are numerous,
but they are more liable to be attacked.
Also, the pastures at the Cavdar village
won't suffice for both our herds.
The location of the Kayis is stronger,
and we have wider pastures.
Looks like you're very happy about this.
Of course. Why shouldn't I be?
God willing, we'll be one.
Bamsi is right, my bey.
It would be best for the Cavdars
to move to the Kayi village.
I'll tell my people about the situation
and prepare them to migrate.
Thanks, Turgut.
Artuk Bey, send the alps.
Tell them to find places for the Cavdars
in the Kayi village.
As you order, my bey.
Let's not keep Ares and the people
waiting for the execution.
My bey, Ares wants to speak to you.
Let's see if his mouth has opened.
Bring him, Dumrul.
As you order, my bey.
Ares, Ares.
Victory and defeat are normal in war.
Ares was defeated.
Let's hope that he's alive.
So, we'll have a hope of saving him.
No matter what,
you'll lead the war for our Empire, Titan.
Don't drive us to doom by being a slave
to your rage for Ertuğrul like Ares.
The sultan gave Söğüt and Domaniç
to Ertuğrul just like Karacahisar.
We can't let Ertuğrul have them.
-If they settle there today--
-Tomorrow they'll have Bilecik and Nicaea.
Damn it.
News from the castle, sir.
-Ertuğrul didn't kill Ares.
-Where is he now?
In the castle's dungeon.
He is to be executed.
-Did your spy send this?
-Yes.
-Who is that man?
-Not a man, a woman.
You'll meet her soon.
She'll tell you
what happens at the castle.
This sword that you treacherously stole
from me will take your head soon Ares.
Not today, Ertuğrul Bey.
Not today.
Speak, then.
I accept your offer.
I'll talk.
If you don't execute me,
I'll tell Sultan Alaeddin everything.
Fear of death brought you to your senses.
I can't give my life for your state
or for a man like Emir Sadettin.
Take him back to the dungeon.
As you order.
Door!
If Titan learns
that we're taking Ares to Konya,
he'll pursue us.
We'll take him out secretly.
We'll travel to Konya in such ways
that nobody will even guess.
The problem isn't just Titan.
Emir Sadettin.
He'll know why I'm taking Ares to Konya.
Then, he'll do anything to prevent me
from showing Ares to the sultan.
You called for me, my sultan.
The threat in the palace is gone.
But something worries me.
What is it, my sultan?
Successive attempts to poison me
have worried me, Sadettin.
I don't fear death.
I fear for my state.
The Mongols wish to invade the South
just like they did in the East
to encircle us and kill us.
They'll capture the Islamic states too.
The whole Islamic world.
They await our weakest moment.
They'll aim for us at the first chance.
May God never take you away from us,
my Sultan.
I'll die sooner or later, Sadettin.
But dying unexpectedly,
that's what scares me.
That's why I have to choose my heir.
Isn't that decided, my sultan?
Your elder son Gıyaseddin--
No. I wish for my younger son Kılıçarslan
to succeed me.
Why, my sultan?
Why would you want this?
If Kılıçarslan, the son I had with
the Ayyubid princess, becomes Sultan
he'll be able to unite the Islamic world
against the Mongols.
Then, Ertuğrul...
Ertuğrul?
What does Ertuğrul have to do with this?
I know that the Turkish tribes
under Ertuğrul will soon conquer
Bilecik and even Nicaea.
I wish for him to be responsible
for the lands he conquers
even after my death.
That's why I can't leave him
or the state up to fate.
I'll issue a decree.
Also, I'll put an important commander
and a regiment of the state
to Ertuğrul's service.
Yakup Bey would be...
great for this duty, my sultan.
Where is he?
He is in Ahlat, by your order.
Then tell him to come to my palace
when Ertuğrul Bey comes.
I'll order him and his troops
to serve under Ertuğrul Bey
to protect and maintain
the Karacahisar Castle.
Well thought, my sultan.
When I return, I'll announce my heir.
As you wish, my sultan.
Excuse me.
Bamsi, choose a group of alps.
Tell them to go ahead and check the road.
Tell them to let us know
if they see any dangers.
As you order, my bey.
Organize the Cavdar Tribe's migration
while we're in Konya, Turgut.
As you order, my bey.
Halime Hatun will accompany me to Konya.
It would be appropriate.
Until we return...
Bamsi will protect the Kayi Tribe,
Turgut, the Cavdar Tribe,
and Artuk Bey,
the castle and the Hanlı Bazaar.
All right, my bey.
You asked for me, Your Highness.
Göktuğ, take this letter to
Commander Yakup Bey at Ahlat, quickly.
When will Prince Gıyaseddin
and his mother Mahperi Hatun
come back from Alaiye?
I heard that they're coming to Konya
to see the sultan
before he leaves for war.
And his tutor, Altun Aba?
He accompanies Prince Gıyaseddin
and his mother.
Good.
Let's see what they'll do when they learn
that the sultan
casts away the tradition and chooses
his younger son, Kılıçarslan, as his heir.
At the end, we'll surely get what we want,
Your Highness.
Go, take the letter to Ahlat quickly.
Yakup Bey will be the biggest problem
I send to Ertuğrul at Karacahisar.
I feel your pain, son.
You control your desires for
the well-being of the state.
It's the right thing.
God will surely help you.
Don't worry about me, Mother.
Don't exhaust yourself.
If you need anything while I'm gone,
Artuk Bey is always here.
Don't worry about us, Son.
I'm fine.
I'll wait for your brother to get
to the castle.
Inshallah, Mother.
Who knows, maybe my brother will arrive
before I do.
Inshallah, my son.
Mother...
If I don't return,
I ask for your blessing.
Anything for you, my son.
Thanks, Mother.
My strong little lion.
Father, can't I come along?
What do you say?
Who will protect this huge castle?
There's Bamsi Alp, Turgut Alp
and many other alps.
What will I do?
They're only alps, you're the chief alp.
A bey's son must lead those alps.
When your mother and I are gone,
you'll protect the castle.
As you order, my bey.
I'm so proud of you.
My son.
Time to go, Ares.
I hope you can save me soon, Titan.
You're my only hope.
Good day.
Farewell, Mother.
Godspeed, Son. May God protect you.
Godspeed, Sister.
-Hafsa...
-Safe travels.
Before, you would only protect the village
and the tent, Gündüz.
Now you protect the castle.
Tell me everything when I return.
Don't worry, my bey.
My dear son.
-May God protect you.
-May God protect you, dear.
My bey.
My Gündüz.
-May God protect you.
-You too, Artuk Bey.
My brave son.
Look after your brother Savcı.
Look after him well.
Come back soon, okay, Mother?
We'll wait for you.
May God protect you.
-Are the other alps ready?
-They're ready.
They await at the secret passage.
Good. Go then.
Let's go.
-May God protect you.
-Thank you.
Come on.
Go and return swiftly.
Alps.
I pass as his prisoner
through the passage I built
to beat Ertuğrul.
Our spy at the castle sent this.
Ertuğrul is taking Ares to Konya.
Ares saved his skin by telling everything
he knows to the sultan.
This can't be true.
Our spy heard this from Ertuğrul's
right hand, Artuk Bey, himself.
Ares...
He must be waiting to be rescued.
We must save him before he gets to Konya.
Ertuğrul will take all the precautions
when taking him to Konya.
They'll use the back roads.
They're already on the road.
We'll never find them.
Don't worry, Titan.
Ertuğrul will surely set Ares free
once he talks.
Now, what we should think about
is how to beat Ertuğrul
and how to stop the Turks.
If Ertuğrul is gone,
we'll attack more in his absence.
But I won't use peasant soldiers,
I'll use real mercenaries.
Ares will surely find us when he's free.
I hope so.
Now tell me,
who sends all this information?
Who's this woman spy?
Marya, Artuk Bey's wife.
Günkut, Abdur Rahman.
Don't leave Ares out of your sights
until we get to Konya.
I'm no ordinary prisoner, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'm a governor.
Don't forget this on the road to Konya.
Tie his hands and feet.
If he speaks, tie his mouth too.
Come on, wife.
Come on, alps.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net