Episode 111 will start after 12:40 min.
You can't do that to me!
I came here as a guest.
You are taking me to be publicly executed!
The emperor will make you pay for this.
Shut up and move.
What do you think you are doing?
How could you put
a state official in dungeon?
Hereafter, you will obey
only Ertuğrul Bey.
Or you will suffer the consequences.
Never mind, Aydoğmus.
Our state will do what is necessary.
Sadettin Köpek.
He tried to betray us again
by using Günalp.
His plan has backfired, brother.
Hereafter, we will take more precautions.
We will show no mercy to anybody.
Why are you not talking, Artuk Bey?
Tell me.
I have something to tell you.
But I don't know how.
Tell me, Artuk Bey.
Your words are precious.
Bey,
I can't tell you what to do.
However, I disapprove of what you did
to the governor of Bilecik.
He might have come here to sign
a treaty that is disadvantageous for us.
And he might be our enemy.
However, Bey, he was invited here.
He came with a white flag.
It doesn't matter who invited him;
it isn't right to execute a man
who came with a white flag, Bey.
You are the bey.
We are under attack! Go, alps!
It is an ambush, Leon.
Did you think I would let you go
with the governor of Bilecik?
You will die this time, bastard.
Attack, brothers.
Great God!
You're just in time, Ares.
These barbarians were going to kill us.
I am grateful to you.
I told you...
I was defeated, but I am alive,
Kritos.
Hereafter,
you will be at my side with the title
you deserve, Ares. I promise you.
I don't care about the titles.
What matters is our holy mission.
Ertuğrul is important.
Tomorrow, he'll go to Söğüt
to locate a new settlement.
I will make him pay heavily for this.
I will put his head in the center
of Söğüt.
We should go before more alps arrive.
-We need to return to the castle.
-Let's go.
Ertuğrul shouldn't come back alive
from Söğüt.
Is everybody okay?
We are fine.
Brother Ahmet fooled that heathen well.
Yes.
Ertuğrul Bey's plan is in motion now.
They cruelly killed the young prince.
I can't stop thinking about it.
Emir Sadettin and his crew won't stop
until they take over the state, Ertuğrul.
Sadettin Köpek.
He will want to kill the sultan, too.
You are right, Ertuğrul Bey.
But he wants to deal with you first.
A peace messenger came from Konya
for Governor Kritos.
What peace?
I don't know the details, but...
Governor Kritos went to Karacahisar
for peace talks.
Köpek.
That bastard must be behind this.
By taking advantage of my absence,
he will have Günalp Bey sign
a peace treaty.
What treaty is this, Ertuğrul?
A treaty that will hurt me, brother.
Otherwise, Emir Sadettin
wouldn't be behind this.
If you are right, then Günalp Bey
represents the state, Bey.
And he is Köpek's puppet,
doing as he says.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Just say the word.
I will kill Governor Kritos for you
right away.
Thank you, Ahmet.
Thank you.
However, we need him alive,
not dead.
And you will gain his respect and trust.
How?
It is a difficult mission for you.
-Are you ready?
-Always, Ertuğrul Bey.
Then, listen to me very carefully.
You see, I apprehended the governor
of Bilecik intentionally,
so Ahmet would save him,
and gain his trust.
I swear to God, Bey,
I thought that Ertuğrul Bey
might have a secret plan.
But I just couldn't stop myself.
Thank God, Bey.
I hope everything goes
as you planned, Bey.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Now, I'll go to Söğüt at once
and decide on a place
for our tribe to settle.
The Governor of Bilecik will be a problem,
my Bey.
He will certainly try to ambush you.
He knows you'll go there.
For sure, Artuk Bey.
For sure.
But
he will be the prey
while he thinks he is the hunter.
We'll clear the way
from the Governor of Bilecik
and all the other infidels.
And then...
it will be Sadettin Kopek's turn.
It's high time for him to die.
How are we going to do that
while he controls the state?
If the state digresses from its path,
then the traditions digress, too.
We will not let that happen.
Turks
would live
without food or water,
but...
not without their state.
Either this state becomes
a fair state...
or we will establish
a new one which is fair and just.
I'll make you pay
for what you did, Ertuğrul.
If you weren't a margrave of the state...
I will get out of here anyway.
Let's see what you will do then.
What's wrong, alp?
My Bey, our alps got attacked
while they were taking the governor.
They all became martyrs.
Bastards.
Send alps there right now, brother.
Tell them not to come back
without finding those responsible.
Long story short...
I have not only escaped from Ertuğrul
but also created chaos
within the state of the Seljuks.
See,
Sultan Alaeddin .
He is dead.
The heir Kilicarslan
who was supported by Ertuğrul.
Also dead.
The state of the Seljuks is
in chaos.
And you contributed greatly
for this outcome, Ares.
Our emperor will also notice that.
Now, once Ertuğrul dies,
and once we deal with Sadettin Kopek...
Then, the Turks will cease to exist.
You've done so much, Ares.
Emir Sadettin.
He will be waiting for me
in the caravansary.
But,
instead of me,
you'll go and meet him.
You'll be there as my envoy.
The only thing he wants
is to see Ertuğrul's death.
You'll tell him that I've set a trap
for Ertuğrul, but I want assurance
about Söğüt.
I have no doubt
that you'll do anything
to come to an agreement.
Am I mistaken?
Absolutely not, Kritos.
Leave Sadettin Kopek to me.
You go to Söğüt.
Get rid of Ertuğrul.
I will be in Söğüt
to kill Ertuğrul.
The big day is tomorrow.
Cheers, my friend Ares.
Shit.
Whatever.
We'll toast next time.
I will be waiting for good news
from you.
Me too, Kritos.
I'll be waiting for the best news
from Söğüt.
How could Altun Aba
disobey my orders
and dare to carry out such a massacre?
How could he murder a young man
and a woman, ignoring my orders?
That's not all, my sultan.
The issue is far more critical.
Tell me what you know, Vizier Sadettin.
Unfortunately,
Ertuğrul Bey is, once again,
at the center of events, my Sultan.
What does it have to do
with Ertuğrul Bey, Sadettin?
I guess he was trying to save the Prince
and use him
for the revolt against you, my Sultan.
Altun Aba must have panicked
and killed the prince and his mother,
disobeying your orders.
Altun Aba paid the price
for his crime
which was committed because
of his weakness and disloyalty.
Now, it's Ertuğrul's turn, my Sultan.
You shouldn't turn a blind eye
to this situation.
Douche.
That's right.
Ertuğrul Bey must be punished.
We've had enough.
My Sultan,
the state has become
-restless.
-Enough!
Ertuğrul sent a letter to me, Sadettin.
Did he?
What does he say, my Sultan?
He says
that instead of taking my brother
to Ankara Castle,
Altun Aba tried to strangle him
with a rope,
that Ertuğrul prevented it,
and while he was fleeing,
he stabbed my brother with a dagger
-and then he escaped.
-So, that's how it is.
Yes.
Altun Aba murdered them
not because of Ertuğrul,
but because of his own decision.
And then, he sent my brother's corpse
to the palace with his alps.
And I buried his late mother
in Ankara Castle.
We are all saddened by this loss.
But I wonder,
after all the unfortunate events,
do you still believe Ertuğrul is innocent?
I don't believe it, I know it.
Ertuğrul is loyal to me and the state.
You punished Altun Aba
who killed my brother and his mother.
I hope one day you will understand
that Ertuğrul cannot be trusted,
my Sultan.
Ertuğrul Bey obeyed my father's orders
and fulfilled my wish.
He risked his own life
to take my brother to Ankara Castle.
That's what I believe.
Once he gathers the Turkish tribes
and comes to Konya with his army,
I'd like to see you
still believing the same thing.
It's not your place...
to question my decisions.
I know that the other officials here
think just as I do, my Sultan.
Blessed Vizier is right, my Sultan.
My Sultan,
for the sake of our state,
it'd be better for you
to reconsider your decisions.
It's our duty to obey our Sultan.
We did what we could and warned you.
May God protect you.
My Bey,
we discussed the topic
with the other beys.
We think that it's unnecessary to migrate
as it hasn't been long since we settled.
We have been through so much hardship.
Now...
why are you making a big deal
out of this migration?
My Bey.
We spilled blood and tears and sweat
for these lands.
We think of these lands as our home.
Why would we go to a strange place now?
And the mentioned area
is so close to the heathens.
They will not let us be.
Well, Beys.
Beys.
who could stand against us
once the two tribes are united?
Who could dare to challenge us
while we are one as a fist?
What are you afraid of?
We used to have the state's support.
We were in the state's favor.
Now,
we no longer feel
the support of the state.
We can't live happily there, Turgut Bey.
My Beys,
get yourselves together already.
It's not like us to be afraid
and keep our heads down.
Our path is not one for cowards.
Our late Sultan Alaeddin Keykubat
gave Söğüt to Ertuğrul Bey
so that we can settle there.
Both Ertuğrul Bey
and I
have said our final words.
We will migrate to Söğüt.
Don't make it a matter
of discussion any longer.
Aslıhan.
You've been through so much.
Turgut was going to die
if it wasn't for Ertuğrul Bey.
But we can't give up
just when we experience the difficulties.
Lady Halime,
I am not able to explain the situation.
Or people don't want to understand.
The situation is much tougher than before.
We are talking about Vizier Sadettin
who controls the state from within.
Why doesn't anybody get that?
Cowards die many times
before they actually die.
What we need to do is
to be with our husbands
and to support them.
Sister,
You talk like you don't know
how evil Sadettin is.
Don't you remember his vendetta
against me and Turgut?
Don't worry.
Our husbands will take care of him,
for sure.
Vizier Sadettin is not an enemy
who fights fairly.
That's why it's hard for us to beat him.
He is so relentless that he tried
to poison us in our own tent.
If the evil has a plan,
then God has a thousand plans.
I understand your concerns.
But if you insist on this attitude,
it won't be good for the sake
of both our tribes.
Mother, did you have anything
to do with the killing...
of the prince and his mother?
Apparently, Altun Aba went too far.
And Vizier Sadettin did
what was necessary.
May God forgive their sins.
I asked you a question.
Answer me, Mother.
Did you do anything?
Do you know what would have happened
if Ertuğrul had saved Kilicarslan,
my Sultan?
I have my army
and the officials of the state with me.
Didn't you say that, Mother?
I did.
But you know Vizier Sadettin's influence
on the officials of the state.
And, the Turks are about to revolt.
It's just a matter of time
before they cause a new headache.
Don't you think that would put our state
in a tough situation, son?
Answer my question, Mother.
Did you have anything to do
with the killings?
I'd consider myself a failed mother
if I hadn't.
If...
you weren't my mother...
I'd kill you right here.
And I wouldn't even hesitate.
I am okay to die
at your hands, son.
Do you think I'd care?
I believe I did what was necessary.
I don't care about dying.
Do you still think
that Sadettin killed Altun Aba
because of his loyalty, mother?
Don't you see you've thrown me
into a difficult position?
I did what I could to ensure your rule.
Now I don't care if I die.
What about Sadettin?
What about him?
You three made me the sultan.
He killed Altun Aba.
Now there is only you.
And you are keeping me locked
in my chambers.
If you are afraid of him,
let me out of my cage.
So that I can keep him under control.
Do you still believe
that he'd be loyal to me?
How can I even be sure of your loyalty?
Why would you not be sure
of my loyalty, my Sultan?
You are my son.
As for Sadettin,
he wants to keep you in power.
Just like everyone else.
He wants to be more powerful.
He wants to be your right hand.
What you should do is control him.
But he is controlling me, mother.
He is playing with me.
Thanks to you, the army and the officials
of the state deeply respect him.
Don't you see that?
You'll do what is necessary
if he goes too far.
You have to get used to the dirty games
of ruling.
Know that I'm on your side until I die.
I will be praying for you
to do the right thing.
Ertuğrul.
Günalp is a dangerous man.
He went too far as soon as he arrived.
If it wasn't for you,
he was going to execute our alps and beys.
Günalp has good intentions
and he is loyal to the state.
But his judgment is clouded.
He is under the spell of Sadettin.
I intend to break that spell
and open his eyes.
Ertuğrul.
I know you calculate your moves.
But for God's sake,
please be careful.
And...
Lady Aslıhan is skeptical
about migrating to Söğüt.
Lady Aslıhan is loyal to us.
She is a brave woman.
Why is she skeptical?
She is afraid
of Vizier Sadettin's capabilities.
She thinks
now that he is even more powerful,
he can do more to harm us.
She wants everyone to be safe.
She has been through so much.
I understand that.
It's her duty to think about her tribe.
But she needs to let go of those fears.
And we should help her
to overcome her fears.
I'll talk to Lady Aslıhan.
That would be great, my Bey.
Why are you here?
We are here to take you.
To where?
You'll see.
Alps, calm down.
Calm down.
How can you treat a kaledar
of the state like a traitor?
Huh?
I came here of my own will.
Learn some manners.
Günalp Bey,
You will see where you are going
when you get there.
Now, don't make it hard for us.
Damn you, Ertuğrul!
What happened, blessed Vizier?
The letter is from Günalp's aide Aydogmus.
He says Ertuğrul stopped the negotiations,
took the Governor to execute him
in his tribe,
and put Günalp in a dungeon.
Let's send some troops
to Karacahisar Castle
and bury Ertuğrul there.
The Governor will take care of that.
Is he still alive?
Ertuğrul's alps were ambushed
while taking the Governor,
and Kritos managed to escape.
Alright.
After this incident,
the Sultan won't let Ertuğrul
remain as the Margrave.
What if our Sultan
still supports Ertuğrul,
what will you do, blessed Vizier?
Send word to the viziers
and the commanders of the army.
Let them know
that the crucial interests
of the state are at stake
because of the stupidity of a sultan.
I'll have a meeting with them tonight.
We will release Ertuğrul
from his duties.
Then, I will go
to the caravansary
to discuss the fate of demoted Ertuğrul
with the governor Kritos.
As you order, blessed Vizier.
Sultan Alaeddin Keykubat
entrusted Söğüt to us.
Söğüt is a gate to a new opportunity
for us
to conquer new lands
and to fight for our cause and the state.
Some wise man said
a rolling stone gathers no moss.
I'd prefer to be rolling
rather than have a sedentary lifestyle.
From now on,
no matter where the place is,
we'll be fighting for our cause
and conquering new lands.
It's better to keep moving
than to stay in the same place.
I hope our new home
brings new joys.
Hopefully so.
-Hopefully so.
What do you think, Lady Aslıhan?
My Bey, I have some concerns.
Let us know what they are.
You know best how evil Vizier Sadettin is.
Unfortunately, he has the state
within his grasp.
I'm afraid he'll be even more cruel to us.
And, this degenerate man
killed our glorious Sultan,
he can do much worse to us.
Lady Aslıhan.
Vizier Sadettin has set so many traps
up till now.
But with God's permission,
we destroyed all his traps.
Each trap of his
brought us even closer to each other.
They made us even more powerful.
You know,
we have an important purpose.
We can't be successful
with fear in our hearts.
On the contrary,
the bigger the trouble is,
the greater the courage should be.
It's the only way to be successful.
Now, I'm asking you...
What would Aliyar Bey do...
if he was here?
My Bey, you have a point,
but what about the beys of Cavdar?
They are against this decision.
I don't want my tribe to be divided.
Lady Aslıhan.
I left my own brothers to pursue the cause
I believed to be right.
My tribe was also divided.
Yet, you see
now I am the Margrave.
We've become a hope for the oppressed
and an instrument of the state.
Regardless of the pains we endured,
it's obvious that it was the right choice.
You shouldn't be afraid.
Our path is clear.
And it's a tough one.
That's why
those who will possibly turn back
shouldn't be on the road
in the first place.
What we need is people
who are not afraid,
and who have a greater vision.
Tell me what happened.
I'd like you to know
that I've protected the reputation
of you and our Sultan
by killing Altun Aba.
So, is this great state not able
to deal with that bastard, Ertuğrul?
It is, Lady Mahperi.
Ertuğrul needs to be relieved of
his duties as the margrave,
because of his actions against Günalp
and governor Kritos.
I'll do what's necessary.
You do what you can, too.
So that
we prevent Ertuğrul
from using our Sultan
against us like a sword.
I'll talk to the Sultan.
Alright.
Tomorrow, I'll meet with Kritos
in the caravansary.
I have no doubts he will do all he can
to get rid of Ertuğrul.
Can you guarantee
that once our Sultan is away,
Governor Kritos won't try to conquer
the Karacahisar Castle,
Vizier Sadettin?
We can't know for sure
whether he'll try to humiliate the Sultan
who was recently enthroned.
Don't worry, Lady Mahperi.
I'll have a spy in his circle,
who will inform me
of every step he takes.
That should do it.
If the Governor intends
to humiliate our Sultan,
I'll know.
Very well.
Excuse me.
You'll die with Ertuğrul, Kopek.
I won't let you devour my son.
My Bey,
I might have upset you
because of this migration issue.
You know, I have no one but you.
I was afraid
to lose you and to divide our tribe.
I know, Aslıhan.
I know.
I don't have anyone but you either.
But don't you worry.
I think about the tribe more than you do.
Hopefully,
we will be happier in Söğüt
than we are here.
The migration will be good for our tribe.
You are my husband.
I lost my mother,
father,
and brother, Turgut.
When I saw you on the gallows,
it was excruciating for me.
I couldn't even breathe.
I felt like I was alone in the world.
My Bey,
that was too excruciating for me.
Don't worry anymore.
Justice has prevailed.
I'm by your side, now.
And I will always be.
When I think about anything,
I consider both our positions.
It's the same with the migration issue.
Don't you worry.
The Governor of Bilecik
will be waiting to ambush us.
There will be many of them.
We must all stay sharp.
Remember,
our first mission is
to clear the passage from the infidels
and then proceed with the migration.
Bamsi.
Are the alps, horses,
and the swords ready?
The alps are strong, the swords are sharp
and the horses are fast, my Bey.
Very well.
You will secretly follow the Governor
and ambush him with the alps, Bamsi.
As you order, my Bey.
Brother Sungur.
Turgut.
You'll be fighting close
to me and Günalp Bey.
As you order, my Bey.
Abdurrahman.
You'll stay in the tribe.
As you order, my Bey.
Our next target is...
Sadettin Kopek.
Sadettin Kopek will die.
We will destroy him and his gang,
and save the state from their grasp.
We will wait for the right moment
and finish him.
What about the Sultan?
Sultan Giyaseddin is a smart man
and he can foresee what future problems
he might face.
We will help the Sultan,
and he will help us
once Sadettin Kopek
corners him with his gang.
And,
we will get rid of Sadettin.
What about his mother, Lady Mahperi?
Well, it's Sultan Giyaseddin's issue
and he will take care of her.
Brave men.
The road we will be on tomorrow
is much longer and tougher than any roads
we've ever taken.
We either save the Seljuks
on this road...
or
we will sow
the first seeds of a new, holy state.
It's either extinction...
or resurrection.
Our cause is a cause
that might need any kind of sacrifice.
We'd die for your cause, my Bey.
I appreciate it.
Much appreciated.
May God help us.
Amen.
Now...
bring Günalp Bey to me.
Who are you?
I'm representing Vizier Sadettin,
the only person who can get you out.
What do you want?
If you are not pregnant,
Artuk Bey will kill you.
If you are pregnant...
he will kill you anyway
once the child is born.
Your fate is obvious, you'll die.
Poor girl.
But if you make an alliance with us...
you can get out of here,
and you can get rich.
What do you want me to do?
We want you to be our spy.
You'll get 100 gold pieces
for any information you provide.
Information about what?
Where do you want me
to gather information from?
From the Governor of Bilecik.
I'll do what you want.
Just get me out of here.
I knew you were a smart woman, Marya.
Be patient.
Vizier Sadettin will get you out of here.
Please send my regards
to Vizier Sadettin.
You wouldn't dare kill me
in front of my soldiers
so you brought me to your pavilion,
Ertuğrul Bey?
I didn't call you here to kill you,
but to make you realize the truth
that you've been blind to.
What do you mean?
You're my guest.
We know how to take care of a guest.
Like how you took care of Tekfur Kritos?
Tekfur Kritos managed to get away from me.
But Söğüt is mine.
I want to talk to you
about the new place that Kayıs
will immigrate to.
Söğüt will be Kayıs' castle.
Since you're my lord in command,
I'd like to make use of your good ideas.
Are you ready for you first duty under
my command, Günalp Bey?
What are you after, Ertuğrul Bey?
You should know that I'm always after
God's path.
Let's see if you are, too.
We'll see about that tomorrow.
Our state won't be at peace while our
Sultan is following Ertuğrul
just like his late father did.
What will you do, Sadettin?
Kemalettin Kamyar, Kayır Han,
Hüsamettin Kamyeri are restless,
angry with us.
They've got a very powerful army.
We still haven't managed to provide
stability in our state.
These Emirs are committed
to the state first.
After Şehzade Kılıçarslan's death,
they won't even dare make a move.
We'll keep them on duty outside of Konya.
But first, tomorrow we'll come together
in Sultan's presence
and take Ertuğrul's Beylic away from him.
It's time to teach the limits to this
naive Sultan who
did horrible deeds even to his own mother.
Otherwise,
all of our positions would be
threatened.
If this continues, Kayıs will start ruling
the palace, not Emirs.
I'm afraid Kayıs' and Ertuğrul's reign
will be the end of us.
We won't let this happen.
So,
how will we manage to save the Sultan
from his own ignorance?
Our Sultan wants to
come back with a victory from
his Amid campaign
that his father left unfinished
to prove his monarchy.
But he'll learn that he's got nothing...
...if he doesn't have us.
Taceddin Pervane...
...what do you think?
You thought of it very well,
Emir Sadettin.
First we have to finish Ertuğrul off.
Tomorrow we'll put the Sultan
in his place.
He'll learn about the supreme
interests of the state.
Yes, he will.
Good.
So tomorrow,
we'll put the Sultan in his place,
and dig Ertuğrul's grave.
-My Halime.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul.
Thank you, my Halime.
I've got things to tell you.
Tell me, Bey.
Tomorrow, with God's help, we will
start the battle for our new home.
If we clean the way before we start
the immigration,
it'll be better for us.
I'd like to get your blessings before
I leave.
Give me your blessings, my Halime.
I give you my blessings.
Give me your blessings too.
May your sword stay intact.
May your horse never stumble.
God willing, my Halime.
God willing.
Why are we immigrating to Söğüt, father?
Because it was given to us as
our home, son.
If we don't, the heathens will get it.
We can't give our home
to heathens, father.
Of course not.
Let me tell you a saga of our ancestors.
Come here.
Once upon a time, Turks
lived in a place called Kamlançu
where it was surrounded by brooks.
Turks sent armies all over.
Everyone obeyed them.
They had a huge rock at their home.
They called this rock The Holy Mountain.
After five generations, one day
a Khan came to the throne.
This Khan married a Chinese princess.
Chinese intented to trick this Khan
through this princess and weaken
the Turks.
So one day, the Chinese got together.
They said, "The amity and
the power of the Turks
comes from a rock that's called
The Holy Mountain."
So they asked for this rock from the Khan.
Khan gave it to them without hesitation.
Chinese took the rock,
broke it into pieces and took it home.
After that day, Turks started to go
through some disasters.
The brooks dried out.
The trees died.
A famine took over the Turks' home.
The impulsive Khan died within seven days.
His successors died quickly as well.
Under these circumstances, Turks
woke up one day, hearing the words
of "immigration".
They realized all the animals, trees
and mountains were whimpering
the word "immigration".
Turks started to immigrate by listening
to these divine sounds.
Until they got their amity and
power back.
Have we been immigrating
since that day as well, father?
Yes, son.
We've been immigrating since that day.
I hope our amity continues in our
new home, father.
I hope so, son.
I hope so.
But you should learn from the saga.
If you give a piece of rock
to your enemy, let alone your home,
disasters will follow us.
We won't leave Söğüt to the enemy.
We'll immigrate and get our amity
and power back, if God permits.
I hope so, father.
When I grow up, I want to go to China
and take that rock back.
I'll take my brothers with you.
Praise be!
Let's wait for your new sibling to arrive.
All of you together will revive our tribe,
if God permits.
God willing.
Come on, go to bed.
Aslıhan Hatun,
we've been talking about the immigration
matter with Beys.
Everyone is on the same page with us.
No one wants to move the village
to Söğüt.
You're Candar Bey's daughter.
You're the Hatun of Çavdar Tribe.
You wanted to marry Turgut Bey,
we were okay with it.
You wanted to make him the Bey,
But we're not okay with immigrating.
According to traditions, Beys can't decide
by themselves.
If the other Beys say no,
this can't happen.
My Beys,
we are under Ertuğrul Bey's reign now.
We joined our villages.
He is our frontiersman.
Would Ertuğrul Bey take his own people
if this immigration wasn't beneficial
and necessary?
That's not our business, Aslıhan Hatun.
If Ertuğrul Bey thinks this is the right
thing to do for
his people, he can take them away.
But this is our decision.
You can go with your Bey, if you wish.
We'll stay here as Çavdars.
Giddy up!
My Ahmet...
There are important things
that you need to know about.
Tell me.
Who's this man, Sungur Bey?
He's a friend of Ertuğrul Bey.
Tekfur Kritos
will be waiting at Söğüt,
just as you predicted.
He's determined to get his son's revenge.
He'll bring along a lot of men.
The horse that Titan brought with him
and Hell Warriors will be there as well.
They'll learn their lesson today, Ahmet.
My Bey, there's more to it.
I'd like to be by your side
and make them
spit blood during this ambush.
However, Tekfur Kritos assigned me
a very important duty.
What is this duty?
Emir Sadettin and Tekfur Kritos agreed to
meet at the caravansary.
They want to co-operate to kill you.
Tekfur Kritos,
wants me to meet Emir Sadettin
as his messenger.
My Bey, if you'd like...
...if you'd let me
I'd like to kill Emir Sadettin.
If you win Sadettin's trust
we'd know about the games both
the Emperor and Sadettin play.
You're right, Bey.
Ahmet.
The grudge Emir Sadettin
holds against you is enormous.
Be cautious.
Don't you worry, Bey.
I'll take care of myself.
May God help you.
Thank you, Bey.
Godspeed, my brave man.
Hey!
Sultan Gıyaseddin Keyhüsrev.
Are the preparations for Amid campaign
ready, Cemaleddin?
Our army is ready.
However, we are all worried, my Sultan.
Why do you worry?
As if the Mongolians weren't enough,
now we have to deal with Ertuğrul,
my Sultan.
Emir Sadettin,
I don't want to hear one more word
about Ertuğrul.
Do I need to repeat myself?
My Sultan.
There have been some gossips in Konya
about Ertuğrul Bey.
What are they saying?
They say you...
...worked together with Ertuğrul Bey
to kill your father.
What did you say?
My Sultan...
...getting angry at Georgian Zahireddin
won't solve this matter.
Everyone in this council knows that
you have no such
evil in your heart.
Where are you going with this?
There are no more words to say, my Sultan.
Once again, Ertuğrul Bey caused
a lot of trouble for us.
Tell me.
Ertuğrul rejected the peace treaty that
we were going to sign with Tekfur Kritos.
As if this wasn't enough,
he attempted to murder Tekfur Kritos.
Moreover, he's keeping Günalp Bey
imprisoned.
Why would he do that?
He's getting ready for a revolt against
your reign, my Sultan.
My Sultan, Emir Sadettin is right.
Ertuğrul Bey must be stopped.
This won't end well, my Sultan.
All things considered,
it's not possible to come back with
a victory from the Amid campaign.
My Sultan, we're all worried about you
going on the Amid campaign
with your army, since a troublemaker
like Ertuğrul Bey
is making a fuss on our western borders.
Do you want me to decapitate
Ertuğrul Bey who I trust completely?
No.
I know, my Sultan.
The Amid campaign is
very important for you.
This campaign is
very important to prove to the people
that you are a great Sultan.
But we as the council, don't think
it's right to go on Amid campaign
when we have a troublemaker
like Ertuğrul Bey.
So what do you want from me?
Seems like Ertuğrul Bey
doesn't want to give Söğüt that was
assigned as home
by our late Sultan to anyone else.
Fine.
So he can keep Söğüt as home.
Let him serve our government from there.
Let him cheer us up with his conquests.
Let him be the shield for
the threats against our state.
So we can know that the brave Ertuğrul Bey
is protecting our state
as the shield of our western borders.
But not as a frontiersman.
His existence as a frontiersman is
a threat to our state.
Under these circumstances,
we'd like you to take away
his position
and assign Günalp Bey instead.
When you seal the order that I prepared
we'll be ready to go on the Amid campaign
for you.
Sir...
...following your advice...
I'm trying to get to know our Prophet
better and
as I get to know him,
I love this holy man even more.
However,
there are things that
I'm still curious about.
I'd like to ask you if you let me.
Go ahead, son.
Sir.
What is...
...Islam?
Islam means devotion, son.
What matter is to submit to God...
...and to lead a life what God wants
and mortify the flesh.
To make our Prophet Muhammad Mustafa
your guide.
Islam is the only religion that covers
all the monotheistic religions, son.
Almighty God commands in Quran,
"The only religion in the eyes of God
is Islam."
In another verse, he commands
"Today, I made your religion perfect,
I completed my blessing for you
and I chose Islam as your religion."
Thank God...
...for letting me follow
such a holy religion.
Amen.
May God let me live
this religion properly.
Amen, son.
So, sir...
What am I supposed to do...
...to be a good Muslim?
You must be a reliable person.
Our Prophet commands,
"A Muslim is a person who makes people
trust himself by what he says and does."
He made an example by living this life.
That holy person was so reliable that
even polytheists would entrust their
valuables to him.
Before our Prophet immigrated with
Ebubekir, he had some valuables
that he was entrusted with.
Do you know whose valuables
were they, son?
Of those polytheists
who tried to murder him.
And before our Prophet immigrated
he designated Ali to
to deliver their valuables.
Imagine a community
who attempts to murder a man
but also entrust their valuables
to only this man.
That's what...
...being trustworthy means.
There's so much wisdom in this.
We have to follow our Prophet's example
in every case.
We should act like he did as much as
we can.
Only then we can be a good Muslim.
If we start something with a good
intention and make an effort,
God will make up for it.
I'm so lucky to be among the people
of such a holy man.
May God let me become one of the
people who try.
Amen.
Sir.
Ertuğrul Bey has given me
an important duty.
Maybe at the end of the journey
that I'm on, comes death.
So, before I go on my way...
...I want you to pray for me.
Good faith will follow someone who
has good intentions.
God will be by your side on your
holy case.
Our prayer are always with you
and those who fight for God's cause.
Thank you, sir.
Godspeed and good luck, son.
Praise be!
I have never seen such fertile lands, Bey.
You kept your promise, Ertuğrul Bey.
If Gündoğdu was here today,
he'd be so proud of you.
I hope we'll see that day, brother.
I hope Gündoğdu brother and you
will immigrate here as well.
When I get back, I'll talk about this
with Gündoğdu Bey.
Because I agree with you.
What do you think, Günalp Bey?
Good lands.
A village could live here
and herds would be fed.
However it's right by the heathens.
You'll be too busy fighting.
Especially Tekfur Kritos can't stand
the fact that you'll live here.
You killed his son.
You destroyed his reputation
at the castle.
He'll do anything to get his revenge.
That's fine.
We're here to see that happen.
I wanted you to see personally
that Emir Sadettin who you trust so much
and his men are trying to sign
a peace treaty with this kind of a man.
What does that mean?
Tekfur Kritos
and Emir Sadettin are allies.
However,
this alliance is not about peace,
but about betrayal to the state.
Be careful about what you say.
You'll see soon how bad of a betrayal...
...we're about to face and how
unaware you were, Günalp Bey.
Come on.
Kayıs entered the valley, sir.
How many are there?
Not much.
Ertuğrul Bey and about ten Alps.
Easy catch.
It's the best place for the pasture.
They'd like to feed their herds.
They'll only feed the coyotes and ravens
with their dead bodies.
Leon.
Get back to the castle.
Get back and protect it.
Yes, sir.
It's time for revenge.
Are you ready to kill the Turks?
We're ready! Blood, blood, blood!
Revenge, revenge, revenge!
Let's go!
Sadettin convinced Atabey Altun Aba
after he convinced the Sultan.
He and the Emirs close to him threatened
the Sultan with preventing his campaign.
Sadettin's intention is
to kill Ertuğrul and remove the obstacles
in front of him one by one.
I'm afraid after Ertuğrul dies,
he'll also kill our Sultan.
And you'll be the only obstacle left.
I worry that he'll kill you too.
There's nothing to worry about,
Taceddin Pervane.
That's the reality.
You and I are
the next targets of Sadettin.
What we have to do is take measures.
You have to stop him, Taceddin Pervane.
How?
How will I do this?
You have to do this for
the soundness of our state and
my son's reign.
You'll kill Sadettin Köpek!
Send your men after him right away.
He'll go to the caravansary
to meet Tekfur Kritos.
This should end here.
We can't tolerate it anymore.
What about Ertuğrul?
His time will come too.
But first, Sadettin must die.
I know Emir Sadettin is
like a father to you.
That's why you think he never puts
a foot wrong.
He did everything he could to assign
you as a frontiersman here.
For now, I could stop him.
But I know that...
...he won't give up.
He'll convince our Sultan to take away
my Beylic
with any threat he can come up with.
You don't know Emir Sadettin,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Even if you were right, he has no reason
to do this.
You disobeyed the state's order
by breaking the peace treaty.
You'll cause the end of your Beylic
yourself.
Give up when it's early on.
Today, he's asking for the beautiful
land given to us by Sultan Alaeddin.
He wants Söğüt.
We know what he'll ask for tomorrow.
What?
If I hand Söğüt over
in the negotiations today,
he'll appoint you tomorrow
to rule over the lands I've conquered.
His next goal is to see me dead.
Your rage blinds you, Ertuğrul Bey.
My rage sharpens my mind, Günalp Bey.
But blind loyalty
is the truth's greatest enemy.
Father!
Mother!
Father! No, don't leave me!
Don't come any closer!
Are you Günalp,
son of the castle governor, Tayi Bey?
Murderer! You killed my father!
I said, stay there.
Your father, my brave friend Tayi Bey,
was my blood brother.
He was my comrade.
It was the War of the Princes
that killed him, not me.
Just like your father did,
I fight for Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad, Son.
It will be my duty to avenge
your brave mother and father.
Your mother...
your father...
and these soldiers will be avenged.
I'll end this damn War of Princes.
I'll make you an honorable soldier
and castle governor,
just like your father.
When the time comes, you'll serve
Sultan Alaeddin and our country
just like us.
-The scum set up an ambush.
-They're the ones being ambushed.
Time to show us your skills.
Come on then, you dog!
The preparations outside
are complete, Eminence.
Good.
Where is this governor?
He should be here by now.
It's good to see you again,
Sadettin Köpek.
Ares!
Say the word
and I'll take this bastard's head!
Stop.
He's mine.
What are you doing here?
Governor Kritos.
I carry a message from him, Sadettin.
Once again...
we are united against Ertuğrul.
How did this governor come to send you?
Does he not know
what you did and how you cheated me?
I saved his life.
Ertuğrul was going to execute him.
And I saved his life.
He trusts me. And so he sent me here.
Look, I came unarmed.
I have no weapons on me, Sadettin.
My faith in you brought me here.
It would do you well to trust me.
Welcome.
Since you came here yourself, unafraid,
you'll be prepared to pay
for what you've done.
Kill them! Kill all of them!
Leave Ertuğrul to me.
I want to be the one who takes his head.
For God!
Where did they come from?
Ambush! We've been ambushed!
Thanks, Günalp Bey.
Protect me! Protect me now!
Attack! Attack!
Lead the way. We're not done with you.
Wait, Sadettin, listen to me.
Ertuğrul has moved his tribe to Söğüt.
Kritos is preparing to ambush him.
Kritos sent me here
to sign the Söğüt Treaty with you.
We can destroy Ertuğrul together.
To hell with Ertuğrul!
You humiliated me
in front of the entire court!
I was dismissed because of you.
My favorite servant, Göktuğ,
died because of you.
You thought I would
forgive you for all this?
Sadettin, Sadettin. What should I do?
Should I list everything you did?
We must forget the past and cooperate.
Listen to me.
Kritos went to ambush Ertuğrul,
but he has no chance of succeeding.
I lost everything because of Ertuğrul.
Everything.
We have to work together
if we're to destroy Ertuğrul,
and anyone who comes after him.
Hell's Warriors,
they answer to me now.
So, you hate Ertuğrul.
And you came here to make an alliance.
Ertuğrul might have forgiven you.
So might Alaeddin.
But I will not.
Now, you won't get what you hoped for...
but you'll get what you deserve.
Time for you to die, Ares.
Eminence!
Come on, Günalp Bey.
Know the devil you've to make peace with.
-Any martyrs, Dumrul?
-No, thank God, my bey.
Good.
Treat the wounded.
Send the critical ones to the castle.
As you wish, my bey.
I knew you wanted revenge, Kritos.
You might have captured me today,
but the ones that will follow
will avenge me.
Tell me the terms
of your collaboration with Emir Sadettin.
That is a peace treaty
between two states, Ertuğrul Bey.
I won't stand here and listen
to pompous nonsense from a dog like you!
Tell me,
why would a state consider giving
another state land as important as Söğüt?
Tell me!
What did Emir Sadettin want in return?
Was it my head?
Did he want my head? Tell me!
Both Emir Sadettin and I want nothing more
than to see you dead, Ertuğrul Bey.
Because you really do deserve to die.
What about you, Kritos?
Emir Sadettin wouldn't give Söğüt
to secure the peace,
but he would give it to secure your death.
You're only lying about His Eminence
because your life is being threatened.
You know...
what will happen
when we settle on these lands, Kritos.
Make him kneel.
It doesn't matter who comes,
Söğüt will be Turkish land!
Homeland of the Kayis!
Günalp Bey,
you heard what Emir Sadettin
has been doing with your own ears.
Now listen to me, both of you.
Söğüt is mine by right
and belongs to my tribe!
No one can take it from us!
We'll settle here and set down roots.
Our children will grow up here.
Now... if you agree to peace on my terms,
I'll let you live, Kritos.
Otherwise, I'll hang your head
from the walls of your castle in Bilecik.
Dumrul.
Take the governor.
We'll return to the castle.
Anything to say, Günalp Bey?
I have no words to say
against your bravery.
But don't expect me
to believe what I just heard.
So, you plotted against me?
I didn't do it, Sadettin.
Who sent you here?
Speak!
You asked for me, my Sultan?
You made me Emir Sadettin's puppet.
You killed my father to make me Sultan.
And now?
The wretch you conspired with
has made me a prisoner in my own palace.
I even needed his permission to go to war.
If we don't kill Emir Sadettin,
he'll kill us.
How so, Mother?
How so?
When my father was dying
in the Kayqubadiyah Palace,
his trusted emirs,
commanders, followers,
were all gone.
They were too scared
to attend my coronation.
I'm completely alone in this palace.
Can't you see that?
Ertuğrul Bey was right.
You asked me for the truth
and I gave it to you.
I tell the truth.
You can kill me
or you can search for the truth.
You decide.
But if you're careless,
just like our sultan was
once upon a time,
our country will suffer.
Your carelessness will surrender
the country first to Mahperi Hatun
and Altun Aba, and then to Sadettin.
You think you're the state,
but suddenly you'll be nothing.
You'll be nothing more than a paper sultan
who conspired with his father's killers.
A paper sultan.
Köpek will die, Son.
What?
Taceddin Pervane will kill him.
He sent his best men.
He will die.
What if he can't do it, Mother? What then?
Then I'll admit
I threw you to the wolves, Son.
I'll kill him for you myself,
if necessary.
Who are you, dog? Tell me!
I know this man.
He works for Emir Taceddin.
Emir Taceddin?
Emir Taceddin!
So, Mahperi Hatun conspired
with Emir Taceddin to kill me.
What will we do, Eminence?
We'll show them how a conspiracy is done.
My name is Sadettin Köpek.
Nobody conspires against me.
Now we know who set the trap.
If I'd wanted to hurt you I would hardly
have stopped him from killing you.
You still don't trust me, Köpek?
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
They don't look like your men, Günalp Bey.
You're right, Ertuğrul Bey.
They're not my men.
What's wrong, Artuk Bey?
Who are they?
They come from Konya, Ertuğrul Bey.
The Sultan has issued a decree.
What decree, Aydoğmus?
Courier, read it.
By order of His Highness,
Sultan Gıyaseddin Keyhusrev,
Karacahisar Castle
and authority as frontier bey
will be taken from Ertuğrul Bey.
The new master of Karacahisar Castle
and the new frontier bey
will be Günalp Bey.
What did you say?
Artuk Bey. My bey.
What is this man saying?
What do you think you're saying?
Nobody can take the frontier bey position
from us. That decree is a lie!
Here is our Sultan's seal. See?
We won't give up the castle that easily.
Those who voice
the slightest opposition to the decree
will be hanged as traitors
against the Sultan.
Günalp Bey!
Günalp Bey! You knew about this.
You knew about it all along.
But know that you won't get away with it.
Calm down, Bamsi Alp.
I only just learned of it, just like you.
Bamsi.
He has nothing to do with this.
So who does, my bey?
Emir Sadettin Köpek.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net