episode 103 start after 12:40 min.
Aslıhan Hatun, now that we have
cleared your tribe of its traitors,
you should stay with the Kayis,
with my mother and Halime Sultan.
Tell them,
the Cavdar tribe is free of traitors
and that we're heading off to war.
And tell Artuk Bey to send the alps
still at the tribe to the siege.
Yes, Ertuğrul Bey.
Blessed be your holy war.
-Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Amen.
Come on then, Turgut Bey.
Sir, there's still no word from Titan.
I'm concerned.
Titan is a great knight, Kostas.
He fulfils his duties thoroughly.
Nothing can save Ertuğrul from him.
He'll probably return here at night
to avoid making the secret passage known,
I expect word of his victory
will come soon.
We all keenly await
that blessed word, sir.
Still, we should be cautious, Kostas.
Don't forget, this castle
is the beating heart of Karacahisar.
If any harm comes to the castle,
Karacahisar falls.
Double the number of men on the walls.
And reinforce the doors with iron bolts.
Yes, sir.
Marya...
Why have you left your room?
The doctor said you were to rest.
Don't worry, sir. My wound has healed.
I feel much better.
I pray for you constantly.
I pray that your efforts
are rewarded with victory.
Don't worry Marya, victory will be ours.
Ertuğrul's death is imminent.
That barbaric Turk,
who wounded you and attacked my castle,
will get what he deserves.
Ertuğrul will die today.
How so?
As they say in Latin,
Auribus teneo lupum.
Ertuğrul heads into a storm, Marya.
A storm so fierce that
both the margrave
and the Turk tribes will be shattered.
Then you'll see how.
Now, go to your room and rest.
Tonight, I celebrate my victory with you.
Get ready.
As soon as they get off their horses,
we'll take them down.
They found the passage! To the horses!
Now!
God is alive!
God is infinite! God is great!
God is infinite!
Bastard!
Follow him!
Don't let him reach the castle,
dead or alive! Now!
Let's capture this castle first.
If that arrow doesn't kill you...
you will yet come to your death
by our hands.
There.
You go that way.
Take that side.
You bastard! I'll kill you!
I have to get to the castle!
I have to get the secret passage closed.
I can't believe what that snake did
while we are at war!
Ertuğrul Bey is bound to take his head!
Let's pray he hasn't hurt
Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp.
Daughter! Daughter.
Ertuğrul will get there,
he will save them and the Cavdar tribe.
There is nothing we can do but pray.
You're right, Mother.
May I enter, Hayme Hatun?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
Aslıhan Hatun?
-Aslıhan.
-Thank God.
Thank you, Hafsa Hatun.
-Aslıhan.
-Sister!
-Welcome!
-Thank you.
-Are you all right?
-I am, thank you.
Mother Hayme.
Welcome, my girl.
Thank you.
-You are unhurt?
-I am, Mother Hayme.
Turgut, too?
Turgut is fine, don't worry.
The tribe? What happened?
My tribe is free of traitors
and has been saved.
-Good, thank God.
-Thank God.
Aslıhan Hatun, I will thank God
a thousand times
that you have survived this misfortune.
Thank you, Halime Hatun.
Ertuğrul Bey was a godsend.
May God bless him.
God willing, we will see good days
now that these evil ones have passed.
-God willing.
God willing.
Ertuğrul Bey and the alps are riding
to Karacahisar Castle.
Artuk Bey, Ertuğrul Bey commands you
to send the tribes' alps to the siege.
As he commands.
That means...
there will be more work
for us to do in the tribe.
-Hafsa, daughter.
-Yes, Mother Hayme?
Send word to the women.
Tell them come to the tent.
I have new duties to give them
to keep the tribe secure and in order.
Your wish is my command.
I'll send the alps to the siege then.
-Excuse me, Hayme Hatun.
-You're excused, Artuk Bey.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you, Atsiz.
I hope you have good news.
The traitors got
what they asked for, Atsiz.
-Bahadir and his son paid their dues.
-Very good, Ertuğrul Bey.
While we were waiting for you
Titan and three of his men appeared.
We ambushed them.
Titan ran. But I hit him with an arrow.
My duty was to stay here
so I didn't chase him.
But I sent two alps after him,
just in case.
Well done, Atsiz.
When the castle falls,
their heads will fall, too.
God willing.
We found the secret passage, thank God.
Now we hunt our prey in his cage.
Turgut, send word to the beys
who are holding the gates.
No man is to leave his post
until we plant our flag.
-Tell them to keep their eyes open.
-As you command, my Bey.
This passage is Ares'
only way out of the castle.
They'll only use it at night.
Titan would have done the same
if he hadn't been ambushed.
Ares won't expect him until nightfall.
What do we do, my Bey?
Ares is hoping to hear
news of my death from Titan.
We'll convince them
that I am indeed dead.
First, we send word
to the castle that I've been killed.
But Bey,
if all the gates are closed,
how will we do that?
We'll find a way,
Turgut, we'll find a way.
My Bey,
When we came across Titan,
he was carrying this pigeon cage.
Good, Atsiz.
Sisters!
Our beys and alps have gone to the siege.
From now on...
we are responsible
for training and sentry duties.
As you command, Mother Hayme!
Drills and training will be led by
Halime Hatun and Aslıhan Hatun.
-Yes, Mother.
-As you command, Mother Hayme!
You must pay particular attention
to the younger girls.
Remember, as the twig is bent,
so grows the tree.
Hafsa Hatun will be in charge
of the rug house, ointments and food.
-Keep me fully informed.
-As you wish, Mother Hayme.
Saray Hatun.
You are in charge of the women
who take on sentry duty.
Pick some of the younger, alert women.
Check on them day and night
and keep me posted.
As you command, Mother Hayme!
Sisters, our tribe and our families
are entrusted first to God,
and then to us.
Until the battle is over...
keep your sword
by your side day and night.
Come on, now. See to your duties.
As you command, Mother Hayme!
If that's the way Titan sends messages,
then we'll do the same.
Send Ares a message as if from Titan.
Tell him Ertuğrul and his alps
were killed in the ambush,
and that he'll sneak back into the castle
after finding out what's
happening at the Cavdar tribe.
Leave it to me, my Bey.
After you've sent it, tell the alps
surrounding the castle to withdraw.
Once he sees that,
Ares will think he's won
and will be careless.
And we'll disguise ourselves as Titan and
his soldiers and sneak into the castle.
Ares is in the inner castle,
the heart of Karacahisar.
We attack the inner castle first.
Once we've captured it,
Karacahisar Castle will fall.
We'll have to kill the soldiers
guarding the passage first.
But we must be quiet,
so the soldiers at the other
end don't hear us.
If they do, they'll close the passage
on the Karacahisar side.
My Bey, I can't wait to see Ares' face
when he finds out you're not dead,
but living flesh and blood.
We'll all enjoy seeing his face
when we get there, Bamsi.
God willing, my Bey. God willing.
When we're in, we need
to dispose of the archers first.
-That's up to you, Bamsi.
-As you command, my Bey.
May God open the way for our conquest
and help us turn these lands into heaven!
Amen!
Bamsi, leave some of your best alps here.
They need to keep watch over the passage.
We'll go with the rest of the alps
and pray that God
clears a path to our victory.
As you command, my Bey.
Come on.
Sir, the soldiers are eager
for news from Titan.
With Ertuğrul dead, the need to defend is
at an end and we can start our offenses.
We will attack the desperate Turks while
they're still reeling from his death.
We'll make it clear to the world
that we'll never leave
our lands to these barbarians.
Sir, what's next after Ertuğrul's death?
We take Hanli bazaar.
They've seen their catapults burn
and their alps massacred,
then Ertuğrul's death.
The Turks will be truly devastated
when we take Hanli Bazaar.
When Titan and his heroic knights
return it will be our turn.
We'll take Hanli bazaar.
Allahuekber.
Semi'allahu limen hamideh.
Esselamü aleyküm ve rahmetullah.
Mighty God who creates all,
who fills our heart with faith.
We are here for your sake,
to bring justice to the world.
God, bless us with victory.
Amen.
Do not let tyranny defeat us,
do not humiliate us before the oppressed.
Amen.
-God, give our horses strength.
-Amen.
-God, keep our strong swords always sharp.
-God, may our faith be our shield.
-Amen.
We send our prayers for our prophet
Mohammad Mustafa's sake.
-God, answer our prayers.
-Amen.
El Fatiha.
-May God answer your prayers.
-Amen.
Mighty God...
save your soldiers
who are willing to give their lives
to protect our holy
empire and these lands.
Don't spare the help you give us
in our efforts to destroy the Turks.
-Amen
-Amen.
Knights, brave solders of Karacahisar.
You are all brave, heroic soldiers,
blessed by the Father...
Son and Holy Ghost.
Today, in another show of courage,
we will finally destroy Ertuğrul,
capture Hanli bazaar
and deal a final, fatal blow to the Turks.
Let our cry be "Death to the Turks!"
Death to the Turks!
Death to the Turks! Death to the Turks!
Our victory will rise
from the blood of the Turks!
Long live the Holy Empire!
Long live Commander Ares!
Sir, the pigeon came.
Who is it from, sir?
Titan. He's killed Ertuğrul, Kostas.
Ertuğrul is dead!
Long live the Holy Empire!
Long live Commander Ares!
The Turks are withdrawing!
Come, Kostas.
I want to see it with my own eyes.
Ertuğrul is dead! Ertuğrul is dead!
Look, Kostas. They are withdrawing
because their bey is dead.
Thank God.
Titan did a great job again, sir.
Perhaps he'll bring you
Ertuğrul's head tonight.
Titan wrote that he was
heading to the Cavdar tribe.
He'll meet Bahadir there
then return to the castle at nightfall.
My knights!
The brave knight, Titan, killed Ertuğrul.
-Long live Commander Ares!
-The Turks no longer have a leader.
Our victory will now be easier
and bloodier!
Long live Commander Ares!
Long live Titan,
long live Commander Ares!
Long live Titan, long live Commander Ares!
Kostas, prepare a big feast
to be held in the yard.
Let's give Titan a fitting welcome.
-The knights deserve some fun, too.
-Yes, sir.
Then we get out of this castle
and chop the heads off those broken Turks.
Long live Titan, long live Commander Ares!
Alps! My lions!
Heroes! Brothers!
They have their castle walls...
they could build
a towering mountain range
for all it would matter.
As long as our faith burns in our hearts
and noble blood runs through our veins
we will sweep them away with our chests.
Today is the day.
Our battle cries will tear open the skies.
Our swords, sharpened by revenge,
will glide into the enemy's side.
We'll hit them so hard
that the sound of our swords
will be heard in Nicaea
and as far as Constantinople.
That viper's nest
will be our enemy's grave.
May our swords be sharp, our battle
blessed and our final victory glorious!
Allahuekber.
Allahuekber! Allahuekber! Allahuekber!
God...
Aktolgali, my most loyal companion.
Aktolgali, just like I promised you,
the time has come to hit our enemy
like a lightning bolt.
One, two...
three, four...
five, six...
seven, eight.
One more time, women. One, two...
-Sisters, over here.
-Three, four...
five, six...
seven, eight.
One more time. One, two...
three, four...
five, six...
seven, eight.
Well done, Halime Hatun.
Now, practice yourselves.
We'll speed up later.
Women!
Women, your sword hand
must be as hard as stone.
If you bend your wrist, the slightest move
will make your sword fall to the ground.
Come on then, women.
My beauties!
My lovely girls,
you are the future of our tribe.
It is you who will advance and prosper
through the work you do now.
Come on, then.
One, two, three...
four, five, six...
My Bey, it's finally time to conquer
Karacahisar Castle.
If you hadn't brought us here,
we wouldn't have this honor.
-God bless you.
-God bless you, brother.
Together we're a plane tree.
If I am the trunk of the plane tree,
you are the branches.
And our live-giving water is our faith.
What keeps us alive is...
the faith that brought us
all the way out here.
Bey, you said plane tree and it made me
think of the one we planted together.
My God!
May this plane tree embrace the world
with its branches.
May it take root.
It should take root
so our generation can spread your justice
and mercy all over the world.
For this cause,
may the fate of this plane tree
become our fate.
Amen.
When we planted it, I wished
for its roots to take over the world.
We came from Ahlat, Pasinler, Aleppo,
we pressed forward,
right up against the border of Byzantium.
Don't think that borders can hold us back.
There's no doubt about that, my Bey.
When we were kids, all of us would
hunt around the village.
You'd go hunting in the hills
in enemy land.
It was obvious then that
borders wouldn't stop you.
Thank you, brother.
However, this is nothing like hunting
in enemy land.
This is the toughest battle
we've had to fight yet.
With this battle, not only the doors
of Karacahisar,
but if God permits,
the doors of other countries
will open for us as well.
I hope so, my Bey.
Our mission is to spread
God's justice to the whole world.
And to be the hope of the oppressed,
the fear of the cruel.
For this cause, we might become a martyr
or a veteran.
There's nothing we can do
if that is God's desire.
Yes, my Bey.
I don't know if Shahada is in my destiny,
but if the sacred adversary
is coming for me in this battle,
I entrust you with both Aslıhan Hatun
and the Cavdar Tribe.
Of course, my brave man.
We've come all this way together.
We went through
so many struggles together.
Maybe it's not our fate
to see each other again.
So let's hug.
Give each other our blessings.
My brothers.
-I give my blessings.
-Thank you.
The sun is about to go down.
It's time to attack the enemy
in their lodge.
Come on, my brave men. Come on.
Fill it up. Come on, fill it up!
Come on, let's dance!
Let's dance!
Bring it over.
Come on, Commander Kostas.
This is your victory.
-Let go of my arm, woman.
-Come on.
-Welcome, Titan.
-Thank you.
Soldiers! Commander Ares!
My dear God!
I'm grateful to you
for this victorious day.
Amen.
Marya.
What's that sound, Ares?
I told you, Marya.
I told you that victory would be mine.
Ertuğrul is dead.
I avenged your brother.
What you're hearing is the feast I'm
throwing for Titan and my victory, Marya.
Come on, get ready. Join us.
What's wrong? Why are you crying?
Out of happiness.
It's your victory day.
Come on, Marya. Get ready.
You'll join us in the feast.
Tonight, I'll announce
in front of everyone
that you're to be my wife.
I...
Go, herald the coming of Titan, Dumrul.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
The great Titan
and our heroic soldiers are coming!
-Welcome! Ertuğrul is dead.
-Titan is coming!
Victory will be ours. Welcome, Titan.
Come on, let's dance!
Long live Commander Ares!
Titan is still not here, Kostas.
Sir, you know more than I do
how cautious he is.
He doesn't want them to learn where
the passage is.
Even though the Turks lifted the siege,
they will still be on the safe side.
That's right, Kostas.
Give out more wine.
Today is our victory day.
Sir, the places for you and Marya are set.
Please go ahead.
The noise is coming from the yard.
They are celebrating Titan's victory.
That degenerate is celebrating
your death a second time, Bey.
Let them eat and drink, Bey.
Let them eat until we crack them open
with our weapons.
Dumrul.
Go to the yard right away.
Herald the coming of Titan
and his soldiers.
Let them welcome us as we deserve.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
It's the day of conquest, brothers.
My brave men!
May God not lack the faith in our hearts,
and the strength in our arms.
Amen.
-Amen, my Bey.
-Come on.
Ares, I will kill you with my own hands.
I'll will avenge my brother.
Kostas!
Marya is still not here.
I'm sending a soldier right away, sir.
Great Titan and
our hero soldiers are coming!
Titan is coming!
Great Titan and
our hero soldiers are coming!
-Thank God.
-Titan and our hero...
Kostas, let's welcome the hero Titan
and our soldiers properly.
Yes, sir.
Long live Titan! Long live Ares!
My dear friend Titan...
you came back with a big victory.
You buried Ertuğrul's carcass
in this holy land.
May God accept you in heaven.
With this victory,
you have earned admiration.
Not only mine, but all the empire.
My dear friend, get up.
Let me hug you, Titan.
I'm not Titan.
I am Suleyman Shah's son, Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul!
-God is one!
It's a trap! Kill them all!
God is one!
Allahu Akbar!
My God!
Hit them! Allahu Akbar!
God!
-Alps!
-God is one!
Alps, don't leave our Bey alone!
Don't let anyone pass, fight to the death!
-I'll come back for you, Ertuğrul.
-Ertuğrul is here!
Where are you?
So you're here, huh?
-What's wrong?
-Turks are in the castle.
-What?
-Ertuğrul is alive. Hide.
Marya!
Come with me now. We need
to get out of the castle. I'll save you.
Go to hell, Ares!
You vulgar woman! Traitor!
I'll kill you!
Don't run away, come here!
We didn't do anything. We're innocent!
We're innocent! Save us!
-We're innocent!
-Don't be scared.
Don't be scared. You're free now.
Go see your families and children.
You're free now.
May God protect you.
We're grateful to you.
-We're grateful to you.
-Thank God.
May God protect you.
Thank you. Come on!
You're free now, come on.
Come on, praise be!
Brothers, search everywhere.
Make sure there are no soldiers.
Come on, let's be quick. Come on.
There's no way
I'll get out of this castle alive.
I can only get out as a dead man.
Bamsi.
We are responsible for the lives
of these soldiers.
Lock them up until we secure the castle.
Yes, Bey.
Come on. Come on.
Ertuğrul Bey.
What's going to happen
to the degenerate Ares?
I injured him.
I was about to take his life
but the soldiers showed up.
He turned tail and ran away like a dog.
The Alps are after him. At least we made
his castle collapse upon him.
Sooner or later the Alps will get him.
Günküt, Abdurrahman.
Search the castle inch by inch.
Bring him to me, dead or alive.
-Your wish is my command.
Go.
My Bey.
What's going on inside the castle, Bamsi?
We haven't left any heathens.
The castle is under our command now,
my Bey.
Thank you, Bamsi.
Let's fetch our flags. The other villages
should know about our victory.
Your wish is my command, my Bey.
Degenerate scumbag, where are you?
In the name of God.
My God!
Thank God. Thank heaven.
Thank God, brother.
God let us take this holy victory.
If God permits, we'll see many victories.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Our holy flag, that has justice
in every inch,
has been honored here
with the permission and mercy of God.
This is not an end,
but actually a beginning.
We planted a seed here today.
This seed will sprout and become
a plane tree that will cover
the whole world in its shade.
Let's announce our conquest
with the prayer of Muhammad.
Mother, all the women are at their posts.
They keep patrolling day and night.
Great.
Dear.
You couldn't sleep a wink last night.
Come, rest for a while.
Mother.
There's still no news from Ertuğrul.
I can't help but worry about them.
Dear.
Our duty is to protect the camp,
and pray for their victory.
God will surely help them.
I hope so.
May I enter, Hayme Hatun?
I hope to God that it's good news.
Come in, Artuk Bey.
There's news from Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank God.
They raised our flag at the castle.
-The adhan has been pronounced.
-O God, blessed be.
Thank God.
-Thank God.
-Blessed be.
Thank God for granting us victory.
This is what you get for capturing me.
My father showed them
and took their fortress.
Next time, I'll go there as Gündüz,
son of Ertuğrul Bey, and not as a captive.
God bless!
Ertuğrul Bey expects me at the fortress.
You give this good news to our people
and come to the fortress with our men.
Artuk Bey.
Is Marya all right? I'm worried about her.
Who is Marya, Gündüz?
Artuk Bey.
Marya is a woman from the fortress.
Apparently, she helped Gündüz
when he was captured.
All right, Gündüz.
I'll find out when I'm there.
Come on.
Take them away.
You are forgetting that this land
still belongs to us, Ertuğrul Bey.
I know that you're paying taxes
to our Sultan to hold this fortress.
I'm still the ruler of this land,
Ertuğrul Bey.
This fortress was home to a great deal
of treachery, traps, and evil.
Their cruelty could only be redeemed
with their blood.
Thank God,
the light of justice will shine
now that we have defeated
their evil darkness.
With this blow to Karacahisar,
not only will you shake Nicaea,
but even Constantinople.
You said this conquest would lead
to bigger conquests, sir.
Now I see what you meant.
I always said no borders
could contain you, sir.
Now, the whole world will see that.
Thank you, brothers.
Make sure our soldiers are alert.
We need to be careful
until things settle down.
Search around the fortress.
Let's see what's here.
-You got it.
-Right on.
Sir.
There's a locked chest here.
Bring it here, Bamsı.
All right, sir.
Turgut!
Let me help, brother.
Here we go!
There it is, sir.
Is this that one-eyed governor's
treasure or something?
Turgut.
Here we go!
It's my azure sword!
So, that one-eyed governor's been
holding onto it.
It was that very azure sword
that welcomed you here, Ertuğrul Bey.
That bastard must have even been afraid
of your sword.
That's why he locked it in a chest.
God bless.
It seems that...
he dreamed about killing me
with my own sword.
However, I turned those dreams
into a nightmare.
Now, as traditions dictates,
I'll saber the throne.
The cruel will eventually pay their sins.
Justice will prevail.
God is here, and the heathens are gone.
This won't end here.
I'll come back.
I'll take both your life
and your fortress, Ertuğrul.
How is the situation out there, Dumrul?
We sent the bodies of Ares' soldiers
to be buried, sir.
And we'll gather our martyrs
to send them to the camp.
We fought long and hard for this.
If we have a home now,
it's thanks to the martyrs.
God bless their souls.
-Amen.
Amen.
We conquered the fortress.
But we must be cautious.
The emperor could have sent an army.
Bamsı.
Tell the soldiers outside the fortress
that they shall stay put
and wait for my orders.
The Governor of Bilecik may send a unit.
Have some men stationed
at the roads from Bilecik.
As you wish, sir.
Did you find Ares?
Not yet, sir.
Our men are still looking for him.
Dumrul, warn the soldiers burying
Ares' soldiers.
Atsız.
Take some men with you.
It's possible that Ares got out
of the fortress.
If he managed to get away,
he'll make for the Governor of Bilecik.
Be on the lookout, now.
Leave it to me, sir.
I know all the ways Ares can take.
I'll breathe down his neck
and bring him to you.
Thank you.
Günkut, send for the priests.
They should take their paintings
and crosses to their church.
As you wish, sir.
Go on.
Ho!
Give me a hand here.
-What happened here?
-Ares...
He got away. He was hidden
among the bodies.
Let Ertuğrul Bey know.
We'll go after Ares. Hurry!
Ho!
Ertuğrul Bey, the Christian people
are worried about their faith.
We'd like to know
how you'll proceed with it.
We won't meddle in anyone's faith, priest.
We rule our subjects with justice.
You are my people now.
God says in his holy book that
there'll be no forcing in religion.
That's why
as long as you don't disturb others,
you may live and pray as you like.
Now, toll the bells,
and gather everyone in the courtyard.
I have things to tell them.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let's go.
Take everything.
Come on.
Ho!
Get down, check his tracks.
-They went this way.
-That road lets to Bilecik.
Ertuğrul Bey was right.
He'll seek help from the Governor
of Bilecik and gather an army.
We must catch him.
On your horses! Come on!
Sir.
Thank God for letting us see this day.
May our victory be everlasting.
Amen, Artuk Bey.
Thank God for letting us see this day.
Turgut Alp.
May God give strength to your arm.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Bamsı.
May your sword never dull.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
We found these in the cellar, sir.
Thank you.
There might be
confidential reports there, sir.
Read each and every one of them,
Artuk Bey.
I need a connection between
Ares and Emir Sadettin.
I need strong evidence
when I go to see our Sultan.
As you wish, sir.
I'll check all of them
and report back to you.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
I'll take one-fifth of all the spoils
to our Sultan.
Use some of it to set up an almshouse.
Also, we need a small mosque.
Share the rest equally
between the tribes.
As you wish, sir.
What happened, Dumrul?
There's news from Atsız, sir.
He found Ares' tracks.
He went after him.
Atsız will surely find Ares.
Tell everyone to spread out.
As you wish, sir.
Welcome, Mother Hayme.
Thank you.
Good god.
Look at this!
What was a nest of Byzantine evil
until recently
has been honored with Islam.
Thank God, mother.
We got to see these days.
Hopefully, we will prosper
and revive this fortress.
I hope so, dear.
We can't thank God enough
for granting us with such a victory.
My dear.
What happened?
Hafsa?
Are you all right?
I suffered so much in this castle...
that I was born and brought up in.
They killed my father.
I was all alone.
What would I do without you, Mother Hayme?
As I came here, together with you,
I'm both happy and sad at the same time.
My sweetie.
We'll live to see
many great days together.
-Hopefully.
-I hope so.
-Welcome, Mother Hayme.
-Thank you, Günkut.
Let me take you to Ertuğrul Bey.
Okay.
Why is the bell ringing?
Ertuğrul Bey will give a speech
to the residents.
It's to gather everyone around,
Mother Hayme.
I know this fortress, Mother.
Let me show you around.
-Sure, why not?
-So be it.
Come on, take us to your dad.
Come along then, Grandmother.
When you told me that I couldn't
lay a hand on this castle,
I said I'd show you all
whether I could do it or not.
I trampled on your rule.
I destroyed your armies.
And now, both Karacahisar Castle
and your throne are under my rule.
Soon, the emperor of Nicaea
shall see this as well.
Write this down, Artuk Bey.
"Emperor Dukas.
We ruined all the traps and plots
of your Governor Ares.
I made that coward who broke our peace
pay for it.
Now, Karacahisar Castle is
under my rule.
I'll send you Ares' head soon, as well.
If the Governor of Bilecik makes
the same treacherous mistake...
he will share Ares' fate.
Let it be known that...
the might of our armies is enough
to take even Nicaea.
Ruler of Karacahisar,
Margrave of the Seljuks,
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertuğrul."
Go now.
Let everyone in Nicaea know
about my victory.
And if they don't behave,
tell them that we'll come
knocking on their doors.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, sir.
Gather some men.
Have them scribble notices of our victory
and send them everywhere.
As you wish, sir.
Ho!
This way. Come along.
I know my way around here.
Welcome, everyone.
Welcome, Mother Hayme.
-Halime Hatun, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Bamsı...
Hafsa.
Welcome.
Bamsı, God bless you.
We're so happy for this victory.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Marya!
Gündüz.
You are alive.
I was worried about you.
Is your wound okay?
I'm all right, Gündüz.
Now that I see you, I feel great.
I'm all better now.
God bless you, Marya.
I hear you helped Gündüz.
Thank you.
Dear, Gündüz wouldn't stop
talking about you.
I heard you protected him.
God knows what would have happened
to him if you weren't around.
Thank you.
Gündüz is a clever boy.
He'd have taken care of himself
even without me.
Good. Come on now, let's go.
Come on.
Have our men do what's necessary, Turgut.
Yes, sir.
Daddy! Congratulations on your victory!
Come here, big guy.
You too will fight many wars like me
and conquer many other fortresses.
God bless.
Son.
God bless your victory.
I pray that God helps you
take many others,
so that you may gain
more lands and fortresses.
Thank you, Mother.
God bless you, dear.
Now that you took this fortress,
we can never be proud enough of you.
What's important is not
a castle, or a throne, Halime.
What's important is for our flag
to ripple in God's name.
As long as I'm alive,
I'll raise our flag wherever we need to.
Ertuğrul Bey.
God bless your conquest.
May this be the beginning
of many other victories.
Amen, Aslıhan Hatun.
Amen.
I have no doubt that
you'll bring justice to this castle
where my father was once its governor.
I wish you all the best.
Thanks, Hafsa Hatun.
I'm happy to see you
alive and well, Marya.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
You avenged my brother.
What more could I ask for?
Do you have a family
other than your brother?
No.
I have nowhere else to go.
We can't leave you alone now.
If you don't have anywhere to go,
then come live with us
if that's okay with you.
I'd be honored.
But is that all right?
I don't want to trouble you.
Our tribe is home to those
who are brave, and trustworthy.
Anyone may live with us
if they are trustworthy.
You too may live with us.
Rest at ease.
Artuk Bey.
-Yes, sir.
-Treat Marya's wounds.
Do your best so that she heals fast.
As you wish, sir. Leave it to me.
May God protect you, Ertuğrul Bey.
-May God give you strength.
-Thank you, Marya.
I'm so happy that you let
Marya live with us, Dad.
God bless.
My boy.
Brothers.
Let's surrender to Ertuğrul Bey.
We can't surrender to the man
that killed Bahadir Bey.
He killed Bahadir Bey.
It's all over now.
We'll deal with him.
So, you killed Bahadir, huh?
God damn you, Ertuğrul.
Commander Ares.
This isn't over, Ertuğrul.
It's just begun, in fact.
In the name of God
who wills things into existence
and fills our hearts with faith.
I'm Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
Let it be known
that Justice replaces cruelty and fear
in these lands.
We will treat everyone as equals.
From now on,
we shall all live in peace and harmony.
We'll strengthen our home and trade
with justice.
You may practice your religion in peace
on these lands.
Justice, freedom, peace, and unity.
That's our law.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net