Episode 94 will start after 12:30 min.
Who the hell are they?
Don't let Ertuğrul get away.
Damn it. These are Ares' men.
So you found me, bastards.
-Come on, then.
-Attack!
-Ertuğrul is escaping.
-Don't let him get away.
Fall back!
Let them go. We'll deal with them later.
Hurry up. Let's go after Ertuğrul.
The bey was elected as per our traditions.
What is the purpose of asking
for another election?
Our traditions will be lost once injustice
emerges, Lady Hayme.
Dündar Bey made a decision
with his authority.
But decisions against the cause
are not legitimate.
It's my right to ask for an election
given the circumstances.
-Artuk Bey is right.
-We won't give up on the cause.
Nonsense. Ertuğrul Bey became a martyr.
We need to think about the future
of our tribe and children.
If...
the elections aren't held,
I'll consider it a violation of tradition.
With the beys and alps who support me,
I won't obey Dündar Bey's decisions.
How come? Is that even possible?
This situation causes unrest
within the tribe. It needs to be resolved.
It seems you don't think
about the peace of the tribe, Artuk Bey.
But I do.
I'll gather the council
at an appropriate time,
just like my ancestors allowed it
to be gathered...
in even the most extreme conditions.
Make the preparations.
Let's hope for good...
and have a good result.
May God...
protect our unity and peace.
Amen.
I hope it will be good for you
and our tribe, Artuk Bey.
How many traders reside in the bazaar?
We don't have an exact number.
But thanks to the laws of Ertuğrul Bey,
and the location of the bazaar,
it attracts traders and customers.
-But--
-How is the income?
It's good, Your Eminence. It's a fortune
for a man who knows to manage it.
Very well.
Then we need to do whatever it takes
to improve the business in the bazaar.
You'll be my eyes and ears
in the bazaar, Aleko.
I'll wait for the information
you'll provide.
You understand, right?
As you command, Your Eminence. Excuse me.
I'm having a hard time deciding which
of your gifts to wear for the dinner.
Could you please help me pick one?
Why did Simko give you to me, Maria?
Speak.
Or else I'll kill you right here
and throw your body from the walls.
I don't understand what you are saying.
I was his slave.
You took me from him
and gave me a new life.
-I'm just a poor girl.
-Hush.
What do you know about Ertuğrul?
Speak. Tell me.
I don't know anyone called Ertuğrul.
Why did Simko give you to me?
Why did he put you in this castle, huh?
What do you know about Ertuğrul, Maria?
Where is Simko?
I swear I don't know any Ertuğrul.
Simko has a man.
His name is Antheus.
I heard him saying that they found
a Turk who was about to die,
and they were to make lots of money.
I'm begging you.
I don't know anything else.
I don't believe a single word
you say, Maria.
I don't believe you. Where is Simko?
I swear to God, I don't know.
Soldier!
-Get a doctor. Right now!
-Yes, sir.
Mother, you are so valuable to us.
Your word is more important than anything.
I'd like to know what you think
about the matter of migration.
Come sit by me.
The arguments at the party
made me uneasy, Son.
The course of events doesn’t bode well.
If the fire of conflict starts to burn in
our tribe, God forbid, we will perish.
That is why I want the marketplace
to be sold and for us to migrate, Mother.
I want to be one with my brothers.
Otherwise, we will lose
each other at this frontier.
You are right, my son.
Strength comes from unity.
I too find it appropriate
for the Kayi to stand as one.
Then why are you
so deep in thought, Mother?
What's making you uncomfortable?
Look, Son.
We came here
to strike fear in the ruthless
and bring hope to the oppressed.
We, and Ertuğrul, fought hard for this.
I say, let us send a messenger
to your brothers
and call them back here.
And if they don't come,
let us ride to them.
What do you say?
My hope in migrating is
that it will unify the tribes, Mother.
I don't think my brothers would come.
They have grown roots there, Mother.
Yes, but...
how could I leave my Ertuğrul's
grave here and go?
Don't you worry, Mother.
I will send the messenger.
I will do as you say.
That would do, my son. That would do.
Excuse me, Mother.
Ertuğrul Bey.
You'll find out who set you up
sooner or later.
When the time comes,
they will all feel my wrath.
This way.
She has a concussion, my lord.
She is not well.
I don't care what she has.
Make sure she lives
long enough to talk,
-or I'll have you thrown off the wall.
-I will get her to come around, My Lord.
Help me.
Let's take her to the bed.
Careful! Keep her steady!
-My lord.
-Speak.
I sent our best warriors to aid Mihalis.
Ertuğrul will understand that he is
being pursued once Mihalis attacks.
Ertuğrul doesn't know
that I was the one who set him up.
What if he finds out?
Ertuğrul will die before he makes it to
his tribe, Lukas,
or he will die with them.
We are assuming a state of war. I have
had it with this fake peace agreement.
We cannot rid these lands of the Turks
without shedding blood by the gallon.
-Gather the commanders.
-Yes, my lord.
They are in your chambers awaiting you.
Door.
They're coming. Settle down.
He's alive! Ertuğrul Bey is alive!
-Thank God.
-We are grateful.
-You're alive.
-Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Ertuğrul Bey, you're alive!
Thank God you're all right, Ertuğrul Bey.
We are grateful, Ertuğrul Bey.
You saved our lives.
You're welcome.
-Thank you.
-Thank God.
It is now time for us to part ways.
Go to your families, your loved ones.
-No. No.
-No.
We won't leave you by yourself
after all you've done for us.
Pito is right.
We won't leave you, Ertuğrul Bey.
You are good people.
However, their quarrel is with me.
My road is rugged. You won't make it.
-Go to your loved ones.
-No...
This is my fight.
Show us how to fight, Ertuğrul Bey,
so that when we find our families,
we can protect them.
This is our fight too, now, Ertuğrul Bey.
If it weren't for you,
-we'd be galley slaves our whole lives.
-You saved our lives.
-We won't leave you.
-Yeah.
They have horses.
They will find us in no time.
We can't escape.
If you want to stay by my side...
-Yes.
-We do.
...then we will ambush them.
Ambush? How?
How can we do that?
We will lure them in.
None of us even have a sword.
Sometimes a rock is better than a sword.
Know that every rock you throw will
sever a link from the chain of captivity.
It will bring us
one step closer to liberty.
-Yes, that's right.
-It's true. Yes.
-We won't be held captive.
-Yeah!
-We won't be belittled!
-We won't surrender.
-Yeah!
We will show courage against cruelty,
-and fight for liberty against captivity.
-Yeah!
-We'll do it, yeah!
-We will.
"The sultan's crown
depends upon the vizier's pen.
If the ink runs dry,
his rule will come to an end."
What a nice saying by the Seljuks'
grand emir, Nizâmülmülk.
Alas...
his end was grim.
Speak, Göktuğ.
Dündar Bey is on his way, Your Eminence.
He is coming before you.
He must have managed to persuade his tribe
if he is coming so quickly. Good.
Send word to Bahadir Bey immediately.
Call him also.
They'll be introduced to Dündar Bey
and will talk of the agreement.
-So soon, Eminence?
-We have no time to lose.
The caravans from Konya
and Kayseri are already on their way.
The bazaar must be sold fast
and order must be established.
It should be formed
so that the bazaar may grow.
Yes, my emir.
They can't have gotten far.
The tracks lead in this direction.
He is not alone. Someone else is with him.
They must have headed towards
the escaped slaves. Be cautious.
Don't forget that we are after one of
the fiercest Turkish warriors. Move out.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Are the horses ready
to ride to Aslıhan's tribe, Halime?
Word will be sent when they are.
Neslihan.
Speak your mind, my daughter.
You are the wife of Süleyman Shah,
the pillar of the Kayi Tribe, Mother.
The storms you have weathered,
the typhoons you have withstood...
You've held our tribe,
our marquee together.
So, how can you not stand against
Dündar Bey's decision?
Look, my daughter.
Dündar Bey is the pillar of our marquee,
the bey of our tribe.
He has made a decision
so that we don't fall apart.
Mother, we came to these lands
to make them our own,
not to abandon them.
We spilled blood,
gave our lives for these lands.
We worked for it.
We have hope for it.
Ertuğrul lies
in the tribe's burial ground, Mother.
We can't leave.
What do you think my goal is?
I'm only thinking of you.
My girl, don't you see
that we are heading for the worst?
Besides, Dündar isn't like
Süleyman Shah or Ertuğrul.
They are experienced
and have been through a lot.
Dündar is young.
He is not fit to endure
such circumstances, don't you see?
We've got you, Mother. We have us.
We will carry the burden of the world
if need be.
-Right?
-Oh, my girl!
You don't get it, do you?
With Ertuğrul gone, this is no longer
our home, but a foreign land.
Mother!
And...
And don't be hasty.
I've spoken to Dündar.
He will send word to his brothers.
He will call them here
so that we may be together.
How can you trust
in that outcome, Mother?
Neither Sungurtekin Bey nor Gündoğdu Bey
will leave the lands they made their home
for so many years, and come here.
We need to get to Aslıhan
as soon as possible.
She needs us.
These ashes will stop the blood
flowing from your wound, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Pito.
-Fasten the rags securely.
-Okay.
Sharpen the ends of the branches.
The resulting pikes
will pierce the enemy's chest.
Why are you crying?
When I was captured by Simko, I gave up.
I gave in to slavery.
Thanks to you, I've summoned the courage
to return to my kids.
God bless you, Ertuğrul Bey.
May He return you to your loved ones.
We will fight
without giving up hope in God.
Know that He is by our side.
-God bless you.
-God bless you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Permission to enter, my bey.
Enter.
What is this chest, my bey?
The real spoils of the war, my lady.
This will secure our legacy
Permission to enter, my bey.
Yes, enter.
Emir Sadettin has sent word.
He's asking to see you.
What could he want?
-Okay. Get ready.
-Yes, my bey.
They said that Emir Sadettin
knew how to fill a chest.
They were right, my bey.
It's clear he has given you this to help
in your role as bey of the frontier.
Emir Sadettin is just
our guarantee, Karaca.
We are more powerful than both Aslıhan
and the Kayis.
From now on...
we will crush whoever crosses our path.
Your way is our way,
your strength is our strength, my bey.
Just as I stood by you in bloody wars,
hard days and difficult resettlements...
I am with you in this to the end.
After I return from the emir,
I will sit down and talk with the beys
and convince them to attend a gathering.
You talk with the women of the tribe.
Get them on our side.
Don't worry about me, my bey.
No woman will stand by Aslıhan.
My good fortune,
my marquee's throne, my Karaca.
It is high time we became
the bey and hatun of all the Cavdars.
Come now. Godspeed.
Godspeed, my bey.
We will find Ertuğrul.
He is our only salvation.
Ares picked up on our tracks, Simko.
He's found out who you are.
Either we get our gold
and get the hell out of this place,
or they take us down one by one!
Look here!
We find Ertuğrul
and twe get our gold,
because Simko never backs down,
never gives up and never fails!
We will be swimming in gold, the likes
of which we've never seen before.
The finest food in the world,
the finest wine and the finest women
will be ours.
Understand? Understand?!
Hurray for gold! Hurray for Simko!
Come here.
Get on your horse and go to Antheus.
Tell him to gather his men
and send them here. Go.
I'll find you, Ertuğrul.
I swear I'll find you.
They went this way.
Let's go.
I left trails everywhere,
just as you asked, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sooner or later,
they will fall into our lap.
Good job.
It's time. Keep your eyes
on the enemy at all times.
Think not of death, but life.
Not of fear,
but of returning to your loved ones.
Now, everyone hide
in the positions I assigned.
Hide yourselves so that when they come,
we might come down on them like thunder
when they least expect.
Come on.
-Come on, hurry.
-Come on.
My bey, may God watch over us all.
Thank you.
Come now, you bastards.
The last light you'll see...
will be the one that shines on my sword.
Have you persuaded your tribe, Dündar?
Artuk Bey is opposed to the bazaar
and matters of immigration.
He accuses me of betraying
my brother's cause.
How dare he!
What does he want?
He has asked for a gathering of beys.
He wishes to be bey himself.
Well, well, well!
Isn't that Artuk Bey insolent!
After the death of Ertuğrul Bey,
he finds in himself the desire
to be a bey after all.
All the while, the son
of Süleyman Shah resides among us.
Don't you worry. I am behind you.
Thank you, Your Eminence.
I have no doubt.
So why do you hesitate?
My mother can't bring herself
to leave these lands.
She wants my brothers to come.
Dündar, do you think your brothers
would abandon the lands
they earned with their valor
and loyalty to the sultan?
Don't worry.
When she reunites with her sons,
Hayme Hatun's troubles will cease.
Your Eminence, Bahadir Bey is here.
Let him come.
Bahadir Bey,
brother of the deceased Candar Bey.
Dündar Bey,
son of the deceased Süleyman Shah.
I had the honor of meeting your father.
I am now honored to meet his valiant son.
Thank you, Bahadir Bey.
Everyone knows of your valor
in the war.
Come, sit.
-The tracks are fresh. They walk this way.
-They must be right ahead.
Let's see if you are everything
they say you are.
They're coming, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let them, Pito.
We will not let the deaths of innocents
be in vain.
We will make them spit blood.
Go now.
The Kayi have duly run the Hanlı Bazaar.
Dündar Bey also managed it
as much as he could.
However, this is business.
When things weren't going well,
he expressed the desire to sell it.
We know of the honesty of the Kayi.
The decision that Dündar Bey made
must be with good intent.
Thank you, Bahadir Bey.
We thought that this
was for the best of our tribe.
I would vouch for both of you equally.
One of you is resolved
to make this their land,
and the other to sell and move on.
It falls upon you both to come
to an agreement and help each other out.
There's no need to get strangers
involved in this matter, Dündar Bey.
It is best to agree among ourselves.
And with this deal, we will fortify
the friendship of the Kayis and Cavdars.
First, the gathering of beys must be held,
and I must be chosen as bey.
If it's for the best, it must be so.
Still, present your hand
so that we may see your loyalty as a bey.
With God's permission,
after you become bey,
I wish to buy the Hanlı Bazaar,
Dündar Bey.
Know that I will pay what it is worth.
With God's permission, as soon as
I become bey, the bazaar is yours.
May it be for the best, my beys.
May God allow you to honor your word.
-With your permission, Your Eminence.
-The permission is yours, Dündar Bey.
A lot of people are out to get you.
You should be with your tribe.
I will come and visit you tomorrow.
Make preparations.
It would be an honor to welcome you
into my tent, Your Eminence.
Tent?
What's the marquee for, then?
Aslıhan Hatun won't welcome us
into her tribe, Your Eminence,
so she continues to keep us in a tent.
By my orders, that is your land.
Who does this Aslıhan think she is?
You will prepare a worthy feast tomorrow
at the marquee for us.
I will come too.
Let this Aslıhan see
who is the one with the power.
May I take my leave then, Your Eminence?
You may.
Göktuğ.
Tell Ares that Bahadir
and Dündar have agreed.
Yes, Your Eminence.
It's a trap. Kill them!
Why don't we go after them too, my lord?
Ertuğrul is alone.
-It would be easy to finish him off.
-We don't know exactly where they are.
And we can't draw more attention
and get in more trouble.
Ertuğrul is heavily wounded.
He can't take on both Mihalis
and the reinforcements I sent after him.
More importantly, Marya will tell me
where Simko sent Ertuğrul.
Mihalis and his men are great warriors.
To this day, they have killed many people
and raided many caravans
without suffering any losses.
-Mihalis will return with Ertuğrul's head.
-What if Ertuğrul manages to survive?
He will come at us
like an arrow let loose.
That's why I gathered you here.
If Ertuğrul finds out that I set him up
and returns to his tribe,
then war will be inevitable.
We cannot leave it to chance.
Let the preparations begin.
-As of now, we are in a state of war.
-Yes, my lord!
Hasten the reinforcement of the walls.
Recruit men from the villages
by force if necessary.
I want all preparations completed
within three days.
-Every soldier in the fort must be ready.
-Yes, my lord!
Don't forget, our first aim is to kill
Ertuğrul before he reaches his tribe.
If we don't succeed,
a bloody war with the Turks awaits us.
What did you do, Ertuğrul Bey?
You needed that man alive.
Burn in hell, Turk!
You will die before you learn anything!
Welcome. Welcome, Hayme Hatun!
Welcome.
Mother Hayme, welcome!
Welcome, Hayme Hatun!
Welcome. Welcome, Hayme Hatun!
-Welcome.
-Take the reins.
Welcome.
-Welcome, Halime Hatun.
-Welcome.
Welcome to my tribe.
Mother.
I'm happy to be here, my girl.
Halime.
We heard of your situation
and came at once.
I am very thankful.
I know you won't leave me alone.
Come.
Those are Ertuğrul Bey's wife and mother.
It shows.
Aslıhan Hatun has already begun
the fight against Bahadir Bey.
This fight will cost many lives,
Karaca Hatun.
May God protect us
from the evil of raging women.
Thank you, dear.
Thank you.
Ever since he arrived,
he made his intentions clear.
He dared to threaten me in my own tent.
What does he want from you?
A council, as soon as possible.
He wants to become bey.
What will you do, Aslıhan Hatun?
I won't give up my cause.
I'll look after my brother's legacy.
And we wish to protect
Ertuğrul Bey's legacy.
But Dündar Bey thinks otherwise.
Hope for the best.
Dündar Bey wants to sell
the Hanli Bazaar
and go live with his brothers Gündoğdu and
Sungur Tekin.
What do you think, Halime Hatun?
Mother,
when I have difficulties,
wherever the issue comes from,
the Kayis used to have my back.
If you go as well,
what will I do then?
Calm down, dear.
Nothing is certain yet.
Let the council start,
let's see what happens.
Turgut will soon come.
We will never leave you alone, neither he
nor us.
Aslıhan Hatun, the molasses is boiled.
The women want you to taste it first.
Let's hope for the best.
Now, let's go see the women.
Let's go.
I serve Mihalis. I swear,
I don't know anything.
I'll kill you if you don't tell me
who Mihalis's master is.
Who is it?
Stop, enough.
I'll talk.
Simko!
Enjoy it, Mother Hayme.
-Well done.
-Enjoy it.
Women!
Well done, it's delicious.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Aslıhan Hatun.
Karaca Hatun.
Bahadır Bey's wife.
Welcome, Karaca Hatun.
We've seen your legendary friendship
with Aslıhan Hatun firsthand.
Thanks, Karaca Hatun.
I hope that when Bahadır Bey is set up
in his tent,
our friendship continues.
As long as Aslıhan Hatun stays here,
our friendship will continue.
I'm disappointed,
given that when her betrothed,
Turgut Alp, returns,
Aslıhan Hatun can't stay here.
She'll go to his village.
Don't be so sure about...
who will live where,
Karaca Hatun.
What a disloyal man you are, Ertuğrul Bey.
Since when does the wolf bow
before the coyote, Simko?
Leave us, Ertuğrul Bey. Save yourself.
Let him go, scum.
Their lives...
are in your hands.
Surrender,
or I'll kill them all.
You won't get away with this, Simko.
Ertuğrul killed two of our men, Simko.
Damned Turk.
What's that?
We found this pigeon on the horse
of one of Mihalis's men.
Now we know how Ares got his news so fast.
Let it fly for us now,
so that Ares...
will know that I have Ertuğrul.
When he does, he'll prepare our gold.
Get ready.
We'll spend the night in the cave.
Will you sell the bazaar and migrate?
Nothing is certain yet, Karaca Hatun.
Really?
Dündar Bey spoke with Bahadır Bey.
He said that after being elected bey,
he wanted to sell the bazaar.
When did Bahadır Bey speak to Dündar Bey?
When Emir Sadettin invited him.
They met there and discussed the issue.
When Dündar Bey said he wanted to
sell the bazaar,
Bahadır Bey asked to buy it,
so that it would still be ours.
Excuse us, dear.
Coyotes waiting for carrion, huh?
You'll only get...
my bloodthirsty sword.
Show your face.
Show yourself.
Who are you?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Why didn't you go?
Why didn't you save yourself?
We do not leave our comrades behind, Pito.
Was it worth it for a thief?
How many times have I told you
not to approach Ertuğrul?
Go there.
Let him go, Simko.
Do what you want to me.
Do you know...
how many slaves I lost because of you?
You cost me a lot.
A lot.
We're almost there.
We'll sell these slaves
and then hand you to your owner.
Then, I'll leave this place.
That scumbag who ambushed me...
knows you and your intentions.
He'll kill you.
Even if you get your cursed gold,
sooner or later,
he'll kill you all.
Now,
if you let us all go...
and tell me who plotted against me,
I'll kill him,
and save you and your men from him.
Ah, Ertuğrul Bey...
Even you aren't strong enough...
for him.
If you were,
you wouldn't have walked into that trap.
Do you see the results
of Dündar Bey's decisions, Mother?
If Bahadır Bey buys the bazaar, his claim
to be the bey will be stronger.
Then we'll have turned our backs
on Aslıhan Hatun.
Aslıhan is my daughter.
And the bride of my village.
First, we must solve our own problems.
-The solution is obvious.
-Mother...
Bahadır Bey wishes to defeat
Aslıhan Hatun and become bey.
So, our solution is to sell him
the bazaar?
Whomever pays the full price
can have the bazaar.
Even if it's Bahadır Bey,
it's acceptable.
And Aslıhan Hatun?
You're not only...
harming us, but her too.
Don't you see, Dündar Bey?
Aslıhan Hatun is no stranger
to our village.
My brother left her to us.
I will always respect her.
She can live in my village with her man.
She'll never come.
She'll keep her word to Aliyar
and will stay in her village.
You'll lose Turgut,
along with her.
I'm against your decision, Dündar Bey.
I'll support Artuk Bey from now on.
Keep that in mind.
Marya.
How could you do this, Marya?
I gave you a new life.
Speak.
Emir Sadettin sent news, sir.
Dündar Bey agreed with Bahadır Bey.
The inn will be sold tomorrow
after the council.
We have to do this soon, Lukas.
We can't risk it.
Any news from Mihalis?
Not yet, sir.
A pigeon arrived, sir.
Must be Mihalis.
Dear Ares, all the men you sent are dead.
I still have Ertuğrul.
For 10,000 gold,
you can prevent a great war
against the Seljuks.
You'll hear from me soon.
If you don't pay me,
Ertuğrul will learn it all.
I won't be responsible for what happens
afterwards.
Simko.
-He killed Mihalis's men.
-How is this possible, sir?
He still thinks Marya will serve him.
If we find Marya's contact,
we'll find them too, sir.
Go now, Lukas.
Kill them all.
-All of them.
-Yes, sir.
Door!
Marya...
Marya.
You'll tell me everything, Marya.
Everything.
Permission?
Come in.
Come.
The food is almost ready.
We'll eat together.
Thank you, Bamsi.
But we're not here for that.
We came to discuss something
important with you.
Good, go ahead.
Come, Halime Hatun, Artuk Bey.
Bamsi,
we feel your pain.
You did everything you could
for Ertuğrul Bey.
But...
you can't change fate.
Get a hold of yourself.
Get well.
Remember your duty.
Duty...
Artuk Bey...
What is this duty?
Dündar Bey wants to sell our rightful
Hanli Bazaar.
And will make us migrate
to Gündoğdu Bey's village.
It's time to rise up, Bamsi.
If we don't rise up,
our cause will be forgotten.
Both me and Halime Sultan
will do our best to reverse Dündar Bey's
decision.
We need all our comrades
to stand with us, Bamsi.
Anything can be forgotten,
but the cause...
the cause can't be.
I'm ready... to do anything
that you need.
Tell me, what can I do to
prevent this calamity?
Tell me.
Artuk Bey will not rest idly.
He'll try to undo my decision
with Halime Hatun.
They'll go to all the Alps and beys.
What should we do, Dündar Bey?
We have to talk to every Alp
and every bey, one by one
to convince them.
Balaban Bey and Elkoca Bey have doubts.
I'll talk to them personally
and convince them.
Giresun Bey,
İnanç Bey is your brother-in-law.
He'll listen to you.
Convince him before the council begins.
As you command.
Thank you.
Say that staying...
means losing money.
Yes.
But if we sell the bazaar, the gold...
will be spent for our village.
We'll have more animals.
When we migrate,
the Kayi villages will unite
and become stronger.
Tell that to everyone.
As you say.
Bamsi, the council is tomorrow.
Artuk Bey is a candidate.
We need the Alps and the beys on our side.
The Alps respect you.
They listen to you.
Speak to them.
Speak with the beys supporting Dündar Bey
and convince them to stop supporting him.
All right. All right, Halime Hatun.
All right, don't you worry.
I'll speak with all of them.
I'll do it.
I'll talk to the women,
so that they can convince
their husbands
not to support Dündar Bey.
I'll do my best
to help you, Halime Hatun.
Thanks, Hafsa.
I'll talk to each bey.
I'll tell them all the troubles we'll have
if Dündar Bey has his way.
If we don't prevent this,
all our martyrs will curse us.
This is an issue of life and death
for the village, Bamsi.
The duty falls on all of us.
The duty...
falls on all of us, Halime Hatun.
Don't you worry.
I'll do my best.
Yeah...
Marya.
Either you speak now,
or never.
I beg you, don't do anything.
I'm innocent.
Marya.
Talk to me.
Your life depends on it.
I can still forgive you.
I can still love you.
Just tell me the truth.
Don't do anything to me.
Have mercy, I'm innocent.
Marya.
Talk.
Last chance.
I'll talk.
Don't do anything.
Simko had a man.
Antheus.
He made me do it all.
He gave me to Simko, to send me
to your castle as a slave.
He wanted me to...
hang that letter on your door.
Why wait this long?
That Turk they have,
they waited to cure him.
You betrayed me, Marya.
Please forgive me.
I had to.
They threatened to kill my little brother
they have as a hostage.
This Antheus...
Where is he?
Save my brother, please.
We'll serve you until we die.
I won't let you perish.
Since they've trapped you,
I'll save you from them.
Tell me.
Where is this Antheus?
Master Simko, Antheus sent the men.
And the letter?
Was it delivered?
Ares has the letter.
Marya did her job.
Good.
Now I have Ares in my hand.
He'll give me back all my gold.
They're numerous.
We can't get away.
I don't care about myself being a slave.
I'm only sad for you.
Don't be sad...
for anyone, Pito.
There's always hope before death.
We...
just have to find it.
Ertuğrul Bey,
I can say that I've never seen
a braver man than you.
But there's no more hope.
All hope is gone.
Hopelessness is a sin, Pito.
We're ordered to never
stop hoping for Allah's mercy.
I don't fear death.
But...
if I die before using my last breath
then I'll go to hell.
What will you do?
Tell the slaves...
to get ready.
We'll fight one last time.
Get the slaves up.
We're going.
Glorious and Holy Emperor,
the Turkish villages on the border
are miserable.
The Seljuk Emir Sadettin will do anything
for his own ends.
For now, I'll run the Hanli bazaar
with him.
But the bazaar will soon
be completely ours.
For our holy goal,
it's time to destroy the Turks and take
back everything they've taken from us.
I want you to send me...
a great army, and someone worthy...
to run the bazaar for the glorious victory
that awaits us.
Your loyal servant,
Tekfur Ares.
They're back.
Welcome.
Welcome, my bey.
The brave warriors are back!
Welcome, brave warriors!
Thank you.
At last, brothers.
They have come.
My brothers are back.
Thank God.
At long last,
they have returned,
thank God.
Welcome.
My sons.
Thank you, Mother.
My son, my child.
-Welcome, son.
-Let me hug you.
My son...
-Welcome Turgut.
-Thanks, Mother.
-Our son is back.
-Welcome, son.
My brave son.
Welcome, all of you.
You've come back alive,
thank Allah.
You've brought joy.
Thank you.
We did our duty
to our Sultan and our state.
We've proudly returned...
to our village.
Welcome!
Welcome.
You've brought us joy.
You've made our village happy.
Thank you.
-Turgut Alp.
-Artuk Bey.
Welcome.
Welcome, son.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, Mother.
Good to see you, brother.
You've unleashed hell upon the enemy
and come back, huh?
-We did, brother.
-Well done, brother.
You seem well.
You've gotten better.
I did, indeed.
I did.
Welcome.
Thank Allah.
You're like a lion.
What's the matter?
Why have they gathered?
We're electing a bey, Turgut Alp.
We'll talk in the tent.
Get some rest.
We'll talk inside.
The pain left behind...
by our Ertuğrul Bey...
is still fresh, Turgut Alp.
So fresh that...
Dündar Bey wants us to...
leave everything behind and migrate to
the village of...
Gündoğdu Bey.
Mother Hayme.
Dündar Bey.
Is Halime Hatun right?
The council is for this?
We wish to sell...
the bazaar to unite the Kayis.
As they were before.
We wish to be one and strong.
We...
fought alongside Ertuğrul Bey for years.
We lost many men.
If we do this,
won't we betray his memory, Dündar Bey?
Of course... That's betrayal, brother.
It sure is.
When Ertuğrul Bey fell,
our village had troubles, Turgut.
Dündar Bey had this decision to make.
The Kayis must be united.
Artuk Bey is against
Dündar Bey's decision
and wishes to be...
the bey himself.
The council will decide.
Aslıhan Hatun has a problem too.
Her uncle Bahadır Bey came.
He wishes to migrate
with his village.
Who is Bahadır Bey?
Is he good?
Not at all, Turgut Alp.
The same as Ural.
Mother Hayme.
Dündar Bey.
The Alps just returned from war.
We have martyrs.
Let's not abandon their families
on this day.
You should be with them,
with the men.
If you agree, Dündar Bey,
the council should be tomorrow.
That would be better, Dündar Bey.
We can't have a council
with the families in mourning.
As you say.
I agree that it should be postponed.
Thank you.
I have to get to the Cavdar Village.
They have martyrs too.
I have to give them...
their dead and my condolences.
May they rest in peace.
Amen.
Brother.
I'll come along. I'll accompany you.
I'll go alone, brother.
You go to your Alps.
All right.
God bless your hands, Hatun.
It's a table worthy of an Emir.
You can tell how triumphant a bey is
by his table.
I'll set up many more amazing tables
for you, my bey.
What do you think you're doing
in my pavilion, Bahadir Bey?
Majesty Emir is visiting.
I'm throwing a banquet for him,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Why didn't I know about his visit?
He told me.
The two of us were talking alone.
I'm the hatun of the people.
And the pavilion is mine.
If Majesty Emir visits,
I should be the first one to know.
If someone is throwing a banquet,
that should be me.
Enough.
If you are a hatun,
I'm a bey.
From now on, this is my pavilion too.
How...
dare you?
Majesty Emir has arrived, Bey.
Take this letter to the castle
and give it to Marya.
This time, leave the letter
on Ares' throne.
Let Ares know we mean business.
His knees will go weak
when he hears that he's paying
10,000 gold coins to take to Ertuğrul.
I'll make you eat that letter
before you die, Antheus.
Ares, catch him!
Simko.
Where did he take Ertuğrul?
Tell me everything.
I'll tell you everything, sir.
Please spare my life.
Where did Simko take Ertuğrul?
Spare my life, sir.
He told me to wait here.
He'd bring Ertuğrul here.
He's bringing Ertuğrul here, huh?
Prepare yourselves!
We'll wait here.
There's a young man
that's chained up, sir.
Look at that,
new slaves fell into our laps.
Surround them.
Such a shame.
They'll become slaves, just like us.
We need men, Pito.
That's good.
There'll be more of us.
Look at me.
From now on,
I own everything that belongs to you.
You're my prisoners now.
Take the four in the back.
Kill the cripple, he won't be any good.
Are you Marya's brother?
Yes, sir.
My sister Marya...
Is she okay?
You'll never know.
Bring Marya here.
Yes, sir!
Attack!
May your table be blessed, Bahadir Bey.
The food is so delicious.
Enjoy your supper, Majesty Emir.
From now on,
I will throw many more banquets
for you, if God lets me.
God willing.
So...
Bahadir Bey's group will be here soon.
When will you establish
the Council of Beys?
I'll have to talk to my beys first.
If they decide on merging two groups,
I'll do what's necessary
for the Beylic council.
Many Turk nomad groups
have departed to immigrate
to these lands with our sultan's order.
Likewise, Bahadir Bey
came here on our sultan's command.
So whatever you
and your beys decide on,
Bahadir Bey will settle down here.
There's nothing
we can do if there's an order.
However my Ertuğrul Bey
and Aliyar Bey have their legacies.
To serve our government
we'll unite with the Kayis.
And I have no desire
to leave the Beylic for this will.
You're dragging your feet, Aslıhan Hatun.
You're still talking about the Kayi.
The Kayis will immigrate.
Bahadir Bey will take over the bazaar.
Think about your own people.
The Kayis haven't immigrated yet,
nor has Bahadir Bey taken over
the Hanlı Bazaar.
Don’t count your chickens
before they hatch.
She's hiding behind the Kayis,
to top it off she got engaged
to their man as a Cavdar woman
who has Bey blood in her.
Don't overstep the line, Bahadir Bey.
You're the one to overstepping
by rejecting tradition,
Aslıhan Hatun.
If you'll excuse me, Majesty Emir.
Aslıhan Hatun, Turgut Alp has arrived.
He wants to come in if you'll let him.
Let him come in, Kırca.
He should come right in.
Guards.
Peace be with you.
Peace be upon you.
We got to the border with the Cavdar men
and fulfilled our mission justly,
Majesty Emir.
We haven't let those bandits
who tried taking advantage
of our government being at war...
to step into our lands.
We heard about that.
The bravery of you and your men
reached our ears.
You have become the pride
of our government
and relied upon by our sultan, Turgut Alp.
Thank you.
May our sultan...
and our government stand tall.
You've got seven casualties,
Aslıhan Hatun.
We have carried out our last duty.
We took their weapons to their families.
I'm sorry for your loss.
It's for our government,
and our land we die for, Turgut Alp.
May God never destroy that.
Welcome.
Thank you.
I'd like to see you when you're available
to return your men to you,
and to give you information,
Aslıhan Hatun.
It's not the time for it,
Commander.
Aslıhan Hatun, sit down.
We are consulting Majesty Emir here.
I think our conversation is over,
Bahadir Bey.
I said what's necessary.
You leave...
the presence of Majesty Emir...
to talk to this commander.
You don't have morals
nor do you follow tradition.
You can't teach me about tradition.
If the hatun of the pavilion
and the Emir is here
your words mean nothing.
How dare you!
What do you want?
Where are you travelling to?
To Red Apple.
Give me your name, brave man.
Atsız.
Come on, Ertuğrul Bey.
It's the battle of freedom.
Come on.
Is it tradition to advance
towards a hatun that took over...
the Beylic, Bahadir Bey?
You have no manners!
How dare you touch a bey?
Turgut!
Ertuğrul Bey, he's running.
Go after that scumbag.
We'll take care of ourselves.
You're all free.
Godspeed to you.
May God protect you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Come on, brave men. After him.
Come on, brave men.
Giddy up!
God help you, Turkish Bey.
I'll never forget you.