Episode 116 will start after 12:40 min.
Everything is in order
at the castle, my bey.
The Christians are able
to trade and practice their faith.
Very good. Send my regards
to the Christian people, Günalp Bey.
I will speak with them myself
as soon as I can.
Yes, my bey.
My Bey, upon your invitation,
scholars and merchants
have begun moving
to the land of your frontier beylic.
Good, good.
Show great respect to the scholars.
And treat every merchant equally.
Trade will flourish at our market.
With knowledge and craftsmanship
coming together,
we will become a fully-fledged
society, God willing.
God willing, my bey.
We will not set up our stand
until we have found the best pitch.
As you wish.
Keep your eyes open.
Where gold flows like water
there will be mud in abundance.
May our hunt be glorious.
We shall soon see our sacks filled.
When will we begin preparations
for the migration to Sogut, my bey?
So that the migration to Sogut
is free of trouble and fighting,
and the people's
prosperity is not affected,
I've decided to delay it, Turgut.
Order has been established, thank God.
Once Ahmet gets here
and we have heard his news,
we can make a start on the preparations.
May it be for the good, my bey.
May it be for the good.
Just as the ones we have lost
have taken root in our hearts...
we will take root in that land,
God willing.
Aslıhan was the first Turk
to be buried in Sogut.
May it fall upon us
to rightfully settle there.
Amen.
God willing, Turgut. God willing.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-Speak.
Preparations for the spring feast
are finished over at the tribe.
The people are waiting for you.
My bey, this feast will be good
for us and for our tribes.
I hope our good fortune increases
with the coming of spring.
Come on, then.
We don't want to keep the people waiting.
Let's celebrate the coming of spring
with a feast worthy of our traditions.
All right, my bey.
What business do those hunters have here?
It's obvious what they want
from the hides they're carrying, Master.
They want trouble.
Then trouble they will find.
Keep an eye on them.
What is it you seek, woman?
I find what I seek
in great forests, my man.
Not in your dump of a shop.
Then don't loiter in front of my stand.
Get going!
-What's this worth?
-Two gold coins.
You're not ashamed to ask for two gold
coins for this quiver?
I bet you ask three
gold coin for this, huh?
Who is this woman?
Woman!
Leave before I trample you
and those so-called hunters
you ride with under my feet.
Why?
So that you can sell goatskin
to people, saying it's deer hide?
I told you to leave, woman!
Who is the protector of this market?
Tell me,
who is the protector of this market?
I am.
And who are you?
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
Now tell me...
who are you and what is your business?
My name is Almila Hatun.
I am a hunter and fur trader.
My brother is Eynece.
The best hunter this world has ever seen.
He is a scout.
From the tension of his bow,
and the range of his arrow,
not a bear or a wolf, a deer
or even a fly is safe, my bey.
And Master Karamis is the best tanner
the world has seen.
All right. Now tell me...
what brings you to my market
and has you arguing with my craftsmen?
This bastard you call a craftsman...
is nothing but a market thug,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We process the hides of the animals.
We hunt in the mountains and forests,
and tan them and sell them.
We don't sell goatskin to people
and call it deer hide,
like this joke of a tradesman.
When we fled the Mongolian threat,
we visited many markets like this one
and frequently suffered
at the hands of bastards like him,
who sell the hides we toil to hunt and tan
for two or three times their worth.
We are at the end
of our road now, Ertuğrul Bey.
Any further and we
enter the land of the infidels.
Either we set down here
and earn our bread honestly,
just like the other tradesmen who
believed in you and came here,
or we make raids on the infidel lands
like our ancestors did... and take lives.
Is what this woman says true?
I do what trade requires me to do, my bey.
My merchandise is displayed on my stand.
People are free to buy it or not.
When you process the leather
you don't use fresh acorns...
but acorns that have fallen
on the ground and crystallized.
As if that wasn't bad enough,
you haven't even managed
to give the goatskin a proper sheen.
You are no craftsman, you are a fraud.
What's worse, you're selling
goatskin by calling it deer hide.
Have you no shame?
You are a disgrace to all craftsmen.
Ertuğrul Bey, aren't you going
to put this woman in her place?
Our God created the heavens
and set the standards.
"To prove the Truth to be true,
and the false to be false."
Doesn't he say that in the holy Qur'an?
He does, my bey.
Does he not also say,
"Give full measure
and weight. Don't withhold from people
things that are rightly theirs."
He does, my bey.
Doesn't he say, "Do not spread
corruption in the land."
Answer me Doesn't he?
He does, my bey.
Alps.
Get this troublemaker out
of my market this instant! Go!
Forgive me, my bey. Ertuğrul Bey!
Artuk Bey...
I don't want to see this man or
his merchandise in my market ever again.
As you wish, my bey.
Forgive me, Ertuğrul Bey.
Please don't do this.
Ertuğrul Bey! Don't do this! Forgive me!
Now speak, Almila Hatun.
What is it you want?
As our God commands,
I want a place at your market
to trade honestly, Ertuğrul Bey.
How can Ertuğrul Bey know
that you'll do your job properly, hatun?
We didn't come here just to sell
our goods and go out to hunt,
but to build a tannery
and develop trade, commander.
We wish to remain here,
with God's permission.
If we fail, you can come
and take our heads.
How will you manage this, hatun?
What will you do?
There are forests filled with acorns
in your territory.
We will provide jobs to the unemployed
at the tannery we will build
next to the river.
We'll bring quality goods
to the market to sell.
We will grow the trade
to the infidel provinces through here.
I have masters coming after me.
They are on their way.
They come to practice their craft
in the place that best suits them.
That is, if you will allow us.
This stand is yours and I agree
to you building a tannery, Almila Hatun.
However, and make sure
you understand this well...
I am in charge here.
If you go against my word,
you won't be able to sell your stuff here.
I will crush you.
Come on, Artuk Bey.
Be wary of that woman, Artuk Bey.
I want to know everything she does.
As you wish, my bey.
A letter has arrived
from the emperor, sir.
What is it, Kritos?
The emperor... he's decided
against sending an army.
He wants peace to continue.
Coward!
He stalled us for months.
We could have destroyed Ertuğrul
while the sultan was on the Amid campaign.
We can't give up, Kritos.
We can never give up.
I can't live without
avenging my son, Ares.
Not just your son,
we have to avenge
every soldier they killed, Kritos.
That is God's command to us.
-My son's death won't be in vain, Ares.
-It won't, Kritos.
Don't worry. We can do this on our own.
We can still avenge your son. Trust me.
I will finish Ertuğrul with my own army.
I'm putting you in charge
of preparing them, Ares.
Get them ready to fight the Turks.
We'll deal with them before Ertuğrul
migrates to Sogut with his tribe.
If we do this, my son may yet
rest in peace in his grave.
Yes, Kritos.
Ertuğrul Bey has returned.
Mother, my father's coming!
I'm going to learn to forge iron
with my father!
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you!
-Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you!
My girl, you're almost due.
Why don't you go rest in the tent?
I'm fine, Mother, don't worry.
It's better if the bey's hatun
is with him on the day of the feast.
Welcome, Ertuğrul!
Welcome, my bey!
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
Well, would you look at my young man!
Father!
-Welcome.
-I'm glad to be back, my brave son.
Mother.
-Welcome.
-It's good to see you, Mother.
Welcome, my bey.
I'm so glad to see you, my doe-eyed one.
May God let you be with us
for many more feasts, Ertuğrul.
Amen. Amen, doe-eyes.
Father, I'm going to learn to forge iron!
I'm going to hit it for Savcı
and for my soon-to-be-born brother, too.
Just look at my brave son.
Then go get your hammer
and take your place next to the anvil.
Come on then, brave boy.
Valiant beys
and valiant hatuns of the Kayi.
Centuries ago, when our ancestors
melted the iron mountain and got out...
it was the first day of spring.
As our ancestors
melted the iron mountain and got out...
the Turks were reborn.
The Turk was reborn
and spring came to the world.
Now, just as we have celebrated
the coming of spring for centuries...
may our future generations
also celebrate the coming of spring
for centuries to come.
God willing.
Amen. God willing.
-Amen.
-Amen. God willing.
Amen. God willing.
Amen.
Then, as our bey,
you must strike the first blow...
so that the iron mountains may hear it!
Let our feast begin, my bey.
-Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
-Thank you, Turgut Bey.
-Thank you, my bey.
Günalp Bey!
Come, let us see your worth.
Thank you, my bey.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
God is life. God is just.
Come on, valiant beys.
-Bismillah.
-God is life!
-God is just!
God is life! God is just!
God is life. God is just.
Look, the guy who told us
about this caravan was right.
-They're carrying plenty of merchandise.
-We're all going to be rich.
Come on, let's not let them get away.
Raid! Raid!
Raid!
Who are they?
Kill them!
I've carried many a sheep before
but it will be my first race against you.
Chief Alp Turgut, who is the most
formidable in the Kayi tribe?
We've raced against Ertuğrul Bey
since we were children.
Nobody's ever won a race he's
competed in yet. That's all I'll say.
Thank you, my friend.
Brave men! Will anyone else race?
I will, my bey!
-Bamsi?
-I will!
My brother! Welcome back!
How could you play Get the Goat
without Bamsi, my bey? How could you?
My Bey, my bey.
Look at my brave man.
Welcome, my brother.
-Welcome, my brave man.
-Glad to be here, my bey.
Mother, Mother Hayme. Mother...
-Mother Hayme.
-Welcome.
It's good to see you, Mother.
How have you been, Bamsi?
How is Hafsa Hatun?
How is the child, Bamsi Alp?
Fine. Fine!
My child was born, praise God.
-Praise be!
Praise be.
I have a daughter... bright as a star!
Praise be!
Would you look at my brother!
May you have armies of sons,
and tribes of daughters, my brave man!
Why didn't you bring them?
They're comfortable
where they are, my bey.
Let them stay a little longer,
collect themselves, then I'll bring them.
Very good, very good.
May God let her grow with
her parents, Chief Alp Bamsi.
Thank you, Günalp Bey. Thank you.
And I said the prayer into her ear.
And I named her... Aslıhan.
May God bestow many children upon you.
May she live long.
May she be lucky, God willing.
Thank you, brother. Well...
I've missed you all so much.
And I got here just in time
for the spring feast.
My Bey, with your permission,
I'd like to join Get the Goat,
get this rust off.
Could there be a contest without Bamsi?
Come on, join us
so that they may see a real competitor.
-Thank you, thank you, my bey!
-Get ready Bamsi, go on!
Thank you, my bey!
Fall back, quickly!
It's time to speak with Ertuğrul Bey.
Take the caravan to Hanlı Bazaar.
You, come with me.
To the Kayi Village.
Come on, men.
Bismillahirramanirrahim!
Allah!
Come on!
Go, Father! Run!
Go! Run!
Run, Father!
Come here, Father!
Father!
Ertuğrul Bey! Ertuğrul Bey!
You were so strong, Father!
You beat them all!
Grow up
and we'll race too.
-Mashallah to my men!
-Mashallah!
Mashallah!
-My bey.
-Günalp Bey.
-My friend.
Mashallah, men.
My dear, don't wear yourself out.
I'm fine, don't worry.
Even when I sit, he doesn't stop.
If he really is Osman, like we've dreamed,
then nobody will be able to stop him.
Halime, a little crazy is always good.
Our babies should be a little crazy
so they can advance their father's legacy.
I hope so.
My bey.
Speak.
Almıla Hatun from the bazaar
and two men are here.
They wish to see you.
Who is this woman?
Where are they?
Damn it!
Stop!
Where to?
Answer me.
Kill this man.
What do you wish to cover
during our council discussion?
A discussion?
Our caravan was ambushed by bandits,
and you want a discussion?
Bandits?
Where?
The forest road. My men are dead.
Chief Alp Bamsi.
It's been a while since we've
encountered bandits.
Where did they come from?
The alps are always on patrol, my bey.
The road for the caravan is clear.
Apparently...
not so clear.
Ertuğrul Bey.
We came at your invitation.
We were told your lands were safe.
We trusted you.
But our men died
before we even reached the bazaar.
We almost lost all our goods.
You can't hold a council meeting
and leave your guests
to the bandits' mercy.
Woman.
Watch your mouth.
You're speaking
to the frontier bey, Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul Bey secured these lands
with pride.
He won't give them up to some bandits.
We'll take care of the bandits.
We'll reimburse you for the lost goods.
Bandits never lasted long
in our territory before,
and they won't last now.
Rest assured.
Go back to the bazaar and do your work.
I hope you're right, Ertuğrul Bey.
We're here for our bread.
If you can't protect us,
we'll have to protect ourselves.
Excuse us.
The woman was out of line, my bey.
Her caravan was ambushed.
Her men died.
We'll overlook it.
Should I send men from the castle
to hunt the bandits?
No need, Günalp Bey.
Bamsi.
Tell the alps.
Turgut, Günalp Bey.
Get ready.
We'll take care of those bandits
who are brave enough
to ambush a caravan.
All right, my bey.
Who is this man, Leon?
I don't know, sir.
He said he was a traveler.
He's no ordinary man.
I'm sure he has important information.
About what?
Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul?
What does he want?
Ertuğrul's head.
Bring him in.
As you wish.
What can you tell me about Ertuğrul?
You are watching Ertuğrul.
You seek revenge for your son.
But first, you must purge
the scum around you.
Who are you? What are you saying?
Just call me the Traveler, Governor.
These must be the bandits.
-They look like bandits.
-You're right, Turgut.
They have good swords.
They must be good at fighting and looting.
The merchants must be good fighters, too,
since they gave them such a beating.
They sure are, my bey.
They learned how to fight
to save themselves
from ambushes like this.
Or perhaps...
they're used to fighting bandits.
My bey.
There's blood on the river bed.
It goes that way.
Come on, let's follow it.
Did you like it?
Yes, Grandma.
I made them myself.
Gave them to the tribe's babies.
It's the spring council.
Let's make them happy.
Don't worry, Mother Hayme.
We'll distribute them
alongside the molasses.
All right, dear.
-Mother?
-Yes?
Whoever that woman is,
she has cast a shadow on the council.
Oh, dear.
Her caravan was ambushed,
so she was angry.
Nobody should enter
a council meeting like that.
I don't know about that,
but I know I don't like her.
Once Ertuğrul kills the bandits,
he'll find out if the woman has
any secrets.
What happened?
I think he kicked.
Halime?
Are you okay?
My dear, that doesn't look like a kick.
You're right.
This isn't a kick.
Lie down now.
Alçiçek.
Prepare the bed.
As you order.
Gündüz, take those clothes and give them
to your brothers and sisters in the tribe.
-Go now.
-Okay, Grandma.
Come, dear.
-All right then.
-Come here.
Slowly, slowly...
Okay.
It hurts, Mother. Your grandson is coming.
Hold on, dear. Be strong.
God willing, my grandson will come.
Who knows, maybe he's our promised Osman.
Alçiçek.
Give Savcı to me.
Oh, dear.
Your brother is coming.
Alçiçek, boil some water.
Tell the midwives.
Halime Hatun is giving birth.
As you order.
Mother, it hurts a lot.
Hold on dear, almost there.
Hold on, Halime. Come on.
Hold on.
Oh, my dear baby.
Who are you? What do you want?
How dare you attack
a caravan in our territory,
headed towards our bazaar?
That's Ertuğrul! Attack!
Who are you?
How dare you attack this caravan
on our land?
We...
A man told us
that they were carrying many goods.
He told us where they would be.
Who was he?
I don't know him.
I don't know.
But we believed him.
This is not a normal caravan attack.
Whoever that man is,
he wanted them to attack this caravan.
Whoever he is, he must
have a problem with the tanners.
Not just anyone could do such a thing
in our land, my bey.
Who did this?
Who made these bandits attack
that woman and the tanners?
Look what I brought you
from Constantinople.
Do you like it?
What happened, Kritos?
Emir Sadettin, the one Ertuğrul killed.
What about him?
Did also you sleep with Emir Sadettin...
to aid in your escape
from Ertuğrul's dungeons?
Kritos!
What are you saying?
You used my son's pain!
You used my hate for Ertuğrul!
You became my woman!
You took my deepest secrets
to Emir Sadettin!
How could you, Marya?
How could you?
You will die!
You're hurting me.
My love and loyalty to you is genuine.
I accepted Emir Sadettin's offer
to leave the dungeon.
But once you took me in,
I never betrayed you.
I loved you, Kritos.
I really did.
You're my everything.
You lie! You will die!
You love me so much you want to kill me.
So...
the Traveler was right.
Now it's Ares' turn.
I mean...
Ahmet's turn.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun, my bey.
Brother Ahmet.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
-Come.
-Thanks.
Come on, men.
I hope you have good news, Ahmet.
I do, my bey. I have great news for you.
Speak.
Did Governor Kritos decide
to conquer Karacahisar Castle?
If only.
That would make things easy.
Indeed.
But you were right, Ertuğrul Bey.
Once Sultan Gıyaseddin ensured stability
in the Seljuk State,
Nicaea didn't send the army.
I had hoped for a fight.
I wanted to go after the infidels.
Patience, Turgut.
The governor won't stand idle.
He'll do everything to prevent us
from getting to Söğüt.
He won't wait long.
He asked me to get the men ready.
The governor's soldiers
are easy prey for us.
But for the wealth and happiness
of the people
in my land,
I will postpone the migration for now.
If the governor acts,
it will be a bloodbath.
It will hurt trade too.
Unfortunately.
There are many innocents,
Muslim and non-Muslim.
The governor's ambition and revenge
will hurt them.
I fear for the order
you've managed to establish.
My bey...
they won't dare attack the castle.
If you allow it, I wish to stand guard
outside with my men.
We can send a message to Governor Kritos
without scaring the people.
Good idea, Günalp Bey.
Do that.
The castle must be guarded
by enough men at all times.
We'll send alps to the castle.
Close the gates after sundown
for security.
As you wish.
We'll use the governor's woman, Marya...
and plot against him, Ahmet.
If we kill the governor,
the fire of his vengeance will dissipate.
As you order.
But... there are other reasons why
the emperor doesn't want peace.
Make sure that the emperor
won't send another army.
Why?
Mongols.
We know that Ögedei
and his armies aim for the south,
the fertile lands
of the Euphrates and Tigris.
I heard in Nicaea that...
Ögedei is ready to invade Anatolia.
His army is led by his trusted commander.
If the Sultan makes a mistake
or shows weakness,
they'll invade Anatolia and spill blood.
Everyone will be killed.
They won't stop until Constantinople.
Who is leading the invasion, Ahmet?
A man called Noyan, I've heard.
Ertuğrul, I've been reborn from my ashes
so I might kill you and your bloodline.
Alangoya.
Yes, Brother.
I trained you for this.
Come here, my brave sister.
Tell me what you've done.
I did my duty.
-Did you see Ertuğrul?
-I did.
Tell me.
I exploited his sense of honesty
and honor and got a place at his bazaar.
He trusts me now.
I even met his wife and mother.
My savage hawk. Well done.
You proved once again
that you're the pride of this empire.
I've made many sacrifices to the spirits
for giving me such a sister.
From now on, you'll be able to offer them
the blood and meat of the Turks.
My comrades...
My comrades died
so that you'd be able
to seduce Ertuğrul.
May the spirits protect them
from Erlik Khan's wrath.
May their paths be clear.
Now, let's do our duty.
What are you saying?
Where did Noyan come from?
He died. My bey,
that demon died. We saw it.
Do you know that devil?
I do, Ahmet.
I know him well.
Welcome to Noyan's hell, Ertuğrul.
So, you're Noyan.
The hellhound himself!
Brother?
Brother, brother!
Hold on. You'll be fine, Brother.
My bey.
How can that be? We all saw it.
When my brother Sungur was injured,
we panicked
and set off to take him home.
We just left Noyan's body there.
My bey. You destroyed Noyan.
You slashed him all over.
That scum was covered in blood.
I know, Bamsi, I know.
But he's alive.
That means that dog...
isn't after Anatolia.
He'll be after you, my bey.
Noyan! Noyan! Noyan!
For Cayan in the upper worlds.
Cayan! Cayan! Cayan!
For the sons and daughters of Erlik Khan
in the underworld!
Erlik Khan!
For the love of Munci and Musval!
-Munci! Musval!
-Death!
Munci, Musval!
My brave warriors who would even make love
until death for Genghis Khan.
Be the nightmare of the Kayis.
Fall onto them like death.
For the love of Munci, Musval!
Munci! Musval!
We are the vanguard,
and we are here to raid these lands.
We will flow steadily but strongly,
like the rivers of Seyhun and Ceyhun,
and open up a path for our army.
We'll drink Turkish blood and go crazy.
Remember.
We are facing a brave
and honorable warrior.
An undefeated warrior. Ertugrul.
Ertugrul! Ertugrul! Ertugrul!
The smartest and bravest warrior
of the Turks.
We're not here to openly challenge him
or his alps to open combat,
we are here to kill their souls,
to lock their souls in the hell
of Erlik Khan.
We are here to put an end
to the state of the Seljuks.
For the love of Munci and Musval!
May Tengri feel the sweat
of our brave warriors.
May the mountain of steel fill
with the awe of the spirits.
May our warriors' courage reach the skies.
May their spirits
enlighten the whole world.
Oh, the moon and the sun!
Blessed trees decorated with rags!
The holy beech tree with leaves!
Owner of the blazing flames, Ak Yayik!
Oh, holy Tengri!
The water of life with a thousand ears!
The lord in the skies with cloudy eyes!
The gentleman with icy feet!
Clouds and horses, Lord!
Please accept them
to the world of spirits.
Noyan! Noyan! Noyan!
They are far away from us, my bey.
They can't harm us from this distance
unless the Mongols decide
to invade our state.
No, Gunalp Bey.
If the task to invade our country
has been given to Noyan...
at first, he will try to surround us
from within.
He will probably place men everywhere,
including our tribes and even the palace.
His hatred towards me is so immense...
that if let inside the western borders,
he will not stop coming after me,
even if I go to the end of the world.
Noyan! Noyan! Noyan!
I've been resurrected
from the ashes, Ertugrul.
I'm back to strike fear and despair
in your heart.
Noyan! Noyan! Noyan!
Push, Lady Halime.
-Mother.
-Huh?
I'm so thirsty. Please give me some water.
Of course. Okay, my girl.
Give her some water.
Here, my girl.
Give it here.
Just a little harder, my girl.
God, please help her.
Balcicek, did you let Artuk Bey know
about the situation?
We did, Mother Hayme.
He must be on his way.
Come on, hang in there.
With God's permission, you'll have
a beautiful, healthy baby.
Come on.
Governor, come. Take a seat.
Welcome.
Go ahead, drink it.
I don't want to drink now, stranger.
Come on, drink it.
It revives the faded spirits.
What kind of wine is this?
It looks like blood.
What I poured into your glass is not wine,
it's blood.
I missed the taste of Turkish blood.
Come on, drink it. It'll help you
to forget about your dead son.
I won't drink it.
I'm here to tell you that you were right.
Maria accepted that she was working
under the commands of Sadettin.
So, you finally believe me, huh?
Now it's that bastard Ares' turn,
who changed his name to Ahmet.
Don't you touch Ares.
What is on your mind, traveler?
Ares will give me Ertugrul
and he will give you his life.
Do you understand?
Good. We will be good partners.
But first, tell me who you are.
I told you. I'm merely a traveler.
I'll be the closest friend
you have ever had or will have.
I'm a traveler who is on the hunt
for Ertugrul.
You'll learn more when I have him
in my grip.
Come on, governor. Drink it. Huh?
Father!
My brother is coming.
Yes, son. Yes, he is.
How is your mother?
Grandmother and the nurses
are taking care of her.
Very well.
You'll be responsible for your brother
once he arrives, right?
Yes, Father. I'll take care of him.
I will even train him with swords
once he is grown up.
Very well, my brave son.
Mother.
Son.
-How is Halime?
-She is fine, son. Don't worry.
Things are going smoothly.
Thank God, Mother.
Thank God.
I am unable to contain myself, Mother.
I know, Son.
Just be patient a little longer.
I'll go help them now.
Pray to hold
a healthy baby in your arms.
I will, Mother.
Father, is the baby a girl or a boy?
Come here, Son.
It will be whatever God wants it to be.
But, we had received the good news
of Osman's arrival.
Your mother, grandmother and I
saw him in our dreams.
But it's up to Allah, Son.
Once the baby is here,
I can protect it if it is a girl.
Of course, you can, Son.
My brave son.
You are the glorious Gunduz Alp.
Father, how did you meet with my mother?
Why do you call her "my gazelle"?
I saw your mother
thanks to a gazelle, Gunduz.
-Father!
-Halime!
Oh, God!
Let's get out of here quickly.
You should go.
We can take care of ourselves.
-It's easy to handle a bunch of templars.
-Let's see how he will handle this.
-Now, he is in trouble.
-He definitely is.
-What can you do as a woman on your own?
-I said we wouldn't come.
We owe you our lives.
And we will repay you one day.
Tell me your name.
Ertugrul, from the Kayi tribe.
As you wish.
May God help you. Farewell.
Let's go with them, Sister.
Is your tribe far from here?
Is that why you call her "my gazelle"?
Yes, Son.
That's why.
Your mother is as delicate as a gazelle.
And she has the eyes of a gazelle.
Should I go and see Mother?
I can encourage her.
Come on, now.
Men don't enter the birth room.
We'll wait for your brother to come.
Ertugrul is here.
He awaits the good news
of his baby. Come on, my beautiful girl.
-Is Ertugrul here?
-Yes, he is.
Come on, Lady Halime. Push.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-Just a little bit more.
The baby is here!
Father, it's the sound of my brother!
That's right, son. It's your brother.
Thank God.
Thank God a thousand times.
Oh, thank God.
Praise to God.
You have had a very healthy baby boy,
Lady Halime.
Oh, my beautiful boy.
He smells like heaven.
A thousand thanks to God.
May God bless your life.
He looks so healthy.
Mother.
My girl.
-My Osman.
-Osman.
-Mother.
-Here, take our Osman.
My Osman.
The news of his arrival came before him.
I would die for you.
You've brought happiness to our tent
and our tribe, my lion.
My baby.
What a beautiful baby he is, Mother.
God, thank you so much for letting me
experience such a beautiful moment.
May God bless his tribe
and his life, Lady Halime.
May God gift him
with beautiful experiences.
Amen.
Ladies, God bless you, too.
Thank you, ladies.
Excuse us.
My girl?
Are you okay?
I'm fine, Mother.
Give the news to Ertugrul.
Take Osman to him.
-My girl, are you okay?
-I'm fine, Mother. Take Osman.
Okay. Try and rest, okay?
Mother.
It's a boy, my son.
Our Osman is here.
Oh, my.
My Osman.
My brave son.
Thank God for giving us our visions
and delivering you.
Father.
Your dreams came true. Osman is here.
My brother.
Mother. Tell me, how is my Halime?
She is fine, Son. She will be better
once she rests a little more.
Hopefully so.
My bey.
Come, Artuk Bey.
Welcome, Artuk Bey.
Our Osman is here.
What a beautiful child.
He rose upon our tribe like the sun.
May God bless him, my bey.
May God make him happy both
in this life and in the afterlife.
Amen.
Lady Hayme.
How is Lady Halime?
She is fine, Artuk Bey.
She is resting.
I wanted you to be here just in case.
Of course.
My bey...
whisper Osman's name to his ears.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Ertugrul Bey, may I come in?
Please come in.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselam.
Finally, you have your baby,
my Ertugrul Bey.
May God bless his fortune.
May he be victorious, just like you.
-Amen.
It's the will of my father, Suleyman Shah.
He wanted his name to be Osman.
I'd like you to be the whisperer
of his name, if you would be so kind.
Allahuakbar.
I bear witness
that there is no God but Allah
and that Muhammad is his messenger.
Come to prayer,
come to salvation.
Allahuakbar.
There is no God but Allah.
Your name is Osman.
Your grandfather gave you your name.
May God give you a blessed life.
Amen.
Let it be known to the angels in the skies
and the subjects on Earth,
your name is Osman.
May God give you a good fortune.
May you live a beautiful life and prosper.
May you be a subject to Allah,
a good follower of our prophet,
and a servant to the world of Islam.
May you be glorious and victorious.
-Amen.
Thank you very much.
Now, excuse me.
Come on, now.
Artuk Bey.
I didn't want to startle Ertugrul,
but Halime is holding her chest
and she has difficulty breathing.
It'd be better for you to be here...
just in case.
Of course.
My Halime.
My beloved.
Mother of my three children.
Our son Osman, whose news of arrival
was given by Suleyman Shah, is here.
Your son, Osman...
He will change our bad fortune
and make these lands a base for Oguz.
Let us take our bows and shields
with the oaths of my Oguz ancestors.
May this be a signature for us.
May we create a jungle
from our iron spears.
Many more seas and rivers.
May the sky be our tent
and the sun be our flag.
Allahuakbar!
My Halime.
We've seen the news of Osman's arrival
in many blessed dreams.
And God gave him to us in the spring time.
What a blessed child this is.
What a blessed baby this is.
He will bring joy and happiness
to our tribe and tent.
Oh, Son!
Fine son!
Blessed son!
May your only guidance be the holy Qur'an
and the deeds of our prophet.
May your traditions be
that of your Oguz ancestors'.
May your sword carry justice and wisdom
just like the sword of Zulfiqar,
and take it
to the four corners of the world.
Have such a great purpose...
so, it shall make the world look small.
Oh, Son!
Fine son!
Be a worthy person of your mother's milk
and your ancestors' blood.
May you always be victorious.
May your flag never drop in your battles.
May you never give in to despair.
We have prayed so much for you,
may God gather them all and accept them
for the sake of our prophet.
We have been waiting so long
for this news.
Osman came in a spring time,
which will bring more happiness
to our tribe.
Then, we will celebrate his arrival
with another fine festival.
Of course, Brother. For sure.
I shall let the beys of Cavdar know
right away.
They will come and visit.
Hopefully, Osman's arrival
will bring good fortune to our tribes.
Hopefully so.
Hopefully.
Ertugrul.
My Halime.
My Osman.
Our Osman is here, my Halime.
Thank God.
Are you okay, my Halime?
I'm okay.
Hush.
Now that I gave birth
to our Osman safe and sound,
held him in our tent...
and smelled his heavenly smell...
I feel like the world is mine.
My gazelle eyed wife...
mother of my three children.
You made me feel like the world was mine
when you gave birth to my children.
Long ago,
because of the clashes for the throne,
my father and siblings and I
suffered very much.
There was always trouble, Ertugrul.
I told myself,
"Halime, it seems
you'll never sleep peacefully."
But my God, who rewards the patience,
has also rewarded my patience.
What a beautiful fortune I have
to be your beloved wife
and your children's mother.
A thousand thanks to God
who led me to you while chasing a gazelle.
You waited for me when I went to battle.
You helped my tent stand strong.
Sometimes, you lost your sleep
and appetite.
You never stopped or rested.
You raised my two children and gave birth
to another in all this chaos.
-How can I pay this debt, my Halime?
-Don't say that, Ertugrul.
I pray for you to be safe and sound.
To be always victorious.
To always be there to lead our tribe.
That's all I ask for.
All I ask of my God is...
for you, my Gunduz, my Savci...
my Osman...
to be safe and sound in this world.
We'll be safe
and sound together, my Halime.
We'll raise our children
and see them become alps.
We'll see them become beys.
My Ertugrul, let me feed Osman
his first milk.
You should go back.
Many will come to celebrate, for sure.
Okay, my Halime. Okay.
Oi! My bey!
My bey!
May God grant him a great fortune,
my bey.
He will be a brave bey
just like his father, for sure.
Hopefully so, Bamsi. Thank you.
-My Turgut!
-My bey!
Congratulations, my bey.
-Thank you, my lion.
-May God bless his life.
And grant him with many victories.
Hopefully so, my Turgut. Thank you.
Sons, I will go see her.
Very well, Mother.
Come, brave men. Take a seat.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillah.
It's my order, Artuk Bey...
extend the celebrations for three days
to celebrate Osman's arrival.
As you order, my bey.
Let the beys of Oguz know.
Invite them to the celebrations.
They should bring their wrestlers, my bey.
So that I can show them
the strongest wrestler is from the Kayis.
Then...
first, you are going to need
to wrestle with the wrestler of Cavdars.
Let's see if you can best him.
My Turgut Bey, who is he?
It's me.
So, you want to wrestle with me, huh?
I'd like to wrestle to honor Osman
if my bey allows me.
Of course, my brave brothers.
Show everyone what it means
to be valiant warriors.
Thank you, my bey.
Then, excuse us, my bey.
We'll make the preparations.
Very well.
-Thank you, my bey.
-Thank you.
Come on, brother.
My bey...
Lady Halime gave birth just a while ago.
It'd be better for me to stay here,
just in case.
Well thought, Artuk Bey.
Stay here, just in case.
My Osman...
I fed my baby for the first time.
After that, I feel at ease.
Wait a little.
You'll have to breastfeed him so many
more times until he can chew meat.
Come here, you little lion.
Your grandma would die for you.
Oh my sweetie.
There.
Come on.
Sleep peacefully.
Oh my dear.
I had the honor of...
being the wife of Ertuğrul Bey...
and the daughter-in-law of Mother Hayme
and Süleyman Shah.
I had three beautiful children
for my Ertuğrul.
Who would think...
that Halime Sultan who swayed...
from side to side with many troubles...
would become the wife of...
the glorious Ertuğrul Bey
and give him three children?
My daughter...
My God granted you such
a beautiful destiny.
My God made you meet Ertuğrul...
you've been a daughter to us,
more than a daughter-in-law.
I thank my God a thousand times
for giving you to us.
You stood tall against many more troubles
than we did.
You've always been by my Ertuğrul's side.
May God bless you.
May God bless you, Mother.
May my Ertuğrul Bey always be
victorious in this world.
May God protect him from any harm.
May he never have
any worries in his heart.
May my village, my home
and you always feel at peace.
My children...
May they be worthy of their names,
fame,
their ancestors and their parents.
I have always fulfilled
my responsibilities...
towards myself and my tribe.
That's my only wish from God.
We'll be happy together.
We'll all see your children growing up
and becoming such brave men.
Who knows...
Maybe you'll have more children.
My daughter!
Halime!
Are you okay?
I'm fine, Mother.
-I'll let Artuk Bey know.
-Mother!
It's not necessary.
I'm fine.
I'm just tired.
Today, we take the first step towards
our holy mission.
Compared to our mission,
our lives are not important.
The order Ertuğrul has established
is solid.
However.
We are strong enough to destroy that.
May all the warrior spirits...
be by our side.
Let's pray and take an oath.
I swear to Tengri,
the ruler of the earth and the sky…
to the conqueror of the earth,
noble Genghis Khan
and the spirits of his warriors
that terrorized the world.
We'll get our revenge from our enemies
like Ertuğrul,
and rule the world with our holy laws.
I swear we'll build walls with their heads
and make it rain with their blood.
If we don't spill the blood of our enemy,
may Tengri drown us in our own blood.
You haven't slept all night, Bey.
You waited just because I was here.
Go and rest a little.
I can't, Artuk Bey.
I want Halime to wake up first.
Then I'll rest.
Mother, did my Halime wake up?
She should wake up soon, son.
I'll make some food for Halime.
Thank you, Mother.
My Osman.
My brave boy who brought good news along.
I'd die for you.
Why is my child crying, Artuk Bey?
I'll go and check.
My Halime!
Halime, talk to me!
Artuk Bey!
My Halime!
Your eyes are open, talk to me, my Halime.
Artuk Bey!
Her eyes are open,
but she won't talk, Artuk Bey.
My God, help us.
What's going on?
Son!
My daughter!
Artuk Bey!
I'm sorry for your loss, my Bey.
My daughter!
Oh, my daughter!
My God!
Father!
What happened to my mother?
-Please.
-Grandma!
Mother!
Son, stop!
Nothing happened to my mother.
Get up, Mother!
Her eyes are open!
Her gazelle eyes are open!
Oh my girl...
My daughter!
Don't close them, mother!
Don't close them!
Mother!
Son!
-My boy!
-Mother!
Mother!
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net