Episode 119 will start after 12:20 min.
Noyan!
Attack!
My Bey, Bamsi is wounded on the ground!
We must get rid of them at once
and get help for Bamsi!
Damn it!
Instead of lying down on the battlefield,
I'd rather fight while bleeding.
My Bey...
-Bamsi!
-Brother!
Bamsi! My lion!
Bamsi, say something. Brother, speak up.
Bamsi! Bamsi, are you alright?
Huh?
Well, well, well!
You are trying to escape
while your knights are dying, huh?
Look, let me go.
Then, come to the Bilecik Castle.
I'll give you anything.
Okay.
Deal.
But what I want is your head.
And you can't give it to me.
But I can take it.
My Bey...
I would've been so upset
if I had been lying down
on the battlefield.
My lion.
Abdur Rahman. We need to take Bamsi
and the others to the caravansary at once.
As you order, my Bey.
You'll get better, brother.
You'll get better.
Look what I brought.
Stop there, Noyan!
Why would I do that, huh?
He betrayed Ertuğrul Bey,
he should be the one to punish him.
You can keep using
the damned dagger of betrayal,
we'll keep using
the sword of the righteous.
We will bleed you and create
an ocean of blood
until you stop your betrayal.
Head Alp Bamsi!
My Bey! My Bey, Head Alp Bamsi passed out.
Bamsi! My brother!
My lion! Open your eyes!
Bamsi, open your eyes.
Be quick! We need to go
to the caravansary.
-Bismillah.
-Bamsi...
-Come on.
-Come on!
-Come on, brothers.
Oh my girl, Sugay.
Where are you, my girl?
Where are you?
May I come in?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey...
Sugay Hatun wanted
to visit her child's tomb.
I allowed it and sent two alps with her.
It has been quite a while
but neither Sugay Hatun
nor the alps are back.
This can't be good.
My Osman is crying inside,
he needs to be fed.
Did she tell you
where the tomb is, Hayme Hatun?
I shall send alps after them at once.
Mother Hayme, may I come in?
Come in, Dumrul.
He barely made it to the tribe.
He wants to talk to you.
Have him sit.
Son, what happened to you?
Where are the other alps and Sugay Hatun?
They kidnapped Sugay Hatun, Mother Hayme.
What?
Who did it?
I don't know, my Artuk Bey.
Their faces were covered.
The other alp became a martyr.
I couldn't stop them, my Bey.
Oh my God!
Günkut, Dumrul.
Inform the alps right away.
Have them search everywhere.
No one is to come back
until Sugay Hatun is found.
-As you command.
-As you command, Artuk Bey.
Let's get him to the infirmary tent.
Who are they?
What do they want from Sugay Hatun?
My God!
Please help us.
Help us.
The Mongols!
Please show mercy! I'm at your service!
Please spare our lives!
Please don't hurt us.
Innkeeper!
I am Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
The Mongols are with me.
Welcome, my Bey.
Get us hot water and some cloth at once.
Hurry, Eftelya!
Get hot water and cloth for Ertuğrul Bey!
Hurry, Eftelya! Run!
Come on, be quick!
We need to take care of the wound.
We must stop the bleeding.
-It's all right!
-Where is the hot water?
Here, my Bey!
Be quick! My soldiers are wounded!
Hang in there, my lion!
You'll recover, my brother.
See, I'm cleaning the wound
with my own hands.
They say a brother's hand heals
the others so fast.
Of course.
Come on, brother.
Come on, open your eyes.
Don't think I owe you my life
just because you saved me.
I saved you because we are on a mission.
Apart from that,
I couldn't possibly care less.
Ertuğrul Bey...
We'd like to take care of the wounded
if you allow us, my Bey.
Very well, innkeeper.
Abdur Rahman!
You go outside and guard the place
with the other alps.
As you order, my Bey!
You'll get better, brother.
You'll get better.
Come on, my lion.
Come on, my brother!
What are they doing here?
What's up, Dumrul?
Sugay Hatun was kidnapped, Günalp Bey.
Sugay Hatun?
Who did it?
We are not sure.
Sugay Hatun left the tribe
to visit her child's tomb.
She had two alps with her.
Some unknown men attacked them.
One of the wounded alps came back
to the tribe and informed us.
Sugay Hatun is missing.
Then, let's find her
before anything bad happens.
Come on, Dumrul.
So, the wet nurse was kidnapped.
This information can be useful
for Alangoya.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
God, please help him.
I hope he recovers by midnight.
God willing, my Bey.
God willing.
The demon is coming again, my Bey.
You are surrounded by your enemies
wherever you go, Ertuğrul.
Even if you stay where you are,
someone of your blood line
tries to betray you.
A tree's roots touch the ground...
no matter how tall it is.
Thank God,
we know for sure how to stand our ground
in situations like these.
But if you were
to join forces with Ögedei Khan...
Let alone conquering Nicaea,
we could even have Constantinople
within our grasp.
Do you really believe
that I would accept your Khan
as my leader, Noyan?
Your kin and your state are about to end.
You're in deep trouble.
Various governors realize your situation
and each one tries to take a bite.
You won yesterday.
You also won today.
But no one knows
what will happen tomorrow.
You neither have a place to run away,
nor a corner to take refuge.
During all your time with us,
haven't you realized
that we aren't afraid of the enemy, Noyan?
Ertuğrul, I say...
do what you do best
when the time comes.
Hold onto your swords and horses.
Ögedei Khan is like a wild river.
I say you should get in the river.
You shouldn't swim against the current.
You either join us and flow with us...
or you and your tribe
will vanish in the desert.
My Bey.
Bamsi is trying to say something.
What is it, my lion?
Say it.
My brother...
You'll get better, my brother.
Don't worry, we are with you.
My Bey...
Don't you go without me, my Bey.
Would we ever do that, my lion?
Goodness gracious.
My Bey...
Don't leave me behind.
I won't let you go there without me.
Would I go on a journey
without you, brother?
Don't worry.
Ögedei can wait for us.
And we can't go anywhere without you.
Much appreciated.
Thank you, my Bey.
Don't worry.
Let him rest, Turgut.
Feed him when he wakes up.
As you command, my Bey.
As you command.
God, a thousand thanks to you.
Please help my brother, my God.
My Osman...
My beautiful child.
Please hang in there a little more.
Hang in there, my brave child.
God, please ease my Osman's burdens.
I hope Sugay Hatun comes back
to the tribe safe and sound.
Please help us, God.
Help us.
May I come in, Hayme Hatun?
Come in, my girl.
Oh, my beautiful baby.
What is it, my girl?
I heard about what happened.
I am terribly sorry.
I'd like to help if you allow me.
Thanks, my girl.
I've sent alps after them.
They will take care of the situation.
God willing, Hayme Hatun.
But we'd like to do what we can.
I can't stand seeing Osman
suffering like this.
My brother Eynece knows
how to locate any living being.
No one can escape him,
no matter where they go.
God bless you, my girl.
Thanks.
Don't worry, Hayme Hatun.
We'll bring Sugay Hatun here,
safe and sound.
I hope so. I hope so, my girl.
My child...
Oh my lamb, my little lamb.
Alcicek, find the woman
who breastfed my Osman in the past.
Tell her about the situation, go on.
Of course, Mother Hayme.
All right, it's okay my sweet child.
All right.
Okay.
Everything will be alright.
Oh my sweet grandson.
My sweetie.
We have the opportunity
to get rid of Günalp's doubts.
We must find and bring Sugay to the tribe,
no matter what.
Don't worry, Alangoya.
You know...
Mountains, hills, narrow passages...
even the tree hollows
are Mergen's expertise.
We'll find her and bring her here.
It'll help you gain more trust
in Mother Hayme's eyes.
Show me what you can do, then.
If we gain Günalp's trust,
we won't need to kill him.
We can use him alive.
But we will kill him
if he is not convinced.
Your wish is my command.
Come on!
My brave brother.
Mother entrusted you to me.
Just be well.
I might not be able
to give you the warmth of my mother,
but I can always feed you
with my own hands.
Don't you be afraid. I'm with you
even if my father isn't around.
I can protect both you and Osman.
I wish my mother was here
to see your beautiful gaze.
To hug you and kiss you.
Savci... Keep eating, my brother.
I won't drink anything you offer.
You wasted yourself
because of this disobedience.
You refused to obey your husband's father
and caused his grandson to die.
My child is dead because of you, bastards!
Don't even speak of my child.
That bastard who is my husband's father
can go to hell.
Sugay!
You are a bride
to a powerful Khwarazm bey.
If you refuse to obey him,
then you shall die.
Actually, you deserve more
as you caused his grandson's death.
Our bey will severely punish you
once we get there.
Oh, God...
You are the protector of the oppressed.
You don't favor the oppressors.
Please grant me your help
to escape from these oppressors.
My Bey...
What I need is meat, not soup.
We let the innkeeper know.
Meat will be here any moment.
Would a bowl of soup be enough
for a mountain-like Bamsi?
Right.
Oh, sister.
Thank you, sister.
Sister, you should...
You should bring more meat,
as it is my remedy.
Thank you, sister.
Here is your remedy.
Come on, eat it, brother.
I...
I should eat it with my own hands.
That'd be even more helpful, my Bey.
Very well then. Enjoy..
Excuse me, my Bey.
Go ahead, my lion.
My Bey...
This guy obviously has a problem.
He wants me to accept Ögedei
as my leader, Turgut.
Ögedei also has plans for Anatolia
as he marches for the Danube.
Noyan can arrogantly offer me this
because of Ögedei.
The same offer
must have been made
to the other Turkish tribes by now.
Our Sultan is tired
of the pressure from the Mongols.
That's why he sent me as his envoy.
Very well, my Bey.
My Bey, what is in the bag
which was given to you by our sultan?
The salvation of our state, Turgut.
Very well, my Bey.
Understood.
Eat. Come on, eat my lion.
Mother Hayme, he refuses my milk
no matter what I do.
I've never seen anything like this.
He got tired and went to sleep.
We need to find the woman
who has been feeding Osman.
Obviously, Osman accepted her
as his mother.
We will find her, my girl.
You did what you could.
God bless you.
May God help Osman, Mother Hayme.
Amen.
I'll stay in the tribe just in case.
-Excuse me.
-Goodbye, my girl.
God works in mysterious ways.
Please watch over this child
and help him.
Your capacity for mercy...
and your ability have no boundaries.
Please help us, my God.
What is it, Günalp Bey?
Did you find something?
This probably belongs to Sugay Hatun.
You are right, Günalp Bey.
This is Sugay Hatun's.
It seems we are on the right track.
Let's go quickly.
Time to go, get yourselves together.
There is nowhere to run, Sugay.
And no one to save you.
Now, our bey will severely punish you
once we get there.
I hope it'll be God who punishes you.
God is good!
Protect Sugay Hatun, brother.
Come on, brave warriors!
Behind you!
We are here to help, alps!
Are you okay?
Thank you, you came to help again.
We all live on the same lands
and drink the same water.
It's our duty, Günalp Bey.
We need to protect and respect each other.
Am I correct?
You are right.
I think more highly of you, now.
You got into trouble
and risked your lives for me.
I don't want to be a burden for you
any more.
Give me your blessings.
Sugay Hatun.
Where are you going?
We can't let her go, Günalp Bey.
What would we say to our bey?
Let's go after her.
Wait. It won't help.
Only I can share her feelings with her
right now.
I need to talk to her, woman to woman.
Sugay Hatun...
Much appreciated.
Sugay Hatun, wait.
Don't come after me, Lady Almila. Go back.
We came here to rescue you
from those bastards, we can't leave you.
I'm grateful for what you did for me.
I only ask you...
to give me your blessings. That's all.
I can't go back to the tribe now.
And why is that?
Don't you see? From the moment I came
to the tribe, I got you into trouble.
Ertuğrul Bey also had a fight with them
the first time he saw me.
I'll leave in order not to cause more
trouble for the tribe and Ertuğrul Bey.
You can't leave, Sugay Hatun.
Why are these guys coming after you?
They hold me responsible
for the death of my child.
Now, let me go.
You can't, Sugay Hatun.
Did you ever think about Osman?
Osman is used to your milk.
You eased his pains with your milk.
Now do you think he will accept
some other woman's milk?
Do you want to leave him to starve?
You know best
how it feels to lose a child.
How can you leave a baby
while he is depending on you?
Now, will you leave
and probably cause a baby to die?
Or will you stay and keep on feeding
that beautiful baby?
Osman must be crying right now.
I need to feed him.
Brother...
Why is this demon...
staring at us?
Don't think about him, brother.
Just rest.
Brother, I'd sleep so well...
if I could cut his head off right here.
How are you, Alp Commander Bamsi ?
Why are you asking?
Just asking.
You came to the battlefield
roaring like a lion.
You're a brave boy.
So are you, Turgut.
I heard you're migrating soon.
If your Bey sets up his pavilion in Söğüt
as a frontiersman, he won't go away, huh?
Why do you care, Noyan?
Emperor of Nicaea won't give you peace
where you'll migrate.
We'll put him in his place.
Let's say you put the Emperor
in his place.
What about Ögedei Khan? Huh?
What will you do
when Ögedei Khan comes here?
Huh?
This won't end well for you.
The weapons of brave men like you
should not only rule Byzantium,
but also the whole world.
We are the new world order.
Don't you still get that?
Noyan!
Screw you, your Khan...
and your new world order.
Do you think we forgot about you
attacking our tribe and killing many?
And how dare you talk about selling
our weapons to your Khan?
My God... Osman is melting away
in front of my own eyes.
My God, don't withhold your mercy.
Take some of my life and give it to him.
My baby.
Can I come in?
Come in.
Sugay Hatun!
Mother Hayme! My Osman.
Thank God you got back alive and well.
How are you?
I'm fine, Mother Hayme.
Thank God.
I got away thanks to Almıla Hatun,
Günalp Bey and the Alps.
I feel embarrassed.
I didn't want to come back
to keep Ertuğrul Bey and you away
from the trouble,
but Almıla Hatun convinced me.
Why do you say that?
Let all the trouble come at us.
You are a Hatun of our tribe,
you're our daughter.
They'll get what they deserve.
Don't you worry. Feel at ease.
I worried a lot about Osman.
When I heard about Osman being hungry,
I couldn't stay so I came back.
You did the right thing.
Do you know that Osman has been hungry
this whole time?
May God bless you too, Almıla Hatun.
I don't know how we can pay you back.
You're our daughter now.
My pleasure, Hayme Hatun.
Ertuğrul Bey's son is our child as well.
I'm glad to be able to help Osman.
My Osman.
My brave boy. I missed you so much.
Don't worry, I won't leave again.
I won't let you starve.
Mother Hayme, I'll feed Osman now.
Okay. We'll get out
so you can get comfortable.
Come on.
My Osman, my son.
May God bless you.
You brought Sugay back alive and well.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
We'll do anything we can
for the Hatun of our tribe
and the children of our Ertuğrul Bey.
Eynece, Almıla praised
your scouting skills so much.
She was right.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Thanks.
Mother, if you'll excuse me,
I'll see Artuk Bey.
Goodbye, son.
Mother Hayme, maybe this is a bad time.
But the people who abducted Sugay Hatun
are not trustworthy.
-Did she tell you something?
-I don't know who they are.
Before, when Ertuğrul ran into her,
they attacked them as well.
Ertuğrul dealt with them.
But it's obvious that these people
won't let Sugay Hatun go.
Seems like there's something
she doesn't want to tell us.
We have to find out who is after
Sugay Hatun, Mother Hayme.
Or she might get in
a lot of trouble again.
You're right.
We have to figure it out right away.
I'll talk to Sugay when the time's right.
The past is in the past.
Now it's time to be smart.
Our holy army will be here.
And they'll slaughter your tribes.
Mongolians and Turks are the children
of the same land.
Instead of hurting each other,
we should rule the world together.
I won't die before I make sure
Aykız's spirit rests in peace!
What happened to Aykız was
because of your stubbornness.
If you had joined our reign,
Aykız wouldn't have burnt to her death.
Turgut! Brother!
We'll destroy you, your Khan,
and his dogs, Noyan. You should know that.
Brother, stop.
With this attitude,
you'd only drown in your own blood.
Don't listen to this demon's words.
Don't bite off more than you can chew.
Noyan!
Don't worry, Ertuğrul.
Me and your brother Turgut are having fun.
Abdur Rahman, get back to your duty.
Your wish is my command.
Alps...
Don't bother my Alps, Noyan.
I don't want anything to happen to you.
It means,
"The sea of mind starts with books...
the sea of water starts
with small brooks."
Getting close to Ögedei Khan
is a big gift to you from the spirits.
Don't underestimate what I just said.
Forgive me, Bey.
I couldn't control my anger.
Our biggest enemy is not the Mongolians!
But it's the anger
we let grow inside of us, Turgut.
If we can't control our anger, we're done.
Now go and get some fresh air.
Okay, Bey.
When I was fighting,
I didn't even realize I got a wound.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Your wound is not deep, Günalp Bey.
But we have to be careful.
I'm glad you're here.
This ointment will help you recover
quickly, if God permits.
God willing.
Almıla Hatun caught up to the fight again.
And then she went after Sugay Hatun
and convinced her to come back.
You got suspicious and inspected them.
But the woman proved you wrong
with what she did.
You're right, Artuk Bey.
We considered every possibility
with Ertuğrul Bey's command.
There were some things
that I was suspicious of.
But like you said,
the woman proved me wrong
with what she did.
Still, Ertuğrul Bey is right.
The spies of Noyan loom around
in these lands.
We'll take more precautions.
I'll investigate the tribes and
the merchants. Feel at ease.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
And thanks for the remedy.
God is the one who gives the remedy,
Günalp Bey.
Thank you.
-Is he asleep?
-He is, Mother Hayme.
He was so hungry.
I'm so sorry I left him to starve.
Thank God you got back alive and well.
You got Osman back and he got you back.
That's what's important.
Sugay, from now on, you're my daughter.
And I'm your mother.
Your problems are ours as well.
Let me know if you have one.
Who are these people
who keep bothering you?
Tell me, so we can take precautions.
It's the relatives of my husband.
When my husband died...
they wanted me to get married
to his brother.
I didn't accept.
I ran away with my child.
But when my child died...
I was all alone.
They held me responsible for the death
of my child.
They want revenge.
They won't let me go.
You are from the tribe
of the glorious Ertuğrul Bey.
You're under his protection.
You're the wet nurse
of Ertuğrul Bey's child.
No one can attempt to harm you
when you're here.
I don't think they'll stop, Mother Hayme.
They won't let me go
until they get their revenge.
Don't worry.
From now on, more Alps will escort you
and no one will get to you.
Do you understand?
God willing, Mother Hayme.
May God bless you.
You have become my family
after I lost mine.
From now on, I won't leave you
or Osman.
May God bless you.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My God, you are...
You are the best one to keep
what you were entrusted with.
I entrusted my kids to you.
Protect them.
Help them.
Give us strength on our tough mission.
Grant us success on our mission.
Help me not let my state down,
and help my state against the enemy.
Help us be victorious, my God.
Help us protect the order that we built
with so much effort and time.
Don't let us submit to
anyone else but you.
Amen.
Look at what God creates.
Look at that vast thing
that they call the sea, brothers.
My God, thank goodness.
Thank you for the beauty.
All these beautiful things were created
by Tengri for my Khan.
From now on, the Black Sea is
my Khan's, just like all the seas.
The water is salty, you can't drink it.
But it helps you to go far away.
Ögedei Khan will send us a ship.
We'll travel the rest of the way by sea.
We'll pass the vicious sea by ship.
Abdur Rahman, our wounded Alps should
wait by the horses until we return.
Your wish is my command.
Alps...
You're safe now, Ertuğrul.
From now on, there are no Crusaders,
no Governors and no traitor Beys.
You'll be safe in the holy lands
of Ögedei Khan.
Don't be so sure, Noyan.
What do you know and hide from me,
Ertuğrul?
Alps, be very careful from now on.
Are you worried about Noyan, my Bey?
I think there are worse people
than Noyan where we are going.
From now on, keep your eyes open
and your weapons ready.
All right, my Bey.
The ship is coming!
My child that I had to bury before
I could get enough of your scent.
You had such a beautiful face.
My only wish from God is
to meet you again there.
Oh, to smell you again, my son.
Can I come in?
Come in.
Gündüz.
Sugay Hatun, why are you crying?
What are you holding?
The socks of my child that I lost, Gündüz.
I miss his scent so much.
So...
I was inhaling his scent from
his socks to try to ease my pain.
I'm sorry for your loss, Sugay Hatun.
You take care of my brother as your own,
you feed him and nourish him.
He is your child too.
Oh my dear.
Your brothers Osman, Savcı and you
are like my children, Gündüz.
You're my only consolation
in the whole world.
Welcome, Almıla Hatun.
Thank you, Gündüz Alp.
Sugay Hatun, you look tired.
Thank God I'm fine, Almıla Hatun.
I got Osman back and fed him.
What else would I want?
Sugay Hatun, how did you
and my father meet?
When I was with my son,
Aktolgali found me first.
After him, Ertuğrul Bey arrived.
So Aktolgali found you, Sugay Hatun?
Aktolgali is very smart.
My horse is very smart too.
Do you like horses a lot?
I love them a lot, Almıla Hatun.
I love Aktolgali the most.
But my father is gone.
No one lets me ride horses anymore.
Come on then. I'll let you ride my horse.
Really, Almıla Hatun?
Really, as long as you want to.
I really want to.
Almıla Hatun, isn't it dangerous?
What if something happens?
Nothing will happen, Sugay Hatun.
I know about horses anyway.
Don't worry, Sugay Hatun.
As long as we are cautious,
nothing bad will happen.
Come on, Gündüz. Go now and
get permission from your grandmother.
So I can let you ride my horse.
Okay, Almıla Hatun.
We've got news from our spy in the palace.
These messengers are taking a very
important letter to the castle.
We'll kill the men and get the letter.
Where did you send the Alps to, Ertuğrul?
I sent them to look around, Noyan.
This is Ögedei Khan's land.
In Ögedei Khan's lands, not even a snake
or a centipede can touch a man.
It could be worse than a snake
or a centipede, Noyan.
Let's just be cautious, that's all.
Eat, you strong boy.
Eat so you can get stronger.
You should eat and get stronger too.
So when we cut you up,
you won't die quickly.
Didn't I tell you there'd be worse things
than snakes and centipedes?
Don't you know me?
We're going to Ögedei Khan's pavilion.
-Who are you?
-Your killer.
Our killer, huh?
Come on and let's see who is dying!
Protect the saddlebag!
We're coming, Bey.
Let's go and end this.
There's a raid!
Attack!
This guy must have the letter.
We'll take advantage of this information.
All the soldiers are dead,
what should we do now?
Take the soldiers' clothes.
And bury their bodies.
We have to take this letter
to Alangoya right away.
Come on!
You were right, Ertuğrul.
Who dares trap me in the land
of Ögedei Khan?
You'll learn about it when you arrive
at the pavilion.
What do you have in your saddlebag?
How do they know about it?
I told you, Noyan...
You'll learn about it when we get there.
Come on, Alps. Let's go.
Sit firmly in the saddle.
Hold the reins tight.
The horse belongs to he who rides it,
the sword belongs to he who wields it.
Come on, Gündüz Alp.
Grandmother, look at me riding.
May your grandmother die for you.
Thank you, Almıla, my girl.
Since you arrived,
my Gündüz has grown into himself.
Just look,
how well he rides.
Just like his father.
Yes, Hayme Ana.
It's evident
that he is Ertuğrul Bey's son.
Thank you.
You look after our children so well.
God sent you to us in these hard times.
God willing
you'll have your own children one day.
Amen, Hayme Ana.
I too would like to have a home, children.
But how could that happen
when there's so much work to be done.
Surely there's a good match out there,
waiting for you.
Always toiling among men,
fighting amongst them,
I've become like them, Hayme Ana.
What man would ever have me?
Don't say that, child.
You are a valiant woman.
And you are beautiful.
God will give you what is best for you.
Hopefully.
Come here, Gündüz Alp.
Grandmother, did you see?
I rode the horse so well.
I did, my brave boy.
You rode well.
But now, let's go to your brothers
and tend to them a little, eh?
-Okay, Grandmother. Let's go.
-Come on.
You come too, Almıla Hatun.
You go with your grandmother.
I need to do something
and then I'll be there.
Okay.
Come on.
We have entered the layer of
the centipedes, let's hope we can get out.
Let's hope, brother.
Let's...
Tell my khan I have arrived.
Tell him, Sultan Gıyaseddin
sent an emissary.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Will you still not tell me
what happened in the forest?
Are you going to ask me
what games are being played
in the lands of your khan,
whom you deem so highly, Noyan?
If you are up to something, Ertuğrul,
you will pay a heavy price.
You being an emissary
is of no concern to my khan Ögedei...
or to me.
Be careful in the presence of my khan.
We have a saying.
Which means
"Think much,
speak little."
If whatever you say
enrages him,
know that you won't leave here alive.
Which would upset me the most.
I wouldn't want to give up
my most valiant enemy.
Alps, wait here.
Once we've done our duty
we will go back to our tribe, God willing.
Ögedei Khan awaits you, Noyan.
You shall pass over
the hot iron, Ertuğrul Bey.
Within the man with bad thoughts...
is a big
dark rock.
Within the man with good thoughts...
is the sun,
the moon.
May the hot iron...
drive out the evil spirits within you.
My khan.
Evil spirits have not come with this Turk.
What word, what gifts
has your sultan sent me, Ertuğrul Bey?
The word my sultan has sent
is on the tip of my tongue.
The presents he sent
are inside this sack, Ögedei Khan.
Has your sultan fit the gift he sent
to Ögedei, khan of khans,
into that little sack?
Inside this sack
is the destiny of your khanate,
Ögedei Han.
What news, Mergen?
Have you retrieved the letter?
We have.
It has information concerning
the activities of Mongolian spies
on the beylik frontier.
It contains very important information,
Alangoya.
That letter will go to Günalp Bey.
Günalp Bey?
Why would we do such a thing?
The information in the letter
puts us at risk too.
Oh, Mergen!
You are a hunter,
yet you still don't know how to set bait.
Our men will dress up as Seljuks
and take it to Günalp Bey.
There must be a secret sign
between them and Konya.
Without our men knowing it,
Günalp Bey will understand
that they are Mongols.
And he will follow them
to find the spies' hideout.
And then?
We will direct those three soldiers
to another target.
Günay Bey will fall for the bait.
That way, what we're actually doing
won't be detected.
And Günalp Bey won't be
suspicious of us anymore.
Seal the letter properly.
Send three soldiers to the castle.
Günalp Bey will be lying in wait
like a tiger with sharp teeth.
Set the bait for him at once.
Since when does the fate
of Genghis Khan's khanate
lie in your hands, Ertuğrul Bey?
I know...
that you are a great khan,
loyal to Genghis Khan's laws, Ögedei Khan.
However, instead of improving cities,
you pillage and burn them.
Did you come here to give me advice
as your Sultan Gıyaseddin's envoy
or to pay tribute to me, Ertuğrul Bey?
Tell your sultan to thank God
that I haven't...
burned his cities yet.
We Muslims don't pillage
and burn the cities we conquer.
We improve them.
This makes us
a blessed state.
We know
that a state seeking to plunder
and pillage
won't last.
That state
and its army
is bound to fall, sooner or later.
Do you invite me into your religion,
Ertuğrul Bey?
For thousands of years,
we and the Turks have known...
that Tengri is the one...
and there has been no higher being
than him for all eternity.
Sitting in
my ancestor Genghis Khan's seat...
I am the only representative
of Tengri on earth.
Now tell me.
How can the fate
of my khanate be in that sack?
Your soldiers at our borders
do not obey Genghis Khan's laws.
They disregard the promises
you have given to our sultan.
That is why...
our sultan sent me as an emissary.
He wishes you to put an end to this.
Your bey,
how much loot
does he give you from conquests?
We...
wage holy war for the sake of God.
We are not after plunder.
What is there...
to take from...
Anatolia's poor land anyway?
You conquer states and what do you get?
You bring destruction
and fear wherever you go.
Your name will surely be erased
from history.
Our holy cause will prevail.
With God's permission.
Because your bey
can't feed you...
you console yourself with this.
But
don't worry.
Just wait.
Our khan will come to your land too.
If you are smart
you too shall benefit
from the riches he brings.
You'll become proper warriors.
soldiers!
Are you Ertuğrul Bey's alps?
We are, thank God.
Who might you be?
I am Kutlubay.
I am a Turk, like you.
I am one of the commanders
in Ögedei's army.
What business do you have
with the Mongolian army?
Conquering the world,
receiving fame and fortune.
There are many Turks like me
in my khan's army.
All the Turkic alps in the tribes
from Karakorum to Tabriz are joining us.
With God's permission,
Anatolia is still under the rule of
Turkic alps.
They too are more than willing to join
Ögedei Khan's army.
All the alps in Anatolia
will become our soldiers.
Now rest a little.
I will come back to talk.
Permission to enter, my Bey.
Come.
Three messengers have come
from Hüsamettin Karaca, my Bey.
Oh. Bring them in.
Door.
Come.
Welcome, brave men.
What word has Hüsamettin Karaca sent?
It's written in this letter, my bey.
How dare you accuse me of breaking
the laws of my ancestor, Genghis Khan?
True words cut like a sharp knife,
Ögedei Khan.
Our sultan has agreed to
double the tribute you ask for.
However...
while he wishes to renew
the peace agreement that is about expire.
It is...
on the condition that you stop
violating our borders.
How dare you tell me
that my soldiers do not obey me,
Khan of Khans Ögedei Khan...
and break Genghis Khan's laws?
If you can't control
a couple of marauding soldiers
at your borders,
how will you manage to dominate
the whole world, Ögedei Khan?
My soldiers are loyal to me.
You and your sultan lie.
If you can't prove what you say...
your death will come
by my hand, Ertuğrul.
Good.
Hüsamettin Karaca has written about
Mongolian spy activities in detail.
You came a long way without rest.
You must be tired.
We are, my Bey.
How was the white river water?
We drank plenty. It was good.
It was good, eh?
Good, good.
Commander.
Yes, my Bey.
These brave men are tired.
Let them go and rest.
Give them food.
Yes, my Bey.
This way, Beys.
Thank you, my Bey.
And by the way...
our waters
are not lesser than the white river.
Drink plenty.
Plenty.
Than you, my Bey.
This way, Beys.
Commander.
Yes, my Bey.
Those aren't messengers.
They are Mongolian spies.
How do you know, my Bey?
When I asked about the water
they should have said,
"Sweeter than soil."
That is our signal with Konya.
They didn't know it.
Say the word
and I will put them to the sword, my Bey.
Wait.
We won't do anything to them.
Don't let them know we suspect them.
Let them rest.
We will follow them later.
They will lead us
to the Mongolian spy hideout.
Understood?
Understood, my Bey.
Door.
Noyan himself is witness that
we were ambushed by the evil
that has taken root within your ranks.
When we came close to your encampment
a band of errant soldiers
attacked us.
The soldiers who attacked
knew that the names of the commanders
who do not obey you
were in the sack.
Is it true
that you were attacked on your way, Noyan?
It is, my Khan.
Who are they, Ertuğrul Bey?
Those who wish you'll attack
Seljuk land...
instead of the land over the Danube.
Know that
those who dare to do this today...
will want to take away
your sovereignty tomorrow
when they get the chance.
Who are they, Ertuğrul Bey?
Give me the names in the sack.
My Sultan...
You command me to go to Ögedei
as your envoy, and stop his soldiers
from violating our borders.
Ögedei Khan
abides by Genghis Khan's laws.
He will keep his word.
There must be a reason why his men
won't honor the peace agreement.
I believe there are commanders
who don't obey Ögedei Khan's orders.
It does not fall on us
to learn who they are.
However, it is possible
to prove they exist.
Therefore, please spread the word,
in your palace,
that you know who the commanders are
that don't obey Ögedei
and violate our borders.
And that you are to send the names
of these commanders
to Ögedei with me.
If I am right,
these commanders
will ambush us on the way
to get the sack with the names.
If you lie...
I will first cut out your tongue
and then I'll cut you into pieces.
Just like our sultan...
I also don't know
who the commanders are that violate
our agreement and assault our land.
However,
I was assured today...
that what I think is right.
The soldiers that attacked Noyan and me...
are the dogs of the commanders
that do not obey you.
Finding out who they are
is up to you, Ögedei Khan.
The only thing in the sack...
is the peace agreement
our sultan sealed with his blood.
Go.
Find the bodies of the soldiers
that fell for Ertuğrul Bey's trap.
Find out who they are.
As you wish, my Khan.
I will seal
this agreement
under the terms your sultan wishes.
And with my own blood.
However, Ertuğrul Bey...
I have a proposition for you.
Hayme Ana, have you talked to Sugay Hatun?
Did you find out who was after her?
We should figure that out
and take precautions.
We spoke.
However, she does not want to say much.
It is clear that this upsets her.
She does not want to remember.
She wants to leave it all behind
and start a new life.
What do you intend to do, Hayme Ana?
Let some time pass.
Sugay Hatun is diffident.
Just let her get used to our tribe.
She will open up on her own.
God willing, Hayme Ana.
It would be good to find out
before Sugay Hatun gets hurt.
God willing, my girl.
Is there any word on Ertuğrul Bey,
Hayme Ana?
I wonder how he is.
Hopefully nothing is wrong.
They were both asleep.
Why would both start crying
at the same moment?
Let me go see, my girl.
I'll come too.
Sugay, my girl,
why are they both crying at the same time?
I don't know, Hayme Ana.
I fed them both.
They were sound asleep.
They started crying simultaneously.
Oh, my brave one.
Oh, my son. My brave one.
My dear boy.
God.
Help us.
For the sake of these children
may you bring...
Ertuğrul and his alps
back to the tribe in one piece.
God, may you protect them.
Amen.
Help us, God.
Oh, my dear.
Okay.
Okay, my brave one.
Don't cry, my boy.
Oh, God.
Oh, the compassionate one.
Oh, the merciful one.
Oh, the bright one.
Oh, God.
Oh, the compassionate one.
Oh, the merciful one.
Oh, the bright one.
Oh, God.
Oh, the compassionate one.
Oh, the merciful one.
Oh, the bright one.
Oh, the compassionate and merciful one
whose compassion surrounds all.
Oh, God whose light
enlightens the whole universe.
With no doubt, it is your light
that shines in all beings.
Oh, God...
you won't leave
those who set out on your path,
half way.
Render Ertuğrul Bey
and his alps victorious
on the journey that they are on.
Oh God,
for your follower Abraham,
you were the one who said...
"Oh, fire...
be cold and pleasing...
to Abraham." when he
was thrown into the fire,
and you protected him.
You are the one who protected
your beloved Muhammed with a spider web.
We entrusted to you
those who set out on your path
May you protect them.
Surely you are the one who sees
and watches over everything.
Put those who ambush them...
and are evil to them, into the ground.
Render them miserable.
Oh, the helper of his friends,
the disturber of his foes.
We take shelter in you, we seek your aid.
Assist them.
I am responsible for all the Turks
in Ögedei Khan's army.
I know who is who, what is what.
The Seljuks are done for.
The Anatolian beyliks are in a bad place,
the alps have had it.
They will come join
Ögedei Khan's army
to conquer the world and gain riches.
What else would they do?
Who wouldn't want to come?
Don't be too sure of that.
In Anatolia
there are still brave men
that won't resort to pillage
and plunder, thank God.
If there's someone we want in our army
we will surely get him.
How would you get someone
that doesn't want to come?
We'll get in his brain, so he will
lose himself, forget his past.
He will submit his body and soul to us.
And whatever we say
he'll do...
without question.
Why did you do this, Turgut?
So, you made him into a puppet.
You are valiant alps.
We might want you in our army.
May Tengri help you.
Brother...
this guy might play us somehow.
They can make us into puppets
with torture.
He's responsible for the Turks
in the Mongolian army.
It's clear...
that he sends spies into Anatolia
and brainwashes the Turks there.
Brother, Ertuğrul Bey must know of this.
We'll need it when we get back.
If we get back.
We need to get out of here...
before they get to us, Bamsı.
We need to go.
Mark my words, Ertuğrul Bey.
Genghis Khan says,
"You should tie an animal from its legs
before you eat it.
You should cut open its stomach.
You should kill it...
by squeezing its heart.
You should squeeze it...
so that it'll get
to the world of spirits...
by comprehending the power of death."
The Seljuk State is an animal...
tied from its legs...
that fell into my trap.
I cut its stomach open...
with my sieges
and the taxes that I ordered.
And now...
I'll come to your land with my sword
that makes the world bow down...
and I'll squeeze Sultan Gıyaseddin's heart
with my majestic hands.
However.
With the decision you'll make...
Sultan Gıyaseddin will lose
and you'll win.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Now,
in my holy pavilion...
I'm asking you to join me.
I am the Khan of all Khans,
Ögedei.
I only ask once
to those brave men that I trust.
Your words are...
such an honor for a frontiersman like me
who wants to find a home for his tribe...
and settle down.
First of all,
I'd like to tell you that I'm honored
by your offer.
I accept to be
under the command of the biggest
Khan the world has ever seen,
the Khan of...
all Khans.
It's an honor for me
to revive and manage Anatolia...
by following your holy mission.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net