Episode 96 will start after 12:28 min.
I swear to God, his holy book, his flag
and to my steel sword.
May the blue skies and the brown earth
be my witness.
I swear on everything
that I will not stop
until I make those who set traps
and betrayed us pay for what they did.
In this pursuit of justice and order,
I will be the nightmare of the oppressors
and the thugs.
I'll keep being the fear of the oppressors
and hope of the oppressed.
Goktug...
Where is this Ares?
He was so willing to sell the bazaar,
it's not a good sign that he is late,
blessed vizier.
Vizier Sadettin...
We've been waiting for you, Governor.
I wouldn't want to keep you waiting
but something came up.
I need to be leaving soon,
so let's get this over with.
Why the hurry, Ares?
You look very worried.
As if you saw a ghost.
The contracts are ready, blessed vizier.
Good.
The governor is in a hurry,
so let's complete the agreement
with us bearing witness.
My Ertuğrul, my brave heart.
We thought he was under the ground,
but he was just out there
somewhere, struggling.
We crushed his hopes and dreams...
while he was away fighting evil.
Mother,
do not grieve any longer.
My bey is back.
Your son came back safe and unharmed.
Who cares if the world burns now?
Do not wear yourself out like this.
You supported the decision
to reunite your sons.
My girl,
what if they sell the bazaar?
How can we look Ertuğrul in the eye?
What about Dündar? What will he do?
Mother...
My beautiful mother.
Let the winds carry your worries away.
Stop upsetting yourself now.
My bey, your son, is back.
That's all that matters.
And you'll see Ertuğrul Bey
will make it there in time.
My girl, I'm thinking about Dündar,
not myself.
My only concern is for him.
I'm afraid Ertuğrul won't forgive him
this time.
Mother, don't you know how close
Ertuğrul Bey is to his brother?
He does whatever is best for his brother.
Every winter carries its spring, Mother.
It's time to dispel the black clouds
above us.
My beautiful daughter-in-law.
You bravely stood your ground.
You saw what was right and wrong.
You showed what it really is
to be a wife of a bey.
My beautiful daughter-in-law.
We've learned how it is to be a wife
of a bey from you, Mother.
May God bless you.
Oh, my beautiful girl.
Oh, my beautiful daughter-in-law.
Dündar Bey,
with this contract, Bahadır Bey
will stay loyal
to the promises given to the traders
by Ertuğrul Bey.
And governor Ares will assign
a skillful trader
to help him out.
They'll improve the bazaar together.
And everyone will win.
I'll stay loyal to the promise
I gave to Ertuğrul Bey.
With the trader I'll assign,
I'll convince Greek traders
to trade in these lands again.
Finally.
Let's get this over with.
We'll establish Islam here.
Allah is everlasting!
We will make it a glorious inn,
having announced the call to prayer.
Let the people know
they are not to be afraid.
The oppression has come to an end.
Ertuğrul Bey...
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Long live Ertuğrul Bey.
Our bey is alive.
My Ertuğrul Bey! Ertuğrul Bey is alive.
May it be for the best.
Let this purchase be prosperous
for trade.
There you go, Bahadır Bey.
Congratulations.
Congratulations to all of us,
blessed vizier.
Brother!
Ertuğrul...
Ertuğrul.
A thousand thanks to God, Ertuğrul,
that you are here with us.
How did this happen?
It seems I still have time to live
and to shorten the lives of my enemies,
Vizier Sadettin.
We all thought you were dead.
We buried you.
The body you buried was not mine,
it was one of the ambushers'.
Very well, very well.
Where have you been
all this time, Ertuğrul Bey?
I was captured by a slave trader.
But thank God, I survived.
I'm here now.
Good.
Welcome back.
We have just completed a good deal.
I know my brother Dündar is here
to sell the bazaar.
But...
I also know that no one is to benefit
from the bad fortune of Kayi tribe.
And that's why
this agreement has no value to me.
What are you saying, Ertuğrul Bey?
Dündar Bey signed the contract
with the stamp of Kayi.
He accepted the gold
in the presence of witnesses.
As long as I hold this agreement
with the Kayi stamp on it,
your words have no value, either.
Ertuğrul!
How could you disrespect my father!
Why the hurry, Bahadır Bey?
It seems you are sick
of waiting to tear apart my dead body,
along with your son.
Bahadır Bey.
Keep your sword in its sheath.
I am the margrave of these lands.
The bazaar is my property.
I'm not selling it.
Either you make my hands dirty
with your blood
or you obey me.
The leader of Cavdars
does not obey anyone,
Ertuğrul Bey!
Then we will spare a place for you
alongside your cousin Ural,
who refused to obey in the past.
How could you let him
tear up the contract, blessed vizier?
How could you rebel against a margrave?
Ertuğrul Bey
is the margrave of these lands.
Sancar Bey.
Take your Alps and leave here at once.
We'll deal with this matter
calmly and collectively,
with Ertuğrul Bey.
Hopefully.
Turgut.
Alps!
Look here, Turgut.
Don't think you'll be relieved
now that your bey is back.
You'll be held responsible
for all your doings.
From now on, think twice
before doing anything.
Look at this halfwit!
Just look at him!
This ignorant halfwit!
He's all talk!
Don't think you coyotes have any chance
to roam freely.
We will not let that happen,
just as we didn't
while Ertuğrul Bey wasn't around.
You, your bey and your tribe
still have a price to pay, Turgut.
The amount is getting bigger and bigger.
You will pay the price in blood
when the time comes.
Your teeth are not strong enough
to chew us.
Don't draw your swords
in the wrong places.
You may end up cutting your own throats.
Then we'll see the pool of blood.
We'll see, Turgut.
We will.
Ertuğrul Bey, bandits took advantage
of your absence
and attacked the traders.
The bazaar's operations were disrupted.
Both my people and the Turks
were harmed as the consequence.
Bahadır Bey was going to buy the bazaar.
Governor Ares was going to assign
a skillful trader
who would improve ties with the Frankish.
As for Dündar Bey,
he stayed loyal to your wishes to the end.
He protected the traders as per your wish.
There is no reason to be angry or resent.
In these turbulent times,
I did my best to protect
both my own people's
and the Turks' interests.
Your death
caused a weakness among Kayi tribe,
that's the issue.
This weakness caused harm
both to trade
and to the livelihoods of the people.
They did the tough thing
by buying a dying bazaar.
So if the operations
of the bazaar were disrupted
while I was away,
as the margrave it's my duty
to re-establish order
in these lands.
Governor Ares,
we will meet and talk
about whatever is necessary
to revive the trade in the bazaar.
I'm sure you want
the best for your people, too.
I'll come to your castle and talk to you.
Now, you can leave.
As for you, Bahadır Bey...
Tomorrow,
I'll gather the council in the bazaar.
I'll question your son,
for he drew his sword
to the margrave.
As for your tribe...
I'll make the decision about your tribe
during the meeting.
I'm the only one
who can make decisions about my tribe.
Then,
your will to decide
will be at the mercy of my sword,
Bahadır Bey.
You can leave now.
Don't forget your precious gold.
Alps!
Take the box.
Bring my horse!
You've cut each other’s throats now,
damn Turks.
Let us be ridden of you all.
You cut each other today,
tomorrow I'll cut you all anyway.
We're leaving!
Shame on you!
How did the order of the bazaar
go sideways, Vizier Sadettin?
Why didn't you take precautions?
How could you let the bandits be
while they didn't let the people be?
Do you hold me responsible
for what happened, Ertuğrul?
You couldn't find those
who ambushed me and killed my Alps.
You failed to prevent the Turkish tribes
from going into turmoil while I was away.
I had my soldiers
chase the bandits for days.
I questioned those we captured.
I did my best to find
who did this to you and your Alps.
Dündar is the primary witness
of my efforts.
Our Sultan assigned you to take care
of these lands while I was away.
And what did you do?
You convinced my brother
to sell the bazaar
for which we lost so many soldiers.
Instead of preventing him from emigrating,
you encouraged him.
Don't tell me you were doing your job.
I'm happy you are alive, Ertuğrul.
Don't dampen my happiness
with your rage.
You'll be my guest at the council tomorrow
for the last time.
I'm back.
Your job here is done.
Don't you dare
enter my territory again.
Now,
I represent the state in these lands.
Even the shadow of my bey
is enough to scare them off.
Let's see how that devil,
so called Bahadır,
talks from now on.
So, let's start your wedding preparations
with Lady Aslıhan then.
Let's have a legendary wedding for you,
so that our enemies envy you
and lose their minds over it.
Just an order of Ertuğrul Bey
would be enough, brother.
No one has the power to prevent it
once he gives the go ahead.
Brother...
I made a mistake.
Forgive me.
I caused all this turmoil.
You surrendered willingly
and knowingly
because of your stupidity, Dündar!
How can you ask for forgiveness?
-Brother--
-Don't!
Don't call me brother!
I'll make you
and those who supported you
pay for this!
-Turgut.
-Yes, my bey.
Go to Cavdar tribe at once.
Let Lady Aslıhan know
that once Bahadır Bey's tribe
reaches our lands,
there will be a council meeting
for the leadership.
Tomorrow, we'll be having
a council meeting in the bazaar.
Lady Aslıhan is also invited.
The sentence for Sancar Bey,
who drew his sword to the margrave,
will be decided tomorrow.
Carry my exact words.
Yes, my bey.
Good.
Make way.
Oh, this bastard.
So you are here.
Let's see where you're going.
Commander Ares, I've got news for you.
You couldn't catch a single man,
yet still you are here speaking nonsense!
-It's important, sir.
-Get inside!
Those bastards.
You'll pay for your dirty tricks.
For sure you'll come out of that hole.
You still have things to explain
to Ertuğrul Bey.
My Ertuğrul Bey is coming!
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Praise be to God, who brings the morning
after the dark night,
and who ends the winter with the spring.
I've heard about the bandit problem.
These are the tricks of the devil.
Don't despair.
Don't be fooled by their ticks.
As long as you appreciate your lands,
properties, and our bazaar
and work hard,
these tricks will become useless.
And our income will be
even more prosperous.
Hopefully.
This I promise as your margrave.
The bandit problem will be solved
in no time.
Hopefully.
Our Sultan,
and I, as the margrave,
are always there for you.
You'll be working and trading
in an environment of peace.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
How did Ertuğrul manage
to get away from you and the slave traders
all by himself, Yorgo?
He didn't, sir. He was rescued.
Rescued?
By whom?
-I don't know who, but--
-But what!
They were no ordinary men, sir.
They came prepared.
-They were master warriors.
-What do you mean?
Ertuğrul is protected by certain people
who are unknown to us, sir.
Ertuğrul doesn't know
I'm the mastermind behind all this!
I'll use this to my advantage!
I'm just getting started!
And I'll not deliver the bazaar to him!
A trader is coming from Nicaea.
His name is Niko.
He'll be here in a couple of days.
We need him to incapacitate the bazaar.
He needs to get here safe and sound.
Understood?
Take your men and accompany him.
And don't be seen by anyone.
-Yes, sir.
-Get out!
Someone is coming!
Ertuğrul Bey! Welcome, my bey!
Long live my bey! Welcome!
Long live my bey!
Thank God.
Long live my Ertuğrul Bey!
God bless you my bey!
Brave hearts of Kayi tribe!
People of Kayi!
I know there is a bleeding wound...
in each of your hearts.
But don't you worry.
The bazaar still belongs to the Kayi!
God bless you! Long live my bey!
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
What kind of Kayi beys are you...
that you decided to give in
when the hard times came,
instead of resisting?
Forgive us, my bey.
We thought you were dead.
Even if I die,
the cause still lives!
This cause...
is the cause of God!
It began long ago
and it will exist forever!
When our prophet...
went to the afterlife,
what did Ebubekir say to his friends
who went into despair?
"Muhammad
was just a messenger of God.
There have been many other prophets
who have come and gone.
Now, if he is to die or to be killed
will you step back from his cause?
Whoever steps back...
cannot harm God.
Yet God will reward those
who feel gratitude."
They didn't step back from the cause
they believed in.
They waved the flags of justice
in every corner of the world.
And you?
What did you do?
Let this be known:
the Kayi is not defined by Ertuğrul Bey!
Those who embrace the cause of God...
stand their ground
even if flames rain on them.
Yet you all failed to stand your ground.
This is my order!
Dündar Bey and other beys
who supported him
are no longer beys.
Your wish is our command, my bey.
We're just grateful you are alive.
As you order, my bey.
Let this be an example for everyone!
Those who don't stay loyal to the cause...
and don't stand their ground...
are not welcome in this tribe!
Those who want to leave can leave now!
Your way is our way, Ertuğrul Bey!
Your path is our path!
I'll wait for you in my tent, Dündar.
Come and see me.
How could they lose themselves like this?
How could they
draw swords on a frontier bey?
Ertuğrul Bey will give the decision about
Sancar in the feast of beys tomorrow.
Bahadir Bey will listen to no decision,
Turgut Alp. He'll do anything for his son.
I remember well how he stood up against
my father and the oba once.
You saw how he got the support of
Emir Sadettin.
He got to my beys too
and persuaded them to a feast!
Turgut, I don't know
how to stop him anymore.
Ertuğrul Bey wishes you
to postpone the feast.
The beys support him. How can I do that?
Tell your beys,
"It is Ertuğrul Bey's command,
there won't be a feast
until Bahadir's oba arrives."
Ertuğrul Bey has thought this through.
Since the two tribes
of the Cavdars are to unite,
the beys of the two Cavdar obas
should come together and decide.
This will buy us time.
My bey wishes to see you too
at the feast tomorrow, Aslıhan Hatun.
Ertuğrul Bey's wish is my command.
Go and tell him,
"Aslıhan Hatun will do what's necessary."
Neither my alps nor my people
will turn their backs on Ertuğrul Bey.
So long as Ertuğrul Bey is here.
So long as you are next to me.
Your oba is my oba...
Your life is my life, Aslıhan Hatun.
I will allow neither him nor his son
to ignite the fire of unrest in our obas.
Don't you worry.
My brave sons.
I was in agony longing for you.
Now, even if they gave me the world...
I wouldn't exchange this for anything.
Father, when will you take me hunting?
We will go, my son. We will go.
From now on, we will always be together.
We will go to your little brother's
first hunt too
and ride into your first battle
together too, God willing.
God willing.
My Gündüz was so brave
while you were gone.
You should have seen him
swearing for revenge,
he roared like a lion.
He was the one
who fought our cause the most.
My Gündüz...
is my trusted one, my source of pride.
While this innocent boy's heart
is aflame
our cause could
never be left undone, Halime.
My Gündüz's heart is larger than Dündar
and those witless beys.
Gündüz, go to Aktolga, my son.
I won't go.
I'm going to stay with my father.
Gündüz.
There is more to being an alp
than the sword.
Come, tend a little to Aktolga.
Without being a fellow to your horse,
you can't be an alp.
As you wish, my bey.
Run along then.
I'd die for him.
Ertuğrul.
Dündar made a bad choice.
I stood against him.
He made a mistake.
You stripped him of his beyhood
in front of everyone.
Why don't you go easy on him now.
Things are not what they seem, Halime.
There are bigger forces at play beneath
this market and immigration business.
What are you saying, Ertuğrul?
The hungry wolves have gathered.
My brother and the witless beys
were about to be fed to them.
We stopped it for now.
However, the game is still on.
Dündar will learn
what his foolishness has cost.
He will pay the price.
Eminence.
Even if an outcast from my oba is harmed
I would make that man regret he was born.
That Ertuğrul slew my alps
in front of my eyes.
Give me permission to slaughter him
with my hands and feed him to the ravens.
Whether we like it or not, Ertuğrul Bey
is the frontier bey of these lands.
If you stand up to a frontier bey,
you will deal with the consequences.
Forget it, it's in the past.
Now, be patient, it is time for patience.
Eminence, not even a dog
can stomach what he did.
I cannot be patient. Give me permission,
I will take his head off.
Bahadir Bey.
When rage is high, all logic is lost.
Learn to take control of your anger first.
The sultan will soon call me to Konya.
What will you do when I'm gone?
Ertuğrul is the frontier bey of this land.
Do you think he will let you stay here?
It is up to Ertuğrul
to let you settle here. Don't you see?
I see, Eminence.
Good.
Now, quickly get to your oba.
Gather your beys in the morning
and hold the feast.
Become the bey.
When you get to Ertuğrul,
he will have nothing to say to you
as you will be the bey of the Cavdar.
As you wish, Eminence.
When I sat on this hide,
I had but one goal.
To take my homeland further than
where Suleyman Shah had carried it.
I was left without ancestors.
But I did not leave my oba leaderless,
helpless and run away!
What did my...
beloved brother do?
Just because the bey died he tried to bury
the memory of all those people and run.
Whatever punishment you see fit...
I will take on, brother.
I...
I am not you, brother.
I am not as powerful, as brave as you.
I did what I could.
I was afraid the Kayi would fall apart.
I was afraid I couldn't handle them.
Son.
If there is a fault, it falls on us all.
Stay out of this, Mother.
The one who assumes beyhood
should be ready to pay the price!
You!
You were the flag-bearer of a cause!
Did you not know our way at all?
Everything went awry
in your absence, brother.
Hanlı Bazaar's order was disturbed.
Bandits hit the caravans.
We couldn't take them down.
Tekfur Ares came to the market.
He said he would pull out his merchants
if I didn't sell the market.
Ameer Sadettin backed me into selling.
I had no other choice.
You know who Tekfur Ares is, Dündar?
Tekfur Ares is the one who ambushed me
and my alps and killed them!
What did you say, son?
Foul bastard!
Brother...
How could I have known?
Forgive me.
What's been said here
will be kept a secret.
I have things to attend to.
Now, we wait.
When the time comes,
everything will be dealt with.
This shame is too heavy for me, brother.
Give the order...
I will get that bastard's head
to make up for my faults.
You're going to take his head, eh?
I will fight together with the ones
who gave their hearts to my cause.
However, you have no place in that fight.
It is my order...
gather your things.
Get to my brothers' oba in haste.
Tell them
that your brother Ertuğrul is alive,
so they don't mourn for their sibling.
And don't return to this oba
until I send word.
Son...
As you command, my bey.
We have a rough war awaiting us.
There is no place in it
for the faint-hearted or the weak-minded.
Who are you?
You!
-Guards!
-What's that?
God forbid, my bey,
if anything happened to you
we saw what would become of us.
Everyone will have learned
their lesson from it.
You sought our cause in my absence.
You did not leave the path.
Thank you, my beys.
Thank you, too.
Ever be here to lead us, my bey.
Until we find who ambushed you
and our alps and make him pay,
may God not let us rest, my bey.
I know who ambushed me.
Who was it, my bey?
Tekfur Ares.
My bey, then...
Then what are we waiting for,
my bey? To war!
Let's take that bastard infidel's head.
That scoundrel! Let us get to his fort
right away and give him what's coming.
Make him pay.
Let us hang that dog from the walls of
Karacahisar and make an example of him.
I will set up the one who set us up
with the biggest of ambushes, Turgut.
I will catch him off-guard
at his own fort.
I will not let him hide behind his lies,
his deceit or his walls.
It's Commander Yorgo. Commander Yorgo?
Send word to the fort.
I will write a letter to our sultan
explaining everything.
We will get everything ready
by the time the firman to conquer arrives.
But my bey,
why didn't you behead that infidel today?
I wanted to see if he had anything
to do with Ameer Sadettin, Bamsi.
I will act as if I know nothing.
Meanwhile, we will begin preparations
to conquer.
We will go visit the fort.
I will reach out in fellowship.
When we are there,
we will inspect the fort thoroughly.
We will see how fortified it is.
If they fight us from behind the walls
the emperor will send help.
The siege will last for months.
We will raid it off guard.
We will catch them as if in their sleep.
With you leading us, my bey...
we have no fear of the enemy,
no doubt of victory.
None, my bey, none. Oh, my heart!
It runs wild like a horse, my bey.
May God permit me to see
the day we take it, my bey.
We had been left to rust in your absence.
Now we are sharp as honed swords, my bey.
Our cause is to engrave God's justice
onto even the smallest stone.
Now, we fight for this cause.
The firman is from our sultan,
martyrdom is from God.
May God be with us and help us.
Yes, Ertuğrul Bey. As you command.
Ertuğrul...
He is to decide about my son
and my oba in front of the beys tomorrow.
Let's see what his decision will be.
Who does he think he is
to decide in front of the beys?
After all his impertinence,
what business do we have there?
Let's not go, so he'll be humiliated.
Don't get involved in things
you don't understand, Sancar.
I want Ertuğrul's head more than you do.
Alas, everything has its time.
He humiliated us in front of everyone.
To top it off, he slew our alps.
-I can no longer take it.
-Sancar!
Don't do something crazy.
This is a serious matter.
It is time to think with your head.
Ertuğrul said that he will decide
both about you and our oba
at the feast of beys tomorrow.
Don't you get that?
It would not benefit us to stand back,
Father. We cannot bow to his threats.
Tomorrow morning, at our oba's feast,
Bahadir Bey will sit in our marquee.
Bahadir Bey will arrive at Ertuğrul Bey's
feast as the bey of the unified Cavdars.
Then, he will decide accordingly.
Oh, Sancar!
If only you had half the wit my hatun has.
Do you think I will stomach
what Ertuğrul has done?
Let him play sovereign for now.
I will make the real decision
once the time comes.
Permission to enter, Bahadir Bey.
Come in, Kırca.
Aslıhan Hatun wishes to see you
with the beys at her marquee, Bahadir Bey.
What is that impudent woman up to now?
Let us go and see.
You'll be of great use to us, bastard.
You will confess to everything.
As-Salaam-Alaikum.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Come, sit, Bahadir Bey.
I consulted with my beys on a matter.
I wanted you to participate as well.
What's is it, Aslıhan Hatun?
What did you consult without informing me?
I have things to say about the feast,
Bahadir Bey.
I have postponed our oba's feast
for beyhood,
with permission from Ertuğrul Bey.
When your oba arrives, the beys
of the two fellow obas will sit...
and choose the Cavdar's bey.
You have no authority
or power to do that, Aslıhan Hatun.
You've had the Cavdars be belittled
following Ertuğrul's tail long enough.
I will no longer allow it.
The feast for beyhood
will be held in the morning.
You cowards!
What is this, Bahadir Bey?
Will you rebel against me too?
Will you stab me too?
I heard that your son and your alps...
stood up to our frontier bey
and drew their swords on him.
You sacrificed two alps in your fury.
Still, you come before me and think that
I will surrender my oba to you.
Alas, you are wrong.
Just wait till our Ertuğrul Bey
makes his decision,
then we will decide what to do together.
We decided to hold a feast with the beys.
-Why does Ertuğrul meddle in our feast?
-He is not just a frontier bey.
Ertuğrul Bey has defended our oba's honor
and given many a life for it.
Do not make us choose
between the two of you.
You will lose.
It will be as our Ertuğrul Bey has said.
Those who don't like my decision
may leave my marquee.
This feast will be held sooner or later.
My oba will settle here.
I will become the bey of all the Cavdars.
You cannot deprive me of my oba
by coercing with Ertuğrul.
Now, those beys who trust me, follow me.
The rest, what a shame...
May I come in, mother?
Come in, my son. Come in.
Mother.
The apple of my eye.
My son, the lion of great mountains.
Forgive me, mother.
I haven't been able to tend to you
since I returned.
I'd die for a single hair on your head.
Son, you are our only safeguard.
Just you lead us.
You came back, that's enough for me.
What are these, Mother?
Yours, Dündar's...
your brothers' first caps.
I sewed them with my own hands.
Your brothers left us.
You sent Dündar away.
My heart is in pieces.
I look at these and love you
as if all of you were here.
Mother...
Dündar is naive.
He needs to mature.
I did what was necessary.
He will learn that there is a price for
beyhood and the things he did.
I want Dündar to see his mistake, Mother.
When I believe he has,
I will call him back to the oba.
And when he is back,
I will give him an important mission...
to show me that he is ready.
You are right, son.
May God watch over you.
Come, Marya.
My lord.
You haven't slept for days.
I fear your rage might hurt you.
What if you rested a little?
Ertuğrul is back, Marya.
There will be no sleep for me.
I will not rest until I kill Ertuğrul.
That wretched man again.
Everything is his doing.
My brother died because of him.
A man that...
goes dark at night and bright in day
is unpredictable.
I have to be cautious at all times, Marya.
I will not rest until I kill Ertuğrul
with his own sword. Understand?
Nobody can harm you
so long as you stay strong, my lord.
Even Ertuğrul.
Let our enemies fear you.
What is it?
My lord,
we found two dead soldiers in the fort.
What?
Who killed them?
We don't know, my lord. We found no trace.
What do you mean, you don't know,
you idiot? What good are you?
Search every corner of the fort!
Find who did this!
Nobody sleeps until you do! Now get out!
Yes, my lord.
My lord...
Ertuğrul...
What if he knows that I was the one
who set him up?
What if he's playing me?
Door.
Now that Ertuğrul is back at his oba...
our sultan will soon
call me back to Konya.
We cannot leave these lands unattended.
Tomorrow we go to Ares first thing.
Yes, Eminence.
Ertuğrul Bey has sent word to oba beys
about the feast tomorrow at Hanlı Market.
It's clear he will get their backing
and seek revenge.
We need to keep our end tight.
Ertuğrul will figure out this set up
one way or the other.
Then he will occupy the fort
with the order of our sultan.
We cannot let him have this prize.
He will figure everything out
once he learns it was Ares who set him up.
Both Ekaterina...
and you.
It's crooked.
I put so much effort into it...
but it's still crooked.
A crooked arrow won't find its target.
So, I shouldn't work on it.
I worked hard
to pull Ertuğrul my way.
But he always went in his own direction.
He always stood in the way of my goal.
Alas, from now on
I will do whatever it takes...
collaborate with whoever I need to
so that he may not.
Even if I leave this land...
I will break his arms and wings.
That's what happened, Halime.
I finally made it back...
by evading human traffickers
and the ambushes of the inglorious.
I came to you.
Oh, the things
you've gone through, Ertuğrul!
How did you put up with all that?
I took refuge in God
and thought of my cause...
my oba, my sons and you, Halime.
It's God's will.
I have life left to further our cause,
see our children grow...
and grow old with you.
May God give you a long life, Ertuğrul.
May he not leave us without you.
We saw what would happen in your absence.
It is all over now.
I am at the head of our oba...
and with you and our children.
I will hold a great feast tomorrow
at the Hanlı Market in honor of my return.
All the beys in the vicinity will come.
I want you and my mother to be there.
May it be a feast worthy of us.
Let both our friends and our foes see that
we are one and in prosperity.
-Turgut, take precautions.
-Alps! Surround him.
Who the hell are you?
Show your face.
Else I'll cut you with my sword.
Speak, who are you?
As-Salaam-Alaikum, Ertuğrul Bey.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam, Atsız.
Who is this Atsız, my bey?
What is this?
I have important news for you.
I caught one of the men who ambushed us.
He has things to tell you.
Where is he?
Come with me.
Come on alps, after him.
Who is this, Artuk Bey?
It's clear he came in the nick of time,
Turgut Alp.
You're talking about power, rulership,
gold, Emir Sadettin but...
you couldn't handle even a margrave.
Ertuğrul buried you in the ground
in front of us.
Once...
I was playing chess here.
Commander Vasilius
was sitting right there.
He used to say the exact same words
as you do.
But he didn't listen to me.
Then, Ertuğrul beheaded him.
So, be careful.
You might face the same destiny.
Know, Emir Sadettin, that I only
tolerate you in the name of peace
and trust between us at the bazaar.
You're so noble.
You're the one who ambushed Ertuğrul
and killed his alps. I know that.
I could take your head
and your castle if I wanted to.
You could never prove that, Emir Sadettin.
That wound on your back.
How did you get it?
Is it getting better?
The wound dealt to you by Bamsi,
one of Ertuğrul's alps,
when you set up the ambush.
Emir Sadettin...
If you think I’m not aware
that you sent that letter to Ekaterina
to get me to ambush Ertuğrul,
you’re wrong.
The letter wasn't sealed
by you, obviously.
But your rage was in there.
Let me give you some advice.
A man should not pursue dreams
that he cannot ever achieve.
Otherwise, it will end in frustration.
Only pursue God and the truth.
Truth is gold.
And gold is what fills our pockets,
providing there is peace
between the two states.
If you wish to get rich
by committing to our agreement,
then you will heed my words.
Yes.
But you'll go back to Konya soon.
Then what?
Bahadir Bey is here.
Regard him as my lieutenant.
Our agreement will proceed as is.
Bahadir Bey.
I saw the wrath of him and his sons
at Hanlı Bazaar.
We have wrath, don’t we Ares?
What about Ertuğrul's wrath?
What about that?
Last night,
two men were killed in my castle.
The killer is still at large.
So?
I doubt Ertuğrul knows the truth.
But he might be involved
in last night's incident.
What if...
he knows the truth and is playing with us?
Rest assured, Tekfur Ares.
If Ertuğrul knew
that you were the ambusher,
he would have already taken your head
at Hanlı Bazaar.
He'll gather his beys today.
He'll go after the brigands
that attacked merchants,
as well as the man that ambushed him.
Before he finds out it was you,
we'll take him down, god willing.
Maybe it is indeed wise
for you go back to Konya, Emir Sadettin.
While we prepare for Ertuğrul's end,
you can distract the Sultan
and keep his eyes diverted.
Hopefully, he'll never open them again.
As long there is peace, Emir Sadettin,
we have the same interests.
Then appreciate the peace, Tekfur Ares.
Let Ertuğrul die,
so we can profit forever.
I know everything.
Ares ambushed me, killed my alps.
Knowing that I'm alive,
he sent you after me.
You ran to him
right after you escaped from us.
I know everything.
Then why don't you kill me?
You'll tell me everything you know.
I know nothing.
Talk...
or face pain.
Wait, I'll tell you everything!
Were you there when Ares
ambushed my alps and I?
How did he know where I was?
That night...
We got the command that night.
We were told to dress like brigands.
Ares was dressed like one, too.
He said we were going to kill you.
Bey...
Ares probably got the command
right after Sultan decided on voyage.
Who told Ares...
we were going off on a voyage?
I don't know, I swear.
Ekaterina was with him.
They were pretty sure you were dead.
They were laughing with joy.
Ekaterina...
Bey...
She took an oath to take revenge on Ural.
So, she's in on it, too.
Who told her?
Anyone close to the Sultan
who knew about the voyage
has to be a suspect.
Emir Sadettin was there too, bey.
I see him as a suspect too, Artuk Bey.
Ertuğrul's return has
messed everything up.
In addition to that, our strongest ally
is returning to Konya.
This will make things difficult.
But we'll get through it.
What is our next move against Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul acted like he didn't know
I was the one who ambushed him.
I still doubt whether he really knows.
But the soldiers killed in the castle
last night have risen my suspicions.
Ertuğrul could be behind it.
So, you think Ertuğrul
might be playing with us, Sir?
Anything is possible.
Ertuğrul is not just a warrior.
He is a quick-witted Turk.
Remember, even Emir Sadettin
couldn't bring him down.
But to defeat the Turks,
we must defeat Ertuğrul.
And until then,
we must be quick-witted too.
Ertuğrul will be the object of focus
until we regather our strength.
We'll accept the olive branch he extended,
but on the sly, we'll corner him.
If he's playing games with us,
we'll play one with him, too.
When you escaped,
what did you talk about with Ares
in the castle?
He was angry with you
for breaking the bazaar agreement.
He swore to kill all trade in the bazaar.
Nicaea...
There is this merchant from Nicaea.
Niko...
He sent me to bring
that merchant alive to castle.
When is this merchant coming?
In a few days.
Bey.
I think that merchant is the same one
whom Emir Sadettin included
in the agreement
to facilitate trade with the Franks.
Emir Sadettin again?
He definitely made a deal with Ares...
before Bahadir attempted
to take over the bazaar.
He brought Bahadir here
and allowed him to set eyes
on Aliyar Bey's tent.
Emir Sadettin seems to appear
under every stone.
May those stones crush his head, Bey.
I told you everything I know.
Let me live.
Bamsi...
Do what is necessary.
Will you let the Sultan know
what we've learned, Bey?
I will, Artuk Bey.
Our Sultan will know
what a traitor Emir Sadettin is.
Atsız, get to the castle now.
Keep me posted.
It's a good consistency.
Boil it a little while, then move on.
Sure, Mother Hayme.
Ladies!
Save the best parts of the meat
for the people.
Feed the poor.
Give alms.
With their prayers,
may all evil, seen and unseen,
go away.
God willing!
May things be easy.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
What is this, Göktuğ?
It's from our Sultan, Your Majesty.
Our Sultan?
What for?
A robe and gifts for Ertuğrul Bey.
The Sultan orders you to return to Konya,
since Ertuğrul Bey is back at the tent.
And before returning...
Before returning, what?
Say what you were going to say, damn it!
He orders you to deliver
the margrave insignias to Ertuğrul Bey.
You, yourself,
will announce it to the beys
and dress him in his robes.
God damn it!
Ertuğrul and his margraveship...
God, forgive me!
I just can't get rid of him!
And now, I must dress him up
in his robes with my own hands.
"Mighty Emir Sadettin Köpek
wasn't even a challenge for Ertuğrul,"
they all said.
What is your order, Your Majesty?
What can we do?
We can't oppose the Sultan's orders.
Tell them to prepare the beylic insignias.
Prepare for the voyage to Konya
after the council.
Tomorrow is another day.
I am Emir Sadettin.
God willing,
I'll finish what I've started.
All he's brought is trouble since he came.
He is so blinded by anger.
How dare he draw his sword
against Ertuğrul Bey?
Neither he nor Emir Sadettin
have brought us peace.
Girl, don't you worry.
Ertuğrul always makes
the best possible decisions.
Mother Hayme, this man takes no orders.
Then he shares his destiny with Ural.
Thank God we've lived to see these days.
We had long yearned
for the meeting of the council.
That's not all.
Ertuğrul is back.
And we must think about
you and Turgut's engagement.
Ertuğrul...
Now that he's postponed
the council meeting,
many of the Cavdar beys
don't recognize my reign.
Ertuğrul, you...
I have no patience left for him.
My sword...
I barely can keep it in its sheath,
Your Majesty!
Tame your wrath, Bahadir Bey.
If you drew your sword against him
at the bazaar
accompanied by your sons and alps,
he would obviously look for revenge.
Be patient until the opportunity arises.
Regardless...
you must kiss his hand
and recognize his reign.
Never!
I will never!
Then say goodbye to your Cavdar bey
and your margrave.
Those Oguz beys obey him
without question.
Emir, Your Majesty.
You...
You must allow me.
Allow me to behead that Ertuğrul
in the middle of the council meeting
and put it on a spike
before the Oguz beys!
You'll do what I say.
Be patient.
The Sultan has called me
to return to Konya.
But I'll be back.
When the time comes,
slice up his whole family
along with Ertuğrul, if you wish.
The verdict he gives on you
and your tent, it must be in our favor
Bahadir Bey...
remember my word!
If you can't reunite the Cavdars
and be their bey...
you are nothing to me, either.
Welcome bey!
Welcome, bey!
Good to see you, beys.
Thank you.
You may know that my alps and I
were ambushed,
and the bastards came at us
from everywhere.
In my absence,
they unsettled the bazaar.
They longed to possess...
our food, our trade, our peace.
Like hyenas searching for a carcass,
they attacked from every direction.
We'll knock the wind out of their sails!
Now you're back,
we'll cut their heads off.
We will do!
-Thank you.
-We will do, Bey!
It's obvious that...
Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad,
like all the beys here...
is extremely happy
that Ertuğrul Bey is alive.
Therefore...
our Sultan has given the order...
for me to confer
the margrave insignias.
Good luck, Bey!
Congratulations, bey!
May God be with you!
Thank you, beys.
Thank you.
Ertuğrul Bey.
May this bring good fortune.
To achieve good fortune...
first, we need to clear out
the agents of misfortune among us.
Let Sancar Bey in.
I'll give my verdict before my beys.
The great warrior, Lukas,
died for our cause.
To fill his place, I'll choose one of you
to be commander of the castle.
Commander Kostas...
From now on,
you will have the command of the castle.
I'm sure you'll fulfill this duty capably.
I trust you.
I won't betray your trust, sir.
I'll fight until my last breath.
While we're keeping peace with Ertuğrul,
we'll make te Turk tents run with blood.
Sir...
We paid the brigands,
raided the merchant caravans.
But if we attack the Turk tents,
there will be no more chance for peace.
We won't attack the tents.
Someone else will.
Who, sir?
The legendary knight, Titan.
I sent word already. He'll be here soon.
Sir...
Titan is a dangerous man.
He might cause us great trouble.
We need someone like him, Kostas.
Someone who renders the Turks helpless.
Ertuğrul's hands will be tied.
And I'll strike...
the final blow.
With your two alps,
you pulled a weapon on me.
Have anything to say?
Ertuğrul Bey...
for the sake our peace and unity,
for which you called this meeting,
just blame it on his youth.
Picking at this scab
will do no good for anyone.
Sancar Bey crossed the line.
And he'll pay the price, Emir Sadettin.
Now...
I want to hear what he has to say.
You impinged on my father's rights,
Ertuğrul Bey.
It was my duty to retaliate,
according to our laws and traditions.
I did what it takes as Cavdar Bey.
Your greed and your arrogance
costed two lives.
I thought you would be
ashamed of your actions...
but you're still insubordinate.
You cross the line.
Mighty Turk beys,
I do not wish to keep
this Cavdar Bey among us.
He would poison us.
Today, the weapon has drawn against me.
Tomorrow, it will be drawn against you.
He speaks the truth.
He who stands against the margrave
must face the consequences.
Consequences!
By my will, you will be exiled
from these lands, Sancar Bey.
Take your horse and your weapon
and leave these lands, now.
If I see you on these lands again...
I won't hesitate to chop off your head.
Alps!
Ertuğrul Bey...
I won't let you exile my son.
If you're looking
for agents of misfortune,
look to your brother Dündar and the beys
who agreed to sell me the bazaar.
Neither my brother Dündar...
nor the beys in my tent
are tolerated when they make mistakes,
Bahadir Bey.
Not at all.
First, you obey me.
If you do, we fight together
to make these lands our own.
Otherwise, I exile you and your tent,
just like I did to Sancar Bey.
You interfered in our council
to banish from my own ancient tent.
Is this what you call justice?
Is this how you govern as margrave?
And you, you cheer this tyranny
when you should stand against it!
Shame on your bey!
Bahadir Bey!
Enough!
Know your place!
If you don't, you'll find your fate
on the tip of Ertuğrul Bey's sword.
Don't push us.
Ertuğrul Bey is the margrave
of these lands.
In politics, in peace, in war,
in trade and in law,
his word is law.
His word is the word of the state.
Don't you know that?
-His Majesty speaks the truth.
-Yes, he speaks the truth.
Now...
either obey Ertuğrul Bey
along with the other beys, here...
or take your tent with you
and leave these lands.
Thanks.
Beys!
Our duty is to bring justice to the world
so that we may please God.
We won't be tyrannical ourselves,
nor will we surrender to tyranny.
In this cause, we will dominate
and force the enemy to kneel.
God willing, the holy flag of the justice
will be raised around the world.
God willing, Ertuğrul Bey!
God willing.
God willing, bey!