Episode 99 will start after 12:49 min.
Know that I don't fear death.
But I did not poison you!
I am not guilty of this treachery!
Enough!
What is it, Artuk Bey?
Stop, my Bey.
My Bey, Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp
were not poisoned by Bahadir Bey.
What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
I found the poison given to the Sultan
in the cave of the herbalist, my Bey.
-Are you sure?
-I am sure, my Bey.
The poison that was given
to our sultan contained wolfsbane.
Among other poisonous herbs.
I'm sure, my Bey. Absolutely sure.
Bahadir wasn't here when
our sultan was poisoned.
My Bey, whoever poisoned the sultan
also poisoned Turgut Alp
and Aslıhan Hatun.
This person used Esma and Bahadir's alp
so that we would pin the blame on him.
Only one person is capable of this.
Emir Sadettin!
-Brother! Brother!
-Turgut!
Stop.
You weren't poisoned...
by Bahadir Bey.
Release Bahadir Bey.
Untie his alps.
You...
humiliated me for nothing.
How do you intend to make amends?
Consider it your punishment
for the evil you have spread up until now.
I suggest you get a grip of yourself
from this point on
so that your head might remain
upon your shoulders.
That's all I'll say.
We'll discuss this later, Turgut.
Be wary of Bahadir from now on.
He'll come after you
for his revenge sooner or later.
As you command, my Bey.
What is Niko the Merchant
doing with all these soldiers, Atsiz?
Ares must have asked
the emperor for reinforcements.
That's a good-sized Byzantine unit.
If we can't stop them...
they'll cause us problems
when we attack the castle.
Abdurrahman, go quickly.
Ertuğrul Bey should know about this.
What will you do?
I'll try to infiltrate them.
I'll see what I can learn
from this merchant, Niko.
God help you, my Bey.
They've travelled far.
They have carriages full of equipment.
They can't travel at night.
They'll set up camp soon.
Abdurrahman, this will have
to be done tomorrow. Be quick.
All right.
Hopefully this balm will heal
the wounds caused by the poison.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Thank God this curse has gone
from your bodies.
Thank God.
God spared your lives and gave you
back to us, my beautiful daughter.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
May God keep you with us.
Who did this?
Who dared infiltrate our tribe?
Who had us poisoned in our own home?
Turgut Alp, we don't have any evidence
yet, but we'll find out who it was.
Alpamis was Bahadir Bey's alp.
Given we know Alpamis had
something to do with this,
why did you let Bahadir go, Ertuğrul Bey?
There are some secrets
which are heavier than mountains.
If they're revealed at the wrong time
they would crush everyone.
He killed Alpamis and Esma
to leave no traces behind.
Don't worry.
I'll find out who was ultimately
responsible for having you poisoned...
sooner or later.
Then the world will know who he is.
What about the conquest
of Karacahisar, my Bey?
Nothing's changed
in respect of that, Turgut.
We'll return home
and continue preparations.
You stay here. Gather our forces.
Assemble the beys.
Bahadir is furious. Be careful.
His fury can't touch me, my Bey.
Don't worry.
Thanks, Turgut. Thanks.
I don't care if they'd shed
only one drop of your blood,
I'll make them pay for an eternity,
my Bey.
He humiliated me and my alps
on my turf and in front of everyone.
I'll drown him and his alps
in their own blood.
I'll make Ertuğrul regret what he's done.
Look at what they did
to the great Bahadir Bey and his wife!
We shouldn't so much as
let them breathe, my Bey.
If they try to make that man bey
tomorrow, I won't stand for it.
What did you just say, wife?
How could he possibly be bey before I die?
I'd rather burn this tent and this tribe
to the ground than hand them over to them.
I'll kill whoever stands in my way
and leave his body for the carrion.
The dye has been cast.
Dark clouds have been gathering
above them for some time.
Henceforth, they'll have all kinds
of trouble raining down upon them!
When Sancar arrives with his alps...
I'll attack Aslıhan Hatun's tent.
Who among them is capable
of escaping your grasp, my Bey?
I'll kill them both
with my own two hands.
Let Ertuğrul see then
who enjoys the last laugh.
A stranger approaches!
Let him approach!
Who are you? What do you want here?
Brave warriors of Jesus!
God bless you all!
I'm a merchant from Hanli bazaar.
My name is Alfonso.
What is it you seek, merchant?
There are a lot of bandits around.
I'm worried about traveling
to the castle alone.
I'd be grateful if I was allowed to spend
the night in your camp, commander.
Your name is Alfonso. Are you from Venice?
No! No, sir.
I am from Genova.
Welcome to Arycanda.
Thank you.
Take Alfonso the Merchant's horse.
So, you're a merchant?
What do you trade at Hanli Bazaar?
My customers are usually Turks.
I sell whatever they desire.
Most of your clients are Turks?
Then you'll know them well.
I know those barbarians all too well.
I'd like to hear what you know.
Commander, the merchant will be
our guest until we get to the castle.
Take his sword.
He can have it back tomorrow morning.
God bless you.
My name is Niko. I'm a merchant too.
Ertuğrul, Bey of the Kayis is back.
Tell me, what do the traders
of Hanli bazaar say about that?
The Turks are happy Ertuğrul's back.
But not you.
Does Ertuğrul Bey not get along
with Christian merchants?
Ertuğrul Bey treats everyone equally.
But that's irrelevant.
He's a Turk.
We don't want a Turk holding the reins.
You make the most of the gold you take
off the Turks, but you don't like them.
I'm not your average merchant
who only thinks of profit.
Until the Turks are thrown
out of these lands,
we'll never have order here.
Both smart and loyal.
It'll be a pleasure talking with you.
But rest now, we can continue this later.
-The soldiers should rest.
-As you wish.
The knights continue their training.
They improve every day, thanks to you.
It won't be enough, Kostas.
The Turks have alps who can shoot
arrows accurately from horseback.
They're all ready to die and go to heaven.
They're skillful enough to scale
the walls of this castle.
Whatever we do, it won't be enough
when the war begins.
The units coming from Nicaea
will make us stronger, sir.
Exactly.
The merchant who came
with the soldiers, Niko...
I can use him to control
the trade in these lands, Kostas.
He's as precious to me as an army.
Will Ertuğrul stand for that?
I saved Ertuğrul's best friend.
He's indebted to me.
My first request will deal with trade.
He won't be able to refuse.
I have no concerns about Ertuğrul.
But first, the envoy
and soldiers must get here.
We'll be a lot stronger
militarily and economically then.
And Bahadir? What's the latest update?
Ertuğrul humiliated him thoroughly,
in front of his own people too.
-Bahadir is furious with Ertuğrul.
-Very good.
Bahadir isn't on good terms
with Emir Sadettin.
And now he's enemies with Ertuğrul.
He's like a tiger that
wants to rip its prey apart.
An ideal partner for me.
What are your orders, sir?
Go to Bahadir at once. Tell him
I want to talk to him over dinner.
Let's see if he wants to be our new ally.
If it happens as I think it will,
I can't even imagine
what we'll do to Ertuğrul.
As you command, sir.
Have you spotted the well?
We have, my Bey.
We await your permission to dig it.
-Is it close to the tribe?
-It is, my Bey.
All right.
One well wasn't enough during the summer.
A second well will be good for the people.
Prepare the stones well.
Get a stonemason if needed.
As you wish, my Bey.
Artuk Bey, has a place been spotted
close by Hanli bazaar for a well?
My Bey, following your order,
I assigned three people to the task.
They'll fulfil that duty soon.
All right.
How are your alps, Bamsi?
They're well, my Bey. Training continues.
The alps are impatient
to attack the castle.
Turgut Alp will live with
the Cavdar tribe from now on.
Hopefully, he'll become their bey.
You'll be responsible
for the alps from now on.
-You're the head alp now, Bamsi.
-Thank you.
As you command my Bey.
I'll perform my duties honorably, my Bey.
Thank you, Bamsi. Thank you.
Thank God, seeing you
like this has reassured us.
Who would dare do such a thing
to the Hatun of the Cavdar tribe?
We should take their heads.
-He's right.
-Let's take their heads.
-Cut their heads off.
-How could this happen?
My beys...
Ertuğrul Bey and I will not let this go.
But there are more pressing matters
in front of us.
The unity and very existence
of the Cavdar tribe is under threat.
We must look to preserve our unity first.
-True. He's right.
-The threat must be defeated.
Bahadir Bey is out of control.
His fury knows no limits.
Our fear is that he might attempt
to hurt the people of the Cavdar tribe
and damage our kinship
with the Kayi tribe.
Bahadir Bey suffered too, Aslıhan Hatun.
He and his wife were humiliated unfairly.
His honor was tarnished.
You forget what Bahadir Bey
has done in the past, Ivaz Bey.
Don't forget what he did
to Ertuğrul Bey at the inn.
And it was Alpamis
who gave the poison to Esma.
Alpamis was Bahadir's alp.
Or didn't you know that?
-How could this happen?
-How could Bahadir Bey attempt this?
Impossible.
If he believed Bahadir Bey was guilty,
why did Ertuğrul Bey let him go free?
Ertuğrul Bey learned Bahadir Bey
hadn't given the poison to Alpamis,
so he freed him.
Bahadir Bey was unable
to control his own alp.
His mistake almost led to my death
and that of Aslıhan Hatun.
-He's right.
-True.
Ertuğrul Bey knows what he's doing.
When the time comes,
he'll tell us everything.
For now, we must focus on keeping
our tribe unified and safe.
He's right.
To this end, I, Hatun
of the Cavdar tribe, demand
a council is convened as soon as possible
to elect Turgut Alp as our bey.
I still don't understand it, my Bey.
How could Emir Sadettin
try something like this?
How could he become so angry that
he was able to do such a terrible thing
to two innocent people, my Bey?
Rage consumes the mind, Artuk Bey.
My Bey, what kind of rage is this?
What kind of rage could have possessed him
to the extent he even tried
to poison the Seljuk Sultan?
Why would he do it, my Bey?
It's obvious he wants
to be Sultan instead of Emir.
My Bey, is it not our duty
to tell our sultan of this?
We will, Artuk Bey, we will.
As soon as we take Karacahisar Castle
I'll go to the sultan myself
to tell him everything we've learned.
But this must remain a secret
known only to you and me until then.
Don't worry, my Bey.
I know how important this is.
Artuk Bey...
our state and Sultan face a deadly threat.
It is our duty to defeat this threat.
If something should happen to me...
I want you to tell our sultan
what we've discovered.
As you command, my Bey.
May God protect our state and our sultan.
Amen.
Aslıhan Hatun is right.
I support Aslıhan Hatun's decision.
My beys...
Turgut Alp has led our alps into battle.
He has their love and respect.
He protected us against the Crusaders,
Governor Vasilius, even my brother Ural.
He deserves to be our Bey.
He is worthy of being our Bey.
He'll make our kinship
with the Kayis eternal.
Bahadir Bey has Cavdar blood.
He's your uncle.
Can a stranger be our bey when
someone with Cavdar blood still lives?
It is not a question of blood,
Ivaz Bey, it is one of merit.
Our unity is threatened.
The enemy grows stronger
and comes closer every day.
For this reason, the Cavdar tribe
needs a strong and brave bey
such as Turgut Alp.
-Aslıhan Hatun is right.
-She speaks the truth.
The Kayi and Cavdar tribes are one.
No differences.
We are Cavdar and we are Kayi.
This is my tribe.
It is my sworn duty to keep
the tribe both unified and strong.
A strong bey makes
for a strong tribe and people.
-May God grant us good fortune.
-Amen.
A council will be held soon.
May I enter, my Bey?
Come in, Bamsi!
Sit down.
Did you catch the trader, Abdurrahman?
He was accompanied
by a lot of soldiers, my Bey.
Atsiz is trying to
infiltrate the military unit
so as to get information from Niko.
He must have been worried
the trader might die in an ambush, my Bey.
He wants to discover what he knows.
He'll do what he said he'd do, Artuk Bey.
The soldiers probably aren't here
purely to protect the merchant, my Bey.
Ares asked for reinforcements.
He makes a show of being our friend
but he's plotting behind our backs.
But this will benefit us
more than it does him.
His precautions are
going to backfire on him.
What are we going to do, my Bey?
We'll attack the soldiers
when they least expect it, Bamsi.
Then, we'll enter castle dressed as them.
So, so... We fight tomorrow, my Bey?
God willing, we fight tomorrow.
It's time for war.
I'll lead the alps
disguised as the soldiers,
while you get the remaining alps
ready to attack the castle, Artuk Bey.
As you command, my Bey.
Your job will be to prepare
the alps for the initial attack, Bamsi.
-We'll set out at once.
-As you command, my Bey.
Kirca!
Yes, Chief Alp Turgut.
Follow Ivaz Bey.
Keep an eye on him at all times.
If he meets Bahadir Bey, let me know...
immediately.
As you command, Chief Alp Turgut.
We've overcome many troubles, Aslıhan.
Curses fell upon us like rain.
We narrowly escaped death. But...
We never gave up, Aslıhan.
I've caused you so much pain and torment.
But at all times you thought only of me,
never yourself.
I don't know how
I can ever repay you, Turgut.
You're my wife, Aslıhan.
You are my life, you are my blood.
My one hope is to protect you...
from all harm.
Hopefully, we have seen
the last of our troubles.
Evil-doers can no longer reach us, Turgut.
Our love is shielded by
faith, belief and passion, Aslıhan.
As long as we keep it that way,
any dangers or hardships
we may face in the future,
will spring back from whence they came.
May I enter, my Bey?
Come in, Kayatekin.
My Bey...
We've heard from Sancar Bey.
He's at the Bloody Hill with the alps.
He awaits your word to attack.
My brave son! Just in time.
At last. No longer will we have
to keep our rage hidden within.
We'll show them what kind
of man Bahadir Bey is.
Tomorrow night I'll attack their tent
and take their heads myself.
I shall become Bey and show everyone
who scorned me who Bahadir Bey really is.
Ertuğrul can't stop me, not even
Sultan Alaeddin himself can stop me.
-Kayatekin.
-Yes, my Bey.
I will go and see Sancar
and the alps tomorrow.
You will be responsible for
preparing our alps here for the attack.
As you command, my Bey.
The tables are turning at last, wife.
God. God.
I don't want to wear it but duty calls.
Forgive me, God. Forgive me.
Amen.
My god!
Who are you?
-Hafsa, what are you doing?
-Bamsi?
What is this?
Hafsa... Duty, I'm doing my duty.
That's the reason
I'm wearing this infidel uniform.
God... I was so scared!
I thought you were one of them!
That's good, good...
If my own wife believed it,
the infidels will surely fall for it.
My sweet wife...
I have to go now.
Let's say our goodbyes, come on.
What's wrong, wife?
I know it's you underneath that
but if I touch you
I'll feel like I'm hugging one of them.
Come on, Hafsa, don't be silly.
Let me say goodbye...
No, no!
Go now, please.
We'll hug all you want when you return.
Go... Godspeed!
My Hafsa... If that's what you want...
Even the clothes of the infidel
bring me bad luck!
Right then. I'll go.
Tomorrow, we attack Karacahisar Castle
like hawks upon an owl's nest.
I hope you return with a victory
worthy of you, son.
May your sword be as sharp
as your cause is just.
Thank you, Mother.
I hope the battle is short, my Bey.
Karacahisar is a formidable fortress.
It will be hard to take,
though you know that better than I.
We are strengthened by
two great forces, Halime.
Effort and faith.
As long as we put all our effort into it,
a century might become a second.
And as we give our all,
so will God give us faith.
God willing, God willing.
I can swing my sword
just like you showed me, Father.
I've learned.
My brave warrior.
The way you swing your sword
is dictated by your enemy.
You must find where he is weakest
and direct your sword to that point.
How?
Come.
Listen, son...
Once upon a time, the Oghuz tribe
kept being attacked
by a monster called Tepegoz.
The monster would eat 500 sheep
and two men every day.
The Oghuz had no way of fighting it.
At the time there lived a warrior
called Basat, son of Uruz.
The monster Tepegoz killed his brother.
So Basat swore an oath to kill Tepegoz.
Even though everyone said
it was impossible,
Basat took up his sword
and headed for Tepegoz's cave.
-Did he kill it?
-Just wait.
Basat had learned that the monster's
weakest spot was its eye.
He found a place to hide
and heated a piece of metal over a fire.
Then he stabbed Tepegoz
in the eye with it.
Tepegoz screamed so loudly
that even the mountains trembled.
Basat, after stabbing
the monster in its eye,
slit its throat with
his sword and killed it.
What a hero, Father!
He who knows his enemy is always a hero.
Always hit them where they are weakest.
Just like Basat hitting Tepegoz
in the eye.
-Got it?
-Yes, Father.
Good boy!
Go along now. I have things to do.
Keep swinging your sword.
God protect you.
May God protect you.
Mother, Father is going to kill
all his enemies at the castle.
I wish I could go too.
What castle, Gündüz?
Put down your sword and go to bed. Now.
Your father will take you
on a hunt, tomorrow.
Sleep now so that morning comes quick.
Go now. Sweet dreams.
-Sweet dreams, dear.
-Come on.
Commerce is unknown to Turks.
They understand only one thing.
War.
Scoundrels!
They'll be sent back to the hell
from whence they came.
I heard that Commander Ares
is a great warrior.
Only a man like him...
can be relied upon to succeed.
You heard right, Alfonso.
It'd be much better for us
if Governor Ares controlled Hanli bazaar.
Commander Ares wanted the emperor
to send me here anyway.
How well do you know Commander Ares?
I don't. Not at all. Never even met him.
All I know is that he's a great warrior.
That's it.
If a warrior like Commander Ares
and a merchant like you ruled
Hanli bazaar, we'd all be rich.
Ertuğrul Bey! You just won't die.
Don't worry...
It's not over yet.
Come to Karacahisar with us.
I'm sure Commander Ares will be
pleased to make your acquaintance.
I'd be glad of that too,
Merchant Niko.
What's wrong?
The wheel's broken.
We can't move until it's fixed.
I own several carriages.
I know how to fix them. I'd like to help.
Speak.
Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun
gathered us together last night.
They asked us to support
Turgut Alp being elected Bey.
How dare they!
After everything they've done...
they still want to usurp my birth right.
I don't know about the others
but I don't support it, my Bey.
You were right. Ertuğrul is doing it
to seize control of our tribe.
Look at me!
Do I look like the sort of man who'd let
Ertuğrul's chief alp
take my tribe from me?
No, my Bey.
They thought I'd stand silently by,
no matter what they do to provoke me.
I'll show them my claws
and roar so loudly they'll be in no doubt
that the lion still lives.
Training must continue.
Keep a close watch over everything.
Hello, hero.
You don't look very happy.
What happened?
My father was meant to take me on a hunt.
But he hasn't come home yet.
I saw your father ride away.
Did he go far away?
If I knew where he went...
I'd be able to tell you
when he'll get back.
So be it.
I can't help if you don't tell me.
He went to fight.
Where?
Karacahisar Castle.
Karacahisar Castle?
You know what? Don't worry.
I've got some good news for you.
-The flying horse is coming.
-The flying horse?
Be quiet. If anybody hears,
the horse won't come.
If you want to see it, come
to the big tree behind the tribe. Okay?
I'll wait for you there.
And... your first hunt will be
on a flying horse.
But don't be dressed like an alp.
-The horse will be scared.
-Okay, okay.
Don't forget what I said.
Come by yourself and don't tell anyone.
If anyone else knows,
the horse will go away, deal?
Deal. I won't tell a soul.
Okay. Go to the tent and get ready.
I'll be waiting for you.
What's up, Darius?
Nothing. We were just talking.
Darius tells good stories.
All right then.
Alps!
Ivaz Bey went
straight to Bahadir Bey's tent.
He probably told him everything.
He won't stay down now.
Kirca, be well prepared.
Bahadir will make his move soon.
As you command, Chief Alp Turgut.
How dare you enter without permission?
You slandered me.
You humiliated me.
Instead of asking for my forgiveness
you claim my right for your own!
Are you wholly without shame?
Know your place, Bahadir Bey.
Know your place!
You're the one who doesn't know his place!
Being Bey is my right!
I'll burn this tent down if I have to,
but I won't let you take my right!
My wife is the Hatun.
It is my right as much as yours...
to be Bey.
If you're so confident of your right,
face me in the council...
and claim it.
Even admitting your right
to challenge me...
would besmirch the good name of the tribe.
You... are a Kayi alp.
You have no right
to be Bey of the Cavdars!
Enough!
It was Ertuğrul Bey's decision.
Turgut will stand. And you will accept it.
Ertuğrul Bey...
And what if I don't?
Then your neck will know my axe.
But...
nobody will save you this time.
I'm warning you for the last time.
Drop this claim...
and don't stand in my way.
You know where we are, Bahadir Bey.
We'll be waiting for you.
I tried everything I could.
I'll gladly shed my blood...
if that's what it takes to stop you.
You'll see who Bahadir Bey... really is.
Door!
Kirca... Follow him wherever he goes.
I want to know everything he does.
As you command, Chief Alp Turgut.
Atsiz has infiltrated them.
He broke the wheel to slow them down.
Indeed, my Bey.
He's stopped them in their tracks.
The gear has fallen off.
We'll have to find it.
Soldiers!
Be careful. Guard both sides of the road.
You go that way and you over there, go!
Everyone else look for the gear. Go!
Do we attack, my Bey?
Wait.
Let's see what happens, Bamsi.
This Atsiz is a smart man, my Bey.
If we proceed carefully
we can finish this, Bamsi.
Put on the Byzantine uniforms we brought
and make your way into their camp.
You'll attack from within,
we'll attack from without.
Got it, my Bey.
We hawks will attack this
flock of birds in unison.
Go now, Bamsi. God help you.
Amen, my Bey. Let's go.
I frequently travel by carriage.
I've never seen such a thing.
No one could be in any doubt we're
approaching the cursed Turkish lands.
Let's put the wheel back on.
We're not going anywhere
without that gear.
Be on your guard!
That's Kostas,
one of Ares' commanders, my Bey.
At ease.
-What's he doing here?
-Ares is obviously looking for a new ally
to replace Emir Sadettin.
Something wrong, commander?
Lost your way?
I thought I might have,
Bahadir Bey, but...
now that I've seen you,
I know we're on the right path.
I'm sorry for what was done to you.
If it hadn't been for Governor Ares,
Ertuğrul would have had your head.
Governor Ares told Ertuğrul,
where to find the antidote
for Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun.
Thanks to Governor Ares,
Ertuğrul realized you were innocent.
So are you saying
I owe my life to Ares, commander?
Tell me.
Should I consider myself
indebted to him, commander?
You already know that
Ertuğrul is a threat
to commerce and to peace.
So? Say it already.
If you have something to say,
say it like a man!
We wish to live in peace
with the Turks here .
and protect our mutual interests.
But Ertuğrul Bey makes this impossible.
He's the margrave of these lands.
If you have a problem,
I suggest you take it up with him.
Being the margrave means nothing.
He who cooperates
with Governor Ares, wins.
We don't want Ertuğrul Bey to win,
we want you to win.
Well... so...
what do you want from me?
Commander Ares invites you
to dine with him.
He wants to discuss matters
of trade and cooperation with you.
I'd like that too.
But if Ares wants to talk to me,
he should come to my tent as my guest.
When he's ready, have him send
a messenger and I'll invite him.
Now return to your master...
and tell him what I said.
Alps... Let's go.
Bismillah.
Spread out, all sides of the camp.
Guard your positions.
Destroy them as soon
as we get the signal.
Well done, kid.
We'll enjoy many great victories
soon, Marya.
I'd like to celebrate it
with a child of our own.
A child?
Yes, our child.
I grew up alone, Marya.
I'd like to have a family.
And you're worthy
of being the mother of my child.
I like children too.
I raised my younger brother.
I'm grateful
that you believe I am worthy of this.
Sir, a pigeon has come with a message.
Ertuğrul knows everything.
He'll attack the castle tonight.
I'll bring his son Gündüz
to you today, as agreed.
Titan.
I saved your chief alp and best friend,
and still you will not stop!
You won't dare do anything
if your son is in my hands, Ertuğrul.
Is everything all right?
You just said that you liked children
and that you looked after your brother.
Today, for our empire,
I'll give you a son.
We'll make a Turk-blooded knight
out of him...
and you'll be his mother.
I'll give you good news, madam
May your mountains
Stand tall
Your tree that has a shadow
Should not be cut down
May your water that flows like blood
Never dry out
May your wings
Never fall apart
May your white horse never stumble
When it's galloping
He's finally asleep!
Savcı will be just like Gündüz.
That boy just won't stop!
Praise be.
You should have seen Ertuğrul.
He gave us such a hard time!
Alçiçek?
Where is Gündüz?
He said he was sleepy, Halime Sultan.
He's taken off his alp clothes.
He never takes those off.
Where is the boy?
His cap is here too.
No, Mother. That's not a good sign.
If you'll excuse me, I'm going to go
look for Gündüz, or I won't feel at ease.
Wait, don't start worrying.
You go, I'll look after Savcı.
Who knows what kind
of mischief he's up to.
-I'll come with you, Halime Sultan.
-Alçiçek.
Check around the well.
I'll check the training ground.
-Of course, Halime Sultan.
-Hafsa, come on.
My dear God.
Aren't you done with the wheel yet?
I'm talking to you!
Nearly done.
Who are you?
So you'll bring up as your own
the son of a great Turk like Ertuğrul.
You really are a commander
who deserves to be a holy knight.
Excuse us for a moment, Marya.
Is what I just heard true, sir?
He wouldn't dare attack my castle
when I have his son.
If he does, he'll pay for it
with the life of his son.
Tell me, did you speak with Bahadir?
Bahadir Bey said he will host
you in his tent when the time comes.
In his own tent?
Do you know what that means, Kostas?
Bahadir is planning to raid Aslıhan's tent
and take over her tribe.
How will he do that
while Ertuğrul is around, sir?
They'll suck each other's blood, Kostas.
Isn't that enough?
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Show me your face.
I'm your death!
-Damn it.
-Arrows!
God is the greatest!
God is one.
Come on, my lions! Come on!
Finish off those heathens
with your swords. It's time for a battle.
Your swords won't go back into their
sheaths without blood on them!
God is the greatest!
God is one!
My God, my God.
He's nowhere to be seen. Where can he be?
We'll find him, Halime Hatun.
Try to calm down.
Hafsa, he never stops.
Don't you know that?
Who knows where could have got to.
-We'll find him--
-Alçiçek!
He's not here, Halime Hatun.
We went all the way down to the well.
We looked everywhere.
All the way to the gate.
He's gone. God forbid,
I even looked in the well.
He's not at the training ground.
I have this fear in me, Hafsa.
Let's tell the guards.
Get them to look for him.
He's a child, he'll be hiding somewhere.
Alçiçek, let the guards know
they must look for Gündüz.
This doesn't bode well.
Let my mother and Artuk Bey know.
Hafsa, let's check the back
of the training ground. Come on.
-What happened? Did you find him?
-He's nowhere to be found, Mother Hayme.
Halime Hatun and the alps
are looking for him.
I can't just sit here.
I'll go look for him too.
-Don't leave Savcı's side.
-Yes, Mother Hayme.
Where are you, flying horse?
Gündüz Alp? What are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
You should go, you can't be here.
I can't leave you here.
You're away from the tribe.
No, you should go.
I'm looking for the flying horse.
What do you mean, Gündüz?
A flying horse?
Darius!
What are you doing here?
Tell him to go away so that I
can see the flying horse, Darius.
Gündüz. Run home.
Why are you saying that?
Just do what I tell you, Gündüz.
Gündüz, run home!
You scoundrel.
So you're biting the hand that feeds you?
Murderer.
Gündüz!
I'm here, Samsa Alp, I'm here!
Brother!
Brother? Brother!
What happened to you?
Who did this to you? Tell me.
My God.
Samsa! What's going on here?
I don't know, Halime Sultan.
I found our alp here, wounded.
Alp, what happened? Who did this to you?
-Darius.
-Darius?
Gündüz.
Darius took Gündüz.
What do you mean he took Gündüz?
Gündüz!
-Gündüz!
-Halime Hatun.
What are we going to do now?
You couldn't escape us even if you
hid in the seventh layer of Hell.
You... Who are you?
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul?
You... So you were on his side all along?
How did I miss that?
Your mind isn't capable of
comprehending our strength.
Don't exhaust yourself.
You've got a great deal to tell us.
What will we do with him, my Bey?
We'll question him first, Bamsi.
We'll raid the castle tonight.
Let's find a cave to hide in for now.
We'll question him there.
Collect the clothes that are
in good condition from the dead soldiers.
-Take this degenerate.
-As you command, my Bey.
Halime Sultan, it's too dangerous here.
-You should go back.
-What are you talking about, Samsa?
How can I go back
before we've found Gündüz?
Alps! Alps!
Go back right away.
Gündüz has been abducted. It was Darius.
They've taken my son.
They've taken my Gündüz!
Halime Hatun, we'll find him. We will.
I'm not going anywhere
until I find him. Alps!
-With me!
-Come on.
Gündüz!
Where's the loyal servant
of Governor Ares going?
Let me go! Let me go!
It's not that easy.
You've to become a great knight first.
Let me go. Let me go!
But we have to train you first.
Let me go.
My father will destroy you and Ares.
Let me go!
First, he'll have to save you from me.
Murderer. You killed our alp.
My father will catch you.
Let go of me!
Let me go.
-Let me go.
-Get inside.
Let me go.
Halime!
Gündüz!
-Halime!
-Mother!
They've taken my Gündüz, Mother.
-They've abducted my Gündüz.
-I know. I know.
Don't worry, we'll find him.
Our Alps have the place surrounded.
They have nowhere to hide.
-We'll find him.
-I hope so.
-We will.
Gündüz!
Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey, that devil
Darius has taken Gündüz.
Is there any trace of him?
He's already escaped, Halime Sultan.
But he left his horse.
-So he can't go far.
-He can't, Hayme Hatun.
All right. Why do you think he
has taken my Gündüz, Artuk Bey?
In my opinion, Governor Ares
has something to do with this.
He ordered him to kidnap Gündüz.
There will be no peace for any of us
until that degenerate dies.
I'm not going back until I find my son.
No one's going back.
Yağız Alp!
Find Ertuğrul Bey quickly.
Tell him what's happened.
Right away, Artuk Bey.
-We'll keep searching. Alps!
-Come on, Alps!
Alps!
-Gündüz!
May I enter, Bey?
Come in, Oğuz.
You asked for me, Chief Alp Turgut.
From now on, you'll stay
at my side in Cavdar tribe.
As you command, Chief Alp Turgut.
Now, I have a mission for you.
I sent Kırca Alp after Bahadir. However,
I haven't heard from him for some time.
-Look everywhere for him.
-As you command.
We've hunted and trained,
just as you ordered.
We've sharpened our swords with our anger.
We're all waiting to hear your orders
so that we may obey them.
My brave Alps!
We have piled up heads
upon heads in so many battles.
No army can stand in our way.
And now... a few scoundrels...
aim to take our rights away from us.
They think we're weak
and won't put up a fight.
Will we let these fools
get the better of us?
We won't!
No one can run us down.
Now... it's time to
gut our enemies and have
their blood flow as rivers.
We'll ride into that tribe
with our swords unsheathed
and take back with blood what is ours.
We'll take it with blood!
-With blood!
So you were following us?
Kırca is escaping!
Get him!
Go after him!
Gündüz!
-Gündüz!
-My Gündüz Bey!
Gündüz!
-Gündüz!
-My Gündüz Bey!
-Gündüz.
-My Gündüz Bey.
-Gündüz!
-My Gündüz Bey!
My Bey.
-Bey, we found something.
-What is it?
-Tell me.
-Follow me.
Good.
Come on, hurry.
Do you know who I am?
The emperor will have his revenge.
You'll pay a heavy price
for what you've done.
Your emperor sent
a lot of men to fight me.
I killed every one of them.
You think he'll save you?
Now answer my question.
Will other armies come?
Bigger armies will come.
Greater than you could ever imagine.
You'll be destroyed.
Our vengeance will follow you
wherever you go.
All the armies...
in the world could come after us.
To fight the Turks on the steppe...
is nothing like playing games
behind castle walls.
We turned these lands
into our home with our blood.
We're here until doomsday.
What did you gain by killing
those soldiers and capturing me?
What do you think you can do?
Your emperor sent those soldiers
to Karacahisar to fight us.
We will enter Karacahisar
disguised as those soldiers.
You won't be able to. You can't.
Tomorrow...
when I get the head of that traitor Ares,
everyone will see if I can or not.
You'll take that head...
and tell all of Nicaea of my victory.
My Bey! Bey, he's here!
Stop.
The dog of Aslıhan... and Turgut Alp.
Your owner sent you after us.
And you were going to report back to him?
Do whatever you want.
I'm not scared of you.
They say there's no
point in fearing your own death, Kırca.
Don't worry. We'll take over the tribe.
Maybe,
your Hatun and your commander
will come after you.
You think you can take the tribe where
Ertuğrul humiliated you and had you kneel?
You can't do anything.
My Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut Alp
will avenge my death.
They'll humiliate you
and make you kneel again.
This time you won't be
able to save yourself
from Ertuğrul Bey's sword.
Shall we ride into the tribe
carrying this dog's head, Father?
When there are more
important heads for us to take,
there's no point taking this one.
Now... it's time to take back our tribe.
Wait for my word.
These are the tracks we found, my Bey.
They lead up to that cave.
I hope they're there.
Let's be quick, Artuk Bey.
There's no point in waiting, come on.
-My God.
-In the name of God. Come on.
-Gündüz!
Gündüz!
Why does the sultan
want to talk to me, Göktuğ?
I don't know, Eminence.
His servant will come and tell us.
He must have found out.
If Ertuğrul found out about priest's cave,
he'll suspect you were responsible for
what happened to Turgut Alp and Aslıhan.
Worse than that,
they'll hold me responsible for
our sultan being poisoned.
Eminence,
we have to prevent Ertuğrul getting a
message to the sultan with his suspicions.
Ertuğrul is not so stupid that he would
communicate such a sensitive matter
to the sultan by writing to him.
He'll want to tell the sultan about
his suspicions face to face.
Eminence. Our Sultan is waiting for you.
I have received information
from my scouts, Sadettin.
What's wrong, my Sultan?
An attempt was made to poison
Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp.
How dare they?
What is the motive for
such a despicable act?
Maybe to weaken a margrave
as strong and brave as Ertuğrul,
my Sultan.
My Sultan, the news you have received
and the evidence I have collected
match perfectly.
Which evidence, Sadettin?
I have no doubt
that the traitors who cooperated
with the emperor are in Konya.
Don't you dare
cast aspersions upon the people
I have in my palace, Sadettin.
I will not tolerate such behavior!
I know who it was
the traitors cooperated with
to poison you and trap Ertuğrul Bey.
I have their names.
Kırca hasn't returned.
Where could he be?
It's not a good sign that
he's failed to come back.
I've sent Oğuz Alp after him.
-Do you think something's happened to him?
-That's what I'm afraid of.
That demon Bahadir is capable of anything.
He's breathing fire, he wants blood.
There's nothing he won't do.
-Can I come in, Turgut Alp?
-Come in.
Turgut Alp, I looked everywhere,
but I couldn't find Kırca Alp.
No one has seen him.
How's that possible?
Aslıhan.
I can't just sit here doing nothing.
Something's wrong.
I'd better go look for him.
Turgut, wait.
Where do you think you're going?
You haven't recovered yet.
You have to rest.
Let's send the alps.
I can't sit and hide in our tent, Aslıhan.
I have to lead my men.
Turgut.
Please don't go.
Don't worry.
I'll come back to you.
My God, may you protect him.
Who?
Ekaterina.
-Wife of Ural Bey?
-Yes.
She was the one
who provided the connection
between Nicaea and your palace.
What's your evidence, Sadettin?
A priest who abandoned his religion.
We know he's a skilled herbalist.
I've been told by reliable witnesses
that he was known to Ekaterina.
Ekaterina was the one
who asked for the poison.
They heard from the traitors in your
palace that you were at Hanlı bazaar.
But it wasn't enough for them.
They laid a trap for Ertuğrul Bey.
Where is this Hatun?
Find her and bring her to me immediately.
Unfortunately, I've just heard
that she's been killed.
The traitors killed her
when they realized they'd failed.
They then turned their deadly sights
on Aslıhan Hatun.
If you'll let me
I'd like to track down
the traitors in your palace.
I'll have this matter resolved
within the time I promised you.
Otherwise, living would be a sin for me.
Gündüz!
-Gündüz!
Does this belong to Gündüz, Halime Sultan?
My son.
My Gündüz.
It's his, Artuk Bey.
That dog was using
this place as his hideout.
My God.
Please don't let us go through
the pain of losing a child.
I'll kill him with my own hands.
-Halime Hatun, please stop.
-Move, Hafsa! Move!
Halime!
Pull yourself together.
I won't let him take
my son from me, Mother.
-Get out of my way.
-Halime!
-Let go of me!
Look at me.
We'll find him. We'll find him.
Calm yourself.
Artuk Bey will let Ertuğrul know.
Now, let's go back to the tribe.
Ertuğrul will find him
and bring him back to us.
-This is hell.
-It's all right.
It's all right.
It's all right, daughter.
It's all right, dear.
Aziz!
-Yes, my Sultan.
-Ekaterina. And the priest.
I want to know who they are,
and what dealings they had
with those who poisoned me.
Assign your best men
to gather information.
Yes, my Sultan.
We're going to the palace.
The sultan is convinced
the traitors are in the palace.
The time has come.
We move soon to kill the sultan.
You go there first
and let our friends know.
Tell them I'll be waiting
in the Caravansary.
We'll throw a grand feast for them.
What if they don't obey, Eminence?
Then they will be put to death
for attempting to kill the sultan.
It's high time they learned
who really represents the state.
And about Sadettin...
I want to know which emirs and commanders
he contacts when he reaches Konya.
As you command, my Sultan.
My Bey.
My Bey, Yağız Alp is here.
He has news from the tribe.
I hope all is well. Let him come in.
Well, Yağız Alp?
Artuk Bey sent me, my Bey. Gündüz...
What about Gündüz?
I'm asking you. What about him?
Gündüz... Gündüz has been
taken from the tribe, my Bey.
-Who?
-The trader Darius, my Bey.
Titan.
So, you've brought Ertuğrul's son to me.
Welcome to your new home,
my little knight.
I'll raise you to be a great knight.
With your courage and your strength,
you'll become a great
knight of the empire.
From now on, your name is Kronos.
Ares!