Episode 113 will start after 12:09 min.
That's for what you did to
Ertuğrul Bey and my tribe.
Die, Sadettin. Die so that
the world can be a better place.
Kayraldi!
Kayraldi.
How many more beys will die because
of your loyalty to Sadettin, Günalp Bey?
I'll never give up the state
to jackals like you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Günalp Bey!
Daughter, did you find any trace of her?
No, Mother.
Her saddlebag is missing.
It looks like she took it.
Wasn't Aliyar Bey's sword here?
It was here.
She took that too.
My God, may you protect her.
It's obvious what's she's gone to do.
Her intention is clear.
Artuk Bey.
-We've had news from the alps.
-Have they seen Aslihan Hatun?
A shepherd says he saw a woman
riding towards Konya.
Was she alone?
She was, my Bey.
She was riding a black horse.
That's Aslihan Hatun's horse.
You were right, Halime Hatun.
What if Aslihan gets into the palace?
What if Emir Sadettin
does something to her?
Abdurrahman, send the alps after
Aslihan Hatun, right away.
They have to catch up with her
before something happens.
Yes, my Bey.
Let's pray that the alps reach Aslihan.
Aslihan Hatun, no.
Kayraldi.
No one can save you from me, Sadettin.
No one.
Don't do it, Aslihan.
The price will be heavy.
So much blood will be
shed in your tribe.
You'll cause your own death
and that of your people.
I'm warning you for the last time.
Don't do it.
Aslihan!
My tribe was split apart because of you.
It betrayed... my brother...
and Ertuğrul Bey.
But if you...
If you die...
my tribe will be saved.
As will the people I love.
You'll die, Sadettin.
You can't take the ones
I love away from me anymore.
I won't let you do it.
I won't.
Die, Sadettin. Die.
Don't do it.
Kayraldi.
Aslihan.
As...
Eşhedü en lâ
ilâhe
illallâh.
Ve eşhedü enne
Muhammeden
abduhu ve Resuluh.
Aslihan.
I've got you, my brave men.
-Who are they?
-My uncle, Garkin Bey.
Stop the archers!
Stop.
Archers, stop.
May I enter, Your Eminence?
Your Eminence?
Your Eminence.
Your Eminence. Your Eminence!
Aslihan.
You'll live, your Eminence. You'll live.
Soldier! Soldier!
I'll get you out of here.
Call the doctor, quick!
Your Eminence.
Kayraldi.
Take Aslihan to her tribe.
Everyone should know that I killed her.
Don't exhaust yourself, Eminence.
I'll get you out of here.
Do as I say.
Send Aslihan to her tribe.
Make sure Turgut and Ertuğrul
know that I killed her.
That's an order, Kayraldi.
I will, Eminence.
I'll have her body sent to her tribe.
It's you I'm concerned about.
Your Eminence. Your Eminence!
Your Eminence.
Your Eminence!
Günalp Bey. Don't let
any more soldiers get hurt.
We'll settle this here.
Let's not spill any more blood.
Let's do it, Ertuğrul Bey.
Surrender, Günalp Bey.
Don't be so stubborn.
Your loyalty to Emir Sadettin
has cost many beys their lives.
End this now.
I'd rather die than to surrender
to a traitor like you, Ertuğrul Bey.
You're such a smart woman, Marya.
First you betrayed me.
And then the Turks.
What will you do now?
Betray Governor Kritos?
You killed my brother, Ares.
But Governor Kritos
saved me from the Turks.
Why would I betray him?
Besides, I didn't betray you.
You merely paid for my brother's death.
Yes, I killed your brother.
But what about the Turks?
What did they do?
Ertuğrul took care of you.
The Turks let you live among them.
They married you to Artuk Bey.
So why betray them?
I... never liked them.
I took shelter there because
I had no other choice.
If I wanted to stay there I had
to get married, so I got married.
Such a sad story, Marya.
But like always,
it's not even close to the truth.
Let's stop talking about this.
We meet here once again under
the same roof, with the same purpose.
Destroying Ertuğrul.
But I'll keep an eye on you, Marya.
If I see a mistake...
be sure that... I won't pity you.
Burn in hell, Ares.
Burn in hell.
The beys at the council
were going to rebel against Sadettin.
But...
when they realized they risked
destroying the state, they stood down.
And it was you who persuaded
them, Ertuğrul Bey, right?
Are you ever going to stop lying to me?
You saw your death was imminent,
and now you're trying to save yourself.
You have killed many innocents.
That's why you'll pay
for your crimes, now and in the afterlife.
You'll die as
Sadettin's dog and as a murderer.
Then die, Ertuğrul Bey.
Stop!
Kneel.
He's won for now.
You promised, Ertuğrul Bey. Let my men go.
Alps!
Let them go.
Go.
That's an order, go!
Finish me, Ertuğrul Bey.
Emir Sadettin will bring you to account.
From the very start...
I believed you meant well.
Even though your loyalty has
caused so many deaths...
I won't take your life today, Gunalp Bey.
You can't leave that murderer alive,
Ertuğrul Bey!
Sadettin Köpek will do
anything to see me dead.
But as long as you're the Frontier Bey
you won't harm Karacahisar or my tribe
because you're an honorable man.
Our fight is not with the state,
but with that dog, Sadettin Köpek.
So, if that dog has a problem,
he can come see me.
I'm going to release you now, Gunalp Bey.
May you live long enough to see the truth.
Go now.
This isn't over, Ertuğrul Bey.
We shall meet again.
May I come in, Mahperi Hatun?
Come in.
Mahperi Hatun.
What's happened?
An attempt has been made
on Emir Sadettin's life.
What? Who?
Who dared do this?
A woman.
What woman?
We don't know who.
And Emir Sadettin?
I'm told he's badly injured.
Where is he now?
-I don't know.
-He must be in his room.
This is a gift from God, Abdullah.
You can kill him while
he lies helpless in his room.
The state depends on it.
I'd gladly give my life for our state
and our Sultan, Mahperi Hatun.
Come in, Ares, come in.
You sent for me, Kritos.
I have an important mission for you.
An important mission for me? What is it?
-You are to go to Nicaea.
-Nicaea? Why?
To take this letter to the Emperor.
We'll need an army if we're going
to stop Ertuğrul settling in Sogut.
I've explained everything
to the Emperor in the letter.
Emir Sadettin is going to kill Ertuğrul
anyway. Why do we need an army?
It's not just for Ertuğrul.
when Emir Sadettin leaves for Samsat
we'll move in and take back Karacahisar.
I hope the Emperor agrees to send an army.
He will, Ares.
He has to if he wants
Sogut and Karacahisar back.
You will return here
at the head of that army.
-I'll get on the road.
-Go, Ares.
Don't forget,
this army will grant all of us
the vengeance we seek from Ertuğrul.
How did you find us, Garkin Bey?
We caught the dog who told Emir Sadettin
about the council.
I was sure he'd send
his men here to ambush you,
so I came.
I meant to warn you, but I was too late.
We lost many brave beys and alps.
Garkin Bey, move your tribes
as soon as possible.
Leave no trace.
Otherwise Emir Sadettin...
will send his men to kill them,
even the children.
We have to tell the tribes
who have lost their beys.
They will also need to protect themselves.
Ertuğrul Bey,
Sadettin Köpek has killed many
to satisfy his ambition.
He has destroyed many beys.
I would have preferred you to have
killed Gunalp as well, Ertuğrul Bey.
Killing him wouldn't
have achieved anything.
His intentions are good.
His eyes will open soon.
Our target...
is Sadettin Köpek.
Many beys died.
But there was no rebellion.
There was no war between
our state and our tribes.
Unfortunately, our great state will
belong to Sadettin Köpek soon.
It won't, Garkin Bey.
We will never let that happen,
even if it means our deaths.
When the time comes
I'll kill Emir Sadettin.
Ertuğrul Bey.
No one doubts your bravery or dedication.
We all know you'll fight to the very end.
But what if Köpek doesn't die?
Then there will be nothing wrong
in rebelling, Garkin Bey.
But,
unless there's no other choice left to us,
we must not rebel against the state.
If you don't kill him,
Sadettin Köpek will punish
the Turkish tribes severely.
The tribes must go up into the mountains.
Afterwards,
anyone who can hold a sword will rebel.
Until the state is saved
we'll all have to live as fugitives.
Until the state is saved from Köpek
we can't return to our tribes or tents.
We'll travel,
no matter the distance or the weather.
It may be that we never return home.
We'll consider everything
if it means finishing this.
We'll go at dawn. May God help us all.
-Amen.
-Hard times await.
We have to endure
and overcome days like these.
We can accept suffering.
If each one of us is patient,
we'll find peace in the end.
We do this for our state and our country.
Emir Sadettin won't leave his room alive.
We'll finish it quickly.
Then we dispose of all
the soldiers loyal to him.
There will be much blood spilled tonight.
But the state will be cleansed.
How dare you enter Emir Sadettin's
chambers without permission?
Where is Emir Sadettin?
His Eminence is leading his army to war.
Now, leave immediately.
You're lying.
Someone tried to kill Emir Sadettin,
where is he?
What is this nonsense?
So, you won't tell us where he went.
Then you'll answer for
this blood on the floor.
Arrest him.
Let me go, what do you think you're doing?
Let go of me! Let go!
Sadettin, it's time to pay.
Thankfully, we're not afraid of death.
Know that I'll never let you get away
and that no matter how heavy my chains,
they will never protect you from me.
Die, Sadettin. Die,
so that the world might be a better place.
Your Eminence.
Aslıhan!
Your Eminence, the woman is dead.
You'll be fine.
Your Eminence, you will be fine.
-Aslıhan.
-You'll be fine, Your Eminence.
You'll be fine.
Kayraldi, Kayraldi.
Where am I?
The Caravansary, sir.
I feared for your life,
so I brought you here.
Do they know where I am?
No, Your Eminence.
I brought you here in secret.
Good.
You'll be awarded ten-fold
for your quick-thinking.
If... If I had stayed in the palace...
Mahperi Hatun would have tried to kill me.
You're safe, Your Eminence. Rest now.
Wait!
Did you send Aslıhan's body to her tribe?
I did, as per your order, Your Eminence.
Her corpse will give me
Ertuğrul and Turgut.
Your army is ready for you.
We'll set off when you've
recovered your strength
-May I enter, Mahperi Hatun?
-Come in.
What happened, Abdullah? Is he dead?
There was only a soldier there.
Damn it. Where is he then?
The soldier said he went
to war with his army.
How?
How did this happen? Were we lied to?
I don't think so.
-Why not?
-There was blood on the floor.
Then we did hear the truth.
A woman tried to kill Sadettin,
but she died instead.
Sadettin was taken away secretly.
He must have fled in secret
because he knew what awaited him.
His army waits for him to go to Samsat.
Despicable man.
So, he managed to save himself.
Find out who the woman was.
As you command, Mahperi Hatun.
When is the Sultan to return?
We don't know.
Whose hunt is this, Giyaseddin?
Whose hunt?
Let him come.
My Sultan.
Soldiers!
Emir of Sivas, Husamettin Karaca.
Welcome.
-You look well.
-Thanks to you, my Sultan.
Who knows you're here?
Nobody knows.
You know,
not even the roads recognized me.
I know, I know.
I called you here for something important.
Tell me, my Sultan.
The state is going
through difficult times.
There's a snake around our neck.
Suffocating us more every day.
We have to take its head
if we are to breathe again.
Emir Sadettin Köpek, right?
Emir Sadettin Köpek.
He's needed to die for a long time now.
His existence threatens
both the state and your rule, my Sultan.
Thank God, the soul of Sultan
Alaeddin Kayqubad will find peace.
You'll make clear you're worthy of him.
Someone else is to join you
on this mission.
You can accomplish it only with him.
Who, my Sultan?
Ertuğrul Bey.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-Welcome, Ahmet.
-Thank you, my Bey.
-Come.
What news, Ahmet?
My Bey, Governor Kritos
wants me to go to Nicaea.
Interesting.
I'm to demand an army
from the emperor for Governor Kritos.
He wants me to lead that army here.
He'll do anything to keep Sogut.
It's not only Sogut, my Bey.
He wants to take back Karacahisar as well,
now that Sadettin Köpek is gone.
What about you, what will you do?
Before settling in Sogut,
I'll have taken Sadettin Köpek's head.
My Bey...
They'll execute you
if they get hold of you.
Tread carefully.
Don't worry, Ahmet.
Go.
Go and take charge of the emperor's army.
Take charge of that army so that
we may then command it.
To follow this path we have risked all
kinds of torture, torment and suffering.
Don't worry us now.
The tyrant might hold the noose...
but we hold the sword of justice.
God help you, Ertuğrul Bey.
God help us all, Ahmet.
-Amen.
My Bey,
that bastard Sadettin will do everything
in his power to catch us.
Then we'll do everything in our power
not to get caught until
our mission is over, Bamsı.
All right, my Bey. All right.
Köpek holds the state.
We will endure anything until
we can cut off his hand.
Let's get back to the tribe...
and tell everyone what we intend to do.
It'll give us a chance
to say our farewells to our loved ones.
Henceforth, you are to forget
about your tribe, your tent and your bed.
Until Emir Sadettin is dead
we will have no peace.
Either Sadettin Köpek will die
and we will have saved the state
or we will die and the state will fall.
There's no other way.
As you command, my Bey.
-As you command, my Bey.
I had a motive for sending
Sadettin to Samsat.
While he's there you can
begin preparations with our loyal emirs.
On his return journey home,
Sadettin will rest in Sivas.
Sadettin Köpek respects me.
He's nervous around me.
When he returns
I'll look to gain his trust further
and trap him.
That's exactly what I ask, Husamettin.
Welcome him to Sivas.
Then finish him off
with Ertuğrul Bey's help.
As soon as that jackal meets this wolf,
I'll kill him and send you the body.
I'm sure of it.
I have to meet Ertuğrul Bey.
How will he know to trust me?
Take this.
It bears my mark.
It's a secret decree.
Show it to Ertuğrul Bey. He'll trust you.
As you command, my Sultan.
Everyone will come to see
who the Sultan is and who rules here.
It's over.
The state is above everything else.
The state rules again.
It's time to purge ourselves of this scum.
You don't exist.
You're dead.
I killed you.
You're dead!
What is this?
You... are dead.
Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut
will not let you live.
They will kill you.
They'll never be able to.
You're nothing, Sadettin.
I will be...
the Sultan of the Seljuk state.
Their corpses will be food for carrion.
You're nothing.
You'll die poor and alone and humiliated.
I am...
the real son of the
late Sultan Keyhusrev.
My mother, Sehnaz Hatun,
gave birth to me to make me sultan.
I was brought up an illegitimate child,
that's true.
However,
I am the true heir to the Seljuk throne.
You're dead.
Ertuğrul and Turgut will die too.
I'll kill you all until...
one by one your line is brought to an end.
No one loves or respects you.
Look around you.
You're alone, Sadettin. All alone.
You say you'll be Sultan.
You're nothing but an illegitimate child
and it will always stay that way.
You... You....
Your Eminence, are you all right?
Come in.
What is it?
Gunalp Bey approaches.
Let him come.
I have the letter
Aydogmus sent from Karacahisar.
Good. Marya must have done her job.
What does it say, Your Eminence?
"Governor Kritos has sent
Ares to gather an army."
While you're away,
Sogut is to be Ertuğrul's grave.
If they can't do it...
when I return from Samsat,
I'll crush the Kayis with my army.
Let Gunalp Bey come.
Your daughter's, brother?
Yes. Hers.
I have two children but...
I miss my daughter especially, Ertuğrul.
I feel it here.
Daughters are different.
I hope God grants you each one too.
Amen.
Our Prophet fathered four daughters.
They were special to him.
In a hadith he said,
"Treat your children equally.
But if you do treat them differently,
treat the daughters better."
I hope both my Bey
and I will have daughters.
God willing.
Brother Turgut.
You're always the uncle.
Time to be a father.
I hope
you and Aslıhan Hatun
will have babies too.
God willing, brother. God willing.
Let's take care of these problems first.
Then that can happen.
God willing.
Aslıhan Hatun has endured a lot.
She's very brave.
Without her determination, the Cavdars
wouldn't have survived this long.
You have a happy home too.
I'm happy for you, Turgut.
Thank you, my Bey. Thank you.
I love her...
May God love her too.
Amen.
As you said,
she has been through so much.
She's never known good fortune.
Now you've been separated again.
It will be hard.
You're right, my Bey. You're right.
But she'll endure it again.
It will all be worth it
when I reach home and see her.
May I enter?
Come in, Gunalp.
-Your Eminence. Who did this?
-A woman.
Sent by Ertuğrul.
What sort of man sends a woman
to kill me, when he couldn't
manage it himself?
Ertuğrul?
So, when he was organizing
a rebellion of traitors
he also sent an assassin?
He did meet the rebels,
but I killed all of them.
But Ertuğrul Bey, along with Garkin Bey
and his nephew Kutlu Bey, escaped.
Son, get me some water.
I was attacked when I was preparing
to leave for the Samsat campaign.
Devil.
He's a traitor who would kill an Emir
who was preparing
to give his life for his state.
It's nothing, Gunalp, nothing.
Until he's dead,
who knows what else he might do?
Gunalp...
I don't want problems here
while I'm away at war.
Don't worry, Your Eminence. I'll find him.
Good.
I can tell you where he'll be.
He knows he's a fugitive now.
He'll go to his tribe
to say his farewells.
Then he'll set out to kill me.
He'll have his brother,
Sungurtekin, with him
and those savages, Turgut and Bamsı.
But when they reach their tribe
they'll find the body
of the woman they sent to kill me.
Don't give them a chance.
Find them. Kill them.
Gunalp.
Show no mercy to anyone in his tribe.
-I'll do what you ask.
-Good.
Your Eminence...
Ertuğrul Bey had his chance to kill me.
Why am I still alive?
I'm going mad thinking about it.
Gunalp
He did that so that
you wouldn't harm his tribe.
Don't... Don't be fooled by his tricks.
Go do your duty.
Save our state from this bandit.
As you command, Your Eminence.
What's happening?
Those drums never
herald good news, Mother.
Mother Hayme, they're bringing a body.
My God, please no.
Do not inflict a pain
that we cannot overcome!
God... Is Ertuğrul...
My girl, don't talk nonsense.
Whose body have you brought us to bury?
The woman who attempted
to assassinate His Eminence,
Emir Sadettin,
Aslıhan Hatun.
What did you do, sister?
Why did you sacrifice yourself?
Sister Aslıhan.
Soldiers! Let's go!
God, may Sadettin Köpek
suffer this pain a thousand-fold!
Let's take our Hatun's body!
Come on!
Stay away! Stay away! Stay away!
Don't lay a finger on that brave woman!
She's the heroic and selfless Hatun
of the Kayis!
Not of a lot of cowards like you!
Stay away! Stay away!
-Alps!
-My dear girl...
Carry Aslıhan Hatun's body to the tent.
Stop! Stand back!
This valiant woman
sacrificed herself for us.
We, the women, shall carry her.
Women!
Bismillah. Lift.
Aslıhan Hatun.
My dear, brave sister.
Mother Hayme.
Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut Bey have arrived.
Artuk Bey.
Look after Turgut.
Mother?
Artuk Bey?
Who is that?
Aslıhan.
She's sleeping, right?
Mother Hayme?
Mother Hayme, tell me she's asleep.
Tell me she'll live.
Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey, tell me she'll live.
Mother Hayme?
Tell me she'll wake up. Artuk Bey!
Aslıhan... Aslıhan!
-Aslıhan! Aslıhan, wake up!
-Brother...
-Aslıhan, Aslıhan...
-My brave brother.
-Brother.
-Son.
Son.
-Brother.
-Turgut Bey.
-Son.
-Brother.
Aslıhan.
How could they? How could they?
Who did this?
Artuk Bey, who did this?
Emir Sadettin Köpek!
I'll take my birth right, Mother.
I'll take the throne, Mother.
I'll be the sultan,
not as an illegitimate child...
but as the rightful heir to the throne.
When I am sultan, I'll avenge the shame
my father brought on us, Mother.
The branch... saw the rosebud
had bloomed one morning.
The rose... took flight with the wind.
What a treacherous world.
In ten days, a rose
grew, bloomed and died.
While you may pity me...
none of my sins frighten me.
When you're with me,
no obstacle frightens me.
May God revive me with a clean face...
Even if my history is full of crimes,
the darkness holds no fear for me.
I'm going to kill that bastard!
I'm going to kill him!
I'm going to destroy his palace!
-Turgut!
-Let go of me!
Brother!
-Brother!
-Let me go! Let me go!
I won't rest until that bastard's head
is hanging from the palace walls!
Turgut Alp! We feel your pain but you
must calm yourself. Please, my Bey!
Brother get a hold of yourself!
We have to bury our brave sister first!
-Brother Turgut!
-My Turgut! Turgut!
Turgut! Come to your senses, brother!
Come to your senses!
Calm down.
Brother, stay with us.
My Bey, please let me go.
I'll lose my mind.
I can't just stand here, my Bey.
Turgut...
We need you alive.
You can't avenge her if you're dead.
I can't let you just walk
into that bastard's hands.
Patience and revenge will be ours,
Sadettin Köpek
will have pain and suffering.
Keep a clear head, brother.
That bastard Köpek will die
in such a way,
that no one else will dare come after him!
Tomorrow,
after we have buried Aslıhan Hatun,
we set off to kill Sadettin Köpek.
My heart is burning!
I know, brother. I know.
I won't be at peace
until I see that fiend drowning...
in his own blood. I won't.
You'll see it.
I swear, brother. You'll see it.
We'll avenge Aslıhan
and all the other innocents
who were wronged by Köpek.
For Aslıhan Hatun
and all the other innocents,
I swear we'll have our revenge!
I swear!
What's the situation
at the Kay tribe, Aydogmus?
They're mourning.
They bury Aslıhan Hatun tomorrow.
May God forgive her sins.
She was fooled into believing
Ertuğrul's words and sacrificed herself.
Ertuğrul tricked her,
just like he tricked us.
Make sure the soldiers are ready.
We'll set off soon.
Where to, my Bey?
Some of the soldiers will
besiege the Kayi tribe.
I want them to know
we'll allow them no peace.
Ertuğrul, Bamsı, Turgut, Sungur...
they're certain to go there
to say their farewells.
When they find out about Aslıhan,
they'll stay to attend her funeral.
I'll catch them there tomorrow.
As you command, my Bey.
I swear I'll punish
all those who betray the state.
My love, the jewel of my heart.
I overcame so much.
I defied death, but...
how can I defy the torment
of your death, Aslıhan?
What should I make of the black
mountains without you?
What should I make
of the rivers flowing like blood.
What's this world
without you in it, Aslıhan?
I don't even care...
if the world ends, Aslıhan.
This dagger is for you.
I want you to have it,
if you'll accept it.
This dagger...
will remind me that
someone is waiting for me.
I swear that
that bastard will meet his end...
by the dagger you gave me!
I will avenge you, my brave wife.
I will avenge you.
Aslıhan...
Her death has hurt me deeply, Ertuğrul.
Emir Sadettin spilled Aslıhan's
blood with his own hand.
It pains me greatly.
It pains all of us, Halime. All of us.
God doesn't cause pain
to those who can't bear it.
We'll overcome this.
Halime, I've gone into battle many times.
But the task we now face
will be harder and more arduous
than any of them.
It might last for months... even years.
It might be years before I return.
If I return at all.
God will protect you.
Don't say that, Ertuğrul.
My Halime...
I might rule this tent,
but you feed this tent.
My Savci, my Gündüz...
The baby inside you...
are in God's care...
and in your care.
If I don't return...
you must be their mother...
and their father.
Raise them like my mother raised me.
Put them on my path.
If I were to die tomorrow,
it would be with the hope that my children
will save our land and our state.
Don't worry, Ertuğrul.
Godspeed.
We'll wait for you here.
You need think only of doing your duty,
honorably and with courage,
for our greater glory.
If you come back, we will rejoice.
If you fall,
we'll continue to live
with the honor and the pride
you left us with.
My Hafsa.
My Hafsa, my Hafsa.
The path ahead of us
is difficult, my Hafsa.
We might not return...
or...
Hafsa, give me your blessing.
Aslıhan Hatun's death...
and being separated from you...
God help you,
and me,
and our baby.
My dear baby, my dear baby!
The mother of my baby,
the one who has my heart.
My Hafsa, my Hafsa.
Aslıhan Hatun gave her life
so that we may live ours happily.
We go so that our state and our tribe
may grow stronger and prosper,
and so that its children may
grow and live long and happy lives.
My Hafsa,
if no one is prepared to risk their lives,
how can this state and this country
survive and grow strong?
We shall dedicate ourselves to this.
You, Hafsa, should be proud!
Take care of yourself...
and of our baby, my Hafsa.
If I don't return...
tell my baby that his father was brave.
Tell him that he died for his country.
My Hafsa, don't let him forget me.
Don't forget me either, my Hafsa.
My Hafsa, give me your blessing, my love.
Bamsı...
You have my blessing, my brave husband.
Deaths and farewells hang heavy
on all of us.
We can't return here
until the state and our tribe are safe.
These days will pass.
They will.
Go safely, my sons.
Be worthy of your ancestors' blood
and your mothers' milk.
-Thank you, Mother.
I hope Günalp doesn't come here
and try something while you're gone.
Günalp wouldn't harm the tribe, Mother.
He's not like that.
Günalp's only weakness
is Emir Sadettin, Mother.
I warned him.
It was the reason I spared his life.
If another man came and took his place,
his first thought would be
to destroy our tribe.
As you say, son.
Mother, Halime.
You must lead the women.
Starting from tomorrow,
the women must be trained and ready
to deal with anything that threatens us.
But act cautiously until we return.
-As you command, son.
-As you command, my Bey.
Mother,
we plan to set off very soon.
-Give us your blessings.
-You have them.
-Give me your blessing, Mother.
-You have it, son.
You have it.
This must be Günalp.
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
He isn't here, Günalp Bey.
You're wasting your time.
Don't lie to me, Artuk Bey.
I know he's here.
I've told you he isn't, Günalp Bey.
What do you mean?
Don't they know Aslıhan Hatun is dead?
What about the funeral?
They do know and they did come.
They took the body to bury it.
What do you mean?
You think Ertuğrul Bey didn't anticipate
exactly what you
and Emir Sadettin would do?
You're so contemptible
you'd take advantage of a funeral
and strike mourners during a cemetery.
Ertuğrul Bey knew exactly what you'd do,
so he took the body somewhere else,
Günalp Bey.
Allahu akbar.
Esselamu aleyküm ve rahmetullah.
While death is a celebration for the dead,
it is a cause of agony and sorrow...
for those left behind.
Our pain is deep, our hearts forlorn.
But remember, excessive sorrow
and grief will offend God.
Our Prophet showed patience
in the face of loss and pain.
That Prophet, who was sent
to us as a kindness...
came into the world an orphan.
When he was just a child
he lost his mother.
His grandfather took him and his uncle in.
He lost his partner in life,
our mother, Hatice.
He lost his uncle and greatest supporter,
Hamza, in the battle of Uhud.
He buried his children
with his own hands.
His compassionate heart
became somber with this pain.
As he was weeping
after the passing of his son Ibrahim...
one of his companions approached.
"Are you crying too, God's messenger?"
he asked.
"Did you not forbid us to cry?"
Our Prophet replied,
"I did not forbid crying.
I forbade screaming in agony.
For when the heart is filled with sorrow,
tears fall from the eyes."
That blessed prophet
endured so much suffering.
However, with his fortitude,
he never turned his back on his path.
Knowing that it is God
who gives and who takes away,
he endured all kinds of pain.
Now it falls on us to draw
inspiration from our Prophet,
to submit to the will of God...
and bury our grief in our heart.
Know that day awaits beyond every night.
If we show patience,
God will lift our burden...
and lighten our hearts.
Now you must be as unyielding as bronze...
and as vibrant as a waterfall
which flows thick and fast.
Be so, that neither the enemy
nor the treacherous may think you weak...
and find the courage to attack you.
Where will they bury her?
We don't know.
You're lying, Artuk Bey. Ertuğrul is here.
What gives you the right to ride
into our tribe without permission?
Tell me that.
I do as I am told.
I don't need your permission to do it.
This will be the case
until I find Ertuğrul.
Search the camp.
Stand back, Günalp Bey.
Know that you're in over your head.
Don't be so impertinent.
No one has ever dared raid this camp
and no one ever will.
A death warrant has been
issued for Ertuğrul Bey.
Don't make this harder.
Tell me where you've hidden him.
Günalp Bey, you think Ertuğrul Bey
such a coward that he would hide?
If he were here,
he would be the first to face you.
If he had to, he'd fight you.
If he had to walk to the gallows,
he'd walk with his head held high.
As if you don't know that.
I'm just doing my duty.
Now, I'm warning you for the last time.
What will you do, Günalp Bey?
Will you put us to the sword like
they did to your mother and father?
Look here, Günalp Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey went to punish the traitors.
Those traitors have the death
they deserve coming to them.
Don't you share in it too.
You know what's right.
Take your men and leave this place. Go on.
What should we do, my Bey?
Back to the castle.
If Ertuğrul Bey should come here,
if you should get word to him...
with a bird or on the wind, tell him...
I will not stop until he pays
for what he has done.
There's nothing they can do,
God permitting.
Greetings, Artuk Bey.
Greetings.
We have things to discuss.
Take me to Ertuğrul Bey, right away.
Who might you be?
Husamettin Karaca, the Emir of Sivas.
Husamettin Karaca?
My bride that I took with a red veil...
and left in my white tent.
Was it my fate to dress you
in earth when I returned?
If I don't get my revenge
on those who did this to you...
let the land I tread on be my grave...
the sheet I sleep on, my shroud...
the armor I wear, my coffin.
Aslıhan Hatun gave her life for us.
Not everyone could have done
what she did, brother.
Be proud of your hatun.
We will avenge her together.
We will, my Bey. We will.
And not just Aslıhan Hatun...
but all innocents
who suffer at the hands of tyrants.
For Aslıhan Hatun and all
the other innocents like her...
our white swords
will not be returned to their scabbards
until they have been turned
red with traitors' blood,
until no traitor is left in our land...
Tooth for a tooth, blood for blood...
Revenge!
I was your son too.
I too was ready, just like my
brother Kilicarslan,
to give my life to glorify
the holy state of our ancestors.
You did not deem me worthy of your throne.
But I will prove
that I am a worthy son, Father.
I will not let your death
or that of my brother be in vain.
I will rid our state of the menace
which devours it from within.
Welcome home, my Sultan.
I hope you enjoyed a successful hunt.
It was so successful, Mother...
that I will rebuild
that which you destroyed
and razed to the ground.
I didn't go hunting, Mother.
I met with the Emir of Sivas,
Husamettin Karaca.
The spring of vengeance
has been wound, Mother.
-Did you--
-I spoke to Husamettin Karaca.
We took the necessary precautions.
He will be with Ertuğrul Bey by now.
I hope you've thought
this through, my Sultan.
I have done what was necessary
for the honor of my father
and my ancestors, Mother.
You killed my father
and turned me into Sadettin's servant.
Now it's either Sadettin, or me.
Either the state, or rivers of blood.
There can be no other way.
There is no turning back.
My Bey, Artuk Bey is here.
There's someone with him.
I don't know who.
I told him not to come here
unless it was extremely important.
If there's someone with him,
he must trust them.
Let him come, Abdurrahman.
-Greetings, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Greetings.
Artuk Bey told me what happened.
My condolences.
Thank you.
-My condolences, Turgut Bey.
-Thank you.
Who are you?
I am the Emir of Sivas, Husamettin Karaca.
I've heard of you.
Welcome.
Come, sit.
Sit down, everyone.
It must be important
if you've come all
this way, Husamettin Bey.
Our Sultan gave me his orders personally.
Our Sultan gave you orders? What are they?
Here.
This is Emir Sadettin's death warrant.
The duty you asked to be given
has been granted to both of us,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We will do away with
Sadettin Köpek together.
So, the sultan has come
to the right decision at last.
Sadettin Köpek put a stop
to our Sultan's Amid campaign,
so was sent with the army
to Samsat Castle instead.
Our Sultan sent him there on purpose.
We are to ambush him
on the way back from the campaign.
He will be returning with
a victorious army loyal to him.
We will need to prepare for this.
Köpek will come through Sivas
on his way back.
We will wait for him there.
We will first gain his trust...
then finish him off
when he least expects it.
Shah, it has been a thousand years
since the world last saw the likes of me.
You placed me in a land
belonging to someone else.
But it's over now.
No doubt you are surrounded
by a sea of people.
But in the sea, the pearls are found
at the bottom while the scum floats.
You couldn't see that.
It's now my time to rule.
It's time that precious pearl rose
to the surface.
We're ready for the campaign
for Samsat Castle to commence, Eminence.
Your army waits to salute you.
May our holy war be blessed.
May it be blessed!
May your victories be ever-lasting!
Run to your undoing, Sadettin Köpek.
Run to your undoing.
We need to talk to whoever is against
Köpek in the state's ranks, one by one.
We'll need them to both
support us until Köpek is dead
and then to establish order
in the state afterwards.
Ertuğrul Bey, right now they are
paralyzed by their fear of Köpek.
They wait for a spark to catch light.
If we give them power and hope...
they will do what we ask of them.
I will take on this duty myself.
I will pull to our side
whoever is against Köpek.
Ertuğrul Bey,
this will be our one opportunity.
At the end of this path,
either Köpek's blood spills...
or Köpek will spill a lot of our own.
Come, then...
The state needs our help.
I ride to Sivas. My soldiers await.
-May God not humiliate us.
-Amen.
Godspeed.
Now we embark...
on a hard but blessed journey.
My brave men, my alps.
A hard but blessed duty awaits us now.
It's time...
to sever the head of the snake
that has buried its fangs in our state.
The salvation of this glorious
state is in our hands.
Our purpose and our word are one.
For the perpetuity of the state
and the good of our land...
death to the traitors.
Death to the traitors!
Come now, my heroic men,
may our holy war be blessed!
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net