Episode 97 will start after 12:30 min.
Today, we choose
the best archer in the castle.
I want all my men to be at their best.
Therefore, you must practice.
Get up!
Soon enough, you will leave this castle
to conquer the world.
When the time comes,
failing to hit even one Turk
could mean losing our land.
And I'll never let that happen!
Any soldier who hits the apple
will win this sack of gold in my hand.
If anyone misses,
retribution will be swift.
And you can't run from my wrath.
Long live Tekfur Ares!
Bring him to me alive!
-Go, quick!
-Ares!
Run! Run!
Come on, he's running off!
Go, get him, quick!
Stop him!
Upstairs!
Run!
Your soldiers have forgotten
how to fight, Ares.
That's why I wanted you here.
I'm at your command, Ares.
Bahadır Bey.
What do you want Göktuğ?
Don't go, Bahadır Bey.
The emir wants to see you.
I respected the state.
He was the emir of the sultan,
I dismantled my tent for him.
I migrated.
Came to these lands.
If I go to a man
who can't protect me or my child,
may my leg be broken.
If I ask for help
may my house be destroyed.
Did you understand?
Save the rage for your enemies,
Bahadır Bey.
Not for your friends.
Is there a greater enemy than the one...
who took my child
and hope away while my house
was destroyed, Göktuğ?
Do not push away the hand
you respected
which was extended to you
in a time of need, Bahadır Bey.
You'll be alone when you fall.
Your rage will consume you.
It'll let you down.
Don't do it.
Tell your Emir that...
my ears are
deaf to his words.
I'll go my own way.
Let him go.
By order of our sultan,
my mission in these lands has ended,
Ertuğrul Bey.
God willing, I'll return to Konya today.
You'll be responsible for the decisions
you make here,
know that.
I hope your decisions...
will not bring trouble here.
Don't forget this.
I did my duty, Your Highness.
I hope that when you arrive in Konya,
you'll quickly find the ones who poisoned
our sultan, and who trapped
me and my alps.
Do you doubt it, Ertuğrul Bey?
When I saw our Sultan poisoned,
when I was trapped
on my way to war,
I saw that there were people who plotted
against our state, Emir Sadettin.
Ertuğrul Bey.
The rage caused by that trap
has blinded both...
your eyes and brave heart.
You're so blinded
that you can't know friend from foe.
Know it well,
our state is strong enough to punish
the traitors.
When the time comes,
you'll be ashamed of what you said.
But at that time,
I'll be at your side again.
Know the value of these lands given to you
by the Sultan.
I'll sacrifice anything
for the state, Emir Sadettin.
You should know that
I won't allow traitors in my lands here.
Our state will rule forever.
Our Sultan may know
that there are brave men
ready to die for him,
and that's enough for us.
Emir Sadettin.
We'd have liked to see you
at the wedding of Aslıhan Hatun
and Turgut Alp.
But since I know you're so busy
with state affairs, I won't insist.
May God bless them.
Hafza.
Mother Hayme.
The orphans are dressed.
The poor have their food.
Thank you, dear.
Thank you.
Take care of the kitchen.
Yes, Mother Hayme.
Thank God.
Our bey brought the good old days
back as well, Mother.
Thank God, dear.
But...
I wish Dündar could see it as well.
Open the door.
His Highness has a long journey ahead.
Dündar.
Welcome to my castle,
my dear friend Titan.
My friend Ares.
You've already started your games.
Show me your face.
I didn't want anyone
to see that I'd come to your castle,
Ares.
When you have a problem like Ertuğrul,
we can't risk anything.
I know you called me here for him too.
You're right.
Am I to kill him?
Killing him isn't easy,
even for a great warrior like you, Titan.
I'm sure that you'll do it in time, but...
I decided that I needed a demon
like you to hit him where it hurts.
I wish to ambush him where he's most safe
and strong, his own village.
So, I must infiltrate his village.
Yes.
Won't be easy,
but I'll do it, Ares.
It'll be easier than you expect, Titan,
because you'll hit their weakest spot.
What's that?
Mercy.
You'll hit them with their own mercy,
but...
it'll hurt you to do it.
I'm ready to die for our cause.
Are you going right away?
I'll go to my brothers' village
to let them know that our Bey lives.
It's my duty to go to their village
anyway.
Duty doesn't wait.
I was careless
and broke your heart.
Forgive me.
Give me your blessing.
Bless you, Dündar Bey.
You're our brother.
Return quickly.
I'll get on the road, my bey.
Any orders?
An eye to see...
behind the mountains,
a mind to see
what'll come to pass, Dündar.
I hope that this road opens
your eyes and your mind.
Farewell, brother.
Farewell, Dündar.
Artuk Bey,
if I offended you too,
forgive me.
Give me your blessing.
You've had a rough start.
I hope it'll be easier in the end.
Bless you.
Godspeed.
Son,
don't doubt yourself.
You'll grow in the path
that your brother made for you.
I hope so, Mother.
Farewell.
Godspeed, Dündar.
Godspeed.
Son.
Dündar has learned his lesson.
Look at how he's shaken.
His eyes have been opened.
No need for him to go.
Maybe...
you should reconsider?
If I forgive him today,
men will follow his example.
Mistakes like this will lead
to treason.
I can't have it.
Merit is what we need.
If Dündar proves that he's worthy
of this village, he'll return.
Pray, Mother.
You know best, son.
How did he just leave?
Couldn't you catch up with him?
I did.
I did, but...
Göktuğ, say what you have to say
without wasting my time.
Did you tell Bahadır Bey
that I was waiting, or didn't you?
I did.
I did, Your Highness.
But--
But what?
How can he disobey my order?
What did he say?
He said that you didn't protect...
his child,
so your words fell on deaf ears.
What?
Alpamış wants to see you, Your Highness.
Let him come.
Aslıhan and Turgut...
will never live happily.
You too, Bahadır Bey.
I won't even let you be bey
of your own village.
You won't even have a grave.
You'll know who Emir Sadettin is
just like everyone else.
The vengeance in my veins...
will be poison to their veins.
When the Çavdar Village mourns,
I'll have a feast of fun.
Candar Bey's whole line...
will die.
You'll infiltrate them.
You'll tell me everything Ertuğrul does.
Don't worry.
I won't just infiltrate the Kayıs.
I'll set them against each other.
Is it enough, Titan?
Do your duty
with this dagger you once gifted me, Ares.
May the Kayıs drown in their mercy.
Ertuğrul's mercy will cost him
his son Gündüz.
You'll bring his son to me.
God bless our Empire.
Amen.
Your Highness.
Speak, Alpamış.
What news from the village of Bahadır Bey?
We're migrating, Your Highness.
Lots of carriages.
Ox carts slow us down,
but we're almost there.
I wanted to come tell you,
giving scouting as an excuse.
Good.
You're just in time, Alpamış.
Göktuğ and you
have an important task.
Tell me, Your Highness.
Thanks to you,
I've knew everything
that Bahadır Bey did all this time.
Both you and
Aslıhan's friend, Esma,
have been my eyes.
Anything for our state, Your Highness.
Alpamış.
It's very important
that Bahadır Bey becomes
the bey of the Çavdars.
But Aslıhan Hatun slows him down.
She won't get on board.
For both villages to unite...
and for Bahadır to be Bey,
Aslıhan must die.
My sword will obey you, Your Highness.
Keep it sheathed.
Göktuğ will give you poison.
You'll bring it to Esma.
That poison will be our wedding gift
to Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp.
May they be in excruciating pain
until their very last breath.
Their deaths will be an example.
As you order, Your Highness.
In this world...
seas are set on fire.
Love is drowning in that sea.
Even if it rains poison,
love is staying under it.
Love is...
drinking the poison and dying.
He humiliated us in public.
He exiled me,
Bahadır Bey's own son,
from my own village.
Have you lost your tongues?
Are your wrists broken?
We have our tongues...
and our wrists.
Nobody can exile
my son from my village.
But he did, Father.
In front of the Oghuz beys.
And you kissed Ertuğrul's hand
and swore fealty.
If I swore fealty,
it's to avenge us.
If I was exiled too,
who would avenge us, huh?
Let him...
console himself...
with his beys.
The arrow is shot.
Now go, join our migrants.
Choose the bravest
and the strongest alps.
Hide in the mountains.
Hunt and train.
When the time comes,
I'll give you and your men a task.
Wait for blood in the mountains.
Wait, so when the time
for vengeance comes...
you'll have your blood.
And Emir Sadettin?
From now on,
his word...
doesn't mean much.
Son.
We'll fend for our own.
We'll make Ertuğrul pay,
not with diplomacy,
but with our sword.
As you command, Father.
I'll sharpen my blade with rage
until we take our revenge on Ertuğrul.
Patrol the village.
Keep your eyes open.
Go.
Samsa Alp!
Samsa, someone's wounded!
Help.
-Who is this?
-Help.
What happened?
Who did this?
Bandits.
Bandits attacked me.
On my way to the bazaar,
they took it all.
Please don't leave me for dead.
Don't worry.
We don't abandon anyone.
Who are you?
I'm Daryus.
A Christian merchant.
I didn't want to
disturb you, but...
I had no choice.
Patch me up and give me some food.
Please.
Our village and table are open to anyone.
Turks really are helpful people.
God bless you.
Let's carry Daryus to the healing tent.
-God bless you.
-Come on.
God bless you.
Alpamış, what are you doing here?
Our patron sends his regards, Esma.
A small gift for your services.
Anything for His Highness, Alpamış.
This is the wedding gift
from His Highness to Aslıhan Hatun.
What is it?
A poison, which will
kill the lovers and make us rich.
I'll wait for you here when you're done.
Not with one,
but three bags of gold.
The stones you touch
will only shine
when they see a beauty worthy of them.
This necklace
will look beautiful on you.
His Highness' offer
has not only honored you,
but me as well.
If our bey orders it,
I'll surely accept it.
But if I have the final say,
I won't abandon my village.
Çavdar Village will be my home.
Forgive me, Your Highness.
My decision is final.
Nobody,
nobody will take you from me.
I will...
never give up, Aslıhan.
Your Highness, I took the poison from
the priest and gave it to Alpamış.
Esma has it.
Both will die.
Good.
We're ready to depart, Your Highness.
No.
When they're dying in pain,
I'll listen to
the sad drums of the Çavdar Village.
I'll be sure that both that liar Aslıhan
and Turgut are dead.
And Bahadır Bey?
Ertuğrul...
will surely blame him
for Turgut and Aslıhan's death.
Alpamış must die.
When Ertuğrul finds his body,
he'll know he works for Bahadır.
And he'll think Bahadır had them poisoned
and he'll take his head.
You always think the best, Your Highness.
Bahadır will take his share
from Ertuğrul's rage and sword.
Who is he?
His name is Daryus,
a merchant going to the Hanlı Bazaar.
Bandits attacked him on the road,
poor man.
He sought refuge here,
we wanted to help.
Well done.
All right.
On top of beating him,
they stabbed him as well.
We patched it up before he lost
too much blood.
Thanks, Artuk Bey.
Get well.
So, it was the bandits.
Indeed.
They took everything.
You're lucky to have found us.
Those scum are our enemies as well.
We'll take care of you.
Now, get some rest.
God bless you.
May you be stronger.
Thank you.
Poor man.
I'll let Ertuğrul Bey know.
Do whatever he needs.
Don't worry, Turgut Alp.
At last you'll marry Turgut Alp,
Aslıhan Hatun.
God willing, Esma.
God willing.
I wish Aliyar could see it too.
I wish he put this belt on me.
Such is fate, Aslıhan Hatun.
Don't worry.
You have Turgut Alp and Ertuğrul Bey
on your side.
A small gift.
A wolf pelt for a boy,
a deer pelt for a girl.
Thanks, Esma Hatun.
God bless you.
You've kept my secrets all this time.
You've consoled me.
You accompanied me after the deaths
of my father and Aliyar.
God bless you, Aslıhan Hatun.
You treated me like a sister
instead of a villager.
My Bey.
A merchant named Daryus arrived.
Bandits robbed him
and injured him.
He took refuge here, just so you know.
We patched him up, my Bey.
Gave him food.
He's resting now.
Well done.
We can't turn those people away.
But be cautious.
He's a poor man.
I don't think he'll harm anyone.
Foxes hide under sheep pelts, Samsa.
Enemies are everywhere.
Pay attention even to the wind.
As you say.
After eating,
let's measure Turgut's dresses.
What for, Mother Hayme?
Halime Hatun and Hafza...
are making him a dress for the wedding.
Brother Turgut,
such is the life of a married man.
Bamsı.
Bamsı, you do this every time.
Your words will bury you,
watch out.
Why do men and women marry, Father?
Our Prophet said,
"Marriage is my example.
Marry...
so that I will be proud of
your numbers against other faiths."
So, I married your mother.
I have brave sons like you.
Bamsı Alp and Hafza Hatun
will have brave sons like you, too.
God willing.
God willing, Halime.
One day,
you'll have children too, Gündüz.
I want to be an alp first, Grandma.
Oh, my dear.
Gündüz, you're already an alp, son.
I haven't hunted,
or killed an enemy, Mother.
You're right.
I promised you, son,
we'll go together for your
and your brother's first hunt.
Then my mother should measure me as well.
I want an alp's clothes.
I won't marry before being an alp.
Coward men don't get girls here anyway,
Gündüz.
Samsa.
Bring some food to the merchant.
As you order.
Horses go fast,
bards speak skillfully.
Thank you, my bey.
For Turgut's marriage
and for my son's bravery,
sing us something
from the steppes,
and from the lands of our fathers.
All right, my bey.
Resurrection is our holy cause
started by Suleiman Shah's son.
He hunted enemies down,
his name is Ertuğrul the Brave.
His alps died for him,
his presence makes the world shiver,
Turgut, Bamsı, Rahman and Doğan
motherland is holy for them all.
Arabi looks for Mevla,
Artuk Bey cures the wound.
We aim for Karacahisar,
may God bless this army.
Amen.
The mad steel, the brave warriors,
let Sadettin the dog howl,
may their hands never drop the swords,
the heroes stand watch.
Hayme is the mother of the village,
Suleiman Shah's only love,
his only flower in the tent,
Kayı village was her home.
Halime Sultan, love of her Bey,
always proud of her man,
she always stood by him,
the Kayı line will continue with her.
Son of Turcoman,
may our noble line continue,
may our line never die out.
Our councils at the Hanlı Bazaar,
and our armies to victory.
-Thank you, Bard.
-Thanks, my bey.
Thank you.
I called you here because
the castle is unprepared.
What?
Sir, Ertuğrul Bey sent you a letter.
Read.
"Tekfur Ares,
I shall visit the castle tomorrow.
I wish to see everything as I left them.
Bey Ertuğrul, son of Suleiman Shah."
Go away.
Even though this looks like
a regular visit,
he might have other intentions.
Like what, sir?
First,
Ertuğrul knows everything we do.
He's not coming to inspect,
but to see his prey.
Second, he doesn't doubt us.
He'll want to cooperate.
We'll be prepared in any case.
Sir, won't we do anything when he comes?
Absolutely not.
Since he's visiting,
we'll prepare accordingly.
Prepare a welcoming feast.
As you order, sir.
I've heard that Ertuğrul Bey humiliated
the Çavdar bey Batuhan.
He exiled his son.
So, Emir Sadettin is powerless
against Ertuğrul as well.
Ertuğrul will be bolder in
his future steps now.
What will we do now, sir?
Sir, will we only fortify
the walls and have more guards?
Don't you worry.
I took the biggest precaution.
What is that, sir?
You'll learn, along with him, soon.
Have patience.
Wait.
Let me help you.
Stand up.
There you go.
Ertuğrul Bey has sent this to you
from his table.
Thank him.
This is a feast for me.
My mother Hayme and Halime Sultan
cooked these personally.
Sure, it's a feast.
Ertuğrul Bey and his family are very kind.
Does he help anyone who falls on
hard times?
Is that even a question?
He's the hope for the poor.
He treats everyone equally.
The only thing that matters
to him is right and wrong.
How nice.
Tell me, do you have a wife and kids?
We had caravans.
One day, bandits looted everything
in a sudden raid.
They killed my two kids
and my wife.
I reopened old wounds,
sorry for that.
Don't be sorry.
I'm used to being alone.
Your pavilion is very crowded.
How many tents are there?
Whatever you see.
Got it.
I guess all the men here are warriors.
Everyone here is a warrior.
That's right,
the Turks are all warriors.
Your pavilion is very nice
but you don't have walls or a castle.
Aren't you afraid of an enemy's attack?
Our God that we pray to,
our flag that flies,
our bey that we embrace
and take orders from
are more than enough to scare the enemy.
Go ahead, eat your food.
That'll help.
My Ertuğrul Bey is waiting for me.
It's time to conquer
Karacahisar Castle.
Magnificent! Finally.
Thank God.
We've been waiting for this for so long.
-May our holy war be blessed, my bey.
-Finally hypocrisy stops ruling.
Now it's time for weapons to talk.
When do we attack the castle, Bey?
On the morning of Turgut's wedding,
Artuk Bey.
The morning of the wedding
is when Ares will least expect us.
We'll take him by surprise
when he thinks
we're at the wedding, having fun.
That's my wedding present to you, Turgut.
I will sacrifice myself
for that kind of present, Bey.
Will we let the Oğuz beys know?
If we let the Oğuz beys know
Emir Sadettin may hear about it.
And that might jeopardize the conquest.
We won't tell anyone.
With God's help,
our strength will be enough
to take over Karacahisar Castle.
With God's help, my bey.
My bey, my bey...
We can take over ten of them.
With God's help.
The door of the castle
will open at dawn...
and close when the sun goes down.
-Abdurrahman.
-My bey.
You'll get into the castle with soldiers
who are dressed like the people.
When you get in, you'll find Atsiz.
The two of you will figure
out the measures Ares took
without drawing attention
to yourselves.
I want to know everything,
what's in the castle,
how many guards there are,
the weapons of these guards,
even the number of rocks in the walls,
Abdurrahman.
Get out before the castle door closes
and get to Cavdar Pavilion.
I'll be waiting for
your intelligence there.
Yes, my Bey.
What will the soldiers do
once inside the castle?
When the castle door opens,
they'll enter the courtyard.
They'll be the ones to prevent
the doors from shutting
when the soldiers see us coming.
And tomorrow,
I'll go to the castle to visit Ares.
I'll do my best
to make him trust me,
and sleep peacefully in his bed.
Now everyone, back to work.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, my bey.
When we arrive at the castle
you should go to the pavilion
and make everyone carry their weapons,
including the women.
Secure the pavilion.
Your wish is my command.
Don't forget,
we're not battling
for loot or treasure,
but for God's will
and our holy mission.
Don't let that slip from your mind,
so you won't give up.
May our holy war be blessed, my bey.
Amen, brothers.
Thank you, Hatun.
Hatuns!
Make sure there are no flaws
with the food or the service.
Our dear Hatun is getting married,
we wouldn't make any mistakes.
Thank you.
Go back to what you were doing.
Esma.
Keep an eye on them.
Obviously she's coming to spread evil.
What do you want, Karaca Hatun?
For you to get what you deserve.
If you're trying to spread your evil,
don't get too excited.
I won't tolerate you anymore.
While our kid is being exiled,
you're getting ready for a wedding.
Don't think this marriage
will do you any good.
If your kid had some morals
he wouldn't have been exiled,
Karaca Hatun.
Everyone gets what they deserve.
Thank God.
You and Ertuğrul walked all over
your own uncle.
You took his son away.
You devastated our pavilion.
Let's see if your pavilion prospers!
Aslıhan Hatun.
You're going to reap what you sow.
What could you do without Ertuğrul Bey?
Now you threaten me?
Here's my pavilion.
Do your best.
But you should know
that from now on
tongues that talk too much
will be clipped,
and heads of those that rebel
will be cut off.
-Let's meet tomorrow, okay?
-Okay.
What's wrong, Abdurrahman?
Good news, Atsiz.
It's time to conquer Karacahisar.
Our bey will raid the castle
when its doors open in the morning.
He'll visit Ares at noon.
He wants to keep him happy
and catch him by surprise.
Our bey thought it out carefully.
But Ares has increased security
since Ertuğrul Bey's return.
He closes the doors
when the sun goes down,
and opens them when it rises.
We have to get our men inside
so the doors can't shut
when our brave men arrive.
My Ertuğrul Bey knows about this.
My men are in disguise
with me and have infiltrated
with the excuse of trading.
Then our job
will be to fan the flame.
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to learn
about the measures in the castle.
Follow me.
May God protect us.
The frontiersman of my government.
May God grant you
many more high positions.
High positions exist
to serve God's will, my Halime.
May God be pleased,
and may our religion
and traditions stand tall,
that's enough.
You should go to Cavdar Pavilion.
I'll come when I leave the castle.
Today is the big day, my Halime.
May God protect you.
You too.
May God protect you too.
God speed.
Amen.
Salaam-Alaikum.
Alaikum-Salaam, my bey.
Alaikum-Salaam, Bey.
What's the condition of our men, Turgut?
Abdurrahman and our men
have infiltrated the castle.
They'll let us know
what they learn as soon as possible.
Thank you.
How's the pavilion doing, Artuk Bey?
Are the wedding preparations over?
Everything is being done properly, my bey.
Everyone's very busy.
The people...
were covered in cobwebs
for a while.
I hope this will be
the occasion to blow them away.
Weddings come with miracles.
I hope this wedding will open the door
to many happy days.
God willing, my bey.
When we go to the castle
you take care of the preparations here,
Artuk Bey.
Your wish is my command.
Can I come in, my bey?
Come in, Samsa.
My bey,
Merchant Daryus wants to see you.
Let him come in.
I'm honored to be in your presence,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Daryus.
Sorry about what happened.
Thank you.
I escaped death thanks to you.
I wanted to express my gratitude.
Thank you.
So, you're a merchant.
-What do you trade?
-Everything.
I trade anything that might make profit.
Fur, animals... Silk.
The bandit can't harm you
near our pavilion.
Why did you come to us and not Ares?
I don't know.
I lost myself.
I had no idea where my horse was going.
Luckily, I arrived at a pavilion
that's hospitable.
Otherwise...
I would have been dead.
All right then.
You're our guest.
You can stay as long as you'd like.
All your needs will be met.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God bless you.
Turgut.
Don't let your guard down.
Yes, Bey.
Come on, we're leaving.
Ertuğrul is already with Ares.
Both of them will dig each other's grave,
Göktuğ.
They'll try to walk all over each other.
When they get weak,
I'll come back here.
And then, Ertuğrul won't be able...
to find Turkish pavilions
or our sultan by his side.
Are all the preparations done, Kostas?
Yes, sir. We've prepared everything
necessary for the welcome.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Tekfur Ares.
Congratulations on being the frontiersman.
I'd like to gift you this white flag
to maintain the peace between us.
I hope it never gets stained.
Thank you, Tekfur Ares.
If we're the ones to hold the peace flag,
it won't get stained.
However if it was stained before us,
we can't clean it.
I'm throwing a banquet for you.
Come on in, let's talk there.
Hit it, Gündüz!
So you're Gündüz, the son of Ertuğrul.
Your father will pay the price
for what he's done through you.
But first, let's meet and become friends.
Is Tekfur Ares still seeing Ertuğrul Bey?
Yes, ma'am.
You must be the soldiers of Ertuğrul Bey.
That's correct.
I've heard of the fame of the Kayis.
I got to see you today.
Thank you.
You must be a noble that just arrived
from Nicaea.
Otherwise you would have seen us already.
I'm not from Nicaea.
I'm not really a noblewoman.
I was gifted to Tekfur Ares
by the slave trader Simko.
So I was actually a slave.
I guess this visit will be long.
I wish you a good day.
Brother,
what kind of a woman is she?
The way she looks is full of cunning.
I won't drink wine
next to our valuable guest.
In my absence, bandits terrorized
the caravans that stopped in Hanlı Bazaar.
Unfortunately.
The bandit incident
caused all of us trouble.
If that's true,
why haven't you cooperated with us
on this matter?
Your soldiers could have gone after
the bandits.
But Ertuğrul Bey,
the safety of the merchants
on these lands is your responsibility.
-We could only protect ourselves.
-It's obvious how you protect yourself.
You threatened
the Greek merchants by pulling them away.
It wasn't a threat, Ertuğrul Bey.
I did what I had to do.
-You know, Greek merchants--
-The past
is in the past, Tekfur Ares.
Now we have to think about the future.
Hanlı Bazaar is important for us
and for you.
We will cooperate to improve
the trade in the bazaar.
It's nice to hear that from you.
I'm listening.
We'll act together against the bandit.
To improve the trade in the bazaar,
we'll make sure the Greek
and Muslim merchants come to the bazaar.
If we don't,
the peace flag you gave me
won't mean much.
There's peace in this.
There's profit.
There's a partner like yourself.
You'd have to be an idiot to say no.
Good.
Now I'd like to see the castle.
I'm curious about what
the Muslim merchants have been up to.
You should come with me
in case they need anything.
Go on, Ertuğrul Bey.
Brother Abdurrahman.
I've written down everything I know.
The number of the day and night guards,
when they change the guards, everything.
The reaction team that's in the castle
will cause us
more trouble rather than the guards
in the backyard and the towers.
They'll take action to close the doors
when our bey attacks.
Don't you worry.
My men who infiltrated will prevent this.
The number of reaction team members
and their weapons are on that paper.
We'll catch the guards at the door
and towers by surprise.
Before Ares can figure out
what's going on, we'll let Ertuğrul Bey
and his men in.
Brother Abdurrahman,
hopefully, we'll have
Turgut Alp's wedding in Karacahisar.
Amen.
God help us, Brother.
The men who are on duty should
blend into the night
and come to this store.
I'll tell them their duties one by one.
Don't worry.
They'll be on time.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God always let you be by our sides.
Thank you.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
It's impossible not to get jealous
of the love your people are showing you.
I wonder how you keep this
without losing their trust.
With justice, Tekfur Ares.
Justice is the treasure that opens
the door for all blessings and peace.
I share this treasure with them.
You're a brave man, Ertuğrul Bey.
It's an honor for me
to have peace with you.
But if one day
this peace comes to an end,
it would be an honor for me
to have a brave enemy like you.
I'd like to see a brave enemy
as well, Ares.
Not the kind of scumbags
who trap you and hide their faces.
There's no point in talking about
wars and hostility.
If one day this peace comes to an end,
we're the kind of people
who can talk it out.
You should know that,
if one backs down from his word,
we see that
as a betrayal.
We don't talk betrayal out,
we solve the matter with weapons.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
Can I come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
Come in, Bahadir Bey.
Go ahead, Bahadir Bey.
Is there something you wanted to tell me?
Congratulations on your wedding.
I'm here to ask if you need anything.
I don't, Bahadir Bey.
Just don't bother me. That's all I ask.
Girl.
I know we hurt each other a lot.
I didn't want it to be this way.
However, despite everything,
I'm your uncle.
And you're my niece.
As soon as you showed up here,
you tried to take over my pavilion.
You threatened me.
As if that wasn't enough,
you stabbed Turgut Alp in my tent
and you and your son disrespected
Ertuğrul Bey.
Just don't bother me
on this happy day of mine.
You are...
an important Cavdar woman.
At least one man from our bloodline
should be at the wedding by your side.
Allow me to carry out my duty.
Let me be there.
No, thanks, Bahadir Bey.
I still feel hurt by what you did.
So just stay away
from me and my pavilion.
Now I have stuff to do.
Excuse me.
The hero got on that winged horse
and went right to where the monster was.
The monster had three heads.
One was a goat,
one was a lion
and one was a dragon.
The winged horse flew towards the dragon.
The hero drew his sword,
cut all three heads of the monster
and killed it.
And set the winged horse free.
Does the winged horse still live?
Of course it does.
It's still in the sky.
Only heroes can see it.
I'm going to become an Alp anyway.
Can I see the winged horse then?
Of course you will.
Maybe you can even ride it.
-I'd like to see it right away.
-No,
you can't see it right away.
Wait, don't get sad.
You know what,
the winged horse sometimes comes around.
Do you know when?
Sure I do.
Don't worry.
I'll tell you when it comes by.
-Deal?
-Deal.
Thank you.
Thank you, Esma Hatun.
I hope you enjoy it, Daughter.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
It's a small gift, Aslıhan Hatun.
May God bless you.
Magnificent.
They're all so nice.
May God bless your hands.
Bless your hearts.
You haven't let neither me
nor my pavilion alone.
I don't know how I can repay that.
What do you mean?
We see you as a daughter.
And you'll be our daughter in law.
Esma Hatun, hand me the velvet bundle.
In the name of God.
Hafsa Hatun and I sewed this for you,
Aslıhan Hatun.
It'll look very good on you.
God bless your hands.
It's so pretty.
Aslıhan Hatun, it'll look so good on you.
It'll be an addition to your beauty.
Thank you.
Aslıhan Hatun,
let's see how it looks on you.
-Come on.
-Let's see it.
Come on, let's see it.
It looks so good.
Amazing.
You shine like the moon.
Magnificent.
You look like a fairy, Aslıhan Hatun.
Wonderful, Sister.
I hope we can see the days
when your daughters wear these.
Come on.
May God bless you.
You helped me find this peace.
I hope many of us can see
how good our sons and daughters become.
God willing.
God willing, Daughter.
Yah!
Eşhedü en la îlahe îllallah
ve eşhedü enne Muhammeden
abduhü ve resulü.
Amen.
Aslıhan Hatun, daughter of Candar,
do you accept Turgut,
the son of Konur Alp
as your husband, with the condition that
he gives you 100 gold coins?
I do.
Do you?
-I do.
-Do you?
I do.
Turgut, son of Konur Alp,
do you accept
Aslıhan Hatun, daughter of Candar,
as your wife
with the condition that
you give her 100 gold coins?
I do.
Do you?
-I do.
-Do you?
I do.
Witnesses,
do you witness this?
-We do.
I now pronounce you husband
and wife in the presence of witnesses
and the people here.
May God bless your marriage.
Amen.
My God,
we witness this marriage.
May you be a witness too.
Amen.
My God,
bless their marriage.
Amen.
Grant them a good relationship,
love,
and persistence in their marriage.
Amen.
My God,
grant this couple the love
and good relations
that Adam aleyhisselam
and our mother Eve,
Mohammed Mostafa
Sallâllâhü Aleyhi ve Sellem
and our mother Hatice,
Ali Radıyallâhu Anh
and our mother
-Fatima had.
-Amen.
My God, grant this couple
loyal children,
a long life,
and lots of prosperity.
-Amen.
-My God,
bless us in this world
and in the afterlife
with kindness, beauty
and lots of felicity.
Amen.
Save us from the agony of fire.
Subhâne rabbike rabbil izzeti ammâ yasifûn
ve selâmun alâl murselîn.
Vel hamdu lillâhi rabbil âlemîn el Fatiha.
Brave men, listen to me carefully,
and pass on my words to the men
who have infiltrated the castle.
I know very well
that every one of you came here
to be martyrs for the state and for Islam.
Thank you.
-We'd die for our state, brother Atsiz.
-Thank you.
We only have one mission.
And that is to let Ertuğrul Bey
and his alps into the castle.
Know that...
some of us may die
in pursuit of this objective.
When our flag is flying
from the walls of the castle,
our spirits will find peace, God willing.
-God willing.
Right before the guards
change over in the morning...
we will launch our attack on three fronts.
As soon as Ertuğrul Bey and his alps
are spotted from the castle,
the guards will attempt
to close the gates.
Me and the first group
will prevent them from closing them.
You and the second group
will kill the guards on the walls.
We will throw their dead bodies
from the walls, Atsiz.
You are with the third group.
You'll stop the soldiers
who'll try to reach the main entrance.
Brave comrades, that's all I have to say.
Is there anything you want to ask?
-May God help us.
-Amen.
May God make you both happy,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Thank you, my Ertuğrul Bey.
-May God make you happy.
-Thank you.
Be at the castle gate
when the sun rises, Turgut.
As you command, my Bey.
Mother Hayme.
I wish you every happiness, my girl.
May God bless your marriage.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Good man. Good man.
-May God make you happy.
-Thank you.
Son.
May God bless you both.
-I hope to see you always smiling.
-Amen, Mother Hayme.
Long live Aslıhan Hatun!
Long live Turgut Alp!
The people are waiting for you. Let's go.
Long live Aslıhan Hatun!
Long live Turgut Alp!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
What has Turgut Alp done?
What has he done for his beloved?
He made the impossible come true!
Did they break any hearts?
Did they speak ill?
They didn't break any hearts,
nor did they speak ill!
Then may God make them happy.
Amen.
May God make them happy.
-Amen.
Forgive me, Aslıhan Hatun.
Long live Aslıhan Hatun!
Long live Turgut Alp!
Look at that no good Kayi alp.
He's marrying the daughter
of a great Bey of the Cavdars.
It's all Ertuğrul's doing.
I wouldn't be surprised if they make
this alp the Bey of the Cavdars.
That's not possible while I'm here, wife.
These are dangerous men, my bey.
You went to congratulate them
and she dared to refuse you.
Who knows what else
they'll dare do in the future.
Enough!
I've kept my silence today
not because I am weak or fearful,
but because I have plans.
I will bring my tribe here
when Sancar Bey goes to the mountains
and make the world unbearable for them.
Well said, my Bey.
But can't you see the alps of Cavdar
have already embraced them?
Don't be fooled, wife.
The alps will follow
whoever is most powerful
and whoever promises
to lead them into battles.
They'll all be with me
when I take control of the tribe.
We've walked through darkness,
experienced so many hardships...
yet here we are, Aslıhan.
Together we will hold the light
which banishes that darkness.
We'll see our way through
the hardships together, Turgut.
I hope so, Aslıhan. I hope so.
Our tribes will be lit up
just like this tent
when we raise our flag
above Karacahisar Castle's walls.
You are going into battle?
We'll be at the castle gates
when the sun rises.
So you were destined to go to war
on the day of your wedding.
For us, the real celebration is to fight,
Aslıhan.
It's time that we strangle
the enemy with our claws.
If I die trying...
be proud of your husband
for the rest of your life.
May God help you.
May your sword be sharp.
-Amen.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Cruel fate...
you make my heart bleed.
You've ripped joy from my life.
You turn the wind into flames.
You turn my drink into mud.
If my heart is to be in agony,
if I'm not allowed to be happy,
I will not have peace
until I have ruined yours.
Ertuğrul... I will have my vengeance.
You'll groan in pain.
I swear to God...
I'll make you pay for what you've done!
Aslıhan!
Turgut!
Turgut...
Just as Atsiz said,
when the night guards open the gates,
we'll attack the castle.
Our alps inside the castle
will make the first attack
when they open the gate.
We'll enter the castle
before the day guards arrive.
It's likely there'll be fierce fighting
in the yard before you get there.
But Atsiz and our alps should be able
to prevent them from closing the gates.
He said the soldiers within
the castle will counter attack.
You'll be inside the castle
while they fight them off.
But if we're late,
they'll all die, my Bey.
Our horses will ride like lightning
to get there, my Bey, like lightning.
We'll be near the castle before sunrise.
Our horses can rest until the moment
comes for us to go into the castle.
The odds are three to one
in our favor, my Bey.
Neither Ares nor his troops
will be expecting the attack.
They won't know what hit them.
There's one thing I'd like to know,
my Bey. Who is this Atsiz?
He seems to be everywhere.
You'll find out when the time comes,
Bamsi.
Very well, my Bey, very well.
Are the alps ready, Bamsi?
Yes, my Bey. They're ready.
They're awaiting your orders.
Well then.
Go and fetch the ladies, Bamsi.
It's time they know
we're going into battle.
As you command, my Bey, as you command.
Understood.
Turgut!
Aslıhan.
Aslıhan!
Aslıhan...
What's happening to us?
Who did this?
Turgut, I can't bear it.
Hold on, Aslıhan. Hold on.
You'll be all right.
Hold on!
God, give me strength.
Turgut!
I can't take it!
Hang on, Aslıhan!
What is it, son? You called for us?
It's time, Mother.
We're going into battle
for Karacahisar Castle.
I called you here to ask
for your blessings and your prayers.
You have my blessing, son.
May God make you victorious.
May God strengthen the arm
holding your sword.
God willing. Amen, Mother.
I hope you come back very soon.
My Halime.
May God help you, Ertuğrul.
May God protect you all.
Amen.
Take good care of our children, my Halime.
Don't worry, my Bey.
The battle will be ours,
the victory will be God's.
May God protect you, my Halime.
Something's going on
in front of the main tent.
Ertuğrul's alps are gathered there.
Their Bey is here
and their lead warrior is getting married.
Of course they've gathered together.
Prepare the bed.
My bey, this is not an ordinary gathering.
The alps all have their swords
and are wearing their battle kit.
Interesting.
So what is going on?
Let's take a look.
Thank God, my Bey.
Thanks to you, brother Turgut's
loneliness has come to an end.
There'll be twice the joy
once we take over the castle.
I hope so, Bamsi. I hope so.
-Is everything ready, Artuk Bey?
-Everything's ready, my Bey.
The alps in the castle
are awaiting their orders.
Very well.
Come on then, alps! Let's be on our way.
Turgut Alp?
What's wrong?
Ertuğrul Bey!
Turgut.
Turgut Alp?
-Turgut!
-Turgut! Brother!
Turgut!
Turgut, what happened?
Turgut! My Turgut! My Turgut!
My Turgut, what happened to you?
Brother Turgut! Turgut! My Bey!
Artuk Bey! My Bey!
Do something, my Bey.
Artuk Bey, do something!
God!
Turgut, come on.
Aslıhan?
Run to their tent, Halime. Quickly! Run!
Turgut, stay with me!
Get yourself together, Turgut!
Brother! Brother!
Pull yourself together, brother.
What's happened to you?
Aslıhan! Aslıhan!
Aslıhan, what have they done to you,
sister?
-What happened?
-Aslıhan? My girl!
Aslıhan! My girl!
Gently, gently!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim! My girl.
-Aslıhan?
-Open your eyes, my girl.
Quickly, loosen her clothes.
My girl. Aslıhan! My girl!
Come back to us, sister!
Hang in there, for God's sake.
-Hang in there!
-My Bey, he's been poisoned.
God! Poison, he says! My Bey!
-Turgut!
Turgut!
Brother!