Episode 100 will start after 12:30 min.
Titan.
So, you've brought Ertuğrul's son to me.
Welcome to your new home,
my little knight.
I'll raise you to be a great knight.
With your courage and your strength,
you'll become a great
knight of the empire.
From now on, your name is Kronos.
Ares!
Soldiers! Soldiers!
Get a doctor, quickly!
Quickly, quick!
Damn it, my eye!
-Marya. Take him away from here now.
-Let me go!
-Stop it, boy, come on.
Let me go! My father will gut you all!
Let me go!
Kostas, help Marya
get the child out of here.
-Stop fighting me, child.
-Let go!
Let me go!
-I'll murder him!
-No!
-Let me go.
-Ares! Remember, we need that boy.
Let me go.
We'll find Gündüz wherever he is,
have no fear about that, my Bey.
We need to find the one
who ordered this, Ertuğrul Bey.
It's obvious who ordered it.
That bastard Ares.
He's stabbed us in the back,
in our very own tribe.
He has taken advantage of our mercy.
With this despicable act
he hopes to save his castle
and his neck from my sword.
But...
but all he's done is focus my fury, Bamsi.
He saves Turgut and now he does this?
How many faces does this man wear, my Bey?
He must have discovered that
we planned to attack the castle, Bamsi.
He's kidnapped Gündüz
to prevent us from doing so.
Then... Then let's burn
that castle to the ground!
We'll kill that dog
and save Gündüz's life, my Bey.
If we do that... we'll fall into
one of his traps a second time.
We would be risking Gündüz's life
while trying to save it.
God forbid. That bastard
is capable of anything, my Bey.
His intention is...
to use my son against me
and force me to do what he wants.
So, what will we do, my Bey?
How will we save Gündüz?
First of all, we find out exactly
where Gündüz is being held.
Let me go! Let go!
-This castle will be burnt to the ground!
-Keep walking!
Let go.
What are you doing?
-Walk.
-Let go!
Let me go!
Savcı.
They can't hurt your brother.
He has his sword with him.
They couldn't hurt him, could they, son?
My Ertuğrul will find him eventually.
Your brother can look after himself
until he's found, can't he?
And... you are his alp.
An alp leader never leaves
his alps alone, right?
Of course not.
Gündüz will be back here in no time.
Yes, he will.
What do they want with Gündüz?
Do they think they can settle
their differences by using a child?
What kind of cruelty is this?
Mother Hayme, don't worry.
Their disagreement isn't with Gündüz.
-They won't hurt him.
-What then, my girl?
Then why did they kidnap him?
When they confront an enemy
beyond their capabilities,
they resort to tactics like this
in order to subdue them.
My girl, my girl.
I can't take this anymore, Mother.
Volcanos are erupting inside of me.
I can't stand it anymore.
Patience, my girl. Patience.
Ertuğrul will find him
and bring him back to you.
And he will make them pay
for what they've done.
Be patient, my girl.
Atsız.
If he is in the castle, you must find out
exactly where he's being held.
Very well, Ertuğrul Bey.
But how are we going to do this?
Do you have a plan?
You'll go to the castle
disguised as the trader Nico.
You'll have a few soldiers with you.
You'll meet with Ares and gain his trust.
You'll find out where Gündüz is.
If he's being kept at the castle,
you'll find out which room.
If he isn't, you must find out
where they've taken him.
Very well, Ertuğrul Bey. Don't worry.
Question Nico again.
Gather every detail from him
so that Ares won't doubt you
when he meets you.
And tomorrow I'll go to see Ares myself.
Why, my Bey?
Ares
will take more precautions
if he knows I suspect him.
It'll make saving Gündüz even harder.
That's why I'm going to act like I have
no idea he was the one who took Gündüz.
I'll ask for his help locating Gündüz.
And so, he'll relax.
If Gündüz is in the castle,
I won't leave it.
We'll leave at night,
once we've rescued my son.
I'll contact you when
I'm inside the castle.
We'll proceed according to
the information you provide.
Be prepared.
Ertuğrul Bey...
What should I do with him
after I've questioned him?
Keep him here until the battle is over.
I'll hand him Ares' head
and send him back to Nicaea.
-Have a man watch him.
-Of course, my Bey. Don't worry.
Brother Atsız, brother Atsız.
There's something I have to tell you.
Brother, a woman named Marya came to us
when we last went to the castle
with Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut.
Clearly, she's Ares' woman.
Back in the day,
she was one of Simko's slaves.
Simko gifted this woman to Ares.
Why did she tell you all that?
Apparently, there was a disagreement.
If you speak to her, you might
find out what her story is.
Very well, brother Bamsi.
Thanks, thanks, brother Atsız.
-Keep walking. Keep walking, boy.
-Let go!
Open the gates.
Let go!
Let go! Let me go.
Let me go!
Please behave.
I don't want anything to happen to you.
Let me out of here! Let me out of here!
I am Gündüz, son of Ertuğrul Bey!
Let me out of here!
Me and my father
will make you pay for this!
Let me out of here.
I've taken one eye
and my father will take the other.
Let me out!
-Sir.
-What?
-I don't know how to say it.
-Speak, you moron!
I did everything I could but...
I'm sorry, your eye
was too seriously damaged.
Stop blabbering.
When can I take the bandage off?
Sir, I'm sorry, you've
lost your sight in that eye.
What are you saying?
Are you out of mind?
Get me another doctor now!
Sir, I'm sorry. The iris
was very seriously damaged.
Get the hell out of here!
Damned child!
I'll kill all of you. Every single one.
But I'll start with you.
Door!
Bahadir Bey.
What? What do you want?
So, you were hunting.
That's right.
Thank God, I've not come
back empty-handed.
But I see you have.
Not a good day hunting?
Stop speaking nonsense.
Kırca is missing.
We've been looking for him.
Kırca is missing. So what?
You know...
I was just asking,
I thought you might have run into him.
You're meant to be Chief Alp,
and your wife the tribe's Hatun.
Yet your alps are able to wander off
whenever it pleases them.
And you came to ask me?
Am I meant to protect your alps?
We won't rest while Kırca is missing.
And if we don't rest...
no one in this tribe can rest.
Know that.
Welcome, Turgut.
What happened? Did you find Kırca?
No, there's no sign of him, Aslihan.
Why is he still not back?
Don't worry.
With God's permission,
we'll find him safe and well.
Kırca would always return here,
no matter what, Turgut.
It's not a good sign
that he's still not back.
Speak of what's good,
so it shall happen, Aslihan.
I'm afraid Bahadir Bey
has done something to him, Turgut.
If he has dared to do that, he has
signed his own death sentence, Aslihan.
There's a fire of vengeance
raging within him.
There's nothing he wouldn't do.
I'll kill him with my own two hands
if he's done anything to harm Kırca Alp.
Don't worry.
I won't let him do anything.
I'll take every necessary precaution
and double the guards.
Don't upset yourself.
-Ertuğrul.
-Son.
Ertuğrul.
They kidnapped our son.
They took our Gündüz, Ertuğrul.
Who knows where and how he is.
Do not fear for his life, my Halime.
He is alive.
With God's permission,
I'll bring him back to you.
Amen to that.
They don't intend to hurt him,
they want to use him to make me kneel.
Is it Ares, my Bey?
That devil.
First, he separated us from Ertuğrul.
And now he's taken our Gündüz.
We won't be able to rest
until that bastard is dead.
Son, what kind of cruelty is this?
How could they kidnap a child?
They must have learned that
we planned to attack the castle, Mother.
They kidnapped Gündüz to stop us.
Ertuğrul, what if they hurt Gündüz?
How could we live with that pain?
They won't do anything to him
until they get what they want from me.
That's their intention.
Son, you would never bow before them.
So what's going to happen?
I'll neither bow before them,
nor will I let them do
anything to Gündüz, Mother.
I will save Gündüz...
and cause their whole world
to come crashing down.
But there's something
else troubling my mind.
How was Darius able to find out about
the attack and tell Ares about it?
My Bey, Gündüz was with us
when you were talking about it.
He said he wanted to go into battle.
I understand now.
Darius learned about the raid from Gündüz.
My God.
Open the door. Quickly!
Get behind me.
Alps don't fear anyone and they
certainly don't hide behind a woman.
Don't! He's just a child.
Stand aside.
I'm going to take his eye
and send it to his father.
I can't let that happen, Ares.
-I said stand aside!
-No!
You'll get what you deserve, Ares!
My father will make you
curse the day you were born.
You and your father can go to hell!
Ares!
What are you doing? He must live.
He must live for our holy cause.
Look here.
-He took my eye out.
-My friend...
think of everything
our holy empire expects of us.
You can't give in to your anger.
If you kill him,
all our efforts will be for nothing.
Ertuğrul can't attack the castle
so long as we have his son.
Our troops will arrive soon. And then
we can slaughter every one of them.
No one is to know his identity
or his location.
Understood?
I'm not done with you and your father yet.
What about you, Samsa Alp?
When did you last see Darius?
I saw him with the children.
He was talking to Gündüz.
I went over to check.
Gündüz said Darius was telling
them stories. And then he left.
And I haven't seen the bastard since.
My Bey.
What did I tell you about Darius, Samsa?
I'm asked you a question, Samsa.
What did I say?
You said we should watch him, my Bey.
And what did you do?
I told you to keep an eye on him
and then he kidnapped a son
of the bey and you didn't even notice.
You're right, my Bey.
That slap was not just for my son,
but for all our sons.
Today,
they have been able
to kidnap a son of the bey.
Tomorrow, they may
kidnap any child of ours,
all because of your stupidity.
Now, hand over your swords to Artuk bey.
As you command, my Bey.
And stay out of my sight for a while.
My God, help me in my time of need.
Don't upset my mother, father
and grandmother.
Give me the strength
to get out of this place.
I'm not here to hurt you.
-I've brought you some food.
-I don't want it.
But you need to eat.
I don't eat the food of the enemy.
I'm not your enemy like them.
I want to help you,
why are you angry with me?
I don't want your help.
You're all the same.
You aren't any different to them.
What are you going to do, my Bey?
I'm going to talk to Ares tomorrow.
I'll pretend I don't know
he kidnapped Gündüz.
I'll ask for his help saving Gündüz.
My Bey, why would you do that?
To see if Gündüz is in the castle.
One of my men is already inside the castle
disguised as a trader from Nicaea.
He'll find out what's going on
while I keep Ares busy.
Ares doesn't want war.
He won't want to engage us
when he knows they're not strong enough.
That's why he kidnapped my son.
He wanted to take over our trade
by assigning a trader called Nico
to the bazaar.
I'll pretend to accept his demands.
Son, may God help you.
With God's permission,
I hope you bring Gündüz back here.
God willing.
I'll wait until I hear
from my man on the inside.
Once I hear from him...
with God's permission,
I'll grab Gündüz and come back.
-I hope so.
Then...
I'll burn that castle down
with Ares in it.
Nico the merchant is here, sir.
Governor Ares.
I bring you the emperor's regards.
Welcome, merchant Nico.
I wish you a swift recovery, sir.
I hope you aren't in pain.
How did it happen?
The soldiers the emperor sent,
where are they?
The emperor wanted special catapults
to defend the castle.
But the carts pulling the catapults
were slowing us down,
so I asked Commander Teodor's permission
to travel ahead
with a few soldiers as guard.
All right.
-What about the man I sent?
-Yorgo.
He told me what happened.
I know everything.
He made sure we got here safely
and then he went back to Nicaea.
Then you know why
you're here, merchant Nico.
I'm to manage the bazaar,
as you requested from the emperor.
And you'll take over the trade.
Right, but that's easy to say.
How will you do it?
Don't worry, Governor Ares.
I came prepared.
I'm sure you'll like what I have to say.
Wonderful.
Come, let's talk while we eat.
Would you like some sherbet, my Bey?
-May I come in, my Bey?
-Come in.
What's the situation, Kayatekin?
I took a look at the tribe, my Bey.
Turgut Alp has doubled the guards.
With Kırca missing,
he suspects something is going to happen.
The raid tonight...
We can't attack tonight.
Why not, my Bey?
Apparently, the Cavdar alps like Turgut.
If Turgut leads them, we run the risk
too much blood will be shed.
My reputation will be tarnished
if I kill too many of their alps.
There will be unrest in the tribe.
And that will make me lose.
So what do we do, my Bey?
Chief Alp Turgut
was unable to find Kırca today.
He'll surely go out
searching again tomorrow.
We'll move to strike then.
Now, go and talk to Sancar.
Don't let anyone see you.
Tell him to disguise himself
and kill Turgut while
he's out looking for Kırca.
Tell him he is to come here
as soon as Turgut is dead.
I'll take over the tribe
with my son by my side.
Then I'll show Ertuğrul
who has authority here,
him or Bahadir Bey!
As you command, my Bey.
May we come in, my Bey?
The beys are here. Yes!
Welcome.
Go ahead, take a seat.
There is something very important
I want to talk to you about.
Now, we'd like to drink
some sherbet, wife.
I've doubled the guards. I've assigned
an additional alp to every position.
We'll know if a bird flies by.
The other alps are still
out looking for Kırca.
I'm afraid Bahadir Bey has
done something to him, Turgut.
If he has, I will not hesitate.
I'll kill him myself.
He's capable of anything.
I'll look for Kırca again tomorrow.
You should keep your wits about you here.
As long as Bahadir is here, we can't rest.
We're forced to keep
our swords unsheathed.
If he tries to do anything...
I swear to God,
I'll slay him with the sword of my kin.
The Venetian trader, Alessandro,
has agreed to bring his caravans
of precious gems and spices to the bazaar.
What about the trader in Constantinople?
Do you remember now?
-Talk!
-Ares has a close friend
in Constantinople.
The merchant Ricardo.
Ricardo will arrange
for them to meet in the bazaar.
Go on! Go on!
Your old merchant friend, Ricardo.
He'll come here to visit you.
It has been a while since I saw Ricardo.
It'll be good to see him,
even if it is just for business.
Marya, come in.
Meet the merchant, Nico.
My lady.
How is our little friend?
He won't eat or drink.
Are you feeling sorry for him, Marya?
He's just a child, Ares.
I don't care if he lives or dies.
-You either have him behave or--
-Don't worry.
I'll take care of him, Ares.
I'll want to see you tomorrow, Nico.
We still have a lot to talk about.
Good night for now.
Son... Son.
My son.
My son, whom I carried
in my belly for nine months.
My son, to whom I gave
birth in the tenth month.
Where are you, my beloved son?
My beloved son.
My Halime.
Halime.
You have a mother's heart.
My words won't be enough to soothe
the pain you're feeling as a mother.
But have faith in me.
I'll save Gündüz
and bring him back safe to you.
You won't have to sing
sad lullabies any longer.
My Gündüz.
Can you see what our mercy
has resulted in, Ertuğrul?
I can't even look you in the eyes,
I wasn't able to protect our son.
Halime.
It wasn't your fault.
Every cloud has a silver lining.
Our mercy is like an ocean.
We can't renounce it
just because the enemy poured
a few drops of poison into it.
We should be merciful
even if we get harmed in the end.
But if it comes to it,
our revenge will be terrible.
God willing, we'll discover
Kırca's tracks today.
-Pray for us, Aslıhan.
-Stay safe, Turgut.
I hope you find Kırca alive and well.
I hope so too. Oğuz!
-Stay here and guard the tribe.
-As you command, Chief Alp Turgut.
Come on, alps!
Turgut has finally left the tribe, my Bey.
He's taken only a few alps with him.
Sancar Bey will deal with them easily.
Once Turgut has been dealt with,
Aslıhan and her alps will be vulnerable.
And it'll be even easier
for us to assume control.
Now, we must stay alert
and wait for news from Sancar.
You won't grow up
to be a great warrior if you don't eat.
I don't need your food
to grow up to be a great warrior.
I'm already an alp,
thanks to my mother's food.
Do you want to get out of here?
Then you must preserve your strength.
-And to do that, you need to eat.
-I will preserve my strength!
I'm going to make that traitor Darius pay,
just like I did to Ares.
Of course you will.
We showed him mercy, yet he betrayed us.
I'll not show him any more mercy now.
But mercy is a good thing, Gündüz.
It's the only thing that makes us human.
-Are you a merciful person?
-Yes, of course.
Then let me go.
You have a very strong father, Gündüz.
He'll come for you.
Now drink your soup.
So that when your father comes
he will see you are still just as strong.
Trust me.
Here.
Sir?
-What the hell is that?
-It's opium, sir. It'll ease your pain.
Do you expect me to drug myself
at a time like this, you fool?
You're in a great deal of pain, sir.
So much pain might affect
your ability to make decisions.
That's why I thought we should
seek to ease your pain.
Nothing could ever hurt me as much as
knowing the Turks are on our lands!
Now, get the hell out of here!
The gate!
We weren't expecting you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let Governor Ares know I'm here.
I have things to discuss with him.
Soldier, let the governor know
Ertuğrul Bey is here.
Quickly!
Sir, Ertuğrul Bey is here.
-With how many alps?
-Only a few.
-Show him to my chamber!
-Yes, sir.
You've come to me!
You've come to me
all by yourself, Ertuğrul!
He might be here to hold you accountable.
Maybe. Or maybe he
is here to ask for my help.
I helped him save Turgut,
maybe he seeks my help
finding his son Gündüz, too.
Right. We left no traces behind.
He can't possibly know you have the child.
No, but he probably suspects we have him.
He'll try to trick us.
So, what are you going to do?
I'll do the same.
This game will continue
until one of us is dead, Titan.
Come with me and hide somewhere.
Listen to what's said.
This way, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Did you send word to our alps?
-Yes, my Bey.
I'll check on them after this
and get them ready for the raid.
What about you? Did you talk to your alps?
Yes, my Bey. Don't you worry.
Some of the alps will change sides and
fight with us once we've made our move.
Good, good.
Turgut left the tribe.
Sancar will take care of him soon.
Remember, there is to be
no blood shed in the tribe.
Turgut and Aslıhan are our targets,
I don't want anyone else harmed.
-Act accordingly.
-Yes, my Bey.
We should expect Ertuğrul Bey to
come down hard on us afterwards.
What will we do then, my Bey?
Don't worry.
Ertuğrul will accept my leadership
whether he likes it or not.
Once Aslıhan and Turgut are dead...
it'll be Ertuğrul's turn.
The tracks go that way.
Come on, alps!
Turgut bought it.
He's following the tracks.
Remember, this battle is crucial.
Turgut has to die if we're to have
unity and peace in the Cavdar tribe.
I'll be the one who takes his life.
-You go that way.
-Yes, my Bey.
And you go that way.
-You'll come with me.
-Yes, my Bey.
Who can save you
from me this time, Turgut Alp?
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you, Governor Ares.
What happened to your eye?
An unfortunate accident.
If you truly know your enemy
then you'll always be victorious, son.
You need to hit them
where they're weakest.
Just like Basat stabbing
the monster in its eye.
-I'm sorry.
-Come on, let's take a seat.
I wasn't expecting you.
To what do I owe the pleasure?
My son Gündüz has been
taken from the tribe.
Your son's been kidnapped?
And from the tribe?
Who would dare do
something like that, Ertuğrul Bey?
A Greek trader called Darius.
He had been injured by bandits.
We showed him mercy, healed his wounds,
treated him as our guest.
And then he kidnapped my son.
A Greek trader, you say?
I'm so sorry to hear this, Ertuğrul Bey.
But if that's the case, he probably
intends to sell your son as a slave.
I don't care what his plans are, Ares.
I only care about saving my son.
You know how grateful I am to you.
You helped save the lives
of Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun.
It was nothing, Ertuğrul Bey.
After all, we do business together.
You should know that I'll do my best
to help you find your son, too.
I came here confident
that you would help, Ares.
You know the Greek traders well.
You know better than anyone
what they do and where they go.
I'll gladly help you
Ertuğrul Bey. Soldier!
Send out your men.
Question every Greek trader
you can get hold of.
Whoever's holding the son of Ertuğrul Bey
must bring him to me at once.
If they don't,
I'll behead them one by one.
Yes, sir.
-May I come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
-Come in, Oğuz.
Has there been any news?
-The news is not good, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Tell me, what's happened?
Ertuğrul Bey's son has been kidnapped.
Who... who would do that?
How is that possible?
A Greek trader. They let him in
because he was wounded.
Ertuğrul Bey is chasing after him.
Yet another disaster.
God, keep all of us safe.
-Oğuz, gather the beys here at once.
-Yes, Aslıhan Hatun.
Door!
Alps, tether your horses here.
The weather has broken.
I hope that's a sign.
Stay alert.
This was carved on purpose.
Alps, it's a trap!
Surrender if you don't want
your alps to die, Turgut Alp.
If you were only brave enough,
you'd lower your hoods
and face me like real men.
Where's Kırca?
Relax, my Bey. Why don't you sit down?
Now isn't the time to sit.
We move as soon as we hear from Sancar.
Prepare my sword and armor.
It's already done, my Bey.
-My Bey, may I come in?
-Come in.
My Bey, our alps are ready.
We'll surround the tribe
as soon as you give the order.
We need confirmation
of Turgut's death, first.
Come on Sancar, come on.
Bring me word of his death
or even better bring me his head.
Do whatever is necessary,
but get here right now!
Get here so that
we may take over the tribe.
-Brother, are you all right?
-Yes, Chief Alp Turgut.
We need to get back
to the tribe right now.
The bastards might have
already attacked. Come on.
Leave me here, you'll get back faster.
Not going to happen, brother.
We're in this together.
Come on.
Just like I said, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'm happy to help you any way I can.
I hope we find your son safe and well.
I wasn't wrong to trust you, Ares.
You honor me, Ertuğrul Bey.
But I'd like to strengthen this bond.
I think we should show sincerity
in peace and friendship.
-How is that going to happen?
-With trade.
Meaning?
We can reinforce our partnership
through the bazaar.
Tell me what you're thinking, Ares.
Look Ertuğrul Bey, I've brought a skilled
trader from Nicaea. His name is Niko.
Through him, a lot of Venetian and Greek
traders will come to the bazaar.
We'll both make more money.
But in order to do that, I need
some privileges over the bazaar.
I believe you'll be amendable to that
after all the things I've done for you.
Very well. Your offer is reasonable.
But I need to find Gündüz first.
Then we can talk in more detail.
Just let me introduce you
to Niko before you leave.
Summon Niko.
What's this all about, Aslıhan Hatun?
Why have you gathered us here?
My beys and alps. As you all know,
after Kırca went missing
we took the precaution
of doubling the guards.
We now need to take further measures
to protect ourselves.
That's why I asked you here.
But why is this necessary, Aslıhan Hatun?
I received news from the Kayi Tribe.
Gündüz, son of Ertuğrul Bey,
has been kidnapped.
-How come?
-Who could do that?
Who would dare do that?
Whoever's capable of kidnapping the son
of Ertuğrul Bey is capable of anything.
That's why the first thing we need to do
is make sure our tribe is secure.
After that, we'll do whatever we can
to support the Kayi Tribe.
-She's right.
-Aslıhan Hatun has a point.
Alps, double the guards.
Have them patrol the tribe
in groups of two.
Yes, Aslıhan Hatun.
My beys, you should be careful too.
Great games are being
played out around us.
The enemy is rushing towards us
like a river in a flood.
If we don't stand together
this river will wash us away.
-She's right.
-Aslıhan Hatun is right.
-May I come in, my Bey?
-Come in.
Any news from Sancar?
No, my Bey. Not yet.
-But there is something else.
-What?
Aslıhan Hatun, she's doubled
the number of guards patrolling the tribe.
And she gathered the beys and alps
and issued instructions to them.
Interesting.
I wonder if she's learned of the attack.
Sancar! Why have you not yet
brought me Turgut's head?
There's something else
you should know, my Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey's son Gündüz
was kidnapped from his tribe.
What did you just say, Kayatekin?
Ertuğrul's son? From the tribe?
-Who did it?
-We don't know, my Bey.
That must be the reason
Aslıhan has taken all these precautions.
Ertuğrul can't be in his right mind
if his son has been kidnapped.
And once Turgut dies...
everything will be in our favor.
Come on, Sancar, come on.
Come on.
Niko. Meet Ertuğrul Bey,
glorious margrave of the Seljuks
and owner of Hanlı bazaar.
I hope we'll soon be working
together at the bazaar.
Nice to meet you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Niko.
As Governor Ares just said,
I hope we get to work together
at Hanlı bazaar.
Surely Ertuğrul Bey,
that would be in everyone's interest.
Let's see what time brings us, Niko.
We can talk about it again
when the time is right.
I best get going now, Governor Ares.
I'll look forward to hearing
your decision, Ertuğrul bey.
And I'll look forward
to hearing of Gündüz.
Ertuğrul Bey.
It was an honor to meet you.
Get to work, Niko.
I've dealt with the nasty part.
The rest is up to you.
-Prepare accordingly.
-Yes, sir.
Ertuğrul is obviously playing with you.
I know, Titan. But it's not one sided.
I'm playing with him too
and I'll be the winner in the end.
There is still no news.
Do you think something
bad has happened, my Bey?
Wife, think positively!
-May I come in, my Bey?
-Come in, Kayatekin.
My Bey.
Turgut... Turgut is on his way
back to the tribe.
My God.
What the hell are you saying?
Sancar.
Wait here.
-Where are the others?
-Where are the other alps?
Alps!
Where are our brothers?
What's happened to them?
What happened, Chief Alp Turgut?
Did you find Kırca Alp?
What's happened to our brothers?
Who did this, Chief Alp Turgut?
They ambushed us.
They hid their faces.
But... they each got what they deserved.
Take him to the healing tent.
Sancar... Sancar!
-Kayatekin!
-Yes, my Bey?
-Find out where Sancar is, right away.
-Yes, my Bey.
Turgut!
Turgut! If you've done anything to my son,
I swear to God,
I'll rain hell upon you
and take your head in front of everyone.
What happened Turgut? Where are the alps?
We were ambushed.
Good God.
Who? Who did this?
I don't know.
They looked like bandits.
They hid their faces.
First Kırca, and now this ambush.
For God's sake, what's going on, Turgut?
Whoever ambushed us...
knew I'd be there.
I suspect Bahadir.
It might not have been Bahadir Bey.
I got news from the Kayi Tribe today.
Ertuğrul Bey's son, Gündüz...
What about Gündüz?
Gündüz has been kidnapped.
Who?
Who kidnapped him?
I can think of only one person.
Governor Ares.
He might also be the one
who had you ambushed.
Go to Ertuğrul Bey if you like.
Don't leave him alone.
Don't worry about us here.
I've taken more precautions and increased
the guards. Nothing bad will happen.
I feel like I'm drowning in rage.
But... it's still dangerous here.
If I leave here, they'll look
to take advantage of my absence.
This is where I must be.
God willing, Ertuğrul Bey will
save his son without my help.
I hope so.
Gündüz is alive and in the castle.
I'll locate him as soon as possible.
Wait for me
in the empty shop, Ertuğrul Bey.
Gündüz is in the castle.
Where is the empty shop?
-Let me take you there, my Bey.
-Not now.
They must see us leave the castle.
We'll come back in disguise.
Come on.
Come.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My brave son was going to go
hunting on wild horses.
He was to ride horses and win battles.
He will still do those things,
Halime Hatun. Try not to worry.
I'd give my life to hold you
in my arms one more time, son.
There are signs of him everywhere, Hafsa.
Wherever I look, I see him.
I'm dying inside.
Halime Hatun, be patient, for God's sake.
You'll see, Ertuğrul Bey
will come back with Gündüz.
I hope so. I hope so, Hafsa.
My mother must be crying a lot
at the marquee, Marya.
You will soon get back to your tribe.
Ares will not let me go.
Weren't you an alp? Do alps surrender?
Ertuğrul Bey's son, Gündüz,
never surrenders.
Good for you.
People sometimes do things they don't
believe in, but for good reason.
You must be nice to Ares.
Why are you helping me?
Because you remind me of my brother.
What happened to him?
Some merciless people killed him.
But I won't let anything happen to you.
When I get out of here,
I will avenge your brother too.
I have to go now. I will come back later.
Eat your food.
My God, let my father come and rescue me.
Don't let my mother
and Grandmother worry too much.
Let me see your face, Günküt.
Good, good.
Let me take a look, Bamsi.
Bamsi?
Put down your hands.
Well, would you look at my alp.
Why do you laugh so heartedly?
Look at your own moustache.
I'm not ashamed of my moustache
that I would hide it like you.
Günküt!
You know I cut off
the tips of that moustache before.
When this is over,
I'm going to pull them out one by one.
One by one!
That's enough, Bamsi.
You both shaved like you're meant to.
You have its roots. It will grow back.
I hope so, my Bey.
I hope it grows back in no time.
It will Bamsi, God willing.
Come on, to the horses.
My Bey.
What will Hafsa Hatun say
when she sees me like this?
I fear she might frown
until it grows back.
You're going to go back to the tribe
looking like that.
And you're the head alp.
They will see you like this.
That should be your main concern.
You cut your beard for our duty.
For our duty, we always do
what is necessary without considering
what others might think, right?
Right, my Bey.
Duty is what matters the most.
Good for you, my man.
-To the horses.
-All right.
My God, help me.
Please.
Marya, is the kid all right?
He is so small, Commander Kostas.
Don't be weak, Marya.
He is very valuable to us.
Don't worry.
Oh, Sancar. You couldn't kill that dog.
I hope your life is safe.
My Bey... Calm down, my Bey.
If anything had happened,
Turgut would've said something.
-Permission to enter, my Bey.
-Come in.
My Bey. Sancar Bey...
he is wounded.
Wounded?
Is he all right?
They dressed his wounds, my Bey.
He is all right for now.
My God.
And Turgut?
Did Turgut see his face?
He did not, my Bey.
He did not.
There, my Bey.
Sancar Bey is all right.
And Turgut didn't see who he was.
Hatun, do you think these things
are so easy?
Even if they didn't see Sancar's face,
they will suspect us.
They will be watching us.
They might even...
make a move against us.
We didn't get what we hoped for.
Now we must do whatever we can
so they do not to suspect us.
That's why I am going to visit
Aslıhan and Turgut.
Then I will go see Sancar
without anyone knowing.
Somebody is coming. Get ready.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Ares' courtesan Marya knows
where they are keeping Gündüz.
Bamsi Alp, you were right.
What you said was useful. Thank you.
You're welcome.
You keeping your eye out helped us, Bamsi.
You once again proved
that you deserve to be head alp.
Thank you, my Bey. Thank you.
Then we talk to Marya.
I found Marya's quarters, my Bey.
We can go right away.
Only Bamsi will come with us.
With God's grace,
if we get Gündüz and get out...
we will be out of the fort
before the doors are opened.
And the next time we go there...
it will be to conquer the fort
with God's permission.
Hopefully, my Bey.
You...
lie in wait at the market and the gates.
-As you wish, my Bey.
-Give us your blessing, men.
-It is yours.
-It is yours, my Bey.
I hope you come with your son.
Thank you.
Permission to enter.
Come in.
Selamunaleykum.
Aleykumselamun.
Why have you come, Bahadir Bey?
You were eating, apologies.
However...
I heard something.
Ertuğrul Bey's son was kidnapped.
He was.
However...
our bey will retrieve Gündüz
in one piece, sooner or later.
Hopefully.
If there is anything I can do
to aid you in this...
I am ready to do it,
that is what I came to say.
Thank you, Bahadir Bey.
There is no need for now.
There might have been...
some unpleasant dealings among us.
But...
a boy's life it at stake here.
In situations like this...
hostilities are left behind.
If there is anything I can do...
I will be in my tent.
Good night.
Thank you.
Door.
By kidnapping Ertuğrul's boy...
we have greatly shaken
Ertuğrul and the Turks.
We will continue to do so until they fall.
Up next is Bahadir Bey.
We will pull him into our ranks
and help him to get his tribe back.
Ertuğrul will not like that at all.
And it will cause a stir among the Turks.
That's exactly what I want.
Then it's up to you, Titan.
What is?
Call your men, get them here.
We will watch what goes on among the Turks
from here.
We will make our moves accordingly.
I hope these moves
turn into big slaughters.
They definitely will.
When they start fighting among themselves
we will destroy them all.
You don't have to worry about us.
Me and my men
have been longing to shed Turkish blood.
Just tell us
when, where and what to do.
Then...
get on your walls...
and watch the blood
that flows from Turk camps with pleasure.
To our holy empire and cause.
Here, Ertuğrul Bey.
Who is it?
Tekfur Ares sent me.
What do you want?
Marya.
What are you up to?
What do you mean?
I know you have been
secretly talking to Ertuğrul's alps.
You are out of your mind.
Why did you tell them that you were...
working for that dog Simko?
What are you after, Marya?
Talk to me.
You came here uninvited. Get out!
Ares will punish you.
I don't think so.
Ares will kill you
if he finds out that you have been
whispering into alps' ears,
you know that right?
Tell me.
Why did you talk to the alps?
Either you talk now...
or I will tell Ares what I know.
Come on.
God damn you all!
He will kill that innocent boy
just like he killed my brother.
Enough, I can't take it anymore.
Damn you...
and that scum that is your lord!
Yes.
Damn him.
Ertuğrul Bey!
Where is my son, Marya?
God has answered my prayers.
I will take you to him.
Just avenge my brother.
Halime Hatun!
Hafsa!
I asked the alps,
still no word from Ertuğrul Bey.
Mother...
Still no word.
How will I live
if something happened to Gündüz?
My girl, my beautiful girl...
hope for the best.
My Ertuğrul will find him
and bring him to you.
Don't you lose hope.
You are right, mother.
What can I say,
I can't make my heart listen.
My Ertuğrul and my Gündüz
are at that forsaken fort.
Every minute they don't return,
It eats me up inside.
God willing,
they will return in one piece.
You need to be strong.
Trust in God.
Okay?
My dear God...
please let them return to the tribe
in one piece.
God willing. God help us.
This way.
Ares asked me to look after Gündüz
at night. He won't call for me.
He doesn't want anyone to know that Gündüz
is at the fort. He increased security.
Where are the guards, Marya?
There are two at the door.
And his special guards are on patrol,
his best warriors,
the soldiers who are closest to Ares.
Be careful.
-Bamsi.
-Yes.
I will go with Marya.
Watch out for the guards, watch my back.
Yes, my Bey. Yes.
Do not engage with them unless necessary.
Let's go, Marya.
Tekfur Ares wants to see the boy
right away.
Who is this?
Gündüz...
Father!
Am I dreaming?
It is not a dream, my boy.
I came to take you home.
You taught me
that a Turk doesn't surrender,
and I never did.
I did not bring disgrace upon you.
Well done, my boy.
Ertuğrul Bey,
the sun is about to rise,
the gates will be opened. Hurry.
all right.
Come on, my boy.
This is yours from now on.
Take it. You deserve it.
Protect yourself if need be.
This is the day, father.
If enemies should befall me
I will hit my first one with this.
You will, my boy.
You will.
Come.
Alert Tekfur Ares.
Ertuğrul is in the fort.
Ya Allah!
Marya! Are you all right?
Are you all right, Marya?
I'm fine.
Ertuğrul Bey,
You go.
I...
I will take care of myself.
Avenge...
my brother.
I give you my word, Marya.
I will avenge your brother.
Come on, son.
The light of my dark eye
Atop the mountain that lies dark ahead
My son
May your wings never break
May your rivers never run dry
Mighty Lord,
for the sake of the prophet Muhammed...
please spare my Gündüz.
Spare him.
My dear God, help us.
God damn it!
What happened here?
Marya!
She's hurt! Send for the healer at once!
Gündüz!
We need to pass the soldiers at the gates
before the ones in the fort come.
Come on.
Alert all the guards!
Hold all the gates! Hurry!
-What's going on, Niko?
-Not Niko.
Atsız!
Hide my boy, hide!
Protect yourself, Gündüz!
Kostas.
All the wine I've drunk since morning
has not eased the pain.
Give me some good news
that may help.
My lord...
They took Gündüz.
What do you mean, they took him?
What are you saying?
My lord,
they killed the men in the hallway.
I ran to the dungeon but...
he wasn't there.
Have you lost your mind,
what are you saying?
Where is Marya?
Marya is wounded, my lord.
They took her to her room.
Ertuğrul has come to save his son.
Close the gates.
Alert the men, don't let them out.
Why are you just standing there, go!
Door.
Ertuğrul!
I will not let you win this time...
no matter the cost.
Father!
Come, son.
Come on.
Thank you.
I told you if Ertuğrul leaves, he wins.
I can't let that happen.
Run to the gates, don't let them out.
They penetrated
the deepest corners of my fort,
killed my men and left.
Ertuğrul will pay for this.
Ertuğrul broke the peace, Ares.
Goddamn the peace!
It is time for blood!
Close the gates!
No one goes out!
The war with the Turks has begun!
Yah!
My girl...
My girl, this is eating you up.
Come, sit a little.
How can I sit, mother?
There's still no word.
I cannot stay sat in this tent.
I cannot rest until my Ertuğrul
and my Gündüz are back.
My dear God,
let them come to their tribe in one piece.
The kettledrum.
I hope they're signaling good news.
God willing.
My God.
Ertuğrul Bey brings Gündüz!
Rejoice, Ertuğrul Bey is back.
Gündüz!
Gündüz! My son!
Ertuğrul Bey is back!
Welcome, my Bey.
Mother, I'm back.
Welcome, my Gündüz.
My Gündüz.
You are all right, aren't you?
Those fiends didn't do anything to you,
did they?
Don't worry, Mother,
your son made them sorry.
Good for you.
My Gündüz.
Grandmother.
I'd die for you.
Oh, my dear.
Oh, my dearest.
Ertuğrul.
Oh, my dear.
Welcome.
It's nice to be back.
My Gündüz.
I'd die for you.
My son.
God bless you.
You gave us the joy of reunion.
I was burning up inside, my Bey.
But now that I see you in one piece...
I wouldn't be sad even if the world fell.
You gave me the biggest of joys.
From now on, the fire in your heart
will subside, Halime.
Their fire will begin.
The enemy...
can take nothing from us with traps.
To the fiends
who rage to rid us of these lands...
we have no son to give them.
We have not an inch of land to give them.
Evil has revealed its face.
Conquest has become necessary
to keep order.
From now on, swords will be drawn...
and until the order of evil
is destroyed...
they will not be put away.
Allahu akbar!