Episode 121 will start after 12:20 min.
-Murderer! Bastard! Traitor!
-You'll get what you deserve! Traitor!
-You'll get what you deserve!
-Traitor!
He is a traitor!
Traitor!
He thinks he can escape from us.
-Let's go, Özalp.
-Come on, Brother.
What is going on outside?
Don't cry, sweet child.
Don't cry. It's okay.
Now, go to sleep.
Almıla Hatun.
Sügay Hatun, what is going on outside?
They woke Osman up.
The Mongol spy tried to escape.
That's the cause of the noise,
Almıla Hatun.
What are you doing here?
Osman was crying. I came to check on him.
Thank you, Almıla Hatun.
You go and rest.
I'll take care of Osman.
Okay then.
I'll check outside.
Let me see what's going on.
The boatman is there.
The Mongols are keeping an eye on him.
My bey, isn't there any other way?
I don't want to get in that dinghy.
I get seasick. I don't like the waves.
I feel trapped at sea.
My bey, I have never seen Bamsi
so afraid before.
Brother, we don't have wings,
so we can't fly.
We don't have fins either,
so we can't swim.
If we don't get on that boat,
we won't get to the tribe until winter.
We need to get there quickly
to remove Noyan's spy from the tribe.
If Noyan doesn't catch us, that is.
My bey.
I hope those bastards don't do
anything bad before we get there.
Noyan stationed them there...
so that they could hit us from behind
during the battle.
They'll act like one of us
until the right moment arises.
But...
Ögedei Khan is dead.
Noyan is outraged.
We need to get to the tribe
before his messengers do.
Let's deal with them quickly
and get to our tribe, my bey.
Don't let any harm come to the boatman.
-Watch out.
-Very well.
Come on, my lions.
God is the greatest!
Abdur Rahman, don't let him get away!
Don't kill me!
Get up!
Move! Move!
Move!
Please don't kill me, my bey.
You will take us to Anatolia right away.
Noyan will kill me, my bey.
You'll get your payment.
Then you'll be free.
You can go wherever you want,
whenever you want with your ship.
But you must take us to Anatolia
before Noyan gets there.
As you order, my bey.
The wind blows in your favor.
Let's hurry, then.
Let's go.
-Traitor! Get the traitor!
-He is running away!
Get him! Traitor!
Get the bastard!
He is running away, get him!
Stop, you traitor! Get him!
Stop! Don't run! Get him!
Traitor!
Punish him!
-That was a nice one, Brother Günküt.
-Thank you, Brother.
There is no escape from this tribe
for bastards like you.
Move!
Why are you still letting him breathe?
Not before Ertuğrul Bey arrives.
He'll take care of him once he is here.
-Hopefully so.
-Move!
Kill him! Traitor!
Move!
I'll make you pay
for lying to Ögedei Khan, Ertuğrul.
I'll be the one to behead you
when the time comes.
If you don't die of grief
for your children, you'll die by my sword!
TEN DAYS LATER
Will they stain our honor
with these leathers?
Remake them from scratch.
The Turks shall know
that we're the best manufacturers.
Take these away!
Tell them to work.
Someone is coming, Alangoya.
We'll learn who.
Who are you?
Harsünlü Nurahbono.
Noyan sent me.
Speak.
Speak!
Tell me!
Ögedei Khan is dead.
What are you saying, you black dog?
What do you mean he's dead?
Noyan and Ertuğrul came before our Khan.
Ertuğrul made everyone believe
that he obeyed our Khan.
He sent his alps forward.
Our Khan was gone for the festivities.
He was dead in the night.
And Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul and his men ran away from Noyan.
He'll be back at his village soon.
What does Noyan ask?
That you kill Ertuğrul's family
before he returns home.
And our secret mission?
Your only secret mission is
to kill his family.
Then, you'll go to Gündoğdu Bey's village.
You'll kill Selcan Hatun, Sungurtekin Bey
and his family.
Then...
it's time for war.
Our army will crush the Seljuks.
I'll go there in the morning.
If they kill me...
set off at sunrise.
We'll end Ertuğrul's line.
Grandmother...
Yes.
Still no news from Father.
I miss him.
When will he be back?
Patience, my son.
I miss Ertuğrul too.
Only God knows how much I miss him.
May God bring him back
quickly and safely.
May he protect him from harm.
Amen.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Son!
-Father.
-My son.
My little lion. Mashallah.
My brave son.
Did you look after your brothers?
Of course, Father.
I sure did.
I fed them myself.
I'm proud of you.
Mother...
Son...
Welcome.
Welcome, my brave son.
Thank God.
Welcome, my sons.
Thank you, mother.
Oh, my son.
Artuk Bey.
My Bey.
Welcome, my Bey.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Thank God.
Indeed.
Chief Alp Bamsi.
-Welcome.
-Artuk Bey, thanks.
Welcome.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Now that you've returned safely,
my prayers have been answered.
What happened? Tell me.
We did the duty the Sultan gave us.
Bless God, the peace is signed.
Thank Goodness.
My Osman.
Welcome.
My little son.
My strong son.
Your eyes are beautiful.
Osman looks strong, Mother.
You looked after him well.
Sugay Hatun.
God bless you.
-Where is Savcı?
-Inside. He's sleeping.
Good. Let him sleep.
Come, Mother. We must talk.
Okay, son.
Tell me.
What's the matter?
Where is Almıla?
At the tannery.
Why?
We learned that Almıla's real name
is Alangoya.
Alangoya?
Almıla is actually
that scum Noyan's sister.
She infiltrated us.
But...
What are you saying?
How could this happen?
We learned it at Ögedei's base.
Don't tell anyone yet.
So, that girl I considered...
a daughter was an enemy?
She infiltrated us.
Indeed, Mother.
We couldn't tell friend from foe
for a long time.
Now it's time to see the difference.
First, I'll make the Mongol spy
caught by Günalp Bey talk.
Excuse me, Mother.
Thank goodness.
Welcome, my Bey.
Thank you, Oğuz Alp.
Did he talk?
Not yet. We didn't push him
until you came back.
Good.
Who is your leader?
Who gives you orders?
Noyan!
Only Noyan.
Besides him.
There's no one else.
And Noyan's sister, Alangoya?
I mean Almıla Hatun...
Her men at the tannery.
They're all Mongol spies.
Don't deny it. I know everything.
Almıla is Noyan's sister, Alangoya.
Her men are Mergen the hunter...
and Samuan Bergütay.
Noyan told us to come here.
Our goal was...
to destroy you from within.
Let me go! I'll do anything!
Forgive.
Forgive me.
In the lands of Ertuğrul,
son of Suleyman Shah...
there's no mercy...
for traitors.
Kadan Khan!
Kadan.
Noyan.
While we were still mourning
for Genghis Khan,
we sent your dear father Ögedei Khan
to the spirits.
I'm sorry.
I feel your pain.
After my father Ögedei,
my mother rules,
as the regent.
We decided this would be best,
to preserve the State,
with my brother Göyük.
May Tengri keep Töregene Hatun strong.
I've become the ruler
of Desht-i Kipchak...
in accordance
with Genghis Khan's partition.
Strengthening the rule of Europe
will also be my duty.
May Tengri help you, my Khan.
About you, Noyan.
Yarımagun acquired a great piece of China.
He subdued them.
And you get Anatolia.
The two-year peace agreement
that my father made
with the Seljuks,
has no meaning for me nor for my mother.
Take my army and go quickly!
Hearing this great news that I have
waited for so long from you
has made me the happiest man in the world.
The sitting man grows fat.
The moving dog finds a bone.
As your loyal dog,
I'll go to Anatolia to bring you
flesh and blood.
Victory...
or victory!
I don't deserve death.
They're back.
Be careful, Mergen.
The rats want to escape.
Easy.
Welcome, Turgut Bey.
Welcome.
-Thank you.
-Thanks.
What's the matter?
Are you closing the tannery?
What's all this?
Only reorganizing.
You brought alps.
Is there a problem?
Yes. There is. An important problem.
What?
Nothing to worry about.
We learned about the Mongols
infiltrating our lands.
Did you?
Also, their identities...
Who are they?
Guess who!
Tanners.
Bergütay.
Permission to enter, Mother Hayme?
Come in, dear.
Where are Gündüz and Savcı?
They're with Sugay Hatun. Why?
We'll leave tomorrow to sell leather.
I wanted to see you before I go
and to see and kiss the kids goodbye.
Good thinking, dear.
Come, sit.
Once Osman is asleep, I'll come.
I had a dream, Mother Hayme.
What did you see?
I saw Ertuğrul Bey safely returning.
I hope that will be true.
We know the Mongols are among us.
They're so close.
We suspect
that they're even in our village,
even in our tents.
How can that be?
Günalp Bey caught Noyan's scum.
Günalp Bey sent news, dear.
He learned the truth.
Noyan's spy he brought here was
just a pawn.
They fooled us all.
They wanted to take advantage
of us sharing our village,
our happiness,
and sadness.
Where is Günalp Bey now?
He took his soldiers to ambush that scum.
Who is the scum, Mother?
Noyan's sister, Alangoya.
You'll all die!
A snake in my tribe!
And now she dies.
Don't try to bite off
more than you can chew.
You cleaned our tribe's honor
with Suleyman Shah's sword.
You deserved to kill her.
May you spill Noyan's blood, son.
May God grant you to avenge the ones
whose blood he spilled.
God willing, mother.
God willing.
You came to the wrong place.
We are not prey.
I hunted many men.
Now you'll be my biggest prize!
Brother, are you okay?
I'm fine, brother.
I was just about to take his head...
but these dogs attacked me.
So, he saw this and...
ran away.
Don't worry, brother.
Don't be hard on yourself.
Look, we killed them all.
Where will that dog go?
We'll surely get him.
Brother. Our Bey killed Almıla.
Come. Let's go home.
Let's go, brother.
Let's go. Come on, alps!
Come on!
When we enter Anatolia,
we'll kill the Turks that don't obey us.
The ones who obey will be our slaves.
May Tengri bless your sword, Noyan.
But...
we'll let them kill each other first.
They'll blind themselves.
They'll cut their own tongues.
Crows will feed on their corpses.
Anatolia will be a warzone.
Many spies are among the Turks,
just like my sister Alangoya.
They will always provoke rebellions.
And everything...
will be so messed up that...
young Sultan Gıyaseddin will become
the rebel Turks' puppet.
Sultan Gıyaseddin gathers an army
of Frankish soldiers to fight us.
Franks will just bring more flame
to the fire in Anatolia.
Whatever happens,
I'll trap the Turks at Kösedağ in the end.
I've wandered there for months.
That's where I'll make my coup de grace.
Let all my forces unite and march
as soon as possible.
And Nicaea?
We'll crush the Turks from the east.
When Ertuğrul is crushed,
it will be Nicaea's turn.
Son...
I think about Turgut, Mother.
I hope they killed those scum.
Of course, they did.
Don't worry.
Nobody can run away from them.
Indeed.
Did you ever kill an enemy, Grandmother?
I did...
Many times...
My Gündüz...
My mother's hands are talented.
Both at curing our friends...
and killing enemies.
Permission to enter, my Bey?
Here they are.
Come, brothers.
There are my brave men!
Thank goodness.
My brave warriors.
My Bey, God granted us victory
over the scum.
We killed them all, my Bey.
I'm so proud of you.
Mashallah.
God bless your hands.
May he keep your swords ever sharp.
-Amen, my Bey.
-Thanks, my Bey.
Mashallah.
My grandmother killed Almıla, Turgut Bey.
She killed that snake with her sword.
Well done, Mother.
Let me kiss that hand.
God bless you, Mother.
Son...
My mother has led women for years.
Almıla is nothing for her.
My dear Mother.
Turgut Bey...
Artuk Bey.
Chief Alp Bamsi.
Glory to your hearts
and your swords, my sons.
Thanks, mother.
He who follows God has many enemies.
May God grant us the strength,
courage and power
to face those enemies.
May we always be victorious.
-Amen, Mother.
-Amen.
Amen, Mother.
My Gündüz.
Go, be with your brothers.
As you order, my Bey.
Since we took care of this,
now it's time.
Time for what, my Bey?
To migrate, brothers.
Send news.
We migrate to Söğüt.
-Alright, my Bey.
It's tradition.
We must hold a council before we go.
So, we'll listen to the beys
before we go,
and we'll hear about the tribes.
Then, I'll make preparations
at the Hanlı Bazaar.
-Thanks, Artuk Bey.
-Thank you.
-Permission to enter, my Bey?
-Come, Melikşah.
Speak.
My Bey... messengers from Nicaea.
From Nicaea?
Who? The Governor?
No, my Bey. The Emperor's son.
The Emperor's son?
My Bey. Why would the Emperor's son come?
Surely, to make a treaty, Bamsi.
They know they can't fight
against the Turks.
Especially when the Mongols are close.
Welcome the Emperor's son before the tent,
Turgut.
Then invite him in.
As you order.
Artuk Bey...
Stay with me.
As my Bey commands.
As you order.
Let me help you, Sugay Hatun.
I'm so proud of you, my boy.
The Emperor's son is here to see Ertuğrul.
Why, Mother Hayme?
For peace and for the issue of Söğüt.
Grandmother...
The Emperor's son himself comes here
to see my father.
How did my father become so strong?
Sit down.
Sit down. I'll tell you.
Everything started when Suleyman Shah
sent Ertuğrul to Aleppo as a messenger.
What do you want?
I'm the messenger of Suleyman Shah,
the Bey of Kayıs.
I'm his son. Ertuğrul.
I'm here to ask for land.
What will you give in return?
In return, 2,000 alps will be with you
every time you need them.
Two-thousand alps, huh?
Even my palace has more guards.
Safe travels, son of Bey.
Next.
My Bey.
Come on!
Your guards are three less.
Whatever your father did,
he got lands from the Emir of Aleppo.
But it wasn't easy.
Your father had many troubles.
He had many threats.
He risked many things
so that we'd have a land to call home.
We lost many people to have a land.
We faced many troubles.
Ertuğrul risked his life many times
so that we'd have a permanent home.
He risked death many times.
What a glorious man my father is.
What great troubles he faced.
Me and my brothers,
we'll be brave beys worthy of our father.
God willing. You will all be so.
Just as I believe in your father,
I believe in you.
Because you will walk in the path
that your father made.
You'll help the innocent and fight evil.
Amen, Grandmother.
It's obvious he's the Emperor's son.
Do you think he brings trouble?
He won't, if he likes to live.
He shouldn't, brother.
He shouldn't.
I'm Prince Theodor.
I'm the son and heir of Emperor Yannis.
I'm Turgut Bey, Bey of the Cavdars.
Welcome, Prince Theodor.
I'm here to see Ertuğrul Bey
in our Emperor's name.
I wish to present our gifts
and offer for peace.
Ertuğrul Bey waits in the tent.
Abdur Rahman, let him know.
Prince Theodor is here.
Let him in.
Welcome, Prince Theodor.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Please.
We brought you offers of peace before.
But they were broken.
I'm here for a serious
and lasting agreement.
First, I want you to accept our gifts.
Thank you for the gifts.
As you said, you brought offers
of peace before.
We never denied them.
Yet, they were all broken.
The reason was betrayal
by your governors and commanders.
I, the Heir Apparent
of the Byzantine throne,
came personally to reassure you.
Ögedei Khan is dead.
The Mongols will head to Anatolia.
They will try to destroy us both.
Why be destroyed
when we can live in peace?
Nobody will dare betray and
break the peace, rest assured.
Prince Theodor.
We never deny an offer of peace.
And as long as you keep
your end of the deal,
we'll treat you fairly.
And as long as they're honorable,
we'll treat our enemies the same way.
When your great Sultan Alparslan defeated
and captured Emperor
Romanos Diogenes at Manzikert,
he treated him fairly and like a friend.
I know that you're honorable as well.
That's why making a peace agreement
with you is an honor for us.
Abdur Rahman.
I sign in the name of our Emperor.
And I sign as Frontier Bey,
with the authority given to me
by the Seljuk State
and the Sultan.
When we settle in Söğüt, we'll build
a bazaar greater than Hanlı Bazaar.
The Greek merchants can trade there
as they wish.
We'll ensure their safety.
We'll do our best to support
the new bazaar
as long as the peace lasts, Ertuğrul Bey.
May our peace be eternal, Ertuğrul Bey.
God willing, Prince Theodor.
Please.
Farewell, Prince Theodor.
Then what happened, Grandmother?
That's all for now.
Your father can tell you the rest
after the council...
tonight.
Am I going to the council?
Of course, a brave bey like you.
You deserve to be there.
Really, Grandmother?
Am I invited as a bey?
Of course, son. It was time.
Everyone wants to see you there as a bey.
I'm a bey too.
I'll go to the council.
I'll scare the evil men.
I'll help the poor fellows.
I'll be a brave bey like my father.
God willing, son.
He's really happy, Mother Hayme.
May God always keep him happy.
May his fate be good.
May they ever be happy.
Amen.
Since the Prince of Nicaea came himself,
they must be in trouble, my Bey.
Brother,
the Emperor has no governors left.
So, he sent his own son,
what choice did he have?
They're scared of the Mongols, Bamsı.
They know that if we're not in Anatolia,
Mongols will ride unopposed
and destroy them easily.
That's why they want peace.
Prince Theodor was serious about peace,
my Bey.
Normally, they shouldn't dare break it
until the Mongols are taken care of,
my Bey.
I think the same, Artuk Bey.
The Prince assured me.
But, just in case.
Let's stay vigilant.
All right, my Bey.
My Bey... The infidels are beaten
every time.
They know they can't fight us and win.
God willing, the Mongol devils
will understand that too.
Bamsı...
If the world wants peace and tranquility,
it should know that
it must not fight the Turks.
Once the Turk is angry,
they all know what will happen.
Rest assured.
-Yes, my Bey.
-Indeed.
My Bey, everyone is working hard
for migration.
Good.
Be with them, Turgut.
So, you can help them when needed.
All right, my Bey.
-Thanks, brothers.
-Excuse us.
You were a bird of prey.
Now you're a scared sparrow, Ulu Kam.
News from Karacahisar, Noyan.
What happened?
Speak.
Ertuğrul's alps...
attacked the tannery...
and killed everyone.
How?
How did Ertuğrul know?
And Alangoya?
Tell me! What happened to my sister?
She was--
Ertuğrul and his mother...
trapped her in their tent.
Ertuğrul!
Good day.
Come, brother. Let's see the situation.
Onur Bey.
-Çalık Bey.
-Bring that too!
Good day.
-Thanks, Turgut Bey.
-Welcome, Turgut Bey.
-Thank you.
-Good day.
It seems that...
the village is ready.
It is, my Bey.
Everything should be done before sundown.
Good, good.
All our cart-pulling animals look healthy.
They'll go fast in the mountains.
-Great.
-Mashallah.
Father, you're tired.
I brought you water.
Give it to Turgut Bey and Chief Alp Bamsı.
Oh... Thank you.
Thanks.
May you be healthy as this water.
May it relieve you, Chief Alp Bamsı.
Mashallah.
Do you want some, Turgut Bey?
-Thanks.
-Come on, dear.
Give water to the others too.
Mashallah.
So, do you need anything?
No, Chief Alp Bamsı.
The animals are enough.
They'll be enough for our load.
We're dismantling the tents.
We'll take care of them.
All right.
Let us know if you need anything.
-Take care.
-Thanks, my Bey.
Good day.
Our Frontier Bey, Ertuğrul Bey!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Please, beys.
In all 99 names of God...
he who created and filled
our hearts with faith.
Our council has started.
Amen.
You went to the Mongol Khan Ögedei
as a messenger
and came back alive, Ertuğrul Bey,
praise God.
And you took out the Mongol spies here.
Thank you, my Beys.
Ögedei Khan is dead.
We took out some Mongol spies among us.
But...
the Mongol threat is not over.
Since Ögedei Khan is dead,
the peace agreement with him
means nothing.
The Mongols will attack Anatolia again.
Just as we defeated all threats so far
by standing united,
God willing, we'll beat the Mongols too.
God willing.
We're on a new and holy path.
When, God willing, we settle in Söğüt,
we'll grow even larger.
God willing.
We escaped many troubles so far.
We fought many enemies.
Our path is not limited to Söğüt.
Just as we came here all the way
from our old homeland,
we will spread in the whole world
from Söğüt.
-God willing.
-God willing, my Bey.
It's said that horses are fast,
and the bard's tongue is talented.
Sing us something from our ancestors,
to entertain us, bard.
All right.
The Khan's tent is raised
The drums are playing
The enemy is crushed
Oh how they run away
Anger consumed me
I roared like a lion
I cut down the head Alp
Who can hold me back now
Alps fight bravely
Their swords are strong
They help each other
Their arrows don't miss
Anger consumed me
I roared like a lion
I cut down the head Alp
Who can hold me back now
Alangoya...
Did you see Ertuğrul?
I manipulated his honesty and honor
and got a place in his bazaar.
He trusts me.
I evet met his mother and wife
in their tent.
You took all that I held dear, Ertuğrul.
Now it's my turn.
Wait for me.
I'll come.
I'll bring dark spirits.
I'll end your line...
and I'll make myself a tent
with the skin of your children.
I will trample on their corpses.
Wait for me Ertuğrul.
Wait.
Chief Alp Bamsı.
You mentioned the Templars.
How did you beat them?
Gündüz Bey.
We were surrounded.
The Templar infidels were everywhere,
like trees,
but we were like fire.
With our steel-like faith
and our courage,
our strong wrists
and our armor-piercing swords,
we beat them all.
How did we come so far, Father?
When my father Suleyman Shah died,
we set off with those who believed in us.
That's how, Gündüz.
It was hard to leave your brothers, right?
Of course, Gündüz.
Of course.
Those were the most painful,
most difficult days of my life.
Father, you encountered many difficulties.
That's right, Gündüz.
But those were all tests.
We are on God's path,
so, God helped us in our hard days.
Thankfully, we managed to come here.
-Thankfully.
Tomorrow, the migration caravan
goes before us.
We'll visit the graveyard
and catch up with the caravan
at the Yellow Valley.
From there, we'll all get to Söğüt,
God willing.
-As you order, my Bey.
-Thank you, men.
Come now, Gündüz.
Time for bed.
As you order, my Bey.
Come on, alps.
Praise your name, God.
Son.
My Ertuğrul...
Do you think that scum Noyan
is gone for good?
Will he leave us?
Noyan will never give up.
He'll come again.
But this time with his army
to invade Anatolia.
What will we do?
We'll do whatever we did so far, mother.
Do no evil, and never bow to evil.
Even if he brings all the armies
of the world,
we either win...
or we die with honor, Mother.
We encountered many troubles.
We endured many calamities.
But the pain this scum caused
feels like it was yesterday.
I'm scared of seeing the same things.
And of him attacking our children.
Oh God.
Don't make us suffer those things again.
Rest assured, Mother.
If he comes...
he'll get what he deserves.
We'll take all the precautions at Söğüt.
I hope so, Ertuğrul.
Now, God willing, we'll migrate
to Söğüt.
We lost our loved ones
on this holy path.
My Suleyman Shah died.
We were separated from your brothers.
My Halime. My dear.
We buried her here.
We endured all this pain...
and never gave up.
It was all for this day.
I wish they could have seen this too.
The pain I feel for them burns my heart,
Mother.
But the holy path is full of tests.
The pain for our loved ones was a test.
We carried on, endured the pain,
with the help of God.
Our efforts were rewarded
with God's favor.
Now, Söğüt will be our home, Mother.
God willing, the flame we'll lit
in Söğüt with mercy and justice
will be carried everywhere in
the world by our children.
God willing, son.
I'll check on the children.
Farewell, son.
My Gündüz...
My first boy.
My Savcı...
Face white like milk...
eyes blue like the sky.
Go to sleep, son.
Sleep, son.
My Osman...
My promised son.
Brave like a lion.
Eyes like a wolf.
You were promised in holy dreams.
Took your name from my father,
Suleyman Shah.
You were born during the spring council.
God willing...
you'll grow up with Söğüt as your home.
At one side, may you have strong,
and brave warriors,
and at the other side,
angels saying prayers.
May armies follow you.
May you lead holy wars.
Oh son...
May you carry the fire of Söğüt...
from far east to far west.
May the seas and rivers be yours.
May the blue sky be your tent,
and the sun be your banner.
May your only goal be God's favor, son.
Mother...
My brothers and I miss you.
We miss your warmth.
Now we go to our new home.
Don't worry.
I'll look after my brothers
like a good big brother.
We'll come visit you.
You wanted us all to be great beys.
I swear, Mother.
We'll be beys worthy of you and Father.
Mother...
My Gündüz...
My brave son...
Come on...
Time to go.
Come.
Gündüz...
Oh dear.
Come.
My Halime...
My brave wife with beautiful eyes.
I miss you so much.
It burns me.
It's time to go to Söğüt, Halime.
It's time to light the flame at Söğüt,
that we dreamed of for such a long time.
Don't worry, Halime.
Rest in peace.
I'll raise our sons to be worthy
of their fathers' blood
and their mothers' milk.
Rest assured.
I loved you, Halime.
May God bless you.
May you rest in heaven.
I hope that God...
in the name of our Prophet,
unites us in the afterlife as well.
We prayed for our fallen and
watered their graves.
Well done.
Today, our cause...
is their legacy.
May God send them to heaven.
Amen.
May our unity prevail in Söğüt.
Amen, my Bey.
Come on.
Time to go.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun.
Welcome.
Thank you.
We, the Mongols...
are Tengri's punishment on Earth.
If the Turks had obeyed...
If they weren't so proud...
Tengri wouldn't send us against them.
Noyan, our flesh and blood are yours.
Yours!
Now...
We're going to invade Anatolia.
At last, the Turks will lose.
They'll pay for not obeying me, Noyan.
I know that you're loyal to me
until death.
But that's not enough.
Even if I rot in the Gobi Desert,
you won't give up.
You are my bravest commanders.
When we enter Anatolia,
The Turks will stand like a wall
against us.
But the strength of this wall
depends on the courage of its defenders.
First, we'll break their courage.
With our spies everywhere...
with the traps of our loyal men...
we'll paint Anatolia in blood.
We'll set the Turks against each other...
and we'll collect their heads
like pears from a tree.
The greatest happiness for a warrior
is to be victorious.
To track them down,
to beat them,
to take their goods and loved ones.
Then, we shall...
drink kumis on the Seljuks' broken table
and get drunk.
We'll celebrate our victory.
May the spirits be with us.
Noyan! Noyan!
You traveled on many hard roads.
You lost loved ones.
You lost alps in battle.
But, with unshaken determination...
and the faith in your heart,
you didn't give up.
You're dedicated to a holy cause.
You adopted God's cause,
and you hold it higher than anything else.
Now, you're about to have great conquests,
God willing.
My only wish from God is
that we can serve his cause
to gain his favor.
I'll try to bring justice, mercy and hope
everywhere on earth until my last breath.
Holy God says that:
"The ones who have believed,
emigrated and striven in the cause
of God...
it is those who are the attainers
of success."
God is merciful and forgiving.
You set off on God's path for jihad.
God willing, his favor will be upon you.
-God willing.
God willing.
I hope that...
you'll shine like the sun
in your new home...
and enlighten the world.
Now, time to say goodbye.
I'll go to Konya with my brothers.
We owe you.
You guided us.
You helped us escape the darkness.
I'll never forget your support and help.
We can't ever repay you.
We thank you.
God bless you.
Ertuğrul Bey.
You gave hope to the poor
and scared away the evil.
You protected the innocent.
Your goal is to serve God's cause.
Our cause is to serve God's servants.
Thank you.
Now, we go our separate ways.
But know that death is not goodbye.
There is no separation
for those who share one heart.
You'll always be in our hearts
and we'll pray for you.
Pray for this poor fellow.
Always.
I would love to hear your words again.
Farewell, son.
Thank you.
Gündüz... Son...
You grew up into a man.
You aren't Gündüz the baby,
but Gündüz Bey.
You have a duty too.
To look after your two brothers...
make them ride and swing a sword.
Make them brave beys like yourself.
Brothers are like arrows.
They're stronger when together.
I hope you'll be worthy of your father.
I won't forget your lessons, sir.
I'll be a good big brother to them.
We'll be worthy of our father.
I hope so.
Give us your blessing, sir.
You have it, son.
You have it.
God help you, alps.
God protect you.
-Thank you, sir.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Come on, alps.
We can't keep them waiting.
We have to go now.
Come on, men!
Our way is the way to holy war.
We won't stop until our horses
reach the horizon,
and until we spread the justice of God
from the east to the west.
Our destination is,
the seven climates,
all the seas and rivers.
Our road is to the holiest goal,
it is the Red Apple.
Bismillahirahmanirrahim.
"Surely, we have given you
a conquest.
That God may forgive you
for what preceded of your sin
and what will follow
and complete His favor upon you.
and guide you to a straight path.
And that God may aid you
with a mighty victory.
It is He who sent down tranquility
into the hearts of the believers.
He fills their hearts with faith
and makes them peaceful.
To God belong the soldiers
of the heavens and the earth,
and God is all knowing.
And God is Wise.
He may admit
the believing men and the believing women
to gardens beneath which rivers flow.
Those believers can go to heaven
and stay there forever
because God cleanses their hearts.
Before God, it is such a joy
to have this opportunity.
All Episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net