Episode 110 will start after 12:05 min.
Günalp Bey!
Sooner or later, you'll pay
for what you're doing.
You're signing your own death sentence
by breaking the hearts of innocents,
and hanging them
in the castle they conquered.
We're here today...
to punish the traitors
responsible for taking our sultan's life.
Their punishment won't stop here.
They will turn in their graves with
the guilt of killing our sultan...
while he was on his way to war.
As for the tribes they leave behind,
if they rebel against our state...
I won't hesitate to mete out
the same punishment.
You'll pay for this,
you and the one who pulls your strings,
Sadettin.
With God's help.
Günalp Bey, if one of us dies, a thousand
of us will rise up in his stead.
You'll never succeed in what you're doing.
I won't allow anyone
to rebel against our state.
Go to hell.
-Sungur Bey!
Who did that?
Suleyman Shah's son, Ertuğrul.
-Our Ertuğrul Bey!
-Ertuğrul Bey!
My Bey.
Ertuğrul.
Despite the palace being
taken over by snakes and rats,
my innocence was proven to all.
Sultan Giyaseddin Keyhusrev's
verdict is that
my brothers and I are innocent.
Now...
remove the rope you've put around
the necks of my brave men, Günalp Bey.
I've got a score to settle with you
and the cowards who ordered
the deaths of my brave men.
It was Sultan Alaeddin's orders
that Günalp Bey should be
sent to Karacahisar
to ensure the duties of his margrave
were carried out properly.
Günalp Bey is a valued servant
who fought many battles
by your late father's side.
When we leave for Amid,
you can rely upon him
to keep our western borders secure.
Ertuğrul Bey is innocent,
you know that as well as I.
My father died of old age.
That is what everyone will be told.
Fine.
Ertuğrul Bey will continue to
be the margrave of our western borders,
in line with my father's final order.
My Sultan!
I'm glad to hear Ertuğrul has been
judged innocent, of course I am.
But we obviously run the risk
of him swimming against the current
and causing problems while you are away.
Sehzade Kilicarslan is still alive.
Given those circumstances, we can't
be sure what Ertuğrul Bey might do.
-You should be cautious, my Sultan.
-Enough!
None of you have the authority
to have my father's orders withdrawn.
I trust Ertuğrul completely.
He keeps his position.
Günalp Bey will swear loyalty
to Ertuğrul Bey and serve him.
Those are my orders.
Understood?
As for my brother, Kilicarslan.
He and his mother will be allowed
to live in peace in Ankara Castle.
I don't want anything to happen to them.
If it does,
you'll be the first to pay for it.
They'll kill us just like
they killed my father, Mother.
You are Alaeddin Keykubat's son,
Kilicarslan.
You will not allow anyone to trample
over your father's will or our pride.
We must escape first, Mother.
There are still soldiers
loyal to their state
who are ready to lay down their
lives for you and for your father's will.
When the time comes,
they'll fight that demon Altun Aba
and his soldiers while you escape.
-They'll have a horse ready for you.
-What about you?
My son, my Kilicarslan.
It was your father's wish
that you took the throne to ensure
the Turk tribes and Islam survive.
Never forget that the future
of the state depends on you.
Run and fight for your rights.
Your father's soul
cannot rest until you do.
You went too far, Günalp Bey.
You know you'll have to pay for it.
I was ordered to kill you
and the other Beys
in your council, Ertuğrul Bey.
Insidiously...
you stole into the castle I conquered.
Worse still, you took my position here.
Why did you dare do that, Günalp Bey?
Answer me.
I was doing as I should,
I was carrying out my duty.
And what of Artuk Bey, Turgut Bey,
Bamsı Alp, and my brother Sungurtekin?
Why did you try to have them hanged?
Your brother Sungurtekin
broke into the castle
and attempted to free
the convicted prisoners.
And were my Beys convicted of a crime?
What else could Sungurtekin Bey have done
to prevent you killing innocent people?
How dare you attempt,
on the word of the Emir,
to kill heroic men serving their state.
Is Emir Sadettin our sultan?
Who is he to order the deaths
of men loyal to their state?
Is Altun Aba the judge?
He acts like the spokesman of sharia law,
with you as his executioner.
Don't you understand that I was only
carrying out my orders, Ertuğrul Bey?
You're either a traitor who rented
his weapon to Emir Sadettin
or you're a pathetic person
who's blinded by loyalty to his state.
Tell me...
which is it, Günalp Bey?
Enough, Ertuğrul Bey. Know your limits.
You have been forgiven by our sultan
on the basis of İbn-i Arabi's guarantee.
For my part, this matter is at an end.
The ones who accused me
of taking our sultan's life
know now that I'm innocent.
Good.
The loyalty my Beys and I have
for our state is obvious,
as is our innocence.
So...
your presence here
is no longer required, Günalp Bey.
Now... leave my castle immediately,
and take your soldiers with you.
It's not in your power
to dismiss me and my soldiers
from our roles
at Karacahisar Castle, Ertuğrul Bey.
Are you asking me to hand
the castle I conquered over to you?
Not at all.
I neither have the right
nor would I dare to ask that.
Emir Sadettin and Atabey Altun Aba's order
became obsolete the moment
you were proven innocent.
However...
the final orders of our late
Sultan Alaeddin must be followed...
by you and I both.
What are you saying, Günalp Bey?
Our late Sultan Alaeddin sent
these orders to me...
when I was at Ahlat Castle.
He ordered me and my
soldiers to Karacahisar Castle
to serve under your command.
If you are as loyal to our late sultan
as you say you are...
you have no choice but to obey that order.
I'll gladly follow... our sultan's order.
I'll agree to you remaining here,
Günalp Bey.
However...
if I see any sign of disloyalty
or if you fail to obey my orders,
know that I will destroy you.
Allahu Akbar.
Semi Allahu limen hamideh.
Esselamu aleykum ve rahmetullah.
Sir...
what a beautiful state of being this is.
I've never...
felt this level of true peace and ease...
in my life before.
When I'm praying...
it feels like...
my soul is cleansed.
I couldn't stop the tears
falling from my eyes.
The clear water that flows
from the springs...
is the representation of cleanliness.
It cleans people of dirt, cleans
the flowers and meadows of dust.
The tears which fall from our eyes
waters the garden in our hearts.
It nurtures the flowers in our hearts.
You should be happy
to shed tears for God.
Your tears show the peace
you have achieved in your soul.
Sir...
you opened a door for me.
I'm so grateful for that.
But...
I'm curious about
the doors that will follow.
God is the one who opens doors, son.
We are only the cause.
If you hadn't asked for our help...
we couldn't have given it to you.
Holy God orders in the Qur'an...
"If a community won't change
their morals, God won't change them."
If God wishes evil on a community...
there's no way to escape it.
There's no one to help them, except God.
You should be happy
to have come to this realization.
That is God's gift to you, son.
God...
has given me great gifts
even though I don't deserve it.
I feel guilty.
I'd like to give my all.
I want to...
know our religion
and the Qur'an much better.
-Please help me.
-Of course, son.
If you want to learn about
our religion and the Qur'an...
first you have to get to know
our Prophet, Muhammad.
One day, our Mother Ayse
was asked about our Prophet's morals.
And she replied,
"His morals are the Qur'an."
Our Prophet set us an example
by living the Qur'an.
God states in the Qur'an,
"The Messenger of God
is an excellent model
for those of you who put your hope in God
and the Last Day
and remember Him often."
Ahmet, my son,
it is our duty to get to know
that graceful messenger...
and apply what we learn
from him to our lives.
He's such a precious guide that...
in every moment of his life...
there are treasures that we
can adapt to our own lives.
Sir...
I'd like to know this blessed person more,
understand him,
-and follow where he leads.
-Amen.
Sir...
your words warm my heart
and I want to hear more of them.
But...
if I am to carry out the duty Ertuğrul Bey
gave to me, I must begin my journey.
May God let our paths cross soon so that
I may listen to your warm words again.
We are on the same road, son.
Always follow God's path.
Your journey will be hard.
But don't forget that the reward
for this journey is enormous.
Now go on your way to fight your case.
We are on your side
with an army of prayers.
Thank you, sir. May God bless you.
-May God bless you, sir.
-Godspeed, son.
Thank you, sir.
-Brother.
-My brother.
Praise be!
Brother Gundogdu will go
on the Amid expedition with Dündar Bey.
But he said it'd be me facing
the real battle, not him.
He said being by Ertuğrul's side is more
difficult than challenging the Crusaders.
He was right.
There won't be a mountain top without
smoke and a brave man without thunder.
We came into this world to run towards
trouble with our swords unsheathed.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
-Good to see you.
-And you, my Bey.
Thank you.
Good to see you as well!
-Thank you, my Bey.
-Praise be!
Good to see you.
My Bey, you got there just in time.
-Just in time.
-Praise be!
You put Günalp Bey in his place.
I believe Günalp Bey's
intentions were honorable.
But... his loyalty to that dog Sadettin
might cause problems
for us in the future.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, my Bey.
I entrust the castle first to God
and then to you.
Sadettin thrust Günalp Bey
in here like a rusty dagger.
We'll make sure Günalp Bey acts
according to our commands
not Sadettin's provocations.
My Bey, if this man is all about
the survival of the state,
it could make things
more difficult for us.
I haven't come here only to kiss
my mother's hand, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll stay by your side until we can
free our state from Sadettin's grip.
If we can't find some way
of overcoming that scoundrel...
he'll destroy the Kayis
and the rest of the Turk tribes.
-Know that I'm at your service.
-Thank you, brother.
I want to know everything Günalp Bey does.
Make sure he doesn't step out of line.
If he does, you know what to do.
-As you command, my Bey.
My Bey, where is Ahmet Alp?
So, he's following God's path
and is our brother now.
That's right. That's right, Bamsı.
He's following us with İbn-i Arabi.
When Arabi gets to the tribe...
Ahmet will be with Bilecik's governor.
He'll infiltrate them
and send us intelligence.
-May God help him, my Bey.
-Amen, Artuk Bey. Amen.
Amen.
-Bamsı!
-My Hafsa!
My Hafsa! My Hafsa!
Aslıhan.
Thank God.
Thank heaven.
Come in.
My Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey, thank you.
May God bless you, my Bey.
Thank you, Hatuns. Thank you.
Now, let's get back to the tribe.
There are things I want to tell you there.
Ertuğrul is a warrior.
-He's loyal to his state.
-We can't be sure of that, Bey.
I believe he has
good intentions, Aydogmus.
But he's stubborn.
He doesn't know that Emir Sadettin
is like a father to me.
He doesn't know his limits
and that bothers me.
The real problem is that his obstinacy
might prove a disaster for our state.
There's no doubt Ertuğrul Bey is loyal
to our sultan's brother,
Sehzade Kilicarslan.
It isn't only the Emir
who’s worried by that.
The whole palace is.
If that's the case...
I'll kill Ertuğrul Bey
with my own hands.
I lost my mother, my father
and my brothers in Sehzade's wars.
I won't lose my state too.
I want to know every step
Ertuğrul Bey takes.
I hear of it first...
then Emir Sadettin does.
Yes, my Bey.
Hell Warriors.
I've finally found you.
My God, help me in this difficult duty.
Hell Warriors!
That's Ares.
What are you doing here?
Pack up.
We're going to see Bilecik's governor.
What are you going to do
with Bilecik's governor?
I'm going to ask for his support
to get my revenge on Ertuğrul.
You went to Konya and ratted us out
to the Turk's sultan.
The great warrior Titan
died because of you.
You think a pathetic loser like you
could get his revenge on Ertuğrul?
I never sold out.
I was defeated but I didn't die.
Now, you follow me.
We'll get our revenge on those barbaric
Turks with the help of Bilecik's governor.
Did you hear him?
We're supposed to follow his orders.
First you must pay
for what you've done, Ares.
Hell Warriors... Attack.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm the governor!
A defeated, pathetic,
miserable former governor.
Let's take him to the cave.
I'm not finished with him.
We cannot allow Ertuğrul to get stronger
like he did under Sultan Alaeddin.
Günalp Bey is loyal to me.
He won't let that happen.
You tell me that he's an honest man.
What if he takes Ertuğrul Bey's side?
His aide Aydogmus is a dependable man.
I'll be the first one to hear of it
if Günalp makes a mistake.
I'll punish him myself.
Very good.
Giyaseddin knows everything
but pretends that he doesn't.
He wants everyone to believe that
his father died of natural causes.
He obviously knows us
better than we thought.
Don't you dare push his buttons, Sadettin.
Don't worry.
Ertuğrul's next target will be Söğüt.
If he takes Söğüt over too, he'll be
one step closer to a state of his own.
Do you think the letter of peace
you sent to Bilecik's Governor, Kritos
will resolve the matter?
I'll use the governor as a hammer,
and Günalp as the anvil.
Bilecik's governor is full of hate
because his son Angelos
was killed by Ertuğrul's alps.
We'll use that hate
to our full advantage.
This truce must put a stop to Ertuğrul.
This absolutely must end here.
BILECIK CASTLE
My God!
Help me get my revenge on the Turks
who sent my son's head to me
and fed his body to wild animals.
I'll avenge you eventually, son.
Enter!
Governor Kritos, a letter has
come for you from Emir Sadettin.
My prayers have been answered, Leo.
My prayers have been answered.
What does it say, sir?
Emir Sadettin...
wants to make a peace treaty with me
just like he did with Vasilius and Ares.
But what he really
wants is Ertuğrul's head.
And I'll give it to him.
It says they're prepared to give Söğüt
to us as a mark of their good will,
on the condition we keep paying
the taxes we paid to Alaeddin.
It makes sense for him to
want to cooperate with us
when Sultan Giyaseddin is getting
ready for the Amid war.
What about Ertuğrul?
What's going to happen to him?
I heard that he was found
innocent and got his position back.
Ertuğrul will never sit
at the same table as us.
It says I will be discussing
the peace treaty with Günalp Bey.
Ertuğrul won't let that happen.
He knows that too.
His intention is to
let me deal with Ertuğrul.
Neither the sultan nor the state
will support Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul is a lone wolf
and has been disowned by his state.
We all know what happens
to the lone wolf, Leo.
I'll take Söğüt first
and Ertuğrul's head second.
Sir...
Come, my girl.
Sir, whose is this blessed child?
This brave and blessed boy is your son.
He is Osman, Halime Hatun.
Many a valiant man
came and passed through these lands.
Osman will be one of the most blessed,
God willing.
Osman is an almighty plane tree, my girl.
His grandeur will surround the world.
His branches will reach the skies
and protect all humanity.
His roots will cross continents
and spread to all lands.
A brave man to come from his lineage...
will be the subject of...
our Prophet's hadith:
"Constantinople will surely be conquered.
The commander who conquers it...
is such a commander,
and the army, such an army."
Hopefully, sir.
Don't forget, my girl.
The mother makes a family.
She gathers everyone around her
and warms them.
Mother means home.
She feeds, accommodates, protects.
Our Lord commands...
"Heaven is beneath mothers' feet."
That is how sacred
the position of motherhood is.
You are lucky to be
the mother of such a blessed, brave child.
May God render you worthy of it.
Amen, sir. Amen.
Osman is entrusted first to God...
then to you.
Take him.
My Osman!
My brave one.
My glorious son.
My God...
Your wisdom is not to be questioned.
Thank you for granting me
such a blessed dream.
May it be for the good.
My God...
Just as you foretold in my dream,
grant me a blessed child.
Grant me the power to raise
this blessed child righteously.
My God.
Thank you.
Mother!
-Mother!
-Gündüz.
My father is back, Mother. He's back!
Your father?
God, one piece of good news after another.
My sons.
Thank God for giving you to me.
My brave boys.
Come on, Mother, come!
Let's go, Gündüz. Bismillah.
Gündüz. What is this?
My father is here, Grandmother.
Where?
-My son.
-Ertuğrul.
Mother.
My son!
Halime.
-Ertuğrul.
-Halime.
Welcome.
Glad to be here.
My God. He spared you for us.
You came with no hindrance.
Thank God for that.
Thank God, Mother.
Thanks to Ertuğrul Bey.
It's God's will, brother.
Gündüz.
My brave son.
Father.
Just look at my brave son.
Tell me,
did anything bad happen
while I was away from the village?
Who would dare do anything when Ertuğrul
Bey's son, Gündüz Alp, is here, my bey?
Good for you.
He even took me for the enemy
and drew his sword on me.
He has become a valiant alp.
Thank you, Sungur Bey.
My boy will follow in his father's
footsteps and become a bey, God willing.
-God willing.
Thank God.
I saw you together...
If only I'd see my Gündoğdu and Dündar...
What else would I want for?
You will see them too, Mother.
You will.
Hopefully, my son, hopefully.
Hopefully.
First with God's permission,
then with the efforts of our bey,
Ertuğrul, and our alps,
we raised our flags at the castle.
Good.
As a castle commander,
I know how hard it is to both conquer
and manage a castle.
Ertuğrul Bey turned out to be
stronger than I thought.
How did you become a castle commander,
Günalp Bey?
Commanding a castle...
Commanding is my ancestral heritage.
Were they commanders as well?
In the struggle for the throne among
Sultan Alaeddin and Sultan İzzettin,
we took Sultan Alaeddin's side.
We paid a heavy price for that.
My father.
My mother.
My siblings.
They were all killed.
How did you survive?
May God grant him long life...
Ameer Sadettin saved me.
He took me in and raised me.
And I never once
swayed from my loyalty to our state
and to him.
From this day forth to the end of my days
I will never sway in my loyalty
to our state, our sultan,
and Ameer Sadettin.
Thank God.
We did away with the traitors' traps
and are together once again.
May God render our prosperity eternal.
Amen.
Our state has now been overrun
by jackals...
The unworthy have taken command.
Therefore...
we need to migrate to Söğüt, the land
our late Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad gave us.
However you see fit, my bey.
So long as we are all together.
With God's help,
we will defeat traitors anywhere.
With God's help.
But, of course,
it won't be easy to make Söğüt our land.
Even though our sultan conquered it
and imposed taxes on it,
it's still under the control of
the Tekfur of Bilecik.
The Tekfur of Bilecik
will also want to avenge his son.
I don't know why
but that makes my palms itch.
And what a palms they are!
Thank you, Turgut Bey.
We will scratch them together,
side by side.
If God permits, we will take by force
the lands that are rightfully ours.
We are with you as the Cavdar Tribe
until the last drop of our blood, my bey.
Thank you.
We are capable of claiming what is ours
with our own swords, with God's help.
With God's help.
With God's help, my bey.
Good for you.
Hatuns...
Start preparations for migration
as soon as possible.
Yes, my bey.
What is it, esteemed Tekfur?
We crushed you.
Is that how you plan to join us?
You think you have crushed me?
I am stronger than you,
even in this state.
Look what he's babbling.
We must've hit you too hard in the head.
You've lost it.
If you have the courage...
come fight me one on one.
I guess you won't be able to take the pain
and want to die right away.
Kill me if you can.
But be brave enough to fight on your own.
Not with all your men.
Then we'll see how strong you are.
Then we'll see how brave you are.
Untie him.
Get up, it's time for fun.
Courage, you say...
You'll regret it.
You are all under my command
until we rid these lands of the Turks.
Do you want vengeance from the Turks?
Yes!
Do you want to make them pay for Titan?
Revenge!
Blood!
Gather your things.
We go to the Tekfur of Bilecik.
Artuk Bey. Someone is here.
He wants to talk to you in private.
Who is it? Do you know him?
We don't, my bey.
We looked at his outfit. He is no alp.
And he is not a civilian either.
Let him in.
Where does the road lead?
To the Red Apple.
With greetings from my governor
to Ertuğrul Bey.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Shahzade Kılıçarslan
and his mother Melike Hatun
are being taken to the Castle of Ankara
by Altun Aba.
We think they will be slaughtered.
As for the sultan's will
and the state's prosperity,
an important mission
falls to Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey should get moving
before it's too late.
What is it, Artuk Bey?
Dumrul, I need to ride to the village
right away.
You stay here. Keep an eye on Günalp Bey.
Watch his every move.
Yes, my bey.
Door!
Mother!
Permission to enter, my bey.
Come in.
Artuk Bey secretly left the castle,
my bey.
I believe he's heading for
the Kayi village.
He must be going to Ertuğrul Bey.
They are up to something.
Get my horse ready. We ride.
We will follow Artuk Bey.
Yes, my bey.
Door!
My bey...
I keep thinking but...
I can't wrap my head around
this migration business.
What would we do there?
We've been through so much
on these lands
throughout the years.
How can we move there now,
leaving behind this place
that we worked so hard to get?
And the Byzantine infidels
won't leave us alone there.
I understand your concern.
But don't you worry.
We have gained many a victory,
crossing plains and great mountains.
With God's help, we know how to
make a new home on the land of our sultan.
If need be,
we will even take on the emperor.
Turgut...
You know well that since the sultan died
there isn't anyone left
to support us as before.
Ameer Sadettin has taken over the state.
He holds a grudge not only against...
our Ertuğrul Bey but you and me.
Do you think it would be wise
for our bey, Ertuğrul, to reconsider?
Aslıhan.
If Ertuğrul Bey made a decision,
he would have reached it
by splitting hairs.
Don't worry.
Let alone Ameer Sadettin...
We will do away with those bastards
even if they're united.
As long as we are one,
nobody can break us,
with God's permission.
Halime...
Welcome, Ertuğrul.
Happy to be here.
Halime...
Your eyes shine somewhat differently.
Your face smiles somewhat differently.
What is behind this?
Ertuğrul.
I've been feeling it for some time.
Now that...
I've been to the midwives, I am sure.
Midwives?
Are you...?
I'm with child, Ertuğrul.
If it's a boy,
I carry our son Osman in my womb.
Osman?
Ertuğrul, don't do something crazy.
-Ertuğrul!
-Oh, God!
Ertuğrul...
Halime...
My Halime.
Our great Oğuz ancestors
had heralded this in my dreams.
Our Osman arrives, my Halime.
Osman...
He entered my dreams too, Ertuğrul.
Ibn Al Arabi gave him to me to hold.
He said that he would be a brave man
that conquers worlds.
Great God.
Thank you, my God.
Thank you.
May our dreams bode well.
May our Osman be born in our new land
and shine like a sun upon us.
God willing.
Permission to enter, Son.
Ertuğrul.
Come, Mother. Come.
What is it, Son?
You are shaking the ground.
We are having a baby, Mother.
We are having a baby.
-Our Osman comes, God willing.
-My God...
My God, thank you.
I'd die for a rejoiceful night like this.
My brave son...
Oh, my brave...
Mother...
My doe-eyed girl...
My beautiful bride.
Thank God.
May it be for the good, my daughter.
Thank you, Mother. Thank you.
My brave son.
May God give you a great son...
who will carry on your ancestral name.
Hopefully, Mother. Hopefully.
It is my command, Mother.
In honor of this great news,
may sheep and goats on our land be
cut and distributed to the people.
May the hungry be fed.
May the naked be clothed.
May the orphans be given alms.
May debts of the indebted be closed.
And God willing, may we hold
a great celebration in no time.
May there be mountains of meat
and streams of buttermilk...
at the event.
May God always keep you above us, my son.
As you wish, my son.
I'll go.
Halime...
Come...
Let's perform ablution with pure water
and perform prayers of thankfulness.
As you wish, my bey.
Thank you, God.
Thank you, my brave boy.
Permission to enter, my bey.
Come in, Abdur Rahman.
Artuk Bey has arrived, my bey.
Let him in.
What is it, Artuk Bey?
Speak, Artuk Bey.
A messenger came
from the white-bearded ones.
He brought this letter.
What does it say, Ertuğrul Bey?
They are going to slaughter
Shahzade Kılıçarslan and his mother.
Atabey Altun Aba is their leader.
You know I will go on a campaign tomorrow
with my army, Ertuğrul.
You are the closest witness
that there is treachery in my palace.
I have to think of my state’s perpetuity
after I die.
That's why I added to my will
the shahzade I want to take my place.
In my will,
I commanded Shahzade Kılıçarslan,
son of Melike Hatun,
to replace me as sultan.
Appointing Shahzade Kılıçarslan
as your heir
will not only strengthen
our relations with the Ayyubids,
but also allow us
to form a stronger alliance
with the Muslim world against the Mongols.
I'm telling you about my will so that
in the event that...
there is a struggle among my sons
for the throne,
I want you to pick a side.
My side is always evident, my sultan.
Know that I say this
not with my tongue, but with my heart.
When that day comes,
no matter what the outcome,
I would like you to take your place
next to Shahzade Kılıçarslan
and fight together with all
the Turk tribes under your Beyhood.
May God protect us
from such a struggle for the throne
and the cruelty of any enemy that may
use it to its advantage, my sultan.
Amen.
They are going to slaughter
Shahzade Kılıçarslan and his mother.
I can't let that happen.
We can't go to the Ankara Castle
and get them out, my bey.
We will catch up with them
before they reach the Ankara Castle.
If they don't slaughter them
before they get to the castle.
What will you do, my bey?
Tell the alps to get ready immediately.
Turgut and Bamsi
will ride with me as well.
Ertuğrul Bey, I found out
why Günalp Bey is so loyal to Köpek.
You were right. His intentions are pure.
His father was castle commander Tayı Bey.
May he rest in peace.
I remember they fought
together with my father.
He was a valiant man, loyal to his state.
My bey. He was slaughtered
together with his wife
for his loyalty to Sultan Alaeddin.
Köpek took him in and raised him.
That is why he is so loyal to Köpek.
It's evident
he does not know of Köpek's treachery.
Either he will find out, Artuk Bey,
or he will lose his head for it.
You do what is necessary.
As you wish, my bey.
Everything's ready sir.
Günalp Bey's presents are on the horses.
Good.
Let's not wait then.
The sooner we have an agreement,
the sooner we take
Söğüt and Ertuğrul's lives.
Sir, Tekfur Ares is here.
He wants to see you.
Let him in.
Why is he here?
Because he has no other place to go.
I thought you were in Konya?
Yes.
I was.
You're defeated,
at least die with your honor.
But you've been a coward
and told the Turks everything you know.
Don't worry, Kritos.
My words only helped
set the Turks at odds.
And then I escaped.
Why did you come here?
Ertuğrul.
I came here to finish what you started.
He is not only my enemy,
he is an enemy of all of us.
We can only defeat him if we unite.
I don't need you to defeat him.
I know Ertuğrul
and the tents most faithful to him.
You have been defeated
even though you know him well?
You lost the castle
that the Empire has had for so long.
Our holy Empire
had Constantinople for ages
and they lost it to the Latin Empire.
But this doesn't mean we give up
and don't take it back.
I don't want to hear it, Ares.
I don't want you near me.
I always win.
I don't walk alongside losers.
As you wish, Kritos.
I am here
as the leader of hell warriors.
Still, I'll fight with the Turks
without you.
But if we unite...
then we can take
revenge for both Karacahisar and your son.
Fine.
But you'll have no authority.
I let you fight those savages
only under my command.
I accept anything to have my revenge
on Ertuğrul and the Turks.
Agreed.
Now, we're heading to
Karacahisar Castle, the one you lost.
To Karacahisar?
Why?
To make peace.
And you stay here.
Join my soldiers and begin your duty.
Let's go.
What is it, Dumrul?
Bey, I followed Günalp Bey.
First, he was after you
and now he's after Ertuğrul Bey.
What does this man want?
Alps! Let us go forth now!
Dumrul, you come with us too.
As you command, bey.
Don't you have any
political decency, Günalp Bey?
Going after your frontiersman? Really?
Know your place, Artuk Bey.
And stay out of it.
Move aside or I'll ride you down.
I won't let you go.
Allah is infinite!
Allah is the god!
Günalp Bey.
I don't know what's going on in your head,
but if your intent is
to ambush Ertuğrul Bey,
don't even try.
The tracks you followed to get here
don't belong to Ertuğrul Bey.
Those were ours.
These tracks will not take you to him.
If you confront me again...
I'll ride you down.
Apparently, Ertuğrul's heading to Ankara.
We have to find out why.
Emir Sadettin is supposed to meet us
at the caravansary.
-We're going there now.
-As you command, bey.
We'll stop at the fork in the road.
Kılıçarslan, it is time, my son.
You'll escape when we stop.
I won't leave you, mother.
-Come with me.
-Don't worry about me, son.
I sacrifice myself for you and our state.
Just, don't fall into the hands
of these demons.
I am not useful to them.
They want your life, not mine.
They are after you.
I'll wait for you to be sultan
in Ankara Castle where you will save me.
-Mother, I can't leave you.
-Kılıçarslan...
This ring with the Oghuz insignia on it,
three arrows and a bow,
is inherited from your ancestor
Alaeddin Kayqubad.
This is the state ring.
Now it is your destiny.
Turk tents will regard you as the state.
You'll save this
magnificent state
from the hands of Mahperi, Sadettin Köpek
and Altun Aba.
You'll live for our state.
Beys...
From now on,
our new home will be Söğüt,
which Alaeddin Kayqubad granted us
as our right.
Therefore,
all the tents need to start preparations.
Hayme Hatun,
it's not been long since we moved here
under the order of Ertuğrul Bey,
Now you're talking about emigration again.
We understand now,
the value of where we'd settled before.
Ertuğrul Bey wants us to settle in Söğüt.
This is a joint decision of Ertuğrul Bey
and Turgut Bey.
For the peace in our tents,
emigration is necessary.
Respect their decision.
It's the backyard of heathen Byzantine.
They prey on us.
Hayme Ana, Halime Hatun.
The state doesn't stand by us anymore,
like it used to.
You know it well.
What are you saying, Aslıhan?
If we go under Byzantine's noses,
they will prey on us.
I'm afraid to be left alone
while struggling with those heathens.
Aslıhan Hatun...
If we stand united...
and listen to our beys,
no one can shatter us.
Ertuğrul Bey and Turgut Bey's decision
is final.
No need to extend the conversation.
Preparations will start immediately.
If anyone has...
something to say...
say it to Ertuğrul Bey when he is back.
Do you need anything, Melike Hatun?
Stay away. We don't want anything.
-I kindly ask...
-Stay away Altun Aba.
Back off.
Soon, very soon.
You just wait.
Go to your place.
Now, son. It is time.
Give your blessing, Mother.
I do, my son.
I do, my Sultan.
Now, go!
Go!
The Prince is running!
Run, Sultan, run!
-Run!
-Catch him, quick!
Catch him now!
Let go of me!
Kill these dogs!
Get off! Bastards!
Murderer!
I said, get off!
Catch the Prince now!
Quick!
Let go of me!
Traitors!
My brave child Günalp!
Your Highness...
Sultan has decided
that Ertuğrul is not guilty.
That is unfortunate, Günalp.
When he saw the edict
that Sultan Alaeddin sent before he died
he didn't find the courage to stand up
to my authority in the castle.
I settled in the castle with my soldiers.
Well done. Wise choice.
You could only convince Ertuğrul
with Sultan Alaeddin's edict.
But, Your Highness,
I want to ask something.
If Ertuğrul is that loyal
to our Sultan...
why do we still doubt him?
Günalp...
Ertuğrul is a wolf in sheep's clothing.
Don't believe his words.
Like he deceived Sultan Alaeddin
now he succeeds to deceive
Sultan Gıyaseddin.
Even if he deceived our Sultan,
how come he could deceive
His Highness Ibn Al Arabi?
I believe that holy man
has the power to read
the best hypocrite’s face.
Günalp,
do you know the reason why Ertuğrul
rushed to Ankara?
Because he learned that
Prince Kılıçarslan and his mother
exiled to Ankara Castle.
What are you saying, Your Highness?
I think Ertuğrul is planning an uprising
against the Sultan Gıyaseddin.
I heard that
he is in collaboration with
rebel Turkmen beys,
even with wild Babai clans.
How is that possible?
Why do you think
his brother Sungurtekin
left his tent and went?
It is clear that he is in touch with
disorderly Turkmen clans
in Malatya, Kefersud and Amasya.
Not just Sungurtekin,
brother Gündoğdu and Dündar Bey
are also in the loop.
Then,
it is time to take Ertuğrul's head.
Your Highness,
allow me to come with you.
I'll give you
a more important task, Günalp.
Tekfur Kritos. He's coming to Karacahisar.
In the name of the state I want you
to run the peace talks with him.
My directions are in this letter.
Strictly follow them.
Now, go back to the castle immediately.
Your Highness, I--
I'll take care of Ertuğrul's head.
Now you will fulfill this grand duty
that our state assigned to you.
At your command.
If you'll excuse me.
Günalp...
Our Sultan is about to start
this great voyage.
I know you'll do what is needed
considering this significant treaty.
Don't worry.
We found Altun Aba, Your Highness.
We need to get there before Ertuğrul.
We should leave right now.
Aslıhan, daughter.
Tell me.
What makes you worry
about this emigration thing?
The state is surrounded
by the lowest of the low, Hayme Ana.
You saw what they did to Ertuğrul Bey.
Turgut, Bamsi, Sungur Bey, Artuk Bey...
They were almost put to death
right in front of our eyes.
Neither the state, nor the Sultan
stands by us.
Aslıhan...
There were times
our beys overcame hardships
without our Sultan standing by us.
Not just that, they overcame everything
with their swords and fire in their heart.
And we do again now.
Why do you have so little faith?
This time is not like before, Halime.
Emir Sadettin became very strong.
We are strong too
but how do we fight with everyone?
Daughter, this is not you speaking.
Being a woman, you governed
the Cavdar Tent for a long time.
You spoke you mind amongst the men.
What is the problem now?
Why are you so worried?
I'm not worried for myself.
I'm thinking of our tents.
We should not put ourselves at risk.
I am not a coward,
I'm being cautious.
If you think about it,
you'll see I'm right.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Halime.
Traitors!
Leave me alone!
The game is over, Prince.
The law orders me to kill you
without bloodshed,
and this is my first
and last favor to you.
Treasonous bastards!
You won't get away with it!
I said, leave me alone!
Leave me alone!
Your father is dead!
Your mother will soon be dead.
Who will take your revenge?
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah!
Attack!
Attack, my brave men!
Fight for the state! Save the Prince.
-Allah is infinite!
Allah is the god!
My Prince!
My Prince.
Stay strong, my Prince.
Hang on, we'll save you. Hang on!
Abdur Rahman! You take care of my Prince.
Look after his wound! Dress his wound!
Brother, we should go after
Atabey Altun Aba.
-As you command, bey.
-Come.
Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey...
I knew you would spare me.
I knew you would have mercy
for the woman you married.
Our justice, our mercy
is for Allah, Marya.
We embraced you,
yet you betrayed us.
Stabbed us in the back.
You're no longer my wife, Marya.
I divorced you.
Artuk Bey.
Maybe, I'm carrying your child.
Why would you kill me
without considering this?
That's why you wait
in this dungeon, Marya.
Otherwise, I would have killed you
long ago.
Artuk Bey...
Show your kindness and forgive me, please!
I'm going to go mad here.
You should have thought before you acted.
You'll stay here for now.
The verdict will be made in due time.
Artuk Bey, please!
Artuk Bey, forgive me.
Please!
Please forgive me!
Please, Artuk Bey!
Artuk Bey, forgive me please!
Artuk Bey, show some mercy!
Artuk Bey, please, don't!
Forgive me, please!
Artuk Bey please!
Artuk Bey!
Artuk Bey, please have mercy!
Artuk Bey, please!
Please forgive me!
Please, Artuk Bey.
I got your son.
That skunk Ertuğrul appeared!
He couldn't save him.
I killed him!
Traitor!
Murderer!
How could you!
I'll kill you, too!
Die!
Die! Go with your son!
Sadettin...
I'm sorry to hear of what happened.
You came just in time, Sadettin.
I see you killed Melike Sultan.
Where is the Prince?
He ran into the woods.
I caught him.
I was about to strangle him,
Ertuğrul came to his rescue.
Ertuğrul?
Did he save the Prince?
He wounded me with an arrow.
But couldn't save the Prince
from my dagger.
Good.
So, the Prince is dead.
The Prince is dead.
Come. We’ll look at your wound.
Come.
This won't kill you,
but will make your life miserable.
It's over Sadettin.
The state...
is under our heel.
Now we can amend it as we wish.
What are you doing, Sadettin?
Take this arrow out!
We'll amend the state, Altun Aba.
But you won't be here.
This state belongs to Emir Sadettin.
I don't want a partner to my state
and my secret.
I'll ravage you one by one.
That's the promise of Sultan Sadettin.
Follow me.
"This is a death warrant for Altun Aba...
who defied Sultan Gıyaseddin's orders....
and killed Prince Kılıçarslan
and his mother."
Emir Sadettin Köpek.
Why would he do that?
That bastard wants to save himself
from the consequences of his crimes.
Not only that, Turgut.
He kills his enemies one by one.
Now, it is...
Sultan Gıyaseddin and his mother's turn.
Bey, what does this bastard want?
What is he planning by killing the state's
sultans and princes one by one?
It looks like...
he wants to be...
the new sultan.
If we can't stop this,
no one can, Bamsi.
Mother.
I am worrying about Aslıhan.
I hope her being anxious about
migrating to Söğüt
won't cause any dispute
between the tribes.
My dear.
Aslıhan has made a lot of sacrifices
for her tribe.
She didn't let anybody
take her tribe from her.
Now she worries for us
to get in a quandary
at Söğüt, because of Emir Sadettin.
And she is right about that.
But she is exaggerating.
Mother, I know she has been through a lot.
That traitor Emir Sadettin
did very bad things to her.
They have been poisoned,
and Turgut almost got hanged.
Aslıhan has every right to worry.
You are right, my dear.
But we are not here just to sleep
in the tent.
We have a duty.
We have a mission.
And there is no place for fear
on this road.
We have strengthened our tribes
by uniting them.
We can't give up now
because of Emir Sadettin.
You should talk to her.
You should relieve her.
She should know that
this road is not for those who fear
new starts.
This road...
is for those...
who can run through fire with a sword.
Shahzade.
Shahzade, wake up.
Hang on. How is he?
-The prince is badly hurt, Bey.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
Hang on, Prince.
You will live.
You will become Sultan.
This...
is an heirloom from my ancestor
Alaeddin Kayqubad.
It is a state ring.
They've killed my father, and me.
All the Turk tribes should gather
around someone worthy.
Someone worthy should wear the state ring.
Prince!
Send the prince's body
to the palace, Turgut.
Let Sultan Gıyaseddin see
what they did to his brother.
Many princes...
have been tragically killed
in the struggle for power.
How could they do this?
They have killed this young prince, Bey.
What kind of state is this?
They also broke
our millennia-old traditions.
They've killed a member of the dynasty.
This means bad luck for the state.
For me,
the state...
is over now.
Come on.
Lift the prince.
This is not only a prince's body,
but also the massacred future
of a mighty state.
-Artuk Bey.
-What is it?
The governor of Bilecik is here to visit.
He is talking to Günalp Bey.
The governor of Bilecik?
What is he doing here?
What is he talking to Günalp Bey about?
What are they planning to do?
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
Bey.
You look so tired.
I made some ayran for you.
Drink.
Thank you, Aslıhan.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
Turgut.
We've just settled with the Kayi.
It took us a very long time
to organize things here.
I say let's discuss it with the bey,
and talk him out of the migration.
Aslıhan.
We have talked about this.
Do not try anymore.
Let's drop the subject.
I am considering what's best
for our tribe.
Why don't you understand?
Now that the sultan is dead,
Ertuğrul Bey is all alone.
Emir Sadettin has power now.
How can we deal with him?
And do you think it is over
when you say let's drop the subject?
Aslıhan!
Know your place.
How many more times
will I explain it to you?
Turgut.
We have peace here, in our tribe.
Everything in the garden is rosy here.
We will always be sitting
on a powder keg in Söğüt.
Why don't you understand?
I have also discussed it with our beys.
They are not leaning toward
migrating to Söğüt.
Aslıhan, haven't I told you...
that you are not to discuss tribe politics
with the beys?
Why are not listening to me?
It is not your job
to discuss it with the beys.
Turgut.
I was the bey of this tribe once.
I respect you because you are my husband,
however, there is a line here.
And you've crossed the line.
Enough is enough, Aslıhan.
Enough is enough.
Turgut.
Why don't you understand?
Emir Sadettin will not stop
bothering you and Ertuğrul Bey.
I am trying to protect you.
You are saying it's your tribe.
It is my tribe too.
I would be the one who protects it,
if necessary!
It is not your duty
to protect us from that bastard
Emir Sadettin's attacks!
You are the one who needs to know
her place.
This conversation is over.
Thank you for your gifts, Governor Kritos.
You are welcome. This is just
a small token for the peace treaty.
Now, let's talk about the treaty.
What is this impertinence, Artuk Bey?
-You should ask for permission first.
-No, you should ask for permission first.
You are not Ertuğrul Bey.
What is it with you negotiating
with the governor of Bilecik?
What is this?
This is the peace treaty we will sign
by the order of the state.
They wanted me to discuss the peace
and sign the treaty.
What peace is this?
To stop this uncertainty about Söğüt
between the two states.
-So?
-So...
Söğüt will be left to us,
and there will be peace in this land.
Is that right?
-Right.
-Wrong.
Söğüt and Domaniç were given
to Ertuğrul Bey by decree
of the late Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad.
You cannot defy the decree.
That's our state's new order, Artuk Bey.
With this new order, Sultan Alaeddin's
decree is repealed.
-It can't be.
-Artuk Bey!
Ertuğrul Bey has the last word on this.
You can only sign this treaty
with his permission.
Without Ertuğrul Bey's permission,
it is null and void.
Has Ertuğrul Bey become the new
Seljuk Sultan, Günalp Bey?
Rest assured.
We will do our state's orders.
Provided that you pay your taxes,
Söğüt will be in your possession.
Look, Günalp Bey.
We know that you are giving us Söğüt
for the safety of your western borders
when you are on a crusade.
I trusted your word and came here
with good intentions.
I want to sign this treaty, too.
But if this will cause problems...
We cannot have that peace
at your borders.
Are you threatening us, Governor?
Who are you to talk to me like that?
Günalp Bey, who is in charge here?
The treaty will be signed.
What about Ertuğrul Bey?
Since his man is speaking like this,
he will do whatever he can
to break the treaty.
Do you guarantee that Ertuğrul Bey
will stand idle?
Rest assured.
Our state guarantees you everything.
His Eminence Emir Sadettin places
importance on this treaty.
He gave the order himself.
This treaty will be signed.
And no one will break this.
It won't be signed!
No one can do that,
let alone Emir Sadettin.
Söğüt was given to Ertuğrul Bey.
The sultan's decree is still valid,
even though he is dead.
But if you still want to sign that treaty,
then you need to kill all of us first.
Now, I am giving you an order.
Your Eminence Sultan Gıyaseddin,
may I come in?
Come in.
Who did this?
Sultan, we don't know.
But his body was brought
by Ertuğrul Bey's alps.
What are you saying?
Ertuğrul Bey also sent you a letter
with one of his alps.
"First, our state was betrayed.
And now, it is stained with the blood
of the prince.
Everything is rotting, Sultan.
You should stop all of this."
Mother.
It was the best for our state, Sultan.
May God forgive his sins.
May he rest in peace.
Soldiers.
Take my mother to her room.
She will not leave without my permission.
She will be secluded.
Do you hear what you are saying, Sultan?
I hear it, Mother. I hear it very well.
Let's go, Mahperi Hatun.
Do you think being a sultan
at such a young age
will save you from your enemy, Sultan?
Don't do this.
Take her!
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-What is happening, Günalp Bey?
You are signing a peace treaty
without letting me know.
And...
with the bastard that you said
you would trample down.
How dare you insult me, Ertuğrul Bey?
We will sign the peace treaty
with our state's order.
Provided that they pay their taxes,
Söğüt will be in the possession
of Kritos, the governor of Bilecik.
This conversation is over, Ertuğrul Bey.
Söğüt was given to me by decree
of Sultan Alaeddin.
No one can take it from me...
without shedding my blood
and that of the Kayi.
Who is the state, Günalp Bey?
Is it Sultan Gıyaseddin or Ertuğrul Bey?
If the margrave doesn't follow
the state's orders,
it is my duty to solve this.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Hereafter, your words don't have
any power.
Now,
this treaty will be signed.
I am... the state here!
If you want to take Söğüt,
come and take it from me.
That's enough, Günalp Bey.
I came here with your invitation,
to reach an agreement.
But I can see that you can't even
reach an agreement between yourselves.
You are not going anywhere!
What do you think you are doing?
Did you invite me to trap me?
Are you going to kill me
like you killed my son, Ertuğrul Bey?
Our emperor will make you pay for this.
What do you think you are doing,
Ertuğrul Bey?
The governor came here
with the invitation of our state.
The governor is our guest.
This man set a trap for us with Ares.
He put his soldiers under Titan's orders
and killed my alps.
He aided and abetted the kidnappers
of my child.
And...
he kidnapped our women
and tried to set a trap for us.
And now, he is trying to take Söğüt...
with the help of the palace crew.
I will cut his body in half...
in the middle of the village.
And then,
I will go to Söğüt with my alps...
and find a location.
And then,
the Cavdar and Kayi tribes
will migrate to Söğüt.
I won't let you do that, Ertuğrul Bey!
I said that if you tried
to break me,
I would crush you.
How dare you?
You had me followed secretly.
And then,
you tried to sign a peace treaty
without letting me know.
You and the palace crew
made a gift of the lands
that Sultan Alaeddin gave me.
Until you learn to obey me,
you will be locked in the dungeon.
I... promised you that I would obey you.
And now, I will obey you
and willingly go to the dungeon.
However,
I was here to sign the treaty
under the state's orders.
The state will make you pay for this.
You have started a war.
Söğüt will be stained with your blood.
Lucky me.
I can clearly see that my enemies
are united against me.
Now,
it is time for war.
Great God!
Get him out of my castle.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net