Episode 98 will start after 12:38 min.
Thank God, my Bey.
Thanks to you, brother Turgut's
loneliness has come to an end.
There'll be twice the joy
once we take over the castle.
I hope so, Bamsi. I hope so.
-Is everything ready, Artuk Bey?
-Everything's ready, my Bey.
The alps in the castle
are awaiting their orders.
Very well.
Come on then, alps! Let's be on our way.
Turgut Alp?
What's wrong?
Ertuğrul Bey!
Turgut.
Turgut Alp?
-Turgut!
-Turgut! Brother!
Turgut!
Turgut, what happened?
Turgut! My Turgut! My Turgut!
My Turgut, what happened to you?
Brother Turgut! Turgut! My Bey!
Artuk Bey! My Bey!
Do something, my Bey.
Artuk Bey, do something!
God!
Turgut, come on.
Aslıhan?
Run to their tent, Halime. Quickly! Run!
Turgut, stay with me!
Get yourself together, Turgut!
Brother! Brother!
Pull yourself together, brother.
What's happened to you?
Aslıhan! Aslıhan!
Aslıhan, what have they done to you,
sister?
-What happened?
-Aslıhan? My girl!
Aslıhan! My girl!
Gently, gently!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim! My girl.
-Aslıhan?
-Open your eyes, my girl.
Quickly, loosen her clothes.
My girl. Aslıhan! My girl!
Come back to us, sister!
Hang in there, for God's sake.
-Hang in there!
-My Bey, he's been poisoned.
God! Poison, he says! My Bey!
Brother!
-Turgut!
-Brother!
Hang in there, brother.
Hang in there!
Get him up! We'll carry him.
-Let's go.
-Over here.
Don't shake him.
Slowly.
Turgut. Turgut!
Turgut, brother!
-Turgut, brother.
-Turgut!
Turgut, what happened to you?
Speak to me! Turgut, brother!
Brother. Tell me, what happened Turgut?
Brother.
My Bey, Aslıhan is dying. Help her!
-I can look after them both inside.
-Take care of Aslıhan Hatun, Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey!
Brother!
-Bamsi?
-Yes, my Bey.
-Get Turgut inside.
Come on, brothers.
Let's carry him. Brothers!
Come on, brothers!
Let's go!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim!
How is my niece, Ertuğrul Bey?
What's happened?
Bahadir Bey, stay out of my sight.
Even the mountains couldn't
contain my rage. Now leave.
Kirca!
No one is to leave the tribe.
Don't kill anyone who tries to escape.
Instead, bring them immediately to me.
Yes, my Bey.
They're both showing the same symptoms.
Difficulty in breathing,
bruising of hands and lips.
Artuk Bey, they were fine
just a moment ago.
What could have caused this?
Another poison, Halime Sultan. Samsa!
Go and get my pack
of remedies immediately.
Yes, Artuk Bey.
-Hafsa Hatun, bring some water.
-Water.
Turgut, son.
Alps. Go to my tent.
We have matters to discuss.
Aslıhan. Sister.
And some salt.
Ares! Ares, Ares, Ares, Ares!
My Bey, this must be Ares' doing!
He found out we were going
to attack the castle.
Let's have his head.
Let's burn his castle down.
Bamsi...
We have to find out
what kind of poison it is, my Bey.
If we don't find out, I won't be able
to prepare its antidote.
My God.
-God, help them.
-Mother?
I'll find the person who can help us
find the source of the poison, Artuk Bey.
-Very well, my Bey.
-Bamsi, come with me.
God!
-My girl!
-Bring it here.
Aslıhan.
Get the water.
Pour it. Enough.
What're you going to do, Artuk Bey?
We're going to use the salty water
to make them vomit.
Come on.
That's it. Esma's got the job done.
I'll go inform his Eminence.
Wait for Esma. Kill her when she arrives.
You've been serving the blessed Emir
as one of Bahadir's alps all this time.
If you accomplish this mission, too
you'll get to serve the Emir in Konya.
This is a gift from the Emir.
Tell him that the job will be done.
May God bless him.
Very good.
You know where to go
when you finish your task.
Go on then, prove yourself.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
All right.
All right. You're all right, sister.
-All right. Good God.
-Aslıhan.
What kind of poison is this?
Look what they did to them
on their wedding day.
-Come.
-God, please help us in our time of need.
My God, please protect them both.
Don't separate them from each other.
Aslıhan.
-He's back!
-Turgut, son.
-Turgut Alp?
-Thank God.
Make Aslıhan drink it.
-Hayme Hatun.
-Give it here.
Aslıhan? My girl!
Aslıhan? Aslıhan, my girl.
Don't tire yourself, sister.
-Let's get your head up. Bismillah.
-Come on.
Come here, take a sip.
Bismillah.
Sister.
Turgut?
Turgut is here. He's all right, too.
You'll get better, my girl.
Turgut?
Artuk Bey, what happened to us?
How is Turgut?
Aslıhan Hatun, drink the salty water.
It will make you vomit out the poison.
Go on.
-Come on, sister.
-Here.
Hang in there, sister.
Turgut Alp, come on. Come on, brother.
Halime, prepare more salty water.
Brothers,
we first need to find the bastard
who poisoned Turgut and Aslıhan Hatun.
If we get him, we'll find out
who gave the order.
That's why, until this issue is settled,
we hold off the raid on the castle.
Abdur Rahman, let the alps know.
Tell them to come back here.
As you command, my Bey.
Hey! And tell Atsiz to get a hold
of the trader coming from Nicaea.
He should capture him and bring
him to me. You're to help Atsiz.
As you command, my Bey.
Artuk Bey! Artuk Bey!
Tell me, will they live?
We either find the antidote
or we pray for them to die swiftly, Bamsi.
Artuk Bey, what are you saying?
What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
My Bey, I've never seen anything like it.
They are conscious,
they hear what we say.
Yet they don't have
the strength even to talk.
Their bodies are decaying quickly.
Furthermore, they are in agony.
Their bodies are decaying, my Bey.
Whoever did this wanted them
to suffer greatly before they died.
Whoever did this holds
a great grudge against us, my Bey.
How much time do you have
to find the poison and prepare antidote?
If we can't find the source of the poison
we have until the sun goes down, my Bey.
Bamsi! We don't have time to shed tears.
-Yes, my Bey.
-Find Kirca and Esma at once.
Bring whoever goes in and out
of their tents to me. Immediately!
-Yes, my Bey.
If we can't find who poisoned them,
we won't know
who gave the order, Artuk Bey.
We need to find out who gave the order
so that you can prepare the antidote.
Who could it be, my Bey?
There are certain people who would
do this to Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun.
Either Emir Sadettin,
or his lap dog Bahadir.
We'll find out who it was, Artuk Bey.
There's no other way.
We found ourselves in the middle
of a trap during a battle.
If we fail to get something
good out of this turmoil,
then there will be blood.
But first, we save them.
Yes, my Bey.
I'm glad they've been poisoned.
I hope neither of them sees the sunrise.
This is not good, wife.
-Not good at all.
-Why, my Bey?
Don't you see,
they didn't even accept my help.
Ertuğrul sent me away from the tent.
Who do you think they'll suspect first?
It's not as if we're on good terms
with Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut.
They'll interrogate us first.
Obviously, someone has set a trap.
But it wasn't only Turgut and
Aslıhan Hatun who were targeted.
We're also their victims.
Ertuğrul will certainly come for me.
But I know exactly what to do.
Kaya Tekin!
-Yes, my Bey.
-Gather your alps around my tent.
If Ertuğrul's alps come here,
don't let them pass.
As you command, my Bey.
If Ertuğrul dares hold me responsible
for this poisoning scheme
I'll make him pay for it.
Son.
Aslıhan?
Sister, don't wear yourself out.
We're here.
Sister.
Mother Hayme.
My girl, Aslıhan. Don't tire yourself.
You'll get better.
My God, please help them.
I can't take this anymore.
-Give me your blessings.
-My girl.
How can you say that?
Ertuğrul Bey will find
the antidote for you.
You'll be better in no time.
Don't talk like you're saying goodbye.
-Give me your blessings.
-Aslıhan.
Aslıhan!
Aslıhan...
Artuk Bey! Hurry!
Aslıhan Hatun is getting worse!
Aslıhan Hatun?
Aslıhan, sister!
Son.
Artuk Bey?
Aslıhan.
Aslıhan?
Aslıhan...
Thank God.
God, help us. Son.
Ertuğrul, my son.
Sister.
Turgut.
Aslıhan Hatun.
I'll find who did this
and the antidote to the poison, brother.
I'll make them pay for what they've done.
I know, my Bey. I know.
Ertuğrul Bey...
Aslıhan Hatun, don't worry. I'll find
the antidote to this poison, I promise.
I'm not afraid to die.
I'm afraid evil people
will take over my tribe.
Ertuğrul Bey...
I entrust my tribe to you.
Don't let my tribe fall
into the hands of Bahadir Bey. Don't.
-Aslıhan.
-Halime.
That's enough, don't wear yourself out.
-Aslıhan!
My girl!
-Don't worry.
They're so weary, they've gone to sleep.
But Bey, we will lose them both
if we don't find the antidote soon.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun.
What are you doing here?
Looking for an ointment for my wounds.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Someone poisoned
Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp.
I'm here to get Artuk Bey's bag.
Who would do that?
We don't know.
But we'll find out sooner or later.
It's not anywhere!
Where the hell is his bag?
Is this it?
Good man, God bless you.
Come on, we need to go right now.
We'll leave you to it. Come on!
Blessed Emir.
What is it, Göktuğ?
Esma did her job, Your Eminence.
Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp
lie on their death beds.
Very good.
Ertuğrul will go after Esma
if he finds out about her.
Whether it's Esma or Alpamis,
if Ertuğrul gets hold of either of them,
and they give your name
to him, it'll be bad.
Alpamis is waiting for Esma,
Your Eminence.
He will kill her when she arrives.
Take your men and kill Alpamis
as soon as he's done with Esma.
As you command, blessed Emir.
Such a pity, Aslıhan. Such a pity.
My dear friend Ares, I'm sure
you'll find this information useful.
We've already explained
everything, my Bey.
We are the only ones
who entered the tent.
That's all we know, my Bey.
We've nothing else to say.
Leave.
Esma, you stay here!
Think it through, Esma.
You're Aslıhan Hatun's right hand woman.
Did you miss anything?
Who else entered the tent except you?
Except for me, Halime Sultan,
Hafsa Hatun and Mother Hayme, my Bey.
And Kirca.
Kirca! Is there anyone you suspect?
My Bey, we watched
everyone who entered the tent.
I know everyone who went in.
Is this how you do your job, Kirca?
You were meant to protect Aslıhan Hatun!
Whoever poisoned them
did it right before your eyes!
You were meant to protect Aslıhan's life
and the tribe's honor.
Talk to me, Esma!
Find whoever did this
and punish them, my Bey.
Aslıhan Hatun trusted no one but you.
There's no one else I can trust either.
Look at me, Esma!
Look into my eyes!
Pull yourself together.
You will not give up.
Think, Esma, think! Who did this?
What are we missing?
Think about it and answer me!
I don't know, my Bey. I don't.
They made grief out of our joy,
and poison out of sherbet.
God damn them, those fiends.
May God punish them.
-Kirca?
-Yes, my Bey.
-Take Esma Hatun to her tent.
Sister, come on.
I'd die for Aslıhan Hatun.
Kill me and relieve me
of this shame, Ertuğrul Bey.
Bamsi!
-Yes, my Bey.
-Keep watch over Esma.
She's the one who poisoned them.
What do you mean, my Bey?
Then why did you let her go?
You heard what I said, Bamsi.
You have to watch her. And her tent.
Follow her if she leaves the tribe.
She will take us to her masters.
You understand me, Bamsi?
-Yes, my Bey. I understand.
-Go on, then.
Where is the sherbet jug?
My Bey.
It's here, my Bey.
Do you have news, my Bey?
Esma betrayed herself
out of fear, Artuk Bey.
She told me the poison
was in the sherbet.
How could she know
that when we didn't, son?
She couldn't possibly know
unless she was the one who put it there.
Where is Esma, my Bey?
She remains unaware that
I suspect her, Artuk Bey.
She's in her tent.
Bamsi will follow her like her shadow.
If she is indeed the culprit
she'll take us to her masters.
Give Esma to us, son.
Don't dirty your hands
with the blood of a wicked woman.
We'll get her to talk.
Mother! All she could do is confess.
We want to find the one
who ordered her to do it.
Ertuğrul Bey is right.
If we're to save Turgut and Aslıhan Hatun,
we need to find out who poisoned them
but more importantly who gave the order.
Esma couldn't possibly know that.
But Artuk Bey, you said we had no time.
They're dying as we speak!
Once Samsa brings my bag
we'll know for sure
if it was the sherbet that was poisoned.
I can then prepare an antidote.
We have to be patient until we can
confirm the sherbet was poisoned, Mother.
By then, Esma will have tried to escape.
And Bamsi will be following her.
My Bey, what if she doesn't escape?
Then, she'll be talking
through the blood in her mouth.
Günküt!
Yes, my Bey.
Bring Bahadir Bey
and Karaca Hatun to my tent.
Right away, my Bey.
Even if Ertuğrul knows you're innocent
he'll try to use this as an opportunity
to get rid of you, my Bey.
I'm not the type of man
who goes down without a fight.
If he has plans...
then I have my own plans.
My Bey, we've been through a lot.
But this is different.
Ertuğrul will have your head
if he decides he wants it.
Let's take our alps
and leave, if necessary.
Look at me, wife!
Do you want them to say
Bahadir Bey got scared and ran away?
I'm not afraid of anyone.
And I don't want cowards on my side.
Understood?
Ertuğrul can come and take
my head if he has the guts.
You can't take anyone from this tent.
Leave, before you force us
to do something nobody wants.
What's going on?
Our Bey will go only if he wants to do so.
I'll crush every one of you and take
your bey anyway if you don't leave.
I'd like to see you try.
What's going on here?
Release my alps at once!
We're taking you to Ertuğrul Bey,
Bahadir Bey.
We'll do whatever's necessary
if you resist.
I won't be summoned by Ertuğrul Bey.
There is my tent. He can come
here if he has something to say.
Bahadir Bey,
Ertuğrul Bey has commanded you!
Don't make us drag you to him
in front of your alps.
What's happening, Artuk Bey?
They'll die in agony
if we don't find the antidote, my Bey.
God, help us.
Please help us, God.
Dear God, help us.
Son.
-Aslıhan?
-My girl!
Bahadir Bey.
Bahadir Bey did this.
Ertuğrul Bey, Bahadir Bey poisoned us,
All right.
All right!
I'll go talk with Ertuğrul Bey.
Bahadir Bey, Karaca Hatun is to come too.
Look here! Know your place!
What does he want with my wife?
Ertuğrul Bey summoned both of you!
Alps, take their swords. Tie their hands.
We brought Bahadir Bey
and Karaca Hatun, my Bey.
I'll make them pay
for turning your wedding day
into the worst day of your life,
Aslıhan Hatun.
I came to help as soon
as I saw something was wrong.
Yet you sent me away.
Why are you asking for me now,
Ertuğrul Bey?
Someone poisoned Turgut Alp
and Aslıhan Hatun, Bahadir Bey.
You've disrupted the peace here
with your anger and ambition
from the moment you arrived.
You wouldn't let Aslıhan Hatun
and Turgut Alp be.
No one has a stronger motive
to poison them than you, Bahadir Bey.
You ruined my reputation.
You banished my son.
Now you're accusing me
of being a poisoner?
You don't know me at all, Ertuğrul Bey.
If I wanted to kill them, I'd do it
with my sword. Like a man.
Do you think I don't know
that you aim to be leader of the Cavdars
by siding with Emir Sadettin?
If I did side with him,
it means I side with the state.
If this is a crime
then do whatever you can to stop me.
You are the margrave
and I am a bey of the Cavdars.
You have no authority over me,
Ertuğrul Bey.
But, I know exactly what you want to do.
You want Turgut
to be the leader of the Cavdars
and to banish me,
just like you did my son.
You wanted to take control of the Cavdars
through your puppet Turgut.
Tell me,
are you angry now because you can
see your plan slipping away from you?
I banished your son to teach him a lesson.
But I would take your head, Bahadir Bey.
Is that so?
Go ahead.
Do your best.
You have no reason
to blame us for this, Ertuğrul Bey.
We'll not take this lying down.
We'll see.
We will see.
Take Bahadir Bey to the prisoner’s tent.
Karaca Hatun will not leave her tent.
Gather their alps in front of their tent.
I want to talk to each one of them.
You don't know what you're doing,
Ertuğrul Bey.
But, you have my word,
I will stand my ground
until I make you eat your words.
Take him.
Brave warriors, it's time.
As soon as Ertuğrul Bey is in
the castle we start fighting.
Stay sharp.
With God's permission, our flags will
be flying from the walls of the castle
even if we become martyrs.
Brother Abdurrahman!
Are we good to go?
There will be no raid today, brother.
What's wrong?
Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun
have been poisoned.
They're dying.
Bastards!
Who could do such a thing?
We don't know yet.
Ertuğrul Bey has postponed the raid
so he can find out who did it
and save Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp.
Then you should go back to the tribe.
I'll stay here.
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to capture
the trader from Nicaea
and bring him safely to him.
My alps will go back to the tribe.
I'll stay with you.
Let's be on our way then.
We'll need to capture the trader
before he gets near the castle.
Sir, news from Titan.
So, he's managed
to infiltrate the Kayi tribe.
We've finally penetrated
the defenses of our greatest enemy.
Let's see what he has to say
about the Kayi tribe.
What does he say, sir?
Turgut Alp and Aslıhan Hatun
were poisoned on their wedding night.
Why do you look so worried, sir?
Turks are killing each other again.
We can't have Ertuğrul's rage
focusing on us, Kostas.
It could tie our hands
while we're preparing for war.
Who would want to poison them, sir?
Someone prepared to use
even me to crush Ertuğrul.
Emir Sadettin.
With his Sultan's support,
Ertuğrul not only had Emir Sadettin
ordered out of these lands,
he also crushed the horse
Sadettin was betting on.
He even banished Bahadir's son.
But why would Sadettin poison them, sir?
Aslıhan was to marry Sadettin,
but Ertuğrul had her marry Turgut Alp.
But I know Sadettin.
There must be more to this.
But we can't let Ertuğrul suspect us
and force us to stay in the castle.
So, what will you do, sir?
I'd rather face
a brave warrior like Ertuğrul
than scum like Sadettin.
We will go to the Cavdar tribe.
Make the necessary preparations.
Let's show Ertuğrul Bey that we're
with him in his time of trouble.
Get my horse ready.
Yes, sir.
Did anyone follow you?
Don't worry. I was very discreet.
-The job's done, right?
-Definitely. They're both going to die.
Good. His Eminence sends his regards.
He wanted me to give you this
in return for your services.
Who? who is your master? Bastard!
Goddamn it! That's Bamsi, Ertuğrul's alp.
Who gave the order to poison them?
Come on, talk!
Where is the antidote, tell me!
I'll send you to hell
just like I did them.
I won't draw my sword. We need you alive!
Come on.
God!
Now, I have you by the throat.
I've got you!
You'll tell us everything now!
How are they, Artuk Bey?
It's not good, my Bey.
As I said, I first of all need to find out
if the sherbet is what poisoned them.
Then we can identify the poison
and act accordingly.
My Bey. I've brought the bag, Artuk Bey.
Hurry, Artuk Bey.
Samsa, bring the sherbet jug from inside.
Now we'll see if the sherbet
was poisoned or not.
If it's poisonous,
it will turn purple, my Bey.
You were right, my Bey.
The poison was in the sherbet.
Samsa. Bring Esma at once.
Yes, my Bey.
Tell me everything!
Where is the antidote?
Tell me!
Stop, enough. I'll talk.
Kill them.
Alpamis is dead.
Let's go before Bamsi sees us.
Who gave the order
to poison Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut?
Tell me, where is the antidote?
Where is it? Speak up! Speak up.
Tell me. Don't die, speak!
Speak!
You didn't help us,
but maybe your corpse will.
This will help them breathe more easily.
And when the bottle is empty, Artuk Bey?
Then there's nothing
more I can do, my Bey.
That's why we need to get
the antidote as a matter of urgency.
We will, Artuk Bey. We will.
My Bey, Bamsi and Esma
are nowhere to be found.
Bamsi must have gone after Esma.
Make way.
Make way! Move.
Let me pass.
I said make way.
My Bey.
What happened, Bamsi?
Where's Esma? Who's this man?
My Bey, Esma tried
to escape from the tribe.
I followed her as you instructed.
She met with this man outside the tribe.
He gave Esma a pouch of gold coins.
I figured they were working together.
And then this bastard killed Esma.
So I went there and got the bastard,
but just as I was bringing him to you,
someone shot him, my Bey.
My Bey, I couldn't go after them
as I didn't have my horse.
I brought his dead body
thinking it might be useful.
Very good, Bamsi.
-Kirca.
-Yes, my Bey.
Who is he? Is he one of yours?
No, my Bey. That's Alpamis.
He's one of Bahadir Bey's alps.
I told you no one was to leave
the tribe, right, Kirca?
How did he get out?
My Bey, Alpamis was never here.
Is what Kirca said true?
Is this man Alpamis?
He is, my Bey.
Alpamis didn't travel here with us.
He was coming later with our tribe.
I don't know why he's here.
My Bey, Bahadir obviously used
this man to do his dirty work for him.
Come on, brothers, take the body away.
Come on, brothers. Come on.
Alps... Out.
Tell me about Alpamis.
What about him?
Alpamis secretly met up with Esma
outside the tribe.
Then he killed her.
So Esma was the one who poisoned them.
Aslıhan!
And you thought
a woman could be their bey.
If Esma is a traitor,
so is your alp Alpamis, Bahadir Bey.
You ordered Alpamis
to tell Esma to poison them.
I'm fed up with your empty words,
Ertuğrul Bey.
That dog Alpamis was to come
later with the rest of my tribe.
I don't know why he's here.
Still you lie to me.
You gave Alpamis his orders.
You gave Esma gold to poison them.
That's not true... Not true.
Who knows whose dog Alpamis was?
But if you intend to do away with me,
do it now, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let both of us be rid of this.
Until the day
that dog deceives you too, eh?
Still you say it wasn't you.
It wasn't me!
Ertuğrul Bey,
I fear neither you nor death.
Do what you will.
But know that I didn't do it!
My Bey. My Bey.
Ares, Governor Ares is here.
Alps!
Yes, my Bey.
Tie him up well.
I'll finish with him when I get back.
Why are you here, Ares?
I heard what happened.
I thought maybe I could be of use.
So, you heard what happened.
Your ears are sharp.
Everyone from here to Hanli bazaar
heard about what happened, Ertuğrul Bey.
My condolences.
They are still alive.
What fiend uses a poison
that kills so slowly?
One that wanted them to suffer
before they died.
Well, well, well.
Such spite must run deep.
Come with me.
What's going on, Bamsi Alp?
We are lost in a forest, brother.
I can no longer see the path.
I don't know.
I really don't know, brother.
You say you're here to help me.
How am I meant to trust you, Ares?
I came to help a margrave who had offered
his hand in fellowship. Isn't that enough?
You and Emir Sadettin tried to take
control of Hanli bazaar in my absence.
How can I trust your word?
Yes, that's true.
But what of it?
In peacetime, we both want to develop
our trade. It's our duty to do so.
The gold that Bahadir Bey used
to buy the market...
How much of it was yours?
You are very clever, Ertuğrul Bey.
Just one transaction.
It was only business.
You came back,
Emir Sadettin's rule is over.
From now on, I will maintain
the peace and trade with you.
From now on, I deal only with you.
What can you do for Turgut and Aslıhan?
I don't know who did this
but I can give you a lead to follow.
What does that mean?
I had my suspicions riding in,
but when you said the one who did this
wanted them to suffer but not die,
I was sure.
What were you sure of?
The herbalist who prepared the poison.
I now know for certain who prepared
the poison for Aslıhan and Turgut.
Who?
A well-known herbalist from Nicaea.
An old priest who has forsaken God.
Competent enough to make someone
suffer without causing their death.
Where can I find him?
I heard he lived
on the outskirts of Hell Hill.
He went into seclusion in one
of the caves at the bottom of the valley.
If you find the priest, you might be
able to help Aslıhan and Turgut.
And I would have extended
a helping hand to a friend.
Who knows, instead of
offering my condolences,
perhaps I will be able to extend
my best wishes to the newlyweds one day.
But this is all I can do, Ertuğrul Bey.
The rest is up to you.
God save the lovers.
With your permission
I'll leave Commander Kostas here.
I'd like to be kept informed
of what happens.
Thank you, Ares.
Door.
Bamsi followed Esma.
He saw Alpamis killing her,
then caught him.
But we got there in time, Your Eminence.
We finished Alpamis off
before Bamsi could make him talk.
We got away before he saw us.
Good.
Bamsi will have taken
the body back to the tribe.
And when Ertuğrul sees that it is
Alpamis, one of Bahadir's alps...
Everything is working in our favor
for now, Göktuğ.
I have another mission for you.
I'm at your command, Your Eminence.
Find the herbalist who made
the poison and kill him.
We can't leave anything
which ties him to us.
Yes, Your Eminence.
They won't find the antidote
which could heal Turgut and Aslıhan.
First, the two of them will die...
and then Bahadir.
Things will be thrown into confusion.
That is when I will return.
And in order to re-establish order,
I will take Ertuğrul's head.
-Aslıhan! Aslıhan, my sister.
-Turgut, my son.
-Turgut.
-Turgut Alp.
-Turgut!
Sister!
-Sister.
-Artuk Bey, Aslıhan Hatun can't breathe!
Artuk Bey, what are we going to do?
-Turgut, gather yourself.
-Sister.
-Aslıhan!
-Turgut. My God!
-Artuk Bey!
-Halime Sultan. Open her mouth.
Come here, come.
-My God, help them.
-Open your mouth. She won't, Artuk Bey!
-Aslıhan, open your mouth.
-My girl!
-Open up.
-Open it, Halime Sultan.
Aslıhan! Aslıhan!
-Turgut. My God.
-Halime Sultan, have her drink this.
-Hafsa.
-We're losing her.
-What?
-Hafsa.
-Come, Hafsa!
-Artuk Bey! Artuk Bey!
My Bey, we're losing them.
I'm not sure if they
will see another sunset.
Ares came here.
He said he knew the herbalist who made
the poison and told me where to find him.
What is Ares after?
He said Emir Sadettin's rule is over.
He wanted
to further his friendship with me.
Bastard!
Who knows what he's thinking, my Bey.
But we have no choice.
They're both on the verge of death.
Then I must set off right away.
My Bey, let me come with you.
There's nothing more I can do here.
There's nothing I can do to help either
Aslıhan Hatun or Turgut Alp anymore.
If Ares is right, my knowledge
as a healer will come in handy, my Bey.
All right, Artuk Bey.
-We will ride together.
-Thank you, my Bey.
Hafsa, open her mouth.
Turgut! Turgut!
Aslıhan Hatun, open up.
What do you want?
My master sends his regards.
The poison you prepared
was quite effective.
He wants another bottle.
Wait.
My Bey.
What is it, Bamsi? Are there tracks?
There are, my Bey.
There are. And they're fresh, my Bey.
There's no doubt someone's
been here before us.
The bastards that ordered the poison
may well have come to kill the herbalist.
Come on alps, let's find this cave.
Come on.
So, to make the antidote
you also use the poison from that snake.
You do.
Then let's make sure no one can.
Why do you want to kill me?
We can't have others knowing our secret.
I've destroyed your only hope.
There's nothing left to heal you now.
Secure the area, alps.
This is the cave.
Be on your guard.
We don't know what awaits inside.
Have we entered the devil's lair?
What is this place, my Bey?
Just as I thought.
The bastards killed him
to cover their tracks.
My Bey, how will we find the antidote now?
Whoever killed the herbalist chose to kill
only this animal out of all the others.
The poison they gave Turgut Alp
and Aslıhan Hatun must have come from it.
He killed it so that we
couldn't use it to make the antidote.
My Bey, if this animal is dead,
how will we make the antidote
for my brother Turgut and Aslıhan Hatun?
If there's still poison in it,
we can do it, Bamsi.
-Get me a cup.
-Cup. Cup, cup.
Artuk Bey, Artuk Bey,
will this do? Will it do?
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My Bey, I pray it's as I hope.
We'll see now whether
there's any poison left in it.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Thank God, my Bey. This is the poison.
I'll make up the antidote now.
Thank God.
Make it quickly, Artuk Bey.
We have to get it to them before sunset.
-Thank God.
-Yes, my Bey.
Thank God.
Sister, drink this.
Drink.
Sister. Hafsa, fill it.
Hang on, Turgut.
Hang on just a little bit longer, my son.
Ertuğrul has gone to get you
the antidote, Turgut Alp.
Aslıhan.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Hang in there, sister. You'll get better.
Thank God,
she seems to be breathing a little.
Come on.
Thank God. Aslıhan, my daughter.
Aslıhan.
Sister, come on.
Hang on just a little longer. Come on.
You'll be fine.
Sister!
My Bey, get this to them at once.
Have them both drink it when you get
there. It'll have an immediate effect.
Allow me to stay here. I'll gather any
herbs that could be useful to us, my Bey.
All right, Artuk Bey.
Günküt, you stay with Artuk Bey.
Come after us.
Bamsi and I will get the antidote
to them right away.
-God speed, Artuk Bey.
-God speed, my Bey.
Let's go, my Bey.
Artuk Bey?
What is it? What are these herbs?
Are they important?
They are so important that
they will have heads roll
and save others.
We have to get back to the tribe
before it's too late. Come on.
Sister, come on.
Aslıhan.
My girl. Hold on, my girl.
He'll be here soon, hold on.
Give me your...
blessing...
Blessing. Give me...
No! Don't say that!
-No!
-Aslıhan.
-Turgut.
-Aslıhan. Aslıhan!
Sister.
Hold on. A little longer.
No, Turgut!
God, please help us! Dear God!
Mother!
Come, let's get you out. Come on.
-My son!
-Hafsa, you stay. Mother, come.
-Come on, Mother.
-My girl!
Come on!
The sun's nearly setting, Bamsi.
-We have to be quicker!
-Let's go, my Bey, let's go.
My Aktolga, my white maned one.
You are my wings.
Be my wings once more
so that before darkness falls
we may foil this cruel plot! Come on.
They defend it more heavily
during the day.
So, we will do it at night.
-Keep at it!
-Thank you. God speed.
Darius!
Hello, little hero!
What are you doing here? Are you
on your way to claim the flying horse?
No, I...
I just wanted to look around the tribe.
Darius is going to take me
on the flying horse. Right, Darius?
Sure.
It will be soon.
The winged horse will come soon.
But he only comes at night.
I'll tell you when he's here.
-Okay?
-Okay.
Come, let's get to the tent,
Gündüz Bey.
If you should need anything,
ask one of the alps.
You don't know the tribe yet.
Don't wander far from your tent.
Thank you.
Don't worry. I might not know the tribe
but your tribe will know me soon enough.
The herbalist and the snake that the
poison came from are dead, Your Eminence.
It will be impossible to save
Aslıhan Hatun or Turgut Alp now.
Pity.
If you'd had a little more sense...
you could have been one of the most
esteemed women of the Seljuks.
Alas, you did not.
And you paid for it with your life.
Even if you were sorry now,
what good would it do?
Farewell, Aslıhan Hatun.
Farewell.
Göktuğ. We're done here for now.
There's important business
awaiting us in Konya.
Those who think
I am just the Emir of the state...
will see that I am the state itself.
It's in my hands to uphold the state
or raze it to the ground.
Everyone will bow to my power.
Those who don't will pay
the price with their blood.
Ertuğrul...
and the sultan.
Let's go.
Ertuğrul Bey is back!
Did you find the cave?
Ares was right. I come with the antidote.
Tell him I will never forget this!
I hope they survive, Ertuğrul Bey!
Help me, Bamsi.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim. Come, sister.
God, God.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-My God, the healer.
-Help them, God.
My God. My God.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My God, the healer.
My God, the healer. My God, the healer.
Come, brother.
-My God, help them.
-Brother.
-Help them, God.
-My God, the healer.
Here you go, my Bey. Come on. God.
Come back to us, brother. Come back.
Come on, brother, gather yourself.
When will the remedy take effect, my Bey?
I'm worried we're too late.
He who gives the woe,
gives the cure, Bamsi.
From this point on, it's up to God.
Whatever he sees fit, we will accept.
Yes, my Bey.
However...
we now have a great mission.
What, my Bey?
We will get our revenge on the ones
who did this to them, Bamsi.
All right, my Bey. All right.
Come on, God.
Samsa!
-Yes, my Bey.
-Bring Bahadir Bey to my tent.
As you command, my Bey.
We've come to take you
before Ertuğrul Bey.
What for? Is his judgement not over?
The judgement is over,
now he will name your punishment.
So, it's time to take my head.
Tell them to bring my bow.
If he is to kill me, let it be a death
worthy of a bey, by way of my bow.
Don't worry.
Ertuğrul Bey punishes
everyone exactly as they deserve.
My God, you are the healer.
You are the one who heals.
Pull this madness out of my children.
Give them back to us, my God.
-Amen.
Mother, Aslıhan is coming round.
Aslıhan!
-Sister.
-Thank God.
-Thank God!
-Thank you, God!
Sister. Are you feeling better?
My son. My valiant son.
Open your eyes, Turgut.
Come on, son.
Turgut.
-How is Turgut?
-Turgut is fine.
He'll recover, my girl.
Sister, don't you worry about that.
Rest. You're both going to be fine.
Thank you, God.
Why is the sultan here?
His lieutenant said that he's
accepted the envoys from Crimea
together with Cobanoglu Husamettin.
He wants to see you
once the envoys have left, Your Eminence.
Good.
Let's wait and see.
Sir, Ertuğrul Bey has
returned to the tribe.
They found the priest who made
the poison and brought the antidote.
Thank God!
Someone like Ertuğrul Bey
will never forget such a favor, Kostas.
Now he owes us two lives.
We have considerable
leverage against him now.
What will you do now, sir?
We have won Ertuğrul's trust, Kostas.
We will use our leverage
to our best advantage.
Ertuğrul Bey will give
us whatever we ask for.
He'll refuse us nothing.
We'll corner him
with what we get from him.
With the two lives we saved today,
we will slay Ertuğrul
and the Turks tomorrow.
Our Sultan awaits you, Your Eminence.
My Sultan...
Is Ertuğrul fulfilling his duties,
Sadettin?
He's discharging them satisfactorily,
my Sultan.
The Turk tribes are pleased that
he returned safe and sound.
And you? Are you also pleased?
Of course, my Sultan.
Ertuğrul is your chosen margrave.
I respect him as a brave Turk bey.
Of course I'm pleased.
Then why were you incapable
of carrying out my orders, Sadettin?
I went to war against the Ayyubids
when beset by the Mongolian scum.
And you returned victorious.
May God never take you away from us.
And you?
What were you doing all this time?
You failed to find the traitors
who plotted against Ertuğrul.
And you failed to avenge
the blood of his alps.
Did you think I wouldn't hold you
responsible for your failures
and for making the state
look so weak, Sadettin?
My Sultan...
according to the testimonies
of the surviving alps
the attackers were bandits.
Sadettin...
if I was unaware of your long service...
if I hadn't witnessed
your many great victories...
I would crush you right now.
Still you act like some poor
weak child in front of me.
What bandit would dare to
ambush my margrave Ertuğrul,
when he's riding off to war,
armed to the teeth?
Can't you hear what you're saying?
-My Sultan--
-And you still dare to make excuses!
My Sultan...
I interrogated many bandits,
I hanged a number of them.
You still speak of bandits, Sadettin.
Do you not realize the dogs
who attacked Ertuğrul...
are the very same men
who attempted to kill me?
Can you not see that
this assassination attempt,
targeting both of us,
was the work of the same wretched demon?
It did also cross my mind
that Nicaea and the Crusaders
might be behind it, my Sultan, but--
As long as the perpetrators go unpunished
what good are you as an Emir?
In Ertuğrul's absence
I charged you with this duty.
What did you do? Nothing!
Nothing at all!
If that's what you think, my Sultan...
you may take not only my title...
but my worthless head too.
Take my head now so that...
instead of your rage eating away at you,
the crows may feast on my corpse.
Even when I'm dead
I'd still wish to serve my state.
Are you playing with me, Ertuğrul Bey?
Do what you're going to do.
You will talk first.
You're going to admit
you're guilty of this treachery.
I did nothing.
Your alp...
was the one who gave Esma the poison.
Do you still deny it?
Now is the time to show you're a man.
Instead of denying it
like a coward, confess!
I have nothing to confess.
You think I did it but you're wrong.
I swear...
you'll pay a heavy price for this.
If I hadn't sworn never
to leave the path of justice,
I swear...
I'd have done this
a long time before, Sadettin.
You left me and my state...
weakened against both the enemy
and the Turk tribes.
Please, give me three months, my Sultan.
I'll find out who was responsible
and bring you his head myself.
I'll not only find them,
I'll find the dogs
who infiltrated your palace as well.
If I fail...
I'll willingly pay the price.
You claim the foreigners have eyes
inside the palace, Sadettin?
If you're right...
and the foreigners
were indeed responsible...
they must have managed
to get inside the palace.
This is your last chance, Sadettin,
understand?
Now get out of my sight!
My Sultan.
I want Emir Sadettin followed
everywhere he goes.
At all times.
I want to know everything he does.
As you command, my Sultan.
Eminence, our informer sent us this.
Ertuğrul went to the priest's cave.
He left two of his alps behind
then got back on the road.
I believe he has taken the antidote
back to the Cavdar tribe.
Your Eminence!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Get well, sister.
Thank you.
-Turgut...
-Turgut Alp?
-Thank God.
-My Turgut.
My son!
-Aslıhan...
-Turgut?
At last.
Thank God!
My son!
Where is my Bey?
He'll be here soon.
You have to get better!
Where's my Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey is in his tent, Turgut Alp,
carrying out Bahadir Bey's sentence.
-Son, you only just woke up.
-Turgut?
-Lie back down.
-Where are you going, Turgut Alp?
To kill the one... who tried to kill us!
Son, wait!
-My Bey.
-Brother Turgut got better.
Turgut! My Turgut! Brother!
Thank God! He spared your life.
He did all this, my Bey.
He did all this.
He did everything.
Everything.
Don't worry. He'll be punished.
My Bey. Let me make an example of him.
Let me take his head in front of the tent.
He hurt all of us,
but it must be me who takes his head.
Believe me...
every one of you is my enemy.
Know that I don't fear death.
But I did not poison you!
I am not guilty of this treachery!
Enough!
What is it, Artuk Bey?
Stop, my Bey.
My Bey, Aslıhan Hatun and Turgut Alp
were not poisoned by Bahadir Bey.
What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
I found the poison given to the Sultan
in the cave of the herbalist, my Bey.
-Are you sure?
-I am sure, my Bey.
The poison that was given
to our sultan contained wolfsbane.
Among other poisonous herbs.
I'm sure, my Bey. Absolutely sure.
Bahadir wasn't here when
our sultan was poisoned.
My Bey, whoever poisoned the sultan
also poisoned Turgut Alp
and Aslıhan Hatun.
This person used Esma and Bahadir's alp
so that we would pin the blame on him.
Only one person is capable of this.
Emir Sadettin!