Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.SubtitleDB.org today
Are you all right?
Why did you come out like this?
I was going to come see you first, anyway.
I didn't want you to see me wounded
in bed like this, my bey.
You escaped the hands of the cruel
and came back...
I wanted you to see me on my feet.
Besides...
the only thing that kept me going,
despite this heavy wound,
was my will to see you one last time.
My brother.
We undid the torture and trap
of that bastard called Arıkbuka.
Thank God, my bey.
Thank God.
However,
this bastard called Arıkbuka
will cause us big trouble still.
Alıncak's blood brother.
He is hellbent on revenge.
He will do all the cruelty he can.
But we too won't be putting our swords
back into their sheaths.
With God's help, my bey.
With God's help.
We are always ready.
You just rest now.
You need to get strong and well so that...
we may take the heads of our enemies
shoulder to shoulder.
All right, my bey.
Very good, rest now.
What did you do, Abdurrahman?
Were you able to find him?
He threw us off his trail.
But the alps are still looking.
We know
that they won't leave tracks, Abdurrahman.
Still, keep on looking with more men.
Gather a division of alps.
And reinforce the patrols.
Put guards around the tribes
lying in wait.
As you wish, my bey.
My bey.
What is it, Artuk Bey?
Melikşah, you can go.
My bey,
the white-bearded
have sent this urgent message.
What does it say?
Very important matters, Artuk Bey.
They want me to make haste.
I will take some alps and go.
Stay by Turgut's side.
As you wish, my bey.
Artuk Bey.
If the enemy's sword spilled our red blood
onto the black earth...
it is time to ask for vengeance
from the black earth.
Let the souls of my comrades...
fly with fire.
When the black earth
drinks our red blood...
when the blue sky absorbs our souls...
when the souls mount mares
and head towards Heaven...
when my red Mother Fire
with 40 teeth is praised...
the fork horned moose
that I sucked milked from...
the Burkan Kaldun mountain
with its smoky helm...
Mother Rahan in Heaven...
Erlik Khan in black earth...
Tengri up in the blue sky,
ask only one thing of me.
Until the rivers run with blood...
revenge!
-Revenge!
Until the dead of our enemies
pile up like mountains...
-revenge!
-Revenge!
Until we destroy them...
revenge!
-Revenge!
Cowards.
They buried you here
like a beggar with no name...
like an outcast with no lineage, Brother.
A valiant man like you...
an alp like you...
they wouldn't even leave your sword
or your cap on your grave.
But don't worry...
I will take revenge...
from those
who did this to you.
You.
What are you doing here?
I brought what the betrayed
might desire.
Revenge.
Now is not the time for empty words.
Say what you have to say
or else take your shadow and leave.
Commander Alıncak's blood brother
Arıkbuka sent me.
He has a question.
What is it?
"Is Albastı's fair sister...
ready to avenge his brother?"
he asks.
Like never before.
Then wait for word from us.
Arıkbuka will come to see you.
Where?
Selamunaleykum.
Aleykumselam. Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Glad to be here.
From Anatolia to Khorasan,
from Transoxiana,
all the way to Cumania,
all high white-bearded
who have heard our call
have come to the holy feast
to discuss the latest situation
in the great war
we are going to wage.
We are in contact with
many powerful tribes in Cumania.
Alps are ready and waiting
for war with the Mongolians.
And we know who to talk to
in the Turk tribes in Anatolia
and the state.
We've specified steep winter quarters
for the tribes to fall back to
when the war begins.
It would seem that everything is ready.
Now, the crucial thing...
is for the alliance with Berke Khan
to come to a conclusion.
For after this alliance is finalized,
it will be time to
ride horses, draw swords...
and start the insurrection.
I met with Berke Khan's spy Torumtay.
Even though he fell victim to
Arıkbuka's trap,
he told me that Berke Khan
would send us help for the great war.
The first phase of that help
has arrived in Anatolia, Ertuğrul Bey.
It is on its way
through Byzantium land towards us.
We now need to
take delivery of them intact.
For the Turk tribes
who will enter the great war
in Anatolia,
we will be able to procure
horses, weapons,
and all kinds of provisions,
thanks to this help.
The delivery location of the gold
was written in a secret document
Torumtay had with him.
We have that document.
The Mongols might try to stop the gold.
I will take precautions
and make sure they arrive.
It wasn't good
that Arıkbuka saw you with Torumtay.
Arıkbuka will report this to Hülagü.
He will tell him that...
you are in contact with Berke Khan.
He will make you a direct target.
You entered in a hurry, what's wrong?
A secret message has arrived.
From whom?
Berke Khan's marquee.
Open it.
So, Berke Khan is
secretly sending gold to Anatolia.
Ertuğrul.
Only you could receive it.
Berke Khan's men are headed towards Söğüt.
They have crates full of gold.
They are going to meet in Tilkikoyan.
Quickly gather your men.
Ertuğrul will not get that gold.
Yes, sir.
And I will follow Ertuğrul.
If he goes to get the gold...
we'll finish him off together.
Quickly send me the messenger.
It's time to send a letter to Hülagü Khan.
That letter...
will be the sword
that falls on Ertuğrul's neck.
Ertuğrul.
Go on conspiring with Berke Khan.
We are his eyes that see,
his ears that hear,
even his tongue that he speaks with.
Hülagü Khan will send his army upon us,
not only for me, but to destroy
the warm bridges we have formed,
by causing great struggles
and to kill the hope
we nurtured with our blood and our lives.
We need to stop Arıkbuka
from sending information to Hülagü Khan.
And for that
we have useful information for you,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We just received this information.
We learned that a caravansary
on the road to Engörü
was the meeting point of Hülagü's spies.
We identified
that various information from spies
is gathered here
and then sent to Hülagü Khan.
The information about this devil's den
that we discovered is written in detail
on that note.
This is just the information we need.
I will quickly send my alps there.
The information Arıkbuka sends
will never leave this caravansary.
I will not allow it
to reach Hülagü Khan at all costs.
However...
Mongol spies are not only in Anatolia.
Do you suspect something, Ertuğrul Bey?
Hülagü Khan has to this day
been informed of all the contact
we have made with Berke Khan.
Recently, they found out
that Berke Khan's spy Torumtay came here.
All this points to one thing.
There must be
a Mongol spy close to Berke Khan.
We also have grave suspicions
about this matter.
Another very crucial duty
falls on you now, Ertuğrul Bey.
Berke Khan's spy Torumtay was killed.
And in our land.
This will no doubt upset Berke Khan.
From now on,
it won't do to discuss this matter
over spies or emissaries.
You were the one
who always made contact with Berke Khan.
That's why
it would be most suitable
for you to go to Berke Khan in person
both to reveal the Mongolian spy
close to him,
and to bring our alliance
to a favorable conclusion.
Many hardships
lie in your path
and await you at your destination,
Ertuğrul Bey.
The path and traps
of great and holy struggles
are formidable.
And formidable paths
require brave-hearted warriors.
The darker and hazier the path is,
the brighter will be the light of victory
that we will shine
after we overcome it.
Many oppressed souls wait for us
to shine the light of salvation.
Lighting that lantern
falls on us.
Taking on the most formidable duties
on that path
is an honor for us.
It was none other than Ertuğrul
who snatched the secret chest,
took Keykavus away,
and killed Commander Alıncak.
He killed one of the most vital men
we had in Anatolia, Albastı.
And now, he plans to start a revolt
against us in Anatolia,
forming a pact with Berke Han in secret.
If we don't cull the Kayi Tribe
and Ertuğrul, their chieftain,
they will start a huge uprising
in Anatolia.
For the aforementioned reasons,
we are solemnly waiting
for our khan to send an army.
Take this letter to Tabriz at once.
You know who to give this to.
Come, Temüge.
Was that little doe burning of anger?
She was, and you should see it.
She is already consumed by the flames
of revenge. She only needs a nudge.
As my ancestors would say,
"Nobody destroys like a treacherous woman.
And nobody can restore
what she destroys."
Her heart must be blazing with revenge.
Let me have a talk with her...
so she can direct the fire
within her onto the Umuroğlu Tribe.
And the fire there should jump...
to its neighbor, the Kayi Tribe.
On this are written all the details
about the Mongolian spies,
as well as the caravansary
where they gather.
I understand, Bey.
Should we take our men with us?
You can't go with them.
You, Gündüz, and Günküt
will have to suffice.
Disguise yourselves.
-Be alert.
-Yes, Bey.
So, the letter says the Mongol army
might even invade Söğüt, huh?
That's why we must obtain whatever
information comes to the caravansary.
Turn the whole place upside down
if need be.
And don't return without that intel.
As you wish, Bey.
I will depart tomorrow to meet Berke Han.
Melikşah. Head to the Umuroğlu tribe
in advance.
Tell İlbilge Hatun to wait for me
at the camp.
I have important matters
to discuss with her.
As you command, Bey.
Bey.
What should we do afterwards?
Listen to me carefully.
Hello, everyone.
Hello, İlbilge Hatun.
The merchants we deal with
are awaiting the wool.
We must be faster and more agile.
Yes, İlbilge Hatun.
Go on.
Where have you been, Sırma?
Everyone started working
right after the burial.
I waited for everyone to leave, Sister.
It was our funeral, after all.
I took a detour because
I was afraid of the Mongols.
I started to fear everything.
Mongols even attempted to kill
Ertuğrul Bey. Imagine us.
Left alone, I got scared.
Is that Melikşah?
-Hello, İlbilge Hatun.
-Welcome, Melikşah, what happened?
Good news, İlbilge Hatun.
Ertuğrul Bey invited you to the hall.
He has important things to discuss
with you.
As the margrave commands.
I will be there in the evening. Thank you.
All right, İlbilge Hatun.
Since he's calling you personally,
it must be important.
The margrave probably wishes
to talk about the marriage.
-We must start the preparations at once.
-Not yet, Sırma.
Even if that's what it is about,
we still have to take care
of the business here before any wedding.
I must hand down my responsibility
in a manner befitting my position.
What do you mean, Sister?
Who will be the chieftain here
when I join the Kayi Tribe?
I must resolve that first.
I will accept Ertuğrul Bey's invitation.
And do what is necessary afterwards.
Thank God we came through
all that trouble, Bey.
Thank God indeed.
Why did you bother, mother?
I could have poured it.
Pouring sherbet for my son who
just returned from war is hardly a bother.
Here, Son.
Thank you, Mother.
Thank God.
Thank you.
My sons united as one
and defeated the cruel souls.
Son.
Your sword was able to cut down the cruel.
Our home is now in harmony.
Our tribe, our tents were happy,
but we are happier with you.
Thank God.
-Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselamun.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you.
-Welcome, Son.
-Thank you, Mother.
Now I can see two of my sons defeating
the cruel together, praise be!
What more could a mother wish for?
Come, Son, let me pour your sherbet.
-Thank you.
-Let me do it, mother.
Thank you, Selcan.
We swore to be worthy of you
and the blood our ancestors shed for us,
Mother.
For as long as Allah places obstacles
in our path,
we will take down many more cruel men.
We will go through
many more hellish flames,
to hopefully come to rest by your side,
and drink this cold sherbet.
I hope so, Son.
Selcan, dear.
Have the women prepare
the cauldrons and bring flour.
Let us prepare halvah
to celebrate our victory.
Very well, mother.
Excuse us.
-See you later.
-Right, Mother.
The gold Berke Han sent us
went across the Byzantine border.
That's quite all right.
If they had gone through Anatolia,
the Mongols could have ambushed them.
-That's still a possibility.
-How?
There's a Mongolian spy
close to Berke Han.
The spy must have warned the Mongols
that the gold would come.
The Mongols could set a trap
to prevent the gold from reaching us.
The document we found
in Torumtay's clothes
states that the delivery location
is the Fox Valley.
-Be careful.
-Yes, Brother, don't you worry.
That valley is vulnerable to ambushes.
We use this seal to communicate
with Berke Han.
When the men bringing the gold
see this seal, they will know.
Brother, the gold is of utmost importance.
We will send it all to the Turkmen tribes
in Anatolia.
We need it to buy
the necessary horses and weapons.
If something happens to that gold,
Turkmen tribes will be in danger.
And we will lose Berke Han's trust.
I'm aware of all this, Brother.
Don't worry about it.
I know it just looks like
some gold from the outside,
but I understand that it's vital
for the ultimate battle.
And with Allah's help,
I won't let that gold be destroyed.
Thank you.
I will depart to meet Berke Han tomorrow.
It's the last and hardest path
ahead of us,
before we can will light the fire for war.
We carry the prayers of a whole nation,
and face treacherous traps, cliffs,
and endless seas.
However, we made an oath.
To give hope by destroying the traps,
by climbing the mountains
and by crossing the seas.
We will light up Anatolia
with the fire in our hands.
Enough, Savcı.
Thank you.
-This soup was delicious.
-Thank you, uncle.
May it give you health.
Amen.
If you weren't here,
I have no idea who would cook for me.
-I appreciate it.
-Don't mention it, uncle.
Every child in the tribe
thinks of you as their uncle.
Thank you.
May I enter, Turgut Bey?
Come in, master.
Don't trouble yourself, Turgut Bey.
Rest.
I just wanted to see you
and see how you were doing.
I'm fine, master. Thank you.
They said you didn't leave my side.
Just like how it was in my dream...
you really were beside me.
I really appreciate it.
-I hope your dream is a good omen.
-Amen.
Amen.
I hope it is, too.
I was in heaven or something.
There were clear springs,
and flowers everywhere.
And then,
I saw you.
You were planting roses.
When I asked what it was for,
you said it was for our martyrs.
And then you told me about martyrdom.
God bless.
What a nice dream.
May it be a blessing from Allah.
Amen.
May Allah give us a life in good faith,
and martyrdom at the end.
-Amen.
I think about thousands of our martyrs
when I utter the word.
However, I don't know why,
but I remember a particular one.
I remembered many glorious stories,
but also a poor martyr that lived
when the prophet Muhammad was alive.
Tell us about him, master. Who was it?
A young man.
Sa'd as-Sülemi.
He had a dark skin.
That's why he was sad.
His Holiness Sa'd goes to see...
our prophet Muhammad one day.
He's deep in thought,
and a bit sad.
He asks thus, "O prophet,
would the color of my face prevent me
from getting into heaven?"
Our prophet Muhammad responds,
"I swear on the all-powerful Allah
that if you show reverence to Allah
and stay on the path of his messenger,
none of this shall prevent you
from going to heaven."
His Holiness Sa'd bared his soul
to the prophet Muhammad. He spoke thus,
"Then, O prophet, why do people
look down on me?
Why doesn't anybody give me
the hand of their daughter?"
And the prophet Muhammad answered thus,
"Go to the house of Amr ibn Vehb.
Tell him that I greet him and want him
to give his daughter to you in marriage."
His Holiness Sa'd went to
see Amr ibn Vehb at once,
as the prophet Muhammad had said.
He delivered the prophet Muhammad's words.
Amr wanted to think about it.
He said, "Let us discuss it,
and we will give you our answer later."
However, his daughter said,
"If the prophet saw it, then I see it too.
We don't have to discuss it, Father."
Thus, Amr agreed to him marrying
his daughter.
His Holiness Sa'd started
the preparations for the wedding.
When he went to the shopping district
to buy presents for his wife,
he heard something.
The crier of the prophet suddenly
called his subjects to fight
against the enemy that sieged the Muslims.
His Holiness Sa'd, who had been looking
forward to marrying for years,
and had at last realized that wish,
was confused.
Should he stay with his wife
and live a nice life,
or take up his sword and fight?
He made the hard choice.
He bought a sword with the money
he had saved for the presents.
He mounted his horse
and joined the army at once.
Fighting with all his might,
his Holiness Sa'd jumped off the horse,
rolled up his sleeves, and
continued fighting on foot.
At last, his Holiness Sa'd
fell as a martyr.
The prophet discovered his lifeless body.
In a sad tone, he said
to those around him:
"Take Sa'd's sword, his spear,
and his horse
and hand them to the poor woman
who wanted to marry him.
And tell her father that
the man he refused as a husband
for his daughter because of his skin tone
is now married to the houris in heaven."
Martyrdom is a holy position.
But to reach it,
one must live a worthy life.
His Holiness Sa'd rose above selfishness
and dedicated himself to the way of Allah.
And Allah provided him
with the best martyrdom.
He attained the good word
of the prophet Muhammad.
May Allah...
help us live our lives in that way,
and bless us with martyrdom
on his righteous path.
-Amen.
Wait over there, Temüge.
Come then, my doe.
Did you come to show off
your strength? Sit.
As I lifted my head, which I had never
bowed before, and gazed at the Sky God,
I saw dark clouds over great mountains.
I threw bone marrow into the fire
and asked the spirits
what this vision means.
They said it was the anguish of
a great doe grieving over a dead brother.
Do you want to take revenge that much?
Just like the fire that needs air
to grow in strength,
revenge is what I need.
My beating chest...
will only be soothed
when I've avenged my brother.
I will give you the opportunity
to avenge him. Don't worry.
How will you do that?
For us Mongols, comrades are
no mere stranger met on the road.
Albastı was a true comrade to us.
It's a matter of honor for us
to avenge him.
And don't you forget, Sırma Hatun.
A Mongol only lives for his honor.
And how will you do that?
Ertuğrul controls the whole region.
He has beaten and
incapacitated all of his enemies.
Ertuğrul is nothing but some margrave
being spoiled by the imbeciles here.
The bag on a Mongol's horse
contains the heads
of many chieftains, and even khans.
Everybody shall witness
the might of the Mongols.
I sent for the commander in Konya already.
They will march to Söğüt and show
the enemy how mighty the Mongols are.
I don't care what you do to Söğüt.
I want to avenge my brother.
And I know what I need to do.
And what might that be?
There will be a ceremony soon at the camp.
If I get to choose
the new chieftain rather than my sister,
we will be able to do anything we want.
A passionate woman sets
the whole world ablaze.
I like you, my doe.
Your duty is to remove your sister
from the seat of chieftain.
Obviously we need chiefdoms
that carry the torch for us.
But it won't be easy.
Everyone swore allegiance to my sister.
Plus, our chiefs are loyal
to Ertuğrul Bey as well.
And those who were loyal to my brother...
have lost their nerve after
what happened recently.
We must set them on fire first.
And I know how to do that.
How is that?
Gold.
You really are Albastı's sister.
You know that everything has a price,
be it things or people.
Temüge, prepare a chest of gold at once.
Start working towards
taking over your tribe,
and get it done before our armies arrive.
And don't forget that you have
the utmost support of the Mongols.
It must be the spy my father spoke about.
That must be him.
He must be committing some treachery
with that weasel face of his.
We will see, Gündüz Alp.
Thank you.
He's coming.
I will take it.
Oh! It smells nice. Thank you.
I prepared a nice room for you, as well.
I will show you to your room after dinner.
Good. Wait a second.
Take this...
and if we have a good night's rest,
you will get another in the morning.
May Allah bless you on your journey.
May Allah protect you and your loved ones.
Thank you.
That spy went after someone, Gündüz Alp.
Gives me the creeps.
Apparently, they will have a secret talk.
The one that came could be Arıkbuka's man.
Okay. Let's follow them.
You must reap what you sow,
and in Oğuz traditions,
everybody migrates someday.
The generous provide heaven on earth.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-Here, my dear.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
It's been a long while
since I saw such a nice dinner.
Thank God for bringing all of us together.
-Amen.
May Allah bless you
with many more years, Mother Hayme.
I hope you enjoy many more
nice dinners such as this.
I hope so, dear.
I also hope that we will be
even happier very soon.
There's a promise I made,
and a wish we will realize.
It's high time we conclude that.
We've been through a lot.
There's no reason to wait any longer.
From now on, İlbilge Hatun
shall be the lady of our tribe.
Being wedded to the legacy
of Süleyman Şah
and marrying a man of Ertuğrul Bey's
stature makes me happy.
There is abundance in marriage.
May you live in abundance.
Thank you, Brother.
-Amen.
-As you join the Kayi Tribe,
we will have gained Umur Bey's girl too.
The joy goes both ways, dear.
When you are in Ertuğrul Bey's tent,
you will shine like the sun,
İlbilge Hatun.
Let's tell the women
to start the preparations at once.
We are about to leave
for an important mission.
Start when I return, Selcan.
It's been a while since we lit a fire
and cooked to celebrate a marriage.
Come back soon, so that we can
start the preparations, Son.
They went in, Head Alp Bamsı.
There's no sound inside. They are
plotting something. Let's go in.
Shouldn't we wait, Head Alp Bamsı?
It could be dangerous.
We can't let the man we found
escape our grasp.
They will get away if we let them
out of the room.
We must attack while
we have them cornered.
Come on.
Günküt, are you sure they came in here?
I saw it with my own eyes,
Head Alp Bamsı.
They can't have disappeared into thin air.
What are you doing, Head Alp Bamsı?
What are you looking for on the walls?
There must be a secret passage
through the walls.
Otherwise, they couldn't
disappear like this.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Those moles must have used this hole.
Come on, let's go.
We must take this letter to Hülagü Khan.
Arıkbuka's orders are absolute.
I need to depart before sunrise.
You should eat and rest.
We will deal with the rest.
Arıkbuka protected Alıncak's dignity.
Turns out it was the Turk Ertuğrul Bey
who was behind everything.
This is the news they were going to send.
They can send their dead bodies
as news now.
Let's get back before our dinner
goes cold, everyone.
Come on.
Let's go.
We will marry when I'm back
from this mission, İlbilge Hatun.
But before that, we need you
to transfer the seat you are occupying.
I thought about that, too.
I inherited it from my forefathers,
and I want to leave it
to a suitable successor.
That's the right move, İlbilge Hatun.
But you must not let
your guard down in doing so.
Don't worry, I'm thinking things through.
There's still the threat of Arıkbuka.
The Mongols could sustain their reign
over this land with the men they buy.
I doubt they'd dare attempt anything.
What about Sırma Hatun?
What does she think about this?
I had a word with her.
She will do nothing
without telling me first.
She knows I won't tolerate any mistakes.
You should still compare the candidates
for the chiefdom thoroughly.
Designate a chief who's close to you.
Support him in the meeting.
I have someone in mind.
I will talk to him at once.
Did you send for me, Sırma Hatun?
What happened?
As you know, my sister will be
wedded off to the Kayi Tribe soon.
That's why we will have
a chiefdom meeting.
As a loyal chief of Beybolat Bey,
I thought you wouldn't want to give
his seat to those who betrayed him.
The untimely death of Beybolat Bey
saddened us all.
None of us would have wanted that.
However, the truth is out there.
We have no chance against a chief
that gets İlbilge Hatun's support.
I see you give up easily, Taşkun Bey.
But I thought you were a man
who could overcome any difficulty.
And I think it'd suit you
to be the chieftain.
But I see that Ertuğrul
destroyed your hopes.
My poor brother, he trusted in men
who wouldn't even avenge him.
If you want to avenge your brother,
then tell me how we can break through
the solid doors of loyalty
our chiefs have for
Ertuğrul and İlbilge Hatun.
I have just the right key...
to lock many doors,
and open other solid ones.
This should convince the chiefs.
But I'm not convinced yet.
Chiefdom is a burning seat to sit on.
Why would I risk burning myself?
I like to stay chilled, Sırma Hatun.
Would my heart give you that chill?
Why do you look surprised?
I know you've been eyeing me for years.
You wouldn't dare ask for my hand
since I was Umur Bey's daughter.
However...
this is your chance.
Become a chieftain and take the girl.
What's wrong, Osman?
What are you brooding over?
You know what.
My father is going out
on a mission again.
It must be an important mission,
since he's all fired up.
I wonder where he's going.
He never tells us.
I'm coming in.
What is it, my boys?
What are you
talking about between brothers?
You said you were going
on a mission, Father.
That it would be a long journey.
We'd like to know where you are going.
Come here.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Father.
You often tell us exactly what to do,
while other times you say nothing.
Why do you have to keep
where you are going a secret from us?
It's a necessity of the seat I sit on.
I can't mix up my roles
as a father and as a chieftain.
If you want to be a chieftain,
you must know how to be discreet.
Plus, our great prophet says: "Hold
your tongue, and you shall be delivered."
Speech is silver, but silence is gold.
Words are of such value that
they should never be wasted.
We represent a great cause,
for which we wouldn't hesitate
for a second to lay down our lives.
We can't just utter anything
to anyone and anywhere.
It's not because I don't trust you.
It's just a matter of being a chieftain.
In the seat of a chieftain,
one must keep secrets.
You will both become chiefs in the future.
Decide what to tell and to whom,
not based on your selfish judgement,
but in a manner befitting a chief.
Got it, Father.
Thank you.
Dear.
Spring is upon us.
Everyone in the tribe has started
preparations for the spring celebrations.
They're getting ready
to go up to the highlands.
I already miss our tribe.
What's wrong, Selcan?
Do you feel unwell here?
Not at all, dear.
I consider this tribe as my own.
Mother Hayme makes me feel
like one her daughters.
But my fate is tied with my own tribe.
Then why the yearning now, my love?
It's not just now, dear.
I've always had that yearning.
My İltekin.
I miss him.
I always hoped he'd come here,
following us.
But I couldn't see him here, either.
I buried a son under the earth,
and the other within my heart.
You refuse to talk about İltekin too.
How is he? Does he get along well
with his uncles?
Of course he does.
He grew up to be a fine man,
he's so reliable.
We fought the Mongols many times,
and never once has he backed down.
God bless.
They say a son takes after his father.
He must be a nimble, unflinching
man like you.
But I miss him so much.
Once we are through with all the trouble,
we'll meet our son, too.
I hope so, dear.
May I enter, sister?
Come in, Sırma.
What happened? What are you
so alarmed about? Is there news?
On the contrary.
Do you have any news, sister?
You resent me, but I'm waiting
for your news, worrying.
I told you to stop bringing it up.
But you won't understand, will you?
Chiefdom is one thing,
sisterhood is another.
I have a sister, too, and she's getting
married. How could I contain my joy?
What does Ertuğrul Bey say about it?
Tell me, do you want me
to die of curiosity?
He wants to carry out his promise.
I knew he'd do that.
Let me send news to the women,
and have them start preparations.
After all...
our crown princess is marrying
the chieftain of the Umuroğulları tribe.
Ertuğrul Bey is going out
on an important mission.
Once he's back safe and sound,
we'll start the preparations.
We'll choose the new chieftain of
our tribe. We'll hold a meeting tomorrow.
The future of our tribe comes first.
Once that's fulfilled, the rest is easy.
You know best, sister.
State your wish and we shall follow.
But I'll check our supplies just in case.
I want to sew a fitting wedding
dress for my sister.
Allah, help me come back
from this hardship safe and in glory.
The future and hopes of my nation
depend on this journey of mine.
Please help me carry this burden
on my shoulders in a fitting manner.
Don't let me humiliate myself,
and lose to our enemies.
Amen.
May Allah accept your prayers.
Our men are ready and waiting for us.
Thank you, brother.
I, too, once left the camp
to resist the Mongols in the mountains.
And I looked back
at my tent just like that.
You may not return, brother.
But if I ever returned, I swore
to punish all the cruel bastards.
When I'm back, we'll fulfill your oath
together, brother.
I hope so, brother.
I have a long journey ahead.
Will you give me your blessing?
God bless you.
-May I enter, sir?
-Come in, Turgut.
Sir.
I heard you were departing
on a long journey.
I'm ready, too.
I can't just rest when
you are going on a mission.
My brave brother.
You must heal your wounds.
No missions until you heal.
If you want me to rest, we often
sleep on the horses on our way to battle.
I shall rest there again.
In times of hardship, a brave man
can't rest, as they say.
I'm well enough to swing my axe
and fight, sir.
Plus, if I don't come along,
I know my wounds will stop healing.
You know me well, sir.
Let me come with you.
God bless my brother.
Fine. Come with me.
But stay with my brother, Gündoğdu,
and not with me.
My journey is much too long.
It'd be better for you to
stay with Gündoğdu.
Thank you, sir.
As you command.
You sent for me, İlbilge Hatun?
Battal Bey, you are my father's comrade.
There's an important issue.
I'd like to consult you and
make my plans accordingly.
Your word is absolute. Do tell me.
As you know, I represent the chieftain
in place of my brother.
But soon, I'll be the wife of
the Kayi chieftain.
I'd like to choose the real chieftain
in our meeting.
I want to choose someone
that knows us and our traditions
for the seat of chieftain.
You've been a loyal subject
of my father since you became a soldier.
I've no doubt that you'll
make a great chieftain.
It's an honor for me, İlbilge Hatun.
But once the issue becomes who gets to
sit on that seat, it's a free for all.
Plus, people still can't get over
the fact that Beybolat Bey is dead.
Do you think the chiefs would accept me?
Don't worry about it, Battal Bey.
You have my support and Ertuğrul Bey's.
We can't hand this seat to someone
we don't trust at a time like this.
You should talk to the other chiefs.
And let them know about my decision.
As you command, İlbilge Hatun.
Arıkbuka!
My prey got away because of you.
If it's a trivial matter,
you become my prey.
It's about Ertuğrul and Gündoğdu.
-What about them?
-They left their camp.
-They're going in different directions.
-Which way?
Ertuğrul goes east,
while Gündoğdu goes north.
If Gündoğdu is going north,
it means he'll meet Berke Han's men.
What about Ertuğrul?
If Ertuğrul Bey is not going
to take Berke Han's cargo,
he must be going somewhere
even more important.
Where could that be?
If he's going east...
it must be Berke Han.
Plus, Berke's spy Torumtay is dead.
He'll want to meet Berke Han personally.
If that's true, he's no doubt
going to cause trouble.
You've given me
a better prey than that bird.
We can't let Ertuğrul pass.
We must stop him at all costs.
Our men at Fox Valley should
take care of Gündoğdu.
Make sure they catch him properly.
We'll go after Ertuğrul.
We're going to set up a trap for him.
So he'll know his death
awaits him at the end.
Thank God we're going to have
the wife of our chieftain around.
That's not what I'm looking forward to,
but that she's the right person.
You are right, mother.
Did you notice? When Ertuğrul Bey
announced his marriage decision,
İlbilge Hatun looked down
in embarrassment.
İlbilge Hatun has a pure heart, dear.
She has the acumen to be
the wife of a chieftain,
and the modesty to be a fitting
daughter of a chieftain.
I know for a fact she will be
a fitting woman for our tribe.
Ertuğrul brought up his sons
all by himself.
He was both a mother and a father to them.
I had fears for a long time,
that Ertuğrul would get old alone.
Once İlbilge Hatun came along,
all my fears dispersed.
I can die happy now, dear.
Don't say that.
Allah will bestow you a long life.
They're here.
But we can't let our guard down.
I took the necessary precautions,
Gündoğdu Bey.
We are in control.
Well done.
This is the meeting place.
Did you take precautions?
Don't worry.
Our men came to lie in wait around us.
Good.
They will mistake us for
Berke Han's men at first.
We won't lift a finger until
the very last moment.
Then, we'll get them
and catch Gündoğdu alive. Got it?
Here we go.
Did you do as I said, Temüge?
We did.
Everything is ready for the attack.
Let's go, then.
I'll make up for the prey I missed
in the forest by hunting Ertuğrul.
Where are your goods coming from?
From overseas.
Take the chests, everyone.
Did you think you could
take the gold and get away?
We'll send your heads
in those boxes to Berke Han!
We'll see who loses their heads!
Attack!
God is righteous!
This place has no floods or storms, sir.
How could these trees fall down?
It's Arıkbuka!
I told you I would make life
unbearable for you in this land, Ertuğrul.
I'll haunt you no matter where you run.
It seems you have yet
to understand that you can't hold me down.
So I shall beat it into you
with my sword.
Did you think I wouldn't foresee
your ambush?
It's you who is ambushed.
Attack!
Damn it.
Keep wasting your time here, Ertuğrul.
I'll make this journey a living hell.
You have yet to see my worst trap.
You know what kind of
predicament we are in now.
On the orders of the margrave,
Ertuğrul Bey,
I've been representing
the Umuroğulları Tribe.
However, it is time to elect
the real chieftain.
Who are the candidates
for chieftain of our tribe?
I am.
And I am.
There are two candidates for the seat.
As the representative of the seat,
I ask you in the name of everyone here.
What do you hope to gain
by becoming the chieftain?
We've lost our chieftain
in the most exemplary way.
My wish is to
avoid making the same mistakes
and follow our traditions,
hand in hand with Ertuğrul Bey.
That's all I have to say.
What about you, Taşkın Bey?
Tradition is absolute, for sure.
However, I don't believe
dominion alone would be enough.
I side with the interests of
my people, pastures for our cattle,
and markets for our goods.
In short, I'll conduct
my duty in such a way
as to protect our own interests.
That's all I have to say.
In this meeting we talk,
and we find the truth as we talk.
Everybody has a say in it,
and the chiefs make their decisions.
But let me say just this.
Chiefdom is not carried out for interests,
but for justice.
Not to mention, following tradition
is the ultimate goal.
That's what Battal Bey and I think.
Now, the choice is yours.
Hakkı, see if there's anybody else left.
It was obvious that Arıkbuka
would claim the gold.
The death of Berke Han's spy,
and the fact that Arıkbuka
snatched the gold from us...
was not good on our part.
If we can't take back the gold from
Arıkbuka, we'll lose Berke Han's trust.
And put the alliance in jeopardy.
It'll make things harder for Ertuğrul.
We'll take the gold back at any cost.
We'll search every nook and cranny
in the mountains if we must.
We won't return before we find that gold.
All right.
Got it, sir.
Come, Ertuğrul.
Damn it.
I must leave at once.
That heathen will go right back into
his den. We'll follow him.
And take back our gold.
We will not only take our gold,
but also destroy that den.
Come on, let's go.
Who wants to see Battal Bey
as chieftain of the Umuroğulları tribe?
Just two?
Who wants to see Taşkun Bey
as chieftain of the Umuroğulları tribe?
There's no need for us to talk much.
You know what to say.
Thank you, sir.
I want you to repay me in the meeting.
The more loyalty you have,
the richer you get.
If you give me your vote,
when I sit on the throne of chiefdom,
you'll get more of this.
Our chiefs have made their decision.
The rest depends on you, İlbilge Hatun.
As our meeting dictates,
the new chieftain of the Umuroğulları
Tribe is henceforth Taşkun Bey.
God bless.
Enough running around.
Now is the time for justice.
You failed to get a word out
of me despite your best efforts.
However, I'll make sure you
talk at all costs.
You will do nothing.
You'll die here, while your brother,
Gündoğdu, dies there.
Did you think I wouldn't foresee this?
We'll destroy your ambushes.
I'll also find out who it was
that gave you information...
on Berke Han's side.
You know about it.
But I'll say nothing else.
Hülagü Khan will send his armies
to trample this land.
I know you were going
to meet Berke Han, too.
You'll never make it there.
The information you sent to Hülagü Khan
will never reach him.
My men have already confiscated
that information.
And you shall perish
at the tip of my sword.
The chief should pass chiefdom down to me.
It should be you who gives me
the sword of chiefdom.
-Congratulations, sir.
-Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
My horse is right outside...
and my chieftain's sword to hand...
Now all I need is a woman.
Now it's time I took one.
What do you mean, Taşkun Bey?
I have nothing to hide.
I'm acting within my power as a bey.
After all,
now that I'm the chieftain,
I need a woman from the bloodline
of a chieftain.
On the commandment of Allah...
I'd like to marry Sırma Hatun.
What do you say, Sırma Hatun?
Do you want to be the wife
of the chieftain of Umuroğlu Tribe?
Being the wife of a chieftain...
befits the daughter of a chieftain.
I accept the offer.
What's this? What happened?
That damned Ertuğrul's men
came out of nowhere.
Gündoğdu ambushed us and killed everyone.
-Did anyone see you?
-No.
I played dead.
Come, let's get your wound treated.
It's time.
It's like you said, Turgut,
it's time to destroy their den.
Attack!
This is as far as you go, Arıkbuka.
If you don't talk...
I'll make you wish you were dead.
Now, tell me.
Who is the spy close to Berke Han?
Who sent the information?
Just when you think you've got me...
I'll see the fear in your face now
when you realize this is a trap.
I said I'd make this a hellish journey.
This will be your grave, Ertuğrul.
It's time to bury you now.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from SubtitleDB.org