Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.SubtitleDB.org today
We won't take him captive now.
We're here, sir!
Kill him!
Allah is great!
This is not the end
of your troubles, Ertuğrul.
You will die on this journey.
Sir, Abdurrahman and our men
are still fighting. We followed you here.
We can't let that bastard run.
There might be another trap.
You go and help Abdurrahman, now!
-As you command, sir.
On your horses.
-We are being attacked!
-Where did they come from?
You were followed, you clueless fool!
Come on, everyone! Allah is great!
Allah is great!
Come on!
We will take the gold quickly.
Get the chests in the cave as well.
We'll take them to the designated place.
Come on.
The fact that Taşkun Bey
is now the chieftain
does not oblige you to
accept his hand in marriage, Sırma.
You're struggling in vain, İlbilge Hatun.
Your sister made her decision
completely unbiased.
Keep your nose out of our conversation.
I want to hear her say
she wants to marry you.
I can't turn down this prize
that fate itself offered me.
I'll accept Taşkun Bey's offer,
and carry on...
our traditions and cause, sister.
There, you heard it.
You no longer have command
of this tribe, or this tent.
You are not the chief of
Umuroğlu Tribe now...
merely a visitor.
This road that you littered with traps
will lead to your own death!
It's not Arıkbuka.
He played
one of the devil's tricks again, sir.
-Where is Arıkbuka?
-What's the hurry?
Wherever you go, Arıkbuka
shall find you himself.
Should we track him, sir?
He must have erased his tracks.
Going after him is a waste of time.
We'll carry on our journey.
We should go back to
Abdurrahman and the others.
Understood, sir.
I set the game, I manage it,
and I'll finish it as I like, Ertuğrul.
What happened, Temüge?
Where are the others?
We watched the skirmish
from afar as you ordered.
They were all sent to heaven, Arıkbuka.
If they couldn't beat the enemy,
they're better off dead.
We still have work to do, Temüge.
Ertuğrul survived this ambush.
-But we will lay more traps.
-What will you do now?
Ertuğrul found out about the spy
close to Berke Han.
If that spy is exposed, we are done for.
That's why we'll set
the last and greatest trap.
Are we going to send this plan to him?
Ertuğrul finds out about news
we send to Hülagü Khan.
That's why I won't send anyone.
I'll go personally.
I'll get there before Ertuğrul.
That way, our spy won't be exposed.
And we'll prevent the deal
Ertuğrul wants to agree with Berke Han.
And I'll kill him before I'm back.
We should gather our men, then.
You shall stay here, Temüge.
I'll take some men with me.
What should I do here?
Our men captured the goods
Berke Han sent Ertuğrul.
You must protect them.
If something happens to them,
kill yourself before I'm back, Temüge.
Keep in touch with Sırma,
sister of Albastı.
She'll be useful.
As you wish, Arıkbuka.
Sir.
-Are there any wounded?
-No, sir.
We killed them all.
Well done.
Arıkbuka knows that
we're going to meet Berke Han.
He will surely set another trap.
He may even get in touch with his spies
over there.
Sir, could he set a trap
on the ship we're going to take?
Everything has been arranged
beforehand, Bamsı.
He can't even find out
where we are going to take the ship.
It's likely that our struggle
with Arıkbuka will continue on
across Berke Han's lands as well.
We must be prepared for any and
all kinds of treacherous traps.
Be alert at all times.
A tiny mistake now will cost us dearly.
-As you command, sir.
Let's go.
Come on!
Calm down.
Take a breath and think, madam.
How can I calm down, Mengü?
How could all those chiefs...
choose Taşkun Bey over Battal Bey,
who I've been supporting?
All the chiefs pledged their loyalty
to you. It should be impossible.
There must be a reason.
They must have been
enticed by something big.
Nonetheless, I won't let this one slip.
What are you suspecting?
I think there's a plot
behind it all, Mengü.
And I think Sırma has a hand in it.
Why do you think that?
Sırma accepted Taşkun Bey's
offer of marriage.
And she shoved it in my face.
Taşkun Bey asked,
and Sırma Hatun accepted.
It's not that easy, Mengü.
It's obvious that Sırma knew
about this marriage beforehand.
She accepted the offer
since he became the chieftain.
So, she must have known he'd be elected.
How could they be so sure that
Taşkun Bey would be elected?
Now I see what you're getting at.
I'll solve it all.
I'll find out what Taşkun Bey and
Sırma have going on here.
I'll follow them like a shadow.
You got what you wanted, Sırma Hatun.
Now all we need for you to be my wife...
is to have a wedding ceremony.
Of course, I'd like to become
the wife of a chieftain,
but I must make sure that the man
who will take me is a worthy man.
What does that mean?
You know what. I'm telling you
to prove yourself, Taşkun Bey.
Do you doubt me as a chieftain?
I'm not sure.
But if you want to prove your strength,
then you need to carry out your duty
like my father Umur Bey.
And how is that?
What duty would that be?
Collecting taxes.
You know that we came here
on the orders of our government.
That's only possible with a decree.
Where is it?
That is a warrant to collect taxes
from the Umuroğlu Tribe
signed by the sultan himself.
Now...
it's time you proved
if you are worthy of me,
and how strong a chieftain you are.
You shall prove your strength
to the Kayi Tribe first.
One can hunt birds with wits.
However...
one can hunt the lion only with strength.
-What happened here?
-They were attacked.
Check the gold at once.
There is nothing inside.
Damn it! Incompetent idiots!
What should we do now?
What do we say to Arıkbuka?
The only way is to find the gold.
Or Arıkbuka will shred us all to pieces.
Everyone is dead.
There is no one left alive.
Sırma Hatun.
Arıkbuka said she'd be of use to us.
Now is the time.
Look what happened in
the Umuroğlu Tribe, Mother.
Somebody other than İlbilge Hatun's
candidate was elected chieftain.
There's a cunning game behind it all.
It should come to light sooner or later.
What happened, Mother?
What are you brooding over?
Things are going awry in the Umur Tribe.
I was just bothered by the news.
Is it something serious?
İlbilge Hatun called a chiefdom vote.
But her candidate wasn't chosen.
The tradition is clear.
Whoever the chiefs see fit,
sits on that seat.
True.
But there is something strange
about it, Gündoğdu.
The elected Taşkun Bey wants
Sırma Hatun as his wife.
How about that.
Shameless of her
to take up the offer, huh?
I have faith in our traditions, Son.
However, after all they have gone through,
it's not good news that
they are still opposing İlbilge.
Did all the chiefs decide
to pull a trick on İlbilge Hatun?
They must be trying to take
advantage of Ertuğrul's absence.
Let us head there with Turgut
and see the situation with our own eyes.
We can also visit the new chieftain,
and congratulate him.
Excuse me.
Help this poor man, please!
Help this poor man.
Why did you come here?
We need to talk, Sırma Hatun.
Talk now.
We can't do it here. It's urgent.
In the name of Allah.
May Allah bless you.
Where do we meet?
Come to Albastı's grave.
I'll come, wait for me.
Thank you, lady.
Help this poor man.
I wonder what you were talking about
in secret for so long?
There must be something going on,
since she left the camp right afterwards.
I'll find out what
you're playing at, Sırma.
Come on.
Sir.
It's been so long since we last
saw the sea.
I've never traveled by the sea before.
When I think about those who
rule over the seas in ships...
I wonder if we'll ever
be like that, Father.
The oath that was passed down
to us from Oghuz Ata...
says, "Conquer more seas and rivers."
Those days shall come, too.
We'll raise our flag on the mast,
and set sail.
We'll ride the winds and
cut through those huge waves.
We'll conquer overseas lands.
We will need sails and winds, of course.
But those are just tools, son.
In truth, what allows us to travel
across land and sea alike is Allah.
As long as we walk on Allah's path
and work hard for his cause,
we shall pass through many
rivers and seas.
I hope so.
I hope so, sir.
What happened, Temüge?
What happened at the tribe?
Everything is going according to plan.
With the help of the gold I got from you,
my man was chosen chieftain.
The rest shouldn't prove too difficult.
That's exactly what
I needed to hear, Sırma Hatun.
Look at that crooked beggar.
Who knows what you speak
about over Beybolat's grave.
Tell me why you called me here.
I need a lot of men
for a very important mission tomorrow.
And not just any men.
They must be loyal to Albastı.
What do you need them for?
We'll deal a huge blow to the Kayis.
Oh!
And you have a lot of gold
to gain from this.
Leave it to me, Temüge.
The trouble of my friend
is a trouble of mine.
And if I can strike the Kayi
and earn gold for it,
there is nothing that can stop me.
You know the Mongols don't
like to stay in debt, Sırma Hatun.
Once we get this done,
we shall do whatever is necessary.
Leave it to me, Temüge.
You should also know that Umur
never let down their friends.
We've come here in the name
of Ertuğrul Bey, Taşkun Bey.
We wanted to congratulate you,
and also to consolidate relations
between the two tribes.
I was going to visit you.
May it benefit us all, Gündoğdu Bey.
Why were you planning to visit us?
Things cannot remain as they are.
I intend to establish a new order
in the Umuroğulları tribe.
I was coming to inform you
of my decisions.
As long as your new order does not
disturb the rules of the frontier beylik,
nothing will disturb us. But...
it must be one based on justice.
You need have no concerns
about that, Turgut Bey.
We now just await the arrival
of our margrave, Ertuğrul Bey.
Why are you waiting for Ertuğrul Bey?
A duty of taxation has been bestowed
upon the Umuroğulları by the state.
For years, the Umuroğulları
have collected no tax.
There was a dispute between the two
tribes over this issue of taxation.
Pushing this matter
might not be a good idea.
I'm not in a hurry.
But I want to do it in time.
The taxation period is approaching.
And the state expects its taxes.
This is not some worthless scrap
of paper that I hold.
These are the state's orders.
We know better than you
what an order from the state entails.
You should know us better, too.
If you make a decision without consulting
Ertuğrul Bey in his role as margrave,
then the disputes between
our two tribes will continue.
And this time,
it will be much worse, trust me.
My orders are the orders I now hold.
And I will discuss them
only with Ertuğrul Bey.
I will talk to him about this
when the time comes.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you.
We will make landfall close to
Berke Khan's hunting ground.
Very good.
How long will the journey take?
We won't lower the sails. We will get
there tomorrow morning, God willing.
-Your horses will be waiting for you.
-Very good.
Leave two alps with the horses.
Prepare for our departure.
-As you command, my Bey.
What are you up to, Sırma?
Alps!
Where are you both going?
Is it something important?
No, İlbilge Hatun.
Then what's the rush?
We're just attending
to our usual duties, İlbilge Hatun.
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Sırma Hatun doesn't speak so passionately
when she's discussing everyday duties.
We are to welcome a trading caravan
arriving tomorrow, İlbilge Hatun.
That's all.
All right then. Good day.
A trading caravan, is it?
Am I so gullible?
I know how to learn the truth behind it.
We don't like Taşkun Bey's
attitude very much, İlbilge Hatun.
He showed us the state's taxation order.
He will start collecting taxes soon.
This is not about collecting taxes.
He wants to show us his teeth.
He wants to make his presence felt.
How did this man become
bey of the Umuroğulları
instead of your candidate?
Taşkun Bey's election
was organized in advance.
He's obviously planning to do
something over your heads.
We need to find out who has given him
such courage, that is the key.
That is what I came here
to discuss with you.
Daughter, has something happened
in the village to raise your suspicions?
I'm suspicious of Sırma, Mother.
Taşkun Bey wouldn't have been
able to do all this on his own.
But I'm afraid Sırma is working
with someone we don't know.
-Who could it be?
-Sırma met with a man in secret today.
Who? Did you recognize him, İlbilge Hatun?
No, I didn't.
He came disguised as a beggar.
Then he met Sırma again
at Beybolat Bey's grave.
Then he must be a spy.
There is no other explanation.
Had he ever been to your village
before, İlbilge Hatun?
I've never seen him there before.
That's why we need to find him fast.
It isn't only the Umuroğulları who are
in danger, everyone is threatened by this.
I came to ask for your help.
Rest assured, dear.
Your problems are our problems.
İlbilge Hatun.
You have always stood by our side
in the pursuit of truth and justice.
We will do everything
in our power to help you.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
Now, is there anything you can tell us
which may help us find this man?
I saw Sırma giving instructions
to some alps after talking to him.
Apparently, a caravan is coming tomorrow.
They are to welcome it.
But no such caravan is due
to come to the village.
Whatever she was discussing with
that man must be connected to it.
We will take position near
the Umuroğulları village tomorrow.
We will follow the alps when they leave.
Let's see who's behind all this.
-May I come in?
-Come in, Melikşah.
Budak. What are you doing here?
My Bey, I come from the village.
Sungur Tekin Bey has an urgent letter
for you.
Excuse me.
Of course, my dear.
Gündoğdu? What's happened?
I didn't see much of you today.
-Where were you?
-Our friends sent word.
I went to ask what they wanted.
Well. Who are these friends?
It's better you don't know
too much, Taşkun Bey.
Know that you owe your title to them,
that's enough.
I'm aware of everything, Sırma Hatun.
So tell me, what do they want?
They want our alps
in return for their help.
Moreover, they say
they will reward us for it.
That means lots of gold for our coffers.
Talk of gold from the mouth
of an intelligent woman.
What else could I want?
Stop fooling around and tell me what
happened with Turgut and Gündoğdu.
I told them what Umur bey
should have told them.
I said I was going to collect taxes
and that I'm waiting for Ertuğrul.
What did they do?
First, they tried to intimidate me.
Then, when they saw they weren't going to
be able to walk all over me, they left.
Good. You behaved just as I hoped.
They apparently mistook the insignia
hanging from our tent for a lamb.
They will realize their mistake
when the ram's horns hit them.
My son, İltekin... fought the Mongols.
Dündar went after him.
It was chaos, Mother.
İltekin. The Mongols have already
taken one of my children, Mother.
I could not bear to lose another child.
-Calm down, dear.
-Calm down, wife, he hasn't been captured.
But we've had no word from him.
Dündar has gone after him.
He won't come back without him,
believe me. Don't worry.
Dear.
But it means we must set out at dawn.
They're sure to attack the villages again.
We have to be ready.
You're going away again so soon, Son?
Don't be sad, Mother.
Even if I go, Dündar will
no doubt return soon.
He misses you very much.
What about the great war
against the Mongols?
Won't you be with us for that,
Gündoğdu Bey?
I will join the war with the tribes
in the east, Artuk Bey.
Dündar will be here while I'm gone.
He's a tough and brave bey.
You won't notice my absence, trust me.
Turgut, we will leave at dawn.
You will stay with İlbilge Hatun.
You and her will do
what we discussed together.
All right, Gündoğdu Bey.
My mother.
We were shaded by your tent
and warmed by your fire.
Give me your blessing.
My dear, beautiful daughter.
You put up with all our problems,
all our trials.
You weren't just a bride,
but a daughter and a friend.
You must give me your blessing.
Mother.
You have it a thousand times.
Uncle.
I wish we could always live
in the same village and the same tent.
Mother, give me your blessing.
You have it, Son.
My Süleyman Shah named you after the sun.
But you've never had
a chance to enjoy its warmth.
God willing, you will defeat the enemy
and finally feel its warmth on your face,
and be happy in your village
and in your tent, my son.
I hope so, Mother.
God willing, Mother. God willing.
Uncle.
Give my greetings to my brother İltekin
and my uncles Dündar and Sungur Tekin.
I will, Nephew. I will.
Come then, my brave ones. Let's go.
Your horses are ready for you,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We've sent word to Berke Khan
to expect you.
He's hunting.
Very good. We can take it from here.
Safe journey.
My Bey.
Once before, many years ago,
we crossed the sea
to go after the Mongols.
But Berke Khan isn't like those Mongols.
We know him to be an honest Muslim.
That he fought his kin, Hülagü Khan,
for justice, means we can be sure of that.
My Bey.
Berke Khan's messenger,
Torumtay, was killed.
Won't that be a problem for us?
We came here to prevent
possible setbacks, Abdurrahman.
Torumtay's death is important, however.
Berke Khan is a mighty, just and honest
ruler, but he is also a demanding one.
It will be no easy task
to explain his envoy's death to him
and convince him of the culprit.
But every difficulty has its own solution.
It is our duty to tell him the truth.
Allah will ensure he trusts our word,
Abdurrahman.
-Let's get to it.
-Very good, my Bey.
Come on, brothers.
My Khan.
Forgive my wondering, but...
we've been hunting with
our army for almost a month.
And while there are many animals
you could have hunted
for their meat or fur,
you have only hunted crows.
Why is that?
This crow is a mimic.
It can mimic a wolf's howl, a lion's roar.
It can even mimic a man's voice
to mislead a hunter.
When it sees a dangerous
hunter approaching,
it immediately makes
the sound of a predator.
The other predators hear it and then kill
the hunter they've been lured towards.
This bird gets rid of its hunter...
and then eats his flesh.
You must clear these birds
from the forest first,
so you won't be hunted while you hunt.
Where is the hunting army?
We have encircled the three hills,
my Khan.
We're closing in.
But the game has managed to escape
from some of the army units.
They've let the game escape?
Do these men think
that hunting is just a pastime?
Do they not understand that hunting
replicates the conditions of war?
My Khan, visitors from Seljuk lands
have come here to meet with you.
-Ambassadors?
-Ertuğrul Bey, bey of the Kayıs, my Khan.
-Ertuğrul Bey?
-Why would he come in person, my Khan?
It must be something very important
if Ertuğrul Bey himself has come.
-Bring Ertuğrul Bey to my tent.
-As you command, my Khan.
I want you with me
when I talk to him, Kıyat.
Punish the men who let the game escape.
Those who couldn't contain the game today
will never hold the enemy tomorrow.
We're returning to the hunting tent!
The Kayıs took your bey from you.
And now they have stolen our gold,
the gold that would have
made your tribe rich.
Will we make the Kayıs pay?
-Yes!
Ertuğrul deserves to die.
We will avenge our bey!
We will avenge him!
They might be what remains of the Mongols.
But what is Sırma Hatun doing with them?
What are you up to, Sırma?
If you are following my brother's path...
I will never forgive you.
I have been hunting birds with Berke Khan.
I catch my prey earlier than he does,
and I always will, Kıyat.
Berke Khan isn't after
the small birds he shoots, Arıkbuka.
He uses them as bait
for much bigger prey.
Ertuğrul came to see Berke Khan.
And you followed him all the way back.
Tell me, Arıkbuka, what's going on?
Ertuğrul knows about you.
Don't be alarmed,
he doesn't know your name.
He's bound to tell Berke Khan.
It's your job to take
all necessary precautions.
I'm just keeping you informed.
Did you get your hands on
the supplies Berke Khan sent to Ertuğrul?
-We have it all.
-And Torumtay?
Dead.
His envoy has been killed
and the supplies he sent stolen.
Berke Khan won't like this one bit.
I know what to do.
Berke Khan has gone
to great lengths for this alliance.
If he still trusts Ertuğrul despite
everything that's happened...
there's only one option left.
Ertuğrul and Berke Khan die.
The reason I am here is to kill Ertuğrul.
You take care of Berke Khan.
I hope you make a better job
of killing Ertuğrul here
than you did in Anatolia, Arıkbuka.
Ertuğrul... He's tough.
But my teeth are tougher. Don't worry.
You have to learn how to cook
your game better, Arıkbuka.
Otherwise, it might break those teeth.
Umur alps!
Drop your weapons and surrender.
Why would we surrender to you?
That man is a Mongol.
You know what happens to those...
who work with Mongols.
Don't make the same mistake as your bey.
Don't die as traitors, surrender!
Will you listen to the woman
who betrayed your tribe,
or will you avenge your bey?
Revenge!
-May I come in, my Khan?
-Enter, Kıyat.
Where were you, Kıyat?
The hunt only happens once a year.
-You should enjoy it.
-State affairs, my Khan.
As men who have dedicated themselves
to the state, we can never be at ease.
We may only rest when the state apparatus
is running smoothly.
When my brother Batu Khan
founded this state,
the top of his tent was decorated in gold.
It symbolized the sun
shining over our state.
For our state, you are a ray
of light from that sun, Kıyat.
Thank you, my Khan.
I came here to inform you of news
we have just received from Anatolia.
I'm listening. What is the news?
The aid you sent to Ertuğrul Bey...
has been seized by Hülagü Khan's men.
-How did this happen?
-I don't know.
But...
Ertuğrul Bey has obviously
messed up the arrangement.
It's clear now why he's here.
The supplies we sent have ended up
in the hands of our enemy.
Who knows how Hülagü Khan must
have mocked us when he heard about it.
These men have tarnished
our reputation, my Khan.
There is still no word from Torumtay.
God willing,
the same fate hasn't befallen him.
There have been no such setbacks in
the exchanges we've had with them before.
There's something odd about this.
My Khan...
after all this...
I am beginning to have doubts.
-But I don't know how to say it.
-Tell me, Kıyat.
You know that I trust you and that
there's nothing you can't tell me.
The alliance, my Khan,
with the Anatolian Turks should end.
The only reason they sought
the union was to save their skin.
These men couldn't even protect
the gold you sent them.
What hope is there that they could
overcome Hülagü Khan's army?
The aid is gone.
Torumtay's fate is unknown.
Because of their incompetence,
the slightest pressure from Hülagü
Khan's men saw your plans collapse.
I can only conclude that...
Ertuğrul Bey is not as strong
as we were led to believe.
My Khan...
these men want to lead us
into an endless swamp.
The ever-shining sun above our state...
must not be dulled because of these men.
-Wait here, Bamsı.
-As you wish, my Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey is here, my Khan.
Get my servants in here.
Bring Ertuğrul Bey...
-before me.
-As you command, my Khan.
Berke Khan awaits you in his tent,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I salute Berke Khan,
the just and the glorious.
May the sun always shine above your state.
To seal our alliance
against the oppressors,
I have come here personally.
What is the situation in Anatolia,
Ertuğrul Bey?
Anatolia awaits the spark
that will start the great war.
Entire tribes stand with swords in hand
to fight Hülagü Khan's army.
We have them surrounded.
You tell me that Hülagü Khan
is besieged, but...
the latest news I received
suggest otherwise.
Hülagü Khan's men were able
to seize the supplies we sent you.
Our alps went to collect those supplies.
We received intelligence
that Hülagü Khan's men were going
to ambush us there.
But we took measures to thwart it.
That runs contrary to what
we have been told, Ertuğrul Bey.
The aid is now in the hands of the enemy.
Apparently, the fate of the aid
I sent you is a mystery.
What about Torumtay?
What's happened to him?
I met with Torumtay.
But Hülagü Khan's men lured us
into a trap.
Torumtay was killed.
The aid is missing.
My envoy is dead.
How dare you now come before me,
Ertuğrul Bey?
I came here to discuss this with you
and to tell you what you need to know.
It appears a dark cloud
surrounds these events.
We must dispel that cloud.
It was your duty to secure the gold
and ensure my envoy returned unharmed!
You failed to do that! What else
do you think there is to discuss?
What is this dark cloud?
How am I supposed to trust you
and proceed with the alliance now?
That is exactly what those
who are behind this want.
To crush our alliance.
The reason I came here in person
was to discuss something
which involves you personally.
So tell me.
It's confidential.
If we can speak privately,
I will tell you.
As I said, it's you that it concerns.
We have served our khan for years.
We attend all meetings.
What is so secret that it must be hidden
from us, Ertuğrul Bey?
It is my duty to tell him privately.
If he sees fit to do so,
Berke Khan can then tell you.
If it's just a matter of you
repeating your excuses,
there is no need to talk in private,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We know what happened.
We have gathered here to discuss
the war we have waited so long for.
Tell us something about that
or stop wasting our time.
You're Berke Khan's most trusted advisor.
Why would you want to prevent me saying
something which holds so much importance
for your khan and your state?
I don't want my khan's time
wasted with empty words.
Enough!
If I had done something which had
in any way sullied your reputation...
I would never have left Anatolia.
Send me away and end
our alliance now if you must.
But we both still have a duty
to the Islamic world...
to free the oppressed from tyranny.
Without this alliance,
we will fail in our duty.
The decision is yours.
Everyone leave.
I want to speak
to Ertuğrul Bey in private.
Meet your end, you bastard.
So, you came to our village
dressed as a beggar.
We will find out what you're up to.
You won't get a word out of me.
Start walking, then.
We will take him to Umuroğlu Village.
As you say, Turgut Bey.
Go on! Walk!
I'm listening, Ertuğrul Bey.
What do we know about the people involved?
Betrayal.
There's a traitor among you
who sends information to Hülagü Khan.
Inside every state...
there are maggots eating it
from the inside.
You know this well.
But...
sooner or later...
they're always exposed.
But this instance concerns you personally.
Tell me, why?
The traitor is too close to you.
Do you understand...
what you are saying?
Accusing somebody of treason
within my inner circle
is treason in and of itself,
and there's no forgiving that!
The information Hülagü Khan has...
is not ordinary, just the opposite,
quite valuable.
It includes the secret correspondence
between us.
That's how I know
that this traitor is no common man.
Who is it, then?
Give me a name.
We will find out together.
Now, I must know
who your closest confidant is.
I talk about the state's affairs
with many men close to me.
The closest.
The person closest to you.
The one who knows
what nobody one else knows.
Kıyat.
Don't tell me you think it's him.
He's the most valuable vizier
of this state.
You're a wise and a strong khan.
You know well that in affairs of state,
even a son might stab his father
in the back.
History is full of such examples.
That is the truth.
But what is your truth, Ertuğrul Bey?
Kıyat has been at my side for years.
You come to me today from Anatolia
and accuse my best man of treason.
I need hard evidence,
not suspicious words.
Do you have proof?
I will show you proof...
but for that, I will need your help.
What kind of help?
I will bait the traitor
into exposing himself.
All I want...
is your permission to do this.
I understand how hard
this must be for you.
But we have no other choice...
for justice...
or for the state.
We will test him.
Then everything will become clear.
I will test him.
But I have a condition.
If Kıyat is not a traitor...
then I will have your head.
Deal.
Now tell me...
how will we test him?
The alps went to your friends.
Let's hope they stay true to their word.
Don't worry, Taşkun Bey.
I don't deal with traitors.
They're loyal to our friendship.
And they will pay back our help
with interest.
Let's hope so.
If they indeed pay us,
we can distribute the gold on our wedding.
-What's happening?
Listen, the drums.
Time to get the gold that
you've been waiting for.
Temüge.
What is this, Sırma Hatun?
Traitor.
A traitor.
What is this?
Who is that man?
Why are my alps tied up?
You enjoy acting as bey.
But you don't even know your own people.
These are traitors.
Traitors!
How can they do such a thing?
Oh, Allah.
What do you mean?
What treason?
Don't try to talk your way out of this.
Everything will become clear now.
Who do you think you are?
You're talking to the Umuroğlu bey.
Don't forget that.
We will see who is who in the tent, Sırma!
Umuroğlu beys to the tent!
Take these three away.
It's time for the truth to come to light.
Let's find out who holds your leash.
Walk.
Now!
I hope you didn't waste our khan's time
with nonsense, Ertuğrul Bey.
If Berke Khan tells you what I said...
you will know
whether it's nonsense or not.
Let's go, brothers.
My khan.
What did Ertuğrul Bey say to you?
He kept repeating one thing.
He said...
that we have a traitor among us.
Did he tell you who it is?
No, he did not.
But he will prove it
once he's back in Anatolia.
He's going to show me evidence.
Apparently, he's about to catch a Mongol
who knows who the traitor is.
So the traitor will be exposed
once he's back in Anatolia.
Then I will have a ship prepared
at the port right away...
so they can return at once
and give us a name.
They won't use the port.
They couldn't keep our men safe
in their own lands,
but we will demand every precaution.
That's why...
they will use a secret cove in the east.
Prepare accordingly.
As you wish, my khan.
These mimicking crows...
are like the traitors among us.
They fool people.
They mislead people.
The hunter becomes the hunted.
That's why...
we must take their heads.
You gathered us all here.
Tell us what's happening.
This scum will tell you what's happening.
Speak now. What is your plan?
Did we tell you to smile?
Talk.
I don't know anything.
I don't know anyone.
Then why did you contact Sırma Hatun?
Why did you come disguised
as a beggar?
We only wanted to avenge Beybolat Bey.
You're not even an Umuroğlu alp.
What were you after?
Why did you ask Sırma Hatun for alps?
What did you offer her...
in return for her help? Talk!
Speak, Sırma.
What did he give you for the alps?
What do you seek?
You're doing this because your man
wasn't elected bey.
Come to your senses.
I don't know this man.
So, you don't.
Then why did you meet him
at Beybolat Bey's grave?
Why did you send him the alps?
He didn't give me anything.
You wanted the alps...
to take back Berke Khan's gold, right?
What did you offer? Talk!
Speak or I will snap your neck.
We gave the gold to Sırma Hatun.
Were you in contact with Taşkun Bey?
Why would I know him?
Kill him.
Hold on, Taşkun Bey. Hold on.
You wish to kill me...
instead of saving me.
If that's the case...
let everyone know.
We gave the gold to Sırma Hatun.
We've given her gold before.
That man became bey thanks to our gold.
Lies! Slander!
This is a plot to take away my title.
What happened, Kıyat?
Did Ertuğrul talk to Berke Khan?
He did.
There was no deal.
At last, we got what we wanted.
No, a terrible thing happened, Arıkbuka.
-What?
-Ertuğrul told Berke Khan
that there was a traitor close to him.
-Did he say your name?
-No.
But he will reveal it as soon as he's back
in Anatolia.
He will have all the evidence too.
He's about to catch someone who knows me.
If he didn't give your name, don't worry.
You must kill him no matter what.
I will send you soldiers too.
I'm here to kill Ertuğrul anyway.
I won't let him return to Anatolia.
Nobody can save him here.
I will set an ambush near the port.
Ertuğrul won't use the port.
He will use the cove in the east in secret
to be safe.
You will kill him on the road
to the cove, Arıkbuka.
Tell me which road, Kıyat.
Everything is clear now.
You sold yourself to them.
Let's see what you bought with that gold.
I will ask once,
and you will answer me.
Act like beys.
Did Sırma Hatun and Taşkun Bey give you
gold or not?
We got the gold as a gift.
But we didn't know it was Mongol gold.
We regret it, forgive us.
Scum.
Your rule is over, Taşkun Bey.
Your title is gone.
You will pay for this.
End this nonsense now.
I am the bey.
Nobody can take my title.
You tried to bite off
more than you could chew.
Now drown in your own blood.
Ertuğrul!
No matter where you go,
you won't escape my wrath.
Because we have
turned this world into hell!
It's you who has fallen into hell.
You will burn to ashes, Arıkbuka.
-Haldaga!
-For Allah!
I will decide now.
From now on, the new bey of the Umuroğlus
is Battal Bey.
Come, Battal Bey.
He who sells his vote for gold today...
sells his honor, family and tribe
tomorrow.
You are beys no more.
The Umuroğlus will live on with honor.
As for you, Sırma.
You won't leave your tent.
We will find out
who else you plotted with.
I will find everything out and
punish you accordingly.
Even your corpse won't make it
to Anatolia.
You will never tell Berke Khan
the name of the spy.
Ertuğrul Bey doesn't need to say it.
Your ambush has already given
his name away.
How could this happen?
You will say that you will send us
from a secret cove.
Only Kıyat will know about it.
If we are attacked,
then the traitor is Kıyat.
When we make the prisoners talk,
everything will become clear.
Stupid Kıyat!
That dog in Tabriz awaits news from you,
doesn't he?
This world is too small for two rulers,
Berke Khan.
Hülagü Khan will have your heads.
When it's foggy...
the jackals think they rule the world.
But the fog is gone.
We see that you're just a sheep.
Your owner will receive your heads.
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.SubtitleDB.org