Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.SubtitleDB.org today
This is your end, Ertuğrul.
You've brought this upon yourself...
and in so doing, destroyed your family.
Enough! Enough, Albastı.
Didn't I tell you that I wanted
both Torumtay and Ertuğrul alive?
You underestimated the might
of Hülagü Khan, Ertuğrul.
You thought you could save
yourself by killing Alıncak.
You allied yourself to our enemies.
But it's over now.
I haven't said my last
words yet, Arıkbuka!
I'll gladly hear your last words one day.
Ertuğrul will never talk.
We should kill him here.
He'll cause us trouble otherwise.
You said Ertuğrul wasn't alone.
Death means victory for Ertuğrul.
We're taking Ertuğrul with us.
Let's go before his alps turn up.
-May I come in, sister?
-Come in, Sırma.
What are you doing, sister?
Gathering together Beybolat's belongings.
I don't want anything of his in this tent.
You don't have to do this, sister.
I'll have the women do it.
You look exhausted.
I've been noticing things.
It's obvious that a woman
now rules the tribe.
Much has changed.
There's much to be done.
You're right.
Especially considering the good news
Mother Hayme mentioned.
What good news?
What are you talking about?
What do you think
I'm talking about, sister?
I'm talking about marriage, of course.
When we are beset by
so many problems,
it is not the time
to think about such things, Sırma.
It's not wise
to postpone such auspicious
events with endless excuses.
Even if he is a traitor...
Beybolat Bey's corpse
has still not been found.
We cannot celebrate a marriage
while we wait to hold a funeral.
What would people think?
It is beholden on us...
to wait patiently.
Don't put it off, sister.
Because I think Mother Hayme is right.
Don't think about my brother anymore.
It's time to look forward...
and start a family.
I agree that it's not
good to delay matters.
But Ertuğrul Bey has to have
the last word on the subject.
That's true.
Now that Hayme Hatun expects
Ertuğrul to marry
a woman such as yourself,
she will be anxious
to see you in her tent soon.
She knows very well the terrible
suffering we have been through.
Why else would she offer
such a wonderful thing
at a time when we are
assailed by so many problems?
In essence, you must marry Ertuğrul Bey
as soon as possible, sister.
After all the games our brother played...
the stain of his dishonor upon our tribe
can only be washed clean
by your marriage.
Tell the women to come
and take these away. Go on.
Oh Allah!
Brothers, what has happened here?
Oh Allah! Allah!
Alps, stay alert!
Is that Mergen? Mergen!
Mergen, Mergen!
Father! Father!
Father! Allah!
Mergen!
Please, no!
Mergen, brother!
Father!
Dumrul. Dumrul!
Did you say Dumrul?
Is that Dumrul?
No, Dumrul.
Dumrul.
Is that Dumrul?
Father!
Dumrul.
My Bey!
These are my father's!
We'll find your father, son.
We'll find him.
Alps! Look for Ertuğrul Bey.
Search everywhere! Come on!
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
Where is my brother Turgut?
Turgut!
Turgut.
-Brother Turgut! Brother Turgut!
-Turgut.
-Turgut!
-Turgut Bey. Turgut Bey.
He's alive!
Gündoğdu Bey, Gündoğdu Bey!
Turgut is alive!
-Turgut is alive!
-Turgut?
My strong man.
Open your eyes. Open them.
Open your eyes.
That's it! Come on.
Come on, brother. Come on.
Turgut!
Tell us. Who did this?
Beybolat...
Arık... Arı...
Arı...
Arıkbuka?
Ertuğrul. Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
Turgut Bey, Turgut Bey.
Where is my father?
Is he alive? Do you know if he lives?
Come on, come on, brother, tell us.
They...
caught...
him.
They'll torture him.
They'll torture my brother
to make him talk.
My Bey...
Spy...
Berke Khan's...
spy...
His...
clothes...
Find... Find it... Find it.
-All right, brother, we'll find it.
-It... Find... it.
We'll find it. Alps!
Find the spy! Search his clothes. Go on!
Don't tire yourself, brother.
We'll patch you up.
I'll take you to Artuk Bey.
You'll be fine.
You'll be fine. Don't exhaust yourself.
Brother, don't tire yourself.
Brother.
Selcan, daughter.
Yes, Mother.
The work is never done in the bey's tent.
Come and sit beside me,
let's take a breath.
You tell me to rest, Mother, but...
we'll have a marriage soon.
We should have everything
ready as soon as we can.
They say honey can be poured
from a jar which held vinegar.
İlbilge Hatun has shown that
she's an honorable woman.
Now, we must stay true to our word,
Mother, just as you commanded.
You're right.
What we must do now...
is hold a great wedding feast
for all our friends and family to enjoy.
Thankfully...
everyone has seen the Kayı tribe's
strength and the sharpness of our swords.
Now they can come
to Ertuğrul Bey's wedding feast
to see how plentiful his table is
and how generous its host can be.
I hope so, dear.
Mother...
Gündoğdu Bey and Gündüz
left some time ago to go to the bazaar.
Why do you think they're still not back?
Because they're not
finished yet, daughter.
They'll be back soon.
We've been busy talking,
and I forgot all about it!
I was cooking. I must take it
off the fire before it burns.
Go take care of your food.
Go on, dear.
Gündoğdu Bey.
Who is this Arıkbuka?
Arıkbuka is Hülagü’s best spy in Anatolia.
He's the most dangerous
Mongol I've ever heard spoken of.
Listen to me well now.
He'll take Ertuğrul to the brink of death
to make him tell him everything.
My bey will never talk.
Of course he won't, Bamsı, don't worry.
But it means we must act
quickly to save him.
My Bey!
I found these documents
hidden in the lining of his clothes.
We must find Ertuğrul Bey.
We won't return home without him.
Wherever in this world you flee to...
whatever hole you hide yourself in...
I'll find you, Beybolat.
I'll kill you.
My Bey, we're ready to take
Turgut Bey back to the tribe.
Melikşah, listen carefully.
Tell them everything that's happened.
Have them come and take our martyrs.
Tell them Ertuğrul Bey is alive...
and that we've gone to find him.
Every member of the tribe
is to look for Ertuğrul.
Tell the other tribes too.
Everywhere is to be searched.
Understood?
Tell Abdurrahman to go to the Umur.
İlbilge Hatun must be told that
Beybolat is still alive.
She should be on her guard.
As you command, my Bey.
Go on, then. Allah protect you.
Chief Alp Bamsı.
Let him go.
We need to take Turgut Bey now.
Come on, Bamsı.
Come on. Come on. There he goes.
Up.
Let's go. Let's go, alps.
To the horses! Quickly! Let's go!
Not on the ground.
Put his back against the wall.
He can stay like that until he wakes.
Red wine.
Red wine refreshes a man
who has just spilled blood.
It can refresh you, then.
After all this bloodshed,
the Kayı Tribe will mourn.
We've taken their bey.
We killed their most important alps.
Why am I here, Albastı?
I salute the enemy with blood.
They respond with screams of fear.
A sword unties all knots
just as blood unties the tongue.
Ertuğrul is a tough one, be warned.
Did you spend too long
in Ertuğrul's lands and...
forget about the past, Albastı?
Do you have any idea how many times
I've made tough men like him talk?
That tongues hides Keykavus,
the chest, the gold,
and the secret deal with Berke Khan.
If you know how to dig...
you will find treasure.
I'll make him give me everything.
Everything he knows.
Just take your treasure and
leave the rest to me.
I'll bury him in the hole you've dug
once vengeance is mine.
Did they grow wings and fly, my Bey?
Their tracks end here.
Hülagü's most skilled warriors and spies
are under Arıkbuka's command.
He must know we were following them.
They've hidden their tracks.
So what do we do, my Bey?
How will we find my father?
Bamsı, you know this place best.
Tell us.
All right, my Bey.
We are here.
When Melikşah tells the tribe what's
happened, the alps will search the forest.
The others will search
Mount Semadirek and Mount Papaz.
My Bey, we will take this valley.
Where does it lead?
It divides into two,
one leading into Byzantine lands
and the other down to the river, my Bey.
We'll split up to search.
Understood.
We'll search the whole valley.
Gündüz, take the side
on the right with Günkut.
Bamsı, you and the alps
will take the left with me.
Very good, my Bey.
We'll continue through into the night.
No sleeping!
Sooner or later we will find Ertuğrul Bey.
Understood?
-As you command, my Bey!
We'll search with torches.
When they see the light from the torches
they'll come out and reveal themselves.
I hope so, my Bey. I hope so.
I hope they do, so that
we can kill them and save our bey.
God willing. Let's go! Let's go, brothers!
Come on!
Even if Ertuğrul dies, Gündoğdu
will continue from where he left off.
We'll have to take care of him
if we want to avoid further trouble.
Your fear of the Kayıs can be seen in
your eyes and heard in your words.
I already know what to do
and to whom, don't worry.
Is that so?
What will you do?
To destroy the alliance
they made with Berke Khan,
and to put an end to their endless
plots and conspiracies in Anatolia,
I will take Gündoğdu.
It is not enough to catch the eagle.
Not when there's chicks in its nest.
That nest must be destroyed
so those chicks don't become eagles.
He's stretching his wings.
It seems Hülagü Khan no longer values you.
Knowing I've killed
all the Mongols here...
he sent you to me.
My favorite enemy is the one
who is brave even in captivity.
I don't like the easy ones anyway.
It will give me great pleasure
to peel away your courage, layer by layer,
by hurting you, Ertuğrul.
So, you found another master to
hold your leash, Albastı.
Now raise your tail and bark.
Because I plan to cut it off.
When I had your nephew Süleyman,
he talked like that too.
But when I crushed his head
in the lion's jaw,
he spoke a lot less, Ertuğrul.
I remember it clearly.
It makes me happy whenever I think of it.
I figured you out very quickly, Ertuğrul.
But...
you should understand how I work too.
When my darkness falls...
the mountains are mine.
You cannot escape...
and no one will save you.
That's why...
you should give me what I want, easily.
You say you know me.
But they clearly didn't tell you enough.
Even if the mountains are yours...
you'll never control me.
Finally!
You finally made me bleed, Ertuğrul.
This means we really are enemies now.
I won't leave a single drop in your body.
Arıkbuka...
let's crush him now
to show him his mistake.
You have spilled so much blood...
but you still haven't
learned to enjoy it, Albastı.
You must see your enemy
die slowly in agony.
You must make it last so that...
as the words pour out of him...
so the blood empties from his body.
Bring the torture fork!
Who is this coming?
Let it be good news.
It's the alps, Mother.
There's someone behind them.
What's going on?
They're carrying a wounded man.
A wounded man?
Stand aside.
Turgut Bey!
Turgut!
Mother!
My son! My son! What happened?
Son, what happened?
What happened? Artuk Bey!
İlçin Hatun!
Turgut is badly wounded!
You must tend to him immediately!
Take him to the healing tent.
-Hurry!
-Come on.
-Come on!
Who did this?
There was a fight, Mother Hayme.
We have many martyrs.
Dumrul and Mergen are dead.
What did you say?
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
I asked you a question, Melikşah!
Where is your bey?
Ertuğrul Bey...
was captured and taken, Mother Hayme.
Father.
Gündoğdu Bey and...
Gündüz Alp have gone to find Ertuğrul Bey.
Raise your head, Melikşah.
We don't bow our heads.
We take heads!
Who did this?
Beybolat.
Isn't that bastard dead?
No, Selcan Hatun.
He ambushed us with the Mongols.
Brave Kayı men!
And brave women!
Listen to me.
Now is not the time to cry and despair.
Whenever we were in trouble,
our bey ran to help us.
Now we will help him!
-Yes, she's right!
-Yes!
Alps of the tribe!
Go and search for your bey!
Women of the tribe!
Take up your weapons
and get yourselves ready for battle!
If...
those bastards...
dare to attack our village...
we will fight to the death.
We will fight until the last drop of blood
falls from our bodies! We will fight!
-We will fight!
Come on!
Make some healing balm, İlçin Hatun.
We must cover the wound.
-The bleeding won't stop, Artuk Bey!
-Wipe it clean with the cloths you boiled.
Prepare the branding iron.
We'll cauterize it.
How is he, Artuk Bey?
Will Turgut live?
We'll cauterize the wound,
Hayme Hatun. But it's deep.
The traitor who did this
stabbed him in this area
so as to inflict maximum suffering.
It was Beybolat who stabbed him.
-The iron is ready, my Bey.
-Excuse us, Hayme Hatun.
Bring it over, İlçin Hatun.
Be very careful now.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Ya Şafi.
-Allah.
-Ya Şafi.
Help us, Allah.
Ya Şafi.
Does your neck hurt, Ertuğrul?
If you try to lower your head,
or if you fall asleep and your head falls,
the fork will stick
in your throat and kill you.
But then, if you stay like this,
the pain will drive you insane.
So I have given you two options,
pain or death.
Speak and be saved.
What you call death...
I call martyrdom.
Anything you try to scare me with
only gives me courage.
If you want...
you can tear me apart.
You won't see any pain in my face.
I, however...
will get to watch you go mad...
for failing to bend me to your will.
What glorious words.
But not the words I wanted to hear.
You will tell me what
you took from Alıncak.
His life?
I fed him to the vultures.
You're only tormenting yourself
by stretching this out.
Tell me...
what are you planning with Berke Khan?
How is Sultan Keykavus involved?
What's inside the chest?
If you want to know... go after it.
But...
your fate will be the same
as all the others who tried to find it.
Your fingers have been
the ones pulling the strings.
I'll break those fingers...
one by one.
But you can't have
done it all by yourself.
There's a great power behind you.
Who is that?
True. There is.
My God.
My heart.
My sword.
And the gold?
What happened to it?
Did you send the gold that rightfully
belonged to the Mongols to Berke Khan?
Even if I knew where it was
I wouldn't tell you...
I'd tell Arıkbuka.
But then you'd try to kill him
to get the gold anyway.
Just like you tried to kill Alıncak.
What are these black words
scratching at my ear?
Are you not going to tell him...
that when we caught Alıncak,
the first arrow to hit him was yours?
Are you going to deny
trying to kill him, Albastı?
He's right. I did.
I did it to prevent
Alıncak being taken captive.
So that he couldn't expose our secrets.
Anyone in my place
would have done the same.
If Alıncak could be resurrected,
he'd thank me.
You know that.
A true and honest word...
cuts as sharply as a knife.
The arrow you fired at him
pierced my heart too.
But... you're right.
If you had let him live,
and left him to the enemy,
that would have been a crime.
It's clear that making you talk
will be as difficult as
turning steel into dust.
But my strength has no limits.
You will writhe in agony
until the moment you run out of blood.
Welcome, Abdurrahman Alp. What is it?
Thank you, İlbilge Hatun.
What is it? Is it something important?
İlbilge Hatun, I'd rather
discuss this with you in your tent.
All right, come in.
-Go on. I'm listening.
-İlbilge Hatun...
Ertuğrul Bey and our alps were ambushed.
An ambush? What happened?
We lost many alps.
Ertuğrul Bey was captured
and taken by the enemy.
What enemy?
Albastı.
Albastı?
How could he fall down a cliff
with that wound and survive?
Mongol spies saved him.
They were the ones
who attacked Ertuğrul Bey.
They have Ertuğrul Bey now.
What are you saying, Abdurrahman Alp?
He heaps more shame upon us.
I'll make him pay for this.
Gündoğdu Bey went after them.
He'll find them sooner or later.
We'll remain with your tribe for now.
Then we'll join
the search for Ertuğrul Bey.
Do not talk of this to anyone for now.
I'll increase the number of guards.
Allah, protect Ertuğrul Bey from evil.
Our scouts sent word. They've seen
the Kayıs searching the forest.
Brother.
Gündoğdu.
It is so much easier to hunt
when my prey comes running to me.
Shall we go back and surround them?
No need.
We'll set the trap and wait for them here.
When Gündoğdu gets close enough,
we'll attack them.
You hide in your holes...
like the cowardly jackals you are.
Neither I...
nor my brother,
will ever fall into your traps.
Don't push yourself, Ertuğrul.
That fork might pierce
your throat and you'll die.
And that would make me so sad.
I still need you.
No one will ever find us
unless we want them to find us.
Leave something that will
lead Gündoğdu to us.
Leave it at such a place that
they'll reach here at the red dawn.
What should I leave for them?
It must be something they will recognize.
When your brother finds a piece of you,
I wonder how quickly he'll get here.
To find out whether you're dead or alive
he'll rush here as if he's lost his mind.
You're only inviting...
your own death.
It's my job to play with death.
Let's leave him a sign then.
A bloody piece of you.
This is the piece.
And now, some blood.
Do it like I said.
Choose the location wisely,
I don't want them
getting here before dawn.
It's time to get some
sleep before my prey arrives.
May I come in, sister?
Come in, Sırma.
What's going on, sister? You've
posted additional guards everywhere.
The usual precautions, Sırma.
Nothing for you to worry about.
Abdurrahman and other Kayı alps
being here is not usual, sister.
What's going on? I have a right to know.
Ertuğrul Bey.
What about Ertuğrul Bey?
Has something happened to him?
Ertuğrul Bey has been captured.
The entire frontier is on alert.
That's why I've taken extra precautions.
Who would dare do something like this?
Who could capture Ertuğrul Bey?
The Mongols.
The Mongols?
-How do you know?
-Abdurrahman Alp told me, Sırma.
What will we do?
I'll do whatever's necessary.
You should continue
to attend to your work.
As you wish, sister.
You pursued the wrong things, Ertuğrul.
If you had been on the right side,
the Mongols wouldn't be here and...
you wouldn't be in this state.
I would sacrifice my life
to remain true to my cause, Albastı.
Those who have set you on this course
will lead our state into the abyss.
They will destroy it,
and traitors like you will help them.
I knew the state
before I knew my father, Ertuğrul.
There is no place
I've not fought, bled and killed...
for this state.
I've even put up with...
the Mongols for it.
And you think I will destroy it?
This state...
didn't raise the kind of traitor who would
raise his sword against his own people.
Those who you believe are the state...
are the wolves who gnaw at the tree.
I put my back against that tree
to keep it from toppling.
My bones cracked under the burden.
I've put up with everything to save it
from being crushed under Mongol boots.
It's those who you
believe to be the state
who left us all alone, Ertuğrul.
A jackal can't lead
a pack of wolves, Albastı.
Because you chose treachery
and put your own pride above everything,
you now stand alone.
You now run with hyenas.
But...
remember that...
when the haze clears from the field...
all you will see will be our claws.
Who are you, Ertuğrul?
Who is the power behind you?
Scorpion.
A scorpion approaches.
How did you know that
that scorpion was there?
Being strong isn't just a matter of being
tough, you also have to be sensitive.
Sensitive enough to sense a scorpion
coming towards you while you sleep.
The sky god Tengri made even
the deadliest creatures
useful for something.
This scorpion will help us.
Our men left the scrap of clothing.
Good, then a feast of blood
awaits us after dawn.
Take this scorpion.
Extract its poison.
When Gündoğdu arrives
it might prove useful to me.
You'll soon be seeing
your brother, Ertuğrul.
And you'll be seeing your
blood brother Alıncak soon.
There will indeed be
blood after the red dawn.
Swords will determine who drowns in it.
True. But you won't be here to see it.
Take him and leave before dawn.
Go to my secret cave and wait there.
Just in case.
He must not be here during the fight.
I'll lure Gündoğdu here and trap him.
Will you still not speak, Ertuğrul?
Speak, to prevent your brother
being tortured like you.
The power that could make me speak
has not yet been born.
The torture that could break me
has not yet been devised.
You can hold your head up now.
But what will you do when you
become tired?
Show us their tracks.
Allah, show us their tracks.
Allah, show us their tracks,
show us their tracks, Allah.
Where are you, my bey?
My bey, my bey.
My bey!
No, no. There's no sign of them.
No tracks! Nothing!
There's no sign of them!
My bey is gone and there are no tracks.
Bamsı.
Gündoğdu Bey.
We're just wandering around in the dark.
I know we can't give up.
-I do, my bey, but--
-But...
The dawn inevitably follows night.
Isn't that right, brother?
We can't give up hope now,
we won't give up hope.
Very good, my bey. Very good.
I won't give up. I won't give up, my bey.
Someone's coming, my bey!
Gündoğdu Bey! Gündoğdu Bey!
Gündüz Bey's found something.
Good. Let's go, quickly!
My Bey, the dawn is inevitable,
just as you said, my Bey.
Allah willing, let's go! Let's go!
Welcome, Turgut.
Where am I?
Where am I, Hodja?
You're far away and you're close.
It is neither yesterday, nor tomorrow.
You're here, Turgut.
Why...
Why are you planting a rose?
I was told we have many martyrs.
I'm planting roses along their path.
Did I...
become a martyr?
A martyr is a witness.
If you don't know what you're
witnessing, then this is not your time.
When you see it,
you won't have any questions.
That is, instead of asking questions,
you'll simply enjoy the gifts of Allah.
They won't bloom...
until their time comes, Turgut.
What does that mean?
Your roots are still to be
buried and watered.
A rose will grow tall and bloom
in caring hands,
but those who seek
to uproot it will feel its thorns.
You were once a heartbroken,
orphaned child.
Allah raised you up,
and made you his warrior.
You became an alp,
and then rose to become bey.
Most importantly of all,
you shed your blood on the battlefield
in the wars against our oppressors.
There will be more battles to fight,
and more tyrants to kill.
As there are still those
who would seek to uproot Allah's cause,
it falls upon you to pierce
their skin with your thorns.
I have killed many enemies...
on the field of battle.
But...
this time I am very
badly wounded, my teacher.
What plant or medicine
could heal me this time?
Medicine and plants
are only the means, Turgut.
Nothing happens without Allah's will.
Abraham was thrown into fire.
Fire so hot it would melt steel.
But because Allah did not wish it,
the fire didn't burn Abraham.
The knife would have
cleaved a tree in two.
But since Allah did not wish it,
the knife did not cut Isaac.
Now, without Allah's will...
that wound cannot kill you.
Come, Turgut.
Drink some water.
Refresh your roots.
Water is mercy.
It's a blessing.
It is clean and it cleanses.
It heals.
The name "Hayy" means,
"he who gives life to everything".
Drink in his name, Turgut.
Drink in his name.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Hayy!
Oh Allah, you bring the day and the night.
You light up the sky with the stars.
With your unlimited power,
you can create anything.
You help with our hardships.
You have a solution for every problem.
Everything belongs to you.
When Eyyub was hurt, his family
feared that he would never recover
from such grievous wounds.
But Eyyub himself did not give up hope
and reached out to you.
You were the one who healed him.
Now heal this brave man
who was willing to give his life...
in the fight for your holy cause.
You said...
"Pray to me so that I may answer".
Please answer our prayers,
in the name of your messenger,
Muhammad.
Please, accept our prayers,
and in your wisdom act upon them.
Accept them, oh Allah!
Accept them!
Amen.
What is it, my brave man,
what have you found?
My bey...
this is a piece of my father's kaftan.
You are right.
It's one of our fabrics.
However, somebody might have planted this
to lead us in the wrong direction.
My bey, we cannot know for sure
unless we follow the tracks to the end.
Certainly, we'll follow them.
We will follow them.
My God...
you are the one...
with power and might.
Don't let us yield to our enemies.
If it's not your wish...
a life won't leave a body.
In your path...
I have no fear of death.
Grant me the opportunity
to avenge our martyrs...
and make them pay
for killing my brothers.
May I enter, İlbilge Hatun?
Come in, Abdurrahman Alp.
Are the horses ready?
They are, İlbilge Hatun.
We will go out to look.
Good.
I shall come with you.
İlbilge Hatun...
it would be better if you stayed
at the camp for the tribe's sake.
If Albastı should arrive,
none of us will be here.
It could get ugly.
Albastı won't come to the camp
if he has Ertuğrul Bey.
There is no point in waiting here
like this.
Henceforth,
I have to take on responsibility, too.
Gündoğdu Bey is searching everywhere
with his alps.
Under these circumstances,
it could be dangerous for you to go.
Be that as it may, Abdurrahman Alp,
there is no more time to waste.
After all the things
Ertuğrul Bey has done for us...
I am ready to give my life.
All right, İlbilge Hatun.
If that is what you think...
let's head out at once.
May I enter, Sister?
Come in, Sırma.
Sister.
The alps have gathered,
they're readying their horses.
Where are they going?
They are going to look for Ertuğrul Bey.
I will go with them.
Go, Sister.
Don't come back until you find him.
I'll keep an eye on the camp.
Don't you worry.
Take care.
Take care, Sister.
Be mindful on the road.
They will be looking for Ertuğrul
everywhere.
If I don't find him alive
when I get there...
then you won't be alive, Albastı.
Don't worry.
Not even a bird will see him.
Go capture Gündoğdu and bring him there.
Come on.
Master.
What are you doing here alone
with a sad face, Osman?
I'm feeling down.
I am dark inside
like the bottom of this well, Master.
I try to drown my sorrow.
Tell me, what is it that makes you sad?
My father has been taken prisoner.
He's in the hands of the enemy.
There is no word of him.
Your father may be captive,
there might be no word,
and...
your father may never come back
to this camp again.
You say that, Master, but...
what will we do
if something happens to my father?
What will we do without our bey?
When your father embarked
on this holy path,
did he trust his father, Osman?
Did your grandfather trust his father?
He who walks the path of God...
trusts only God himself.
And no matter what...
does not show frustration.
Master, Turgut Bey is heavily wounded.
Countless alps have been martyred.
I don't know what to do.
Then let me tell you what to do, Osman.
It was the first days...
of the announcement of Islam.
Our prophet,
Sallallahu aleyhi ve sellem...
had gathered his tribe
on the mountain of Ebu Kebeys.
Everyone from his family,
all of his relatives, were there.
And our prophet
asked that very important question:
"Who will help me...
on the path of God?
Who will bear this heavy burden with me?
Who will aid
the cause of spreading the word?"
There was no answer.
Uncles, aunts, nieces...
kith and kin.
They were all silent.
Our prophet looked upon the faces
of the people that were present
and repeated his question.
"Who will aid me
on the path that leads to Allah?"
Again, no answer.
Our holy prophet's call
was about to be to no avail.
Right then, a 13-year-old boy
carrying water in a qirba...
not waiting to look around...
not caring who was there...
laid his qirba on the ground...
and said
"I will do it, oh, prophet of God.
I will help you."
Right then, Ebu Leheb said:
"Oh, Muhammed... this boy will be enough
for you for the cause you speak of.
Don't bother with us."
He made light of our prophet's words.
However, there was something
he didn't know.
That boy was to become...
one of our prophet's greatest companions
in spreading the word.
That boy was to become
the lion of Allah...
the wielder of Zulfiqar,
the unbreakable sword of the cause.
He was to become Ali.
Important causes...
are furthered by committed, brave people
who believe in them.
We just buried our martyrs.
All of them were brave,
and they believed.
God's cause...
carries on because of those...
who sacrifice themselves without
looking around when asked to help...
and say "I,"
and who give their life
in the face of cruelty.
You know, when our bey
and our brave alps are with us...
we say "We trust in God.
God will deliver us."
God...
looks down upon us
at times like these when...
our bey isn't here
and our brave alps are wounded...
to see if...
our word is true.
Do we do our best and trust in God...
or do we trust people?
Now...
is the time to prove it.
The cause of Allah...
requires people like Ali...
who will not look around
but will say, "I, oh prophet of God,"
in our age, too.
Now is not the time to be sad or unravel.
Now is the time to come forward and say...
"I will help, oh, prophet of God"...
so that...
God's cause may not be defeated
and the cruel may not defeat it.
May I enter, Sırma Hatun?
Come in.
You sent for me, Sırma Hatun.
What's wrong, Atay Bey?
What are you talking about?
We thought you were a lion.
You turned out to be a nervous rabbit.
Does this uneasiness suit
a bey of the Umur?
Not nervousness but caution, Sırma Hatun.
As you know, it is not safe.
I know that it is not safe.
However, at times like these,
not the war cries of foes...
but the silence of friends is heard.
If I'd kept silent,
my arm would be intact.
Word of it being broken
must have reached you,
since you sent for me.
However, it is not my arm...
but my heart that is broken
after the loss of our Beybolat Bey.
Now, tell me.
What is it you want?
I cannot heal your arm
with a single word...
but I can strengthen your heart.
Speak, I'm listening.
Then listen well.
The bey of the Umur,
Beybolat Bey, is alive.
He is with our Mongolian friends.
They have captured Ertuğrul.
Today is our day.
Now is not the time to be cautious...
but to step up like a brave man.
Let's see who's loyal to Beybolat Bey
and who isn't.
Gather the beys who will support us.
We're going to set up such a game...
that they will see
we won't fit into the grave they dug.
Drink. The journey is long.
Who told you to do that?
No food, no water for him.
Leave my sight. Go.
Bring my provisions.
I've waited for the day
you would fall into my grasp.
Now, I will surely not deprive myself
the pleasure of tormenting you.
You are like a sleazy dog
that brings the hunt to its master.
Or like a rabid dog
that chases the bone that is thrown.
If it wasn't for your master's shadow...
you would jump off a cliff again...
you certainly wouldn't
stand before me like this.
Our terms were equal, Ertuğrul.
You also had your alps with you.
But what happened?
We slaughtered them before your eyes.
You saw with your own eyes
how I drove my sword...
into Turgut's chest.
Look straight into my eyes, Albastı.
See the vengeance
that will take your life.
As my sword cuts through
your wretched body...
these will be the last eyes you'll see.
Your brother Turgut awaits you, Ertuğrul.
You won't be able to avenge him.
But, don't worry,
you will be reunited very soon.
We have a long way to go, Albastı.
Don't go claiming victory just yet.
What will you do?
Did you look into your dear brother's eyes
one last time?
Did you see the fear of death...
the terror of Albastı in his eyes?
Don't you worry.
You will have a similar end.
My eyes!
Oh! My eyes!
Bring water, quick. Come on.
I will not give my life...
without taking out those evil eyes.
I will not let you die without vengeance.
Your death will be worse, Ertuğrul.
It will be such a death...
the devil itself will be scared.
Where are you, my bey?
We'll find you.
We'll find you, my bey.
I won't leave my bey behind.
I won't. I won't.
I'll find my bey. Oh...
Gündoğdu Bey.
My bey.
There are tracks here.
These tracks are fresh, Bamsı.
This way, come on, alps.
Come on. Let's go, alps!
-Artuk Bey.
-Turgut.
Thank God.
At last, you woke up.
What kind of a miracle is this, oh God?
There is no questioning God's will.
My bey...
How is my bey?
Gündoğdu Bey and Bamsı
are looking for him everywhere.
They'll find him sooner or later.
Rest now.
I couldn't protect him.
I couldn't stop that traitor.
Don't trouble yourself
with these thoughts now, Turgut.
You need to get well as soon as possible.
I cannot heal before...
I see my bey alive and well...
one last time...
Hopefully you will, Turgut.
God willing.
As long as I have life in me...
I will not surrender to you.
-Come on.
-Catch him, quickly.
I knew you would try something.
You had a chance to survive.
Now you've lost that too, Ertuğrul.
I'll tie you to my horse
and take you on foot.
It's too early for you to die.
You will die together with
your brother Gündoğdu.
Wound him and take him down. Come on.
İlbilge.
It's too early for Ertuğrul Bey to die.
But it's just the right time for you,
Albastı.
I should've killed you
the first time I suspected you, İlbilge.
The snake has grown.
It has poisoned us.
Gündoğdu Bey.
There is a cave up ahead.
The tracks lead to it but...
there's nobody around.
Let's look in the cave.
We will, Nephew, we will.
However, we must be cautious.
It might be a trap.
All right.
Günkut, tell the alps to surround the cave
from both sides.
Come on, lead the way.
All right, my bey.
You have nowhere to run, Albastı.
Neither a cliff to jump off of...
nor a river to be carried away in...
nor a master to come save you.
You forget the power of my sword,
Ertuğrul.
If one of us is going to die
on this ground...
let our swords decide who that will be.
Everything was for our lineage, İlbilge.
I was the last male in our line.
Our beyhood will perish.
We have died out, İlbilge.
They destroyed us.
Beyhood is not about gender...
but about valor.
You don't have that.
Now, your blood...
will save our lineage's honor.
Your leash is broken.
Your masters' time will also come.
Until the likes of you are wiped out...
this war won't end.
Until the veins of treachery
are dried out...
my sword won't rest.
The wounds were for my nephew Süleyman...
and the people
you have oppressed until today.
This is for Turgut.
I told you the only thing you'd see
before you died would be my eyes.
Any word about Turgut, Abdurrahman?
My bey...
Dumrul, Mergen and all
the other alps there were martyred.
Turgut Bey was heavily wounded.
He is at the camp.
You came just in time, İlbilge Hatun.
Now, take his body to the camp.
Tell the people...
that the traitor has been dealt with.
Give him a proper burial.
You are in charge now.
What will you do?
They lured my brother Gündoğdu
into a trap.
I have to get to him
before something bad happens.
Come on alps, to the horses.
Mother Hayme.
Tell me, my brave boy.
Tell your mother.
My bey...
Has my bey returned, Mother?
He will, God willing.
He will, son.
Hold on, my Turgut.
Hold on.
You've been through much worse,
my brave boy.
You'll get through this too, God willing.
We weathered storms.
We weathered hurricanes.
We became water.
You gave us water.
We flowered.
A day came...
when we faded.
We became ashes.
You fanned the flames.
You became our stove.
We had no branches...
you became our knot.
Nobody loved us...
you became our companion.
I had no mother...
you became a mother to me.
I can never repay you, Mother.
I can't.
I'd die for you.
There is no debt, my son.
I did...
what a mother should do for her sons.
It is I who can't repay you.
You knew no night...
no day...
no snow, no hurricane...
you fought...
put your life on the line...
for the honor of our tribe...
of our banner.
Now...
with God's permission...
get back up...
as soon as possible, to fight again.
My body...
might heal...
without seeing my bey...
alive and well.
However...
my heart won't, Mother.
This wound won't heal.
It won't.
If you wish to...
lighten this mother's heart...
get strong as soon as possible...
and stand up, son.
There's the cave, my bey.
Then they must have gone inside.
There are horse tracks everywhere
leading to the cave.
What if we're too late?
Hold on, Nephew.
Bamsı.
You wait here with Gündüz.
Günkut, take two alps and come with me.
Come on.
Alps, you take precautions, come on.
What are these, my bey?
Preparations for
the sacrifice of souls ritual.
Arıkbuka.
You know my name well, Gündoğdu.
Where is Ertuğrul?
Rest assured,
he is in the safe hands of Albastı.
Now, it is your turn.
You and Ertuğrul have a lot to tell me.
I know.
I'll get what I want.
If I don't get your head first.
What saves the scorpion from the flame
is its own poison.
Even if its salvation is death.
This is poison.
Out.
Günküt, get out.
Out!
Alps.
-Alps.
-What is it? Günküt? Gündoğdu Bey?
What happened to Gündoğdu Bey?
Gündoğdu Bey.
Gündoğdu Bey, what happened?
Are you all right?
Trap.
It's a trap.
Alps, protect our bey.
Take Gündoğdu.
Kill the rest.
Holy juniper tree.
The sleep that comes before death.
Welcome.
Uncle?
-My bey.
-Father.
Ertuğrul.
My bey.
You!
Ertuğrul.
Come on, alps!
God is life!
If you don't beat me...
you won't win, Ertuğrul.
Father!
My brave.
You're all right, thank God.
My bey.
-My bey.
-Praise be.
Thank God, my bey.
Praise be.
Brother?
Brother. Thank God.
Thank God you came.
He dispensed poisonous smoke.
But we're okay.
We're okay.
Thank God, we're okay.
Still, we should make haste
to the tribe, Brother.
It might show its effect later on.
The bastard ran, my bey.
Thank God we didn't fall into his hands.
Follow his tracks, Abdurrahman.
-Be cautious.
-Yes, my bey.
Alps.
Ertuğrul, he knows our secret.
Don't let him get away, no matter what.
He could bring greater trouble upon us.
What he knows is less than
what he doesn't, Brother.
And he will do anything to find out.
And we will do whatever it takes
so that he only knows what we want.
Good.
Let's get to the tribe.
I need to see my brother Turgut, too.
Come on.
Atabey just told us about the matter.
We cannot express how happy we are.
What is it you ask of us?
Tell us, Sırma Hatun.
İlbilge Hatun is deluding herself.
The Umur are not a tribe
to tag along behind the Kayı.
By God, that's true.
We harbor the beyhood tradition.
If we were to be pulled along
with a rope to any path...
our symbol wouldn't be a ram...
but a sheep.
Then it is time to be
as stubborn as a ram.
Until my brother arrives...
we will not allow İlbilge Hatun
to rule this tribe.
Beybolat Bey will soon come
and sit on his fleece...
and pass judgement on those
who colluded with the Kayı.
Brother.
Let this be a lesson to you all.
Anyone who goes against our law...
betrays us...
colludes with our enemies...
and goes after his own ambitions,
even if it is my very own brother.
He does not deserve to lead us...
but to lay under our feet.
By burying this traitor...
we will be burying our shame
in the eyes of
the other Turk tribes.
Now, everyone hear me
and hear me well.
Whoever
strives to...
sway from the law,
sway from the rules of the Umurs...
should know that
my dark sword will take their lives.
Now, take the deceased to the tent.
Come on!
Traitor.
Welcome my bey, welcome.
Welcome, my bey.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Father.
My Gündoğdu.
My God.
Thank you.
My sons have returned safe and sound.
Thank God.
My brave father.
My bey, welcome.
May God always keep you with us.
Just look at my braves!
Come here.
Just look.
You're most welcome.
Welcome.
My son.
Just look at you.
Welcome.
My Hafsa.
Come here, Hafsa.
Just look at you.
Selcan Hatun...
Welcome.
I avenged us.
What did those cruel men do to you?
They couldn't do anything, Mother.
It all collapsed on them.
I brought you good news.
Tell me, Son, what news?
Let me see Turgut first, Mother.
Then I will tell you everything.
My bey.
Will you just look at my brave?
Just look at my brave.
I was so worried
that something had happened to you.
Now that I've seen you alive and well...
nothing can upset me, my bey.
We avenged you.
We got our revenge.
Did we, my bey?
We did, my brave.
We did.
Thank you.
-Turgut.
-Thank God.
Thank God, my brother, thank God.
Come. Come, let me help you.
Brave men...
and able women of the Kayı!
The blunt dagger
that has been stuck in us for so long...
has finally been broken.
The bastard Albastı
whom we knew as Beybolat...
has paid the price of his doings...
with his life.
Great!
The death of our martyrs
and the oppressed
has not been in vain.
From now on,
we will have only one response
to all our enemies.
A tooth for a tooth...
blood for blood.
-Revenge!
Revenge!
All episodes in our site :
https://ardirilisertugrul.net
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.SubtitleDB.org