Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.SubtitleDB.org today
I will kill you with Kiyat send
your bodies to your owners.
I understood that you were doing something when
you set off with soldiers without informing me.
My thoughts were right.
Catch, if you can.
Well done Arikbuka. You did what you could.
Now it's my turn.
Go after him!
I will take your life Berke Han.
And i know how to do it.
You were right Ertugrul Bey.
You stopped the
bertrayal with your trap.
You did your duty. Now it's my
turn.
I will kill that traitor among us.
We haven't fulfilled our duty.
I will keep following Arikbuka.
I must break his wings before he takes
the news to Hulagu Han.
I will give two trackers to you.
Yuo'll need them.
But don't waste your time.
Because i will send my men to everywhere.
Come to my hunt tent when you're done.
There's no obstacle for our alliance now.
I will give some documents to you.
which will be necessary for the big war.
As you wish.
Come on
We are going back to the hunt tent.
Because there is a hunt waiting for us.
And we'll go after Arikbuka.
Come on Alps!
Untie my hands.
I order you as Sirma Hatun. Untie my hands!
You will listen to your
Hatun's order like this.
Sırma Hatun... Ilbilge Hatun ordered this.
She has another order. You
can't leave your tent.
And these 2 Alps will wait at your door.
If you need anything...
Get out! Out!
I said get out! Get out!
Out!
It's not done, Ilbilge Hatun!
I haven't said my last word!
I will ask about this!
May Allah bless you, Turgut Bey.
Thanks to you, we exposed the bertrayal
and saved our tribe.
EyvAllah Ilbilge Hatun.
Destroying it was our duty.
Thanks to Allah, we got rid of the dark clouds above our tribe. Now you should
rule our tribe until you become the Hatun of Kayi tribe, Ilbilge Hatun.
The fur and the tent's is yours.
You are the Bey,  Battal Bey.
You can sit on the Beylic fur whenever you want,
it's halal to you.
EyvAllah. If you allow me.
Ilbilge Hatun.
And there is Sirma Hatu issue.
You will make a decision about her.
Sirma's ambition and anger have always covered
her eyes.
She is like a child who always wants things.
No matter how mad i get at her, I always
have mercy on her.
She might act without thinking.
But we can't make a decision without thinking.
Some time must pass first.
Then i'll make a decision about her turgut Bey.
EyvAllah.
But you be cautious.
If you allow me..
Turgut Bey.
How is Ertuğrul Bey?
Did you hear from him?
Did something happen to him, as he is away?
My Bey got rid of many problems,
he will again, inshAllah.
He will come back soon.
You don't worry.
InsAllah.
I will take important documents from inside.
You can't get in the tent as Berke Han is not
here.
Berke Han ordered me, i couldn't come here on my own.
What is the document you'll take?
Mind your own business. I told you
that it is important.
Make way.
Where are those damn documents?
You, Ertugrul and Islam world will be destroyed
after Hulagu Han receives the documents.
My Bey... we followed them to here...
but they suddenly disappeared.
Where did they go?
They are talented in covering their track.
We know this place well, Ertugrul Bey.
But it might be hard to find the traces again.
then keep following them.
I will go to Berke Han's hunt tent with my Alps.
We will get those important documents.
And we'll see if Kiyat will speak.
Come on.
Come on valiants.
I see that you have no face to look at my
face, Sirma.
It's questioning time.
tell me.
Why did you do all of this?
I did everything for our tribe sister.
But...
For our tribe, ha?
Look at you...
I always supported you as your sister...
But you always disappointed me.
Your were the dagger on my back when i waited
for you to be the shiled infront of me.
I didn't want this to happen this way sister.
I was tricked by the
honour of Bey Hatun.
I thought I knew a lot…
But I was being ignorant.
Our father was a victim in a game.
Our brother died in a shame.
We have no one to give our backs.
Why did you play these games while
could support us as two sisters, Sirma?
I'm telling you, Sirma!
I couldn't understand those games with my
small mind sister.
My greed stopped me from seeing the truth.
My fear is not because of being exiled or execuled.
But because of being dismissed from your heart.
I am shallow, you are broad.
I'm on ground, you are above.
Little ones make mistakes, older ones forgive.
You can kill me if you want.
You can make me suffer.
But i swear... if you forgive me one
more time, I won't disappoint you.
Open your bright heart to
your dard-destined sister.
I swear, I won't disappoint you.
Let me kiss your hand..
Forgive your ignorant and greedy sister.
Punish yourself before the punishment I'll
give you.
Burn inside.
Your uncontrollable self might behave.
What happened, Turgut? Tell me.
Sirma Hatun betrayed after Beybolat, mother.
What are you saying Turgut?
What did she do?
She took golds from Mongols and gave
it to Umur Beys.
So taskun Bey attempted to rule with
Mongol golds.
Traitors are growing up like plants.
EvelAllah we caught the Mongol they
collaborted. We punished him and taskun Bey.
What about Sirma?
Ilbilge Hatun put her in her tent.
She'll make her decision later.
Ilbilge Hatun must know a thing.
Fortunately, her betrayal was exposed before
it resulted with a disaster.
Ilbilge Hatun has been through many sufferings.
But she never gave up even when she was betrayed by
her family.
I want my Ertugrul to come back and see
Ilbilge Hatun as our tent's Hatun.
Bad words annoy people.
Pretty words get the snake out of it's
hole.
You wanted to forgive me.
But I won't forgive you.
You ruined my happiness.
My brother died because of you.
You collaborated with my father's killers.
Now you're being their bride.
I will kill you with this poison...
...just like how you made life unbearable
for me.
You will die.
So that Sirma Hatun regrets, you will show
generosity by forgiving her, my Hanim.
Forgiveness is sometimes the
best way to educate someone.
Yes Mengu.
If punishing the criminal is
justice, forgiving her is grace.
She was regretful.
She asked forgiveness.
I'd forgive her but..
I have to talk to Beys.
She will have a way according to their decision.
Can i come in Ilbilge Hatun?
Come in.
Sirma Hatun wants to see. She has
important things to say.
She can come in.
Sister...
I couldn't tell you before.
But i have important things to tell you.
I want to be alone.
You think temuge is the basis.
But it goes up to Arikbuka.
The real target is not Umur tent...
..it's you and our
margrave Ertugrul Bey.
Bring Kiyat to me!
So you were a worm that
was trying to bite us.
You were a poison that tried to kill us.
Now i will kill that worm.
Where is Kiyat?
Kiyat is not here my Han.
What do you mean?
Where did he go?
He was last seen getting into your tent,
No one saw him again.
Did he get into my tent?
He told us that you ordered him my Han.
We couldn't say a thing.
I didn't order him.
As he got in my tent...
Kıyat!
What do they want from us?
Your lives.
You will swallow that poision Ilbilge Hatun.
You wanted to burn, you'll
die while burning.
Revenge is more powerful than mercy.
First you, then Ertugrul...
You will come together at your graves.
My Hanim! Sirma Hatun!
She poisoned my Hanim!
Doctor Hatuns are not here. We'll take
her to Kayi trabe, Artuk Bey!
Did something bad happen, Berke Han?
Yes Ertugrul Bey.
the worst thing happened.
Did he understand and run?
I wish he ran alone.
He took the secret documents with him.
What was in those documents, Berke Han?
My army, my soldiers, my spies' names.
the preparations of the wat that
we'll get in against Hulagu Han.
We can get those informations again.
But if Hulagu has them...
...the our preparations will be useless.
We must catch them before they ran.
It's not only a few documents we'll
save, but hopes of innocent people..
..we won't let that war and before it starts.
All soldiers will gather!
Send trackers first.
You will look under of every stone.
Search everywhere!
We won't let them escape.
What?
Kiyat came.
Let him in.
Arikbuka...
I'm happy that you are safe and sound.
Berke Han and Ertuğrul understood who I am.
Yes they did.
Because you fell into their trap.
Go off of me.
You stayed with Berke Han for years for this.
And you are exposed when you are needed the
most.
All of our games are ruined because of you.
There is no need for a man like you!
I brought Berke Han's secret informatons!
We are the ones who ruined games, Arikbuka.
What is that?
Get your damn dagger off of me, then i'll tell you.
there are secret informations
about Berke Han's army...
..soldiers and war preparations.
Ertugrul and Berke Han's game will fall
when we take these to Hulagu Han.
We will tie their hands.
How could i come empty-handed?
You showed that your training wasn't for nothing.
Now we must escape and go to tabriz.
You know from which way.
Berke Han and Ertuğrul must be after us.
What will we do?
We will mislead them.
Then we'll set such a trap that..
How?
It's good inshAllah...
Who are they?
They are Umuroglu Alps, mother...
It's good insAllah.
What are they doing here?
Ilbilge Hatun!
What happened to Ilbilge Hatun?
Sirma Hatun poisoned her, Hayme mother.
Doctor Hanims were not at tents,
we brought her here.
take her to the healing tents.
Hurry!
How is She, Artuk Bey?
She is not fine, Hayme Hatun.
Did she puke?
She didn't Artuk Bey,
I found this bottle in the tent.
She threw the poisonous dust into her face.
-Give that to me.
Ilcin Hatun, boil Baldiran and Seytantersi herbs.
Ilbilge Hatun.. she will live, right, Artuk Bey?
It's a poison which is made of Kurtbogan herbs.
It's a famous Mongol poison.
It's hard to get rid of it.
We'll try, and Allah will give shifa. (health)
You will Look everywhere!
We won't go back before we find them!
We haven't encountered a trace.
Apparently he didn't use this way.
This way is the shortest one.
He must've been here if he wanted to leave fast.
My soldiers are looking for him everywhere.
He'll be found soon.
-My Han.
-What happened?
Could you find a trace?
We couldn't find a trace of Kiyat.
But we realized a group of men going to the bay at eat.
What kind of men are they? Did you see?
Watchmen couldn't recognize them.
They are Kiyat's men.
I guess they'll use the bay at east.
That's why he sent his men beforehand, to
take precautions.
Or the opposite.
They will mislead us.
And they will run by using the west road.
Then we'll go to the both bays, Ertugrul Bey.
Secret bay at east is closer to here.
You go there with your Alps.
And I will go to west.
they must've set a trap if they'll escape
from west.
Don't worry.
I have soldiers who are searching at west.
I will take them with me.
Go now.
tell the soldiers at west to wait for me.
We will send an information if we catch them.
Come on!
-Come on Alps!
the poison affected the body.
She is running a fever.
Will she be able to get rid of it Artuk Bey?
She still didn't throw up Hayme Hatun.
Poison is really powerful.
I'm afraid it may harm her lungs.
We must make her throw up.
Ilcin Hatun.
Are her eyes red?
Yes Artuk Bey.
they look red.
Ilcin Hatun bring castor oil.
Hurry!
Hayme Hatun, we must make her throw up.
Help us.
Sure.
I brought it my Bey.
Hayme Hatun make her drink it. We don't have much
time.
Ya Allah Bismillah!
Come on my daughter.
Come on my dear...
Look at those jackals...
They don't look like they are waiting for a ship.
My Bey... Arikbuka is not among them.
the other one is not here as well.
they lurked as they knew we were
going to come.
We won't kill all of them.
We will learn where the ship will go.
Mind that when you attack.
Bamsi.
You know what to do.
I'm going out.
-EyvAllah my Bey.
Come on valiants.
Where will Kıyat and Arıkbuka go?
I don't know.
Where will they go ?
-Will they come here? tell me?
they won't use here.
They will go from west...
Did they set a trap there?
there's no trap.
They will just escape.
they didn't set a trap, ha?
I said tell me!
Berke Han will be killed by the swords he trusts.
What did that jackal say my Bey?
They dragged Berke Ha n to a death trap Bamsi.
We must arraive fast. Come on!
Did you encounter Kiyat's trace here?
We did, my Han.
Where?
Right here, Berke Han.
I killed all of the soldiers you
sent to look for me Berke Han.
Now it's your turn.
Traitor!
You were with me like my son for years.
I gave things that no one could reach.
Even a demon would find the right way.
You are worse than a demon.
It's not being a demon, it's
loyalty to my Han and my duty.
Did you now understand
why we are powerful?
This is worse than death for you Berke Han.
You always said that you'd
sacrifice yourself for me.
Your oath will come true.
But not against my enemies.
You'll die under my sword.
Don't be so sure, Berke Han!
You must've heard the name Arikbuka.
If you heard that name ...
... you must know that no one
can be saved from my hands.
Cruel infidels...
....dogs of cruelty...
As long as we have our swords and we are
alive, we won't have fear but courage...
..we won't be captives but say shahada.
You, who left his ancestors' religion and became
Muslim...
...you are fighting your own people...
...this is the torment which the ground and sky sent
upon you.
There is only one owner of the
ground and the sky.
And he is my Rab.
If you have a plan
HE has a plan too!
Attack!
Death has come at you, Berke Han.
We'll see your plan now.
Allah is Hayy! ( the Eternally Living One)
Ertugrul!
Ertugrul.
I will first get what you've stolen from me...
...then your miserable life...
Search him.
You think you will win after killing us.
But we have thousands of Kiyats and Arikbukas.
You will never be able to win Hulagu Han.
And we have enough swords for every cruel
person.
I will send the news to Hulagu Han.
He will learn this:
Hakk has come, and west has lost.
Make her drink, Ilcin Hatun.
We have to clean her lungs.
All right Artuk Bey.
How is she now, Artuk Bey?
Is there anything to be scared of?
We made her drink herbs...
She is not in danger now...
We will wait for her to wake up.
Thanks to Allah.
thanks to Allah, my child.
Give me water, Ilcin Hatun. I'll wash my hands.
You were a gazelle, but your destiny was
for wolves.
Hang on my brave daughter.
Hang on.
Wake up...
Come on.
There are useful informations in these documents.
As we agreed on an alliance,
you can have it.
We showed many efforts for this alliance.
Now it's time to collect it's fruits.
InsAllah we will save the Islam world from cruels.
The important thing is to take lessons from
our mistakes...
...and build future according to that.
Fitna, greed and caring about positions...
...did this to Islam world.
Mistakes which harmed Islam world...
...were ignored for personal benefits.
Mistakes were seen alright.
Allah's justice is the same for everyone.
But thanks to Allah, we aren't one of
those who give up and don't care.
And Allah gave His mercy on us.
Look.. I am a Mongol.. if i weren't granted with Islam..
i could've been like Hulagu. But what happened?
thanks to Allah, it
brought us together.
We weren't scared as we were a few,
and we didn't stay back as there were many of them.
If we stay strong against our
mistakes and their cruelties...
...and if we can oppose them even
if we are only one person...
... Almighty Allah will
make one of us a thousand.
Now i will carry this da'wah's flag
from Desni Kipcak to Frank lands.
And turks in Anatolia and East will come
together under the flag we'll fly, insAllah.
May Allah help us.
Ameen.
My daughter.
Are you all right?
I'm burning Mother.
I'm so thirsty.
Here, my daughter.
My pure daughter...
Drink it.
Is it enough?
It's enough mother. thank you.
My beautiful faced. dark
destined daughter.
You scared us.
I was so afraid as something bad
was going to happen to you.
Mother...
Sirma?
Sirma is dead my daughter.
Alps buried her next to your brother.
One of them tried to kill our tribe...
..and the other tried to kill me.
But they were my siblings.
I'm now alone in this world.
I have no one.
This is the place...
...you belong, you'll live. and you'll die.
I always wanted a girl.
And you were raised without a mother.
We wll be companions with you.
We will give our backs to eachother...
...and carry eachother.
I'm your mother now...
...and you are my daughter.
Thank to Allah.
I missed my country's
water and air.
My Bey.
Berries, my Bey.
I just had them. Here, eat.
Even this fruit has this forest's smell.
Come on valiants. We have to go to the tents.
EyvAllah my Bey.
Father.
Now we made an alliance with Berke Han.
But there's one thing you made a promise for.
What is that promise?
Toy, father.
You promised to marry Ilbilge Hatun
after the duty is done.
So? what confuses your mind?
War on one side, and toy on the other side.
How is that going to happen father?
We don't delay our da'wah and our promises, son.
One of them will come first, for
sure, but everything has it's time.
If you go to the duty before toy. you may not come back.
If you make the toy before, it's the same again.
It must be hard for you and Ilbilge Hatun.
Look son, our ancestors said
"Bulls' fortune comes from it's horns."
And our fortune is carrying swords until we die.
Because we volunteered
to fight cruels.
Do Turks have a better wedding than war, my lion?
We all wanted this.
It's not an obligation for us, it's a favor.
We will first go to the tent, then we'll
say what to do.
BismillahirRahmanirRahim.
Come on.
You are fine, right, my sister?
Thanks to Allah, I am.
May Allah bless you,
You didn't leave me.
It's our duty Ilbilge Hatun.
If that happened to us, you would do the same.
Forget that.
Let me boil linden and cinnamon for you.
No my sister, don't bother yourself.
Do you want anything else?
No thank you.
Osman?
What is that?
This is for you Ilbilge Hatun.
Why did you bother, Osman?
Why did you tired yourself?
Do you remember, Ilbilge Hatun?
I made a promise when you gave me soap
when i was hurt.
I was going to bring a hunt to you.
It will be shifa to you InsAllah.
Thank you.
What are those noises?
InsAllah it's good.
InsAllah.
Or ... father...
Father..
My father and my brothers came grandmother.
they came back.
Thank to Allah.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Long live my Ertuğrul Bey!
Hey, mashallah.
Kayi's shining swords brave Alps..
Welcome to your tribe, sons!
thanks mother.
- Welcome, father.
- thanks my lad.
- thanks my lion.
Mother...
-Welcome. - thanks mother.
-Welcome brother. -thanks.
Welcome.
-My brother. -My Bey.
Hey mashallah.
Welcome my Bey.
Welcome.
thank you Artuk Bey. thank you Melikshah.
Ilbilge Hatun.
We have things to tell you son.
Let's get in first.
Where is my Gündoğdu brother and Selcan Hatun?
We got the aid with Gundogdu Bey.
And put them where you wanted my Bey, but..
..then we received an information.
And they go back to their tents.
İltekin went after Mongols. And
they couldn't hear from him.
And Dundar is looking for him.
Gündoğdu went there to rule the tents.
He did well.
things will get messy.
It will be good for his tribe.
Dundar will come here soon, son.
Dündar married and built his family there.
He won't be like before when he comes back.
Stronger and braver
Dundar will be with us.
Ilbilge Hatun.
Ilbilge Hatun survived a crisis.
What happened Ilbilge Hatun.
Mongols interfered in Beylic election and..
...attempted to have their own man chosen, Ertugrul Bey.
Thanks to Turgut Bey and Gundogdu Bey...
...we got rid of this...
...danger and
ruined their game.
And Sirma, who was burring with the love
of revenge...
... tried to kill me.
And she died like she deserved.
How are you now?
Did they take good care of you in Kayi tents?
May Allah bless them. they took good
care of me.
Thanks to Allah, I'm fine.
We owe you, as you faught for Hakk and the truth
with your bravery and obstinacy.
Cruel ones got the punishment they
deserved both in Kayi and Umuroglu tribe.
the world has seen that fighting
devoted people is impossible.
We have torn the dark curtain with our
claws.
We did our duty.
today and coming
days will be new.
But...
...we must keep our promise first.
Then we'll go to war with Allah's consent.
Mother...
Make preparations for the toy.
Everyone will see.
...how Kayis make a wedding toy.
Don't worry, son.
It's our Beylic and Hatun
laws to help the poor.
We will make a wedding...
...sacrifice sheeps...
...prepare tables with sherbets...
... even our enemies will admire it.
Now it's wedding toy time.
Mashallah to my lads, Mashallah.
Son, look, Your chest will always face the enemy.
And your waist will be strong.
Come on.
Sons, May your hands be always strong!
If you hold it loosely, you lose your sword.
Come on valiants!
My Aybars.
Aybars, Don't hold it like you hold books,
hold it with your hearts.
Come on my Aybars. MasAllah lads.
MashAllah lads.
MashAllah.
Valiants! Stop a while, listen to me.
I see that you are
talented in attacking.
But u ask now...
...how are you going to defend yourselves?
We answer with swords, Bamsi Alpbasi.
EyvAllah Osman, you thought well, but...
Is there any other way to defend yourselves?
And we have our hand shields...
Mashallah.. masAllah my valiant...
Come here with Osman.
Valiants!
Come on valiants.
Hey, MashAllah.
MaşAllah to my lads.
Fight like wolves...
Come on valiants,
you fight too.
MashAllah to my lads, MashAllah.
Allah is Hayy.
Allah is Haqq. (the Embodiment of truth)
Come on my lions... masAllah...
Selamun Aleykum.
Aleykum Selam.
Aleykum Selam my Hodja.
What is it Bamsii? Didn't
we hear the war noises?
My Hodja. We can't know when we'll go to war.
thus i'm training these young valiants.
A new day is comning my Hodja. the war will come.
And we are training to stop enemies.
-MashAllah.
But, you know that exercising is
not only with swords, right?
What else, my Hodja?
You must always exercise
your heart and mind.
Because wars start
with minds and hearts.
You will first raise the conquest...
...in you hearts..
..then you will fight
in the battlefield.
We are exercising with swords to
strengthen our hands.
What should we do to strengthen
our hearts and minds, my Hodja?
The person is valued with what they want..
...not what they are at that moment.
You will aim such good things that...
..your hearts will be good too.
And your minds will be strong.
Allah-u Teala says:
"So when you have finished [your duties],
then stand up [for worship]."
[Surah Ash-Sharh 94-7]
to do this, you must have good aims and dreams.
As your dreams become supreme,
your efforts grow too.
You will stay at this time with your mind. But
your dreams will affect centuries later.
Dream such things that...
..have such a supreme aim that...
..may that aim look from your eyes...
...and may your walk declare that
dream to others that see you.
Do you know Constantine?
-It's Byzantine's city my Hodja.
It's a great city.
It has strong castles.
No one has defeated there, my Hodja.
the Prophet(Sallallahu Alaihi Wasallam) is reported to have said:
"Verily you shall conquer Constantinople. What a wonderful leader will her leader be, and
what a wonderful army will that army be!' [Musnad Ahmad, Al Hakim, Al Jami' al Saghir]
Be valiants, who have big dreams.
Give your all to be granted with our Prophet's good news.
Even if you are not granted today,
open the ways for your children.
Plant such seeds that, they can even
blossom a thousand years later.
May Allah let us to be gained in that good news.
Amen.
-Ameen Ameen.
-Ameen Osman.
However, do not forget.
You have to live a life by following our Prophet
Efendi to be granted with his good news.
Know that nothing is precious
if you are not following him.
EyvAllah my Hodja. You said well.
You look sad, mother.
I'm not sad.
I'm honoured.
Our mortal life...
...passed with serving to this tent,
which is a deposit from Suleyman Sah.
Such happiness, such grief
have been in this tent.
We shedded our tears
on these carpets.
I wonder how much cries of victory this tent hides.
We sometimes fell.
But we always stood up.
Mother.. you survived many problems...
You suffered a lot...
But we always saw you standing tall.
Being a Hatun is not only serving to the tent, my daughter.
Being a Hatun is giving order to the tent..
...giving belief and strength.
Hatun is such a stich that....
...when it falls,
then tent falls.
Beys fight...
...but Hatun cooks.
Bey holds the tent...
But Hatun orders it.
Bey...
...is the mind of the tent...
...and Hatun is the soul of the tent.
You listened to me, learn it well. May
your daughter listen to you too..
...and learn it well.
News have already raised hopes, my Bey.
It's like people were
sleeping but woke up now.
It's the fruits of our efforts.
We were a tribe with 400
tents, but we spreaded.
Many planes will grow from this seeds insAllah.
InshAllah.
-Son. -Father.
Only coal is not enough.
You need a blower.
I wanted to strengthen my sword, father.
We have a toy too.
Come.
You will care about your horse and
sword more than anything, son.
Because we became famous with these two.
And we rule them.
See the iron as yourself.
It gets hot as you burn it.
Iron gets sharper as you hit it.
And there is no enemy which a sharp sword can't cut.
What do they say?
"Infidels' heads are dough,
turks' heads are iron."
You are right father.
It shouldn't rust, like the hands of valiants.
true.
Irons that don't rust and valiants
that don't give up are the best.
take you hammer.
First iron noise,
then qopuz's voise.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Look at the bride, She is applying henna on her hands...
Don't say anything to the bride,
She might get offended and go back home...
She looks like an angel...
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
May your henna be good and your wishes come true.
"Look at the bride, She is applying henna on her hands...
"Don't say anything to the bride,
She might get offended and go back home..
Her door is hennaed...
She looks like an angel...
May your henna be good and your wiches come true.
Look at the bride may your wishes come true...
You are shining like the moon, my daughter.
May Allah keep you away from bad eyes.
Amein Hayme mother.
May Allah bless you
You let me live this peace.
May the toy's fruitfulness find us.
Amine.
You look like a fairy Ilbilge Hatun.
You will inshAllah build your tent with your
son and daughter.
Amin.
Thanks to Allah my Bey.
We are eating from your toy table.
May Allah keep giving you...
..plentifulness insAllah.
Amin brother. Amin.
We came our Bey's glorious toy.
We ate but we must say a few things...
...or else it won't be good my Bey.
We'll see what Bamsi will say.
EyvAllah my Bey.
Now, deers know where the plants are,
goats know where the grasses are...
...camels know the traces..
...foxes smell everything..
...horses know which is heavy and which is light...
...suffering people know where it hurts...
...the brain knows whet ignorance is....
Now...
Ozan (poet) takes his qopuz ad goes to Beys
-Eyvallah.
Ozan knows which Bey is generous.
May Ozans sing in your tent.
May Allah prevent misfortunes.
My Bey, may your state last!
May it last my Bey!
Amin brother amin.
Bamsi said a few things...
Now it's time for you to say a few things, Ozan.
EyvAllah Ertugrul Bey.
Oghuz's 24 ancestors.
It's the victory day.
Noble breed of glorious turks.
it's the victory day.
Bozok and three arrowed ways.
May the road of conquest open.
It's the victory day.
We have traces in Malazgirt.
we have many martyrs.
We have a thousand years past.
It's the victory day.
Don't forget your ancestors who
built this state.
Don't forget who fell martyr for you.
It's the victory day.
The day will come soon and everyone
will learn it.
Crusaders will be ruined soon.
these lands are not enough for us!
Sun will raise a lot more times!
It's the victory day.
Know that blood is the same during war. Burn
with the love of war.
It's the victory day.
Let's fly our flags. Let's shed
Yezid's blood. It's the victory day.
take your swords and shields.
We shouldn't be ashamed as
Bey's sons when we go to toy.
We won't fight, brother...
What are you doing?
It's  my sword.
It's a glorious sword, Osman.
Let me wear it.
-No brother.
Wear your own sword brother.
I'm the oldest. I must wear it.
You are both talented in swords.
This is the first time for me.
I prepared this sword with my father.
It's my right.
So what? He is our father too.
I will put it in fire and let it melt.
You won with you obstinacy Osman.
What are you doing here?
- The wedding will start son.
-We are ready grandmother.
Your father will leave tomorrow.
But you're Dundar uncle is on the way.
Dundar uncle?
Yes, Dundar uncle.
He will come here after years
this time he won't leave.
He must be a Bey like you.
We'll see what you will do with your Dündar uncle.
Come, come.
Umur's daughter Ilbilge...
... do you accept Suleyman Sah's son Ertugrul as your husband?
I do.
Do you?
- I do.
Süleyman Sah's son Ertugrul, do you accept Umur's
daughter Ilbilge as your wife?
I do.
Do you?
- I do.
Witnesses, do you witness?
-We do.
And I ...
...in front of witnesses and people...
...solemnise. May Allah make it last long.
Amine.
Father...
you just came from the duty. Why are
you leaving tomorrow?
Aslıhan.
My beautiful daughter.
Many wars are waiting for us.
My dear, valiants' duty starts with the...
...adhan when he was born...
... and ends with the sela when he died.
Is it going to take time, father?
My Aybars...
son..
....it might be a day...
or a year.
Son ...
We might not come back.
My children ...
... we will take justice there.
We will take hope to innocent people.
Children... nothing is for today.
Everything  is for tomorrow.
Everything is for to leave a good
future for children like you.
My Bamsi...
... whether you come back or stay ...
...you have a Hatun and children who will be proud
of you even if you go and not come back. Know that.
We pray for you and valiants like you.
EyvAllah my Hafsa. EyvAllah.
Don't I know you ?
MasAllah.
My dear...
My Dear...
My lion, my lion.
Thank you.
Why are you standing up Ilbilge Hatun?
Are you obstaining from your Bey?
Come.
I thought Sogut was going to be
a dungeon for me...
...every dark cloud that descended upon me.
..are not here now.
Thanks to the hope and brightness that
you gave, Ertugrul Bey.
No matter how you've been,
you protected your tribe.
And I believe that...
... you will protect my tent aswell.
We will brighten the darkness together now.
..and pass the hard tests together.
We will be separated now.
the biggest award for me is not only being your Hatun...
...but being with you on the...
..way to Hakk.
This is my most important duty now.
My family was destroyed.
My tent was lonely.
I was in the depth of hopelessness.
There was no light...
But Allah showed his mercy in His tests.
He gave me a family
and a glorious tent.
Humankind is tested with his fur,
beloved ones and position.
You were tested with..
..all of them..
..you never gave up on truth.
Only an honest Hatun like you would..
..fit into this tent after years.
It's time to set off, Ilbilge Hatun.
Safely go, Ertugrul Bey.
Your tent and tribe is a deposit for us.
Now i can turn my back as you're here, Ilbilge Hatun.
I don't have to think about it.
And i hope for the future, Ertugrul Bey.
I believe that you will be told in legends.
Your fights will be told.
And i know that your grand children will
remember you.
Because people who will remember you
with a smile on their face after years..
...are your accepted prayers.
InsAllah. InsAllah.
We try, Allah decides.
I may not come back, mother.
Give your blessings.
they're yours, son.
My child...
..which i raised with my love .. my dear...
May your mother's prayers be wings to you.
EyvAllah mother. EyvAllah.
Father...
Hey masAllah to my valiants.
You are the sticks of our tent.
You will stand tall. so our tent and heads will be up...
Osman...
tent is entrusted to you.
Come, my valiants.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
We saw many cruels.
We didn't give up and went everywhere that were
said to  be impossible.
We went over mountains.
Now there's a..
...new labour pain.
It's not only the pain of a day which splits...
...the dark and the day it's the pain of a new
order...
... and a new period.
And the time we were waiting for has come.
We tried for years.
We may not come back.
Give your blessings.
All yours! All yours!
We won't be one of those who left
this world...
...who became tired and...
..escaped.
Now it's time to seal Anatolia with resurrection
who destiny was mixed with...
...grief and sorrow.
Allah-u Ekber!
May the mountains be pastures to
you may hills be easy to pass for you..
...may stones don't touch your feet..
My son...
Safely go, my Ertuğrul Bey.
Ey my grandfather Suleyman Sah's entrust..
..my ancestors' white tent..
...it's my oath to make you cruels' fear
and innocent people's...
..shelter.
Ey our sword, which is the basis of our Beylic.
It's my oath to not put you in
your case...
until i destroy all of the villains.
Ey my glorious flag....
..it's my oath to carry you..
..around the world and fly.
So that we will raise...
...so that the world will wake up...
... then we will be the bearers of those flags, insAllah.
Come on valiants.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
O, who put starts in the sky
and make the clouds mobe...
..o, my Allah, who defeats the armies...
...You hide lights behind the dark...
...divided islam world
is waiting for a hope.
Make us causes of this salvation.
MAke us the flag bearers of this da'wah.
Make us unite the islam world.
Make our horses strong.
Maake our swords strong, which we raise for justice.
May the sun which shines upon us...
... be the informer of the light days.
May it be the starter of a new day...
...which will brighten years.
Amin.. amin.
Amin.
They saw sun as their flag and sky as their tent.
They rode their horses to endless lands.
They saw their swords as their friends and
made thir armies brave.
they carried the holy news to more lands.
They became the name for Resurrection at a time...
...when there was no hope.
And they shouted.
"Justice forever!
Freedom forever!"
This story belongs to those who dream
of a conquest.
To those who fight fearlessly.
To those who demand sufferings.
This legend is the footsteps ot turks,
on the way to the world's order.
You can watch all episode with English sub in our site :
ardirilisertugrul.net
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.SubtitleDB.org