Episode 87 will start after 12:25 min.
Aktolgali...
We've climbed all the mountains
between the Caspian Sea
and the Byzantine border.
The ground was our bed, the sky our tent.
We gave hope to the poor
and struck fear in tyrants.
We did not torment,
nor did we surrender to oppressors.
As long as this soul resides in this body
we'll pierce the houses
of the infidels like spears.
On this road we'll act like Abraham,
as determined as an ant,
we'll walk through fires if necessary.
However, never ever
will we give up our cause.
Those who plotted our downfall
were themselves overthrown.
God didn't abandon
those who stood by him.
Victory will not carry us
to pride or riches.
We'll conquer one heart
instead of a thousand castles.
We'll unify all of humanity.
Today I might only be telling you,
but tomorrow everyone will know it.
If we keep this goal alive and strong,
one day, this whole world
will be conquered by the Turks.
-Run!
-Sir!
We have to run. We're compromised.
They're after us.
Run! Get them!
-Welcome, my Bey.
Thank you, Aleko. Any news?
Not much since Vasilius
cut trade with the Greeks.
Muslim traders have also suffered.
Vasilius has ruined the long standing
trade balance with his ambition, my Bey.
Even his own folk
are set to rise up, Artuk Bey.
How long can Vasilius
keep this up, Ertuğrul Bey?
We can't let a log dam the river.
Trade will return to normal
eventually, Aliyar Bey.
The issue is what
the people will do until then.
Muslim folk are getting by, my Bey.
They can manage.
But the Greeks are suffering.
Did you do what I said?
We're helping the Greeks
as you ordered, my Bey.
But more is needed.
It's coming, Artuk Bey.
More will come.
Protect the stall holders.
If they go, we'll all suffer.
Don't worry, my Bey.
Nobody's going anywhere.
They all respect you and are grateful.
They won't forget what you've done.
Thank you.
Now, let's go.
We'll discuss what to do.
I swear, before the holy soul of Jesus...
and our virgin mother Mary,
that as long as I live
Ertuğrul, Aliyar and Vasilius
will not sleep easy.
Just as they have taken my son
and my Ural from me,
so I will make them suffer
even greater pain.
Yes.
Çolpan.
Come.
You've been in here for weeks.
I was worried you were dead.
I have no intention of dying
before I have taken my revenge, Governor.
I'll do what you could not.
And how will you do that?
Look at yourself.
You want revenge,
but you can't even leave your room.
Why didn't you protect my Ural
when it was in your power to do so?
You used him as bait for Ertuğrul.
He trusted you.
Don't blame me for what happened
to your husband, Çolpan!
He was the victim of his own folly.
And you? What will you do?
My, my, my.
Çolpan...
You managed to hide
your faith from everyone, huh?
I practiced it in secret.
I'll answer to no one but God.
Our faith is our strongest shield.
Our father in heaven is our savior.
His light will show us the way
while agony will surely find
its way to them some day.
You're stronger than Ural. And smarter.
If we are to be truly strong,
being united isn't enough, Aliyar Bey.
Our people need us
to protect them from other
religions and nations.
Now that the dust has settled,
the situation
that the people find themselves in
has become much
more obvious, Ertuğrul Bey.
The tyranny of Vasilius on one side,
famine on the other.
All non-Muslims are suffering.
We didn't have any food
when we arrived here either, Artuk Bey.
We know their suffering.
We'll share what we have.
For a long time
all they've thought to want
is food and water,
when what they actually need is security,
mercy and prosperity, Ertuğrul Bey.
That's why we have a lot to do,
Aliyar Bey.
We'll create a new order.
We'll work harder, but cautiously,
without letting our victory blind us.
To truly triumph,
it isn't only territory we must conquer,
but the hearts of the people.
Our enemies will have many
sleepless nights ahead of them,
especially Vasilius, Ertuğrul Bey.
That's exactly what we want, Aliyar Bey.
The people are human beings
and deserve to be respected as such.
As God created the universe
and the people, we respect it all.
There's been no word of that dog
Vasilius for a long time, Ertuğrul.
We don't know where he is
or what he's planning.
Vasilius will want to avenge
the wound we inflicted on him.
He'll be planning something big.
His defeats will also worry the emperor.
That's why they'll very likely
send reinforcements.
May I enter, my Bey?
Come in, Samsa.
Forgive me, my Bey,
but I have important news.
Governor Vasilius!
Nikolas.
Great Commander Vasilius,
we're at your command.
Protectors of our empire,
my fearless warriors,
welcome to your castle!
At your command, sir!
You've marched a great distance,
get some rest.
As you command, sir.
My loyal friend, Nikolas.
I've been waiting for this for so long.
Come, we have much to discuss. Come along.
Speak, Dumrul.
We were watching the castle as ordered.
A large unit has arrived from Nicaea.
More than before, my bey.
So that's the reason for
this silence, Ertuğrul Bey.
Vasilius is making preparations.
Vasilius' intention is clear.
These soldiers haven't come to defend
the castle but to spill our blood.
They're about to take their last breath,
because we're going
to take out their lungs.
How did we not hear of such
an important development earlier, my Bey?
The Sultan's eye in Nicaea...
Something must have happened to him.
Either...
he was unable to leave the palace...
or he's been compromised, Ertuğrul Bey.
In either case, his life is in danger.
-I'm all right, keep going!
-Come on.
With no news from the palace,
we're effectively blind.
We have no one at the castle either.
Be our guest today, Aliyar Bey.
We can spend the evening together.
We can discuss what we should do.
God willing, I shall
be there, Ertuğrul Bey.
My armor is dusty
and my sword is rusty, Nikolas
That man in Nicaea...
That fool, that coward...
Most of the generals at the palace agree
with us, Vasilius. They're ready for war.
They've had enough
of this cowardly emperor.
You're a beacon of hope to them, Vasilius.
He's not my emperor.
All he deserves is a hole full of mud.
When I'm done with the Turks,
it'll be his turn.
His throne will be his grave.
Ertuğrul has slowed us down.
He's the great hope of the Turks now.
He's the head of the snake!
Before he came along it was
the Turks who were hiding, not us.
He gave them courage.
If he dies...
the Turks will lose all hope.
If only Ural had succeeded, we'd be
celebrating our victory right now.
Yeah...
Ural doesn't really matter.
He did what I wanted him to do.
They fought amongst each other.
They've lost trust.
We made a breach
in the Turk's shield, Nikolas.
And now we widen this breach.
You've been quiet for a long time.
They'll think you've given up.
Let them, Nikolas.
Let them. That's what I want.
I've been making plans.
I'll attack when they least expect it.
Also...
this old castle has been fortified.
I've repaired all the towers myself.
Sultan Alaeddin has set his eye
on Karacahisar, despite the Mongols.
Everyone knows that.
He's set his eye on his grave.
He just doesn't know it yet.
Even if he laid siege,
he'd have to fight for months.
Anyway, we'll beat them before they
even get a chance to approach the walls.
The time for defense is over.
Now we attack. To victory.
To our victory.
Don't hold the sword
too tightly or too loosely.
It must be an extension of your body.
Understand?
Strength and speed.
Without these...
no sword will obey you.
The sword wants a strong alp.
The sword wants a brave alp.
-Are you brave and strong?
-Yes, we are!
Show me then.
You.
Attack.
Good. Like this.
Attack again.
You're not even at half strength.
We have enemies on all sides.
First, know your enemy well.
Know who's strong, who's weak.
Go on, warriors.
-Now, work harder. Come on.
-As you command, Master Alp!
Come on. Keep going. Great.
God protect you, Dündar Bey.
My children have gone to bed hungry.
Now they'll eat, thanks to you.
Ertuğrul Bey is always with you,
remember that.
-God bless you.
Banu Çiçek Hatun.
Don't worry. We'll take care of it.
Banu Çiçek Hatun...
Think of the baby inside you.
We don't want anything happening
to our nephew.
You never thought about
Doğan while he was alive.
Shame.
You'd been walking around like a bey.
Who knew you'd be a curse on the tribe?
Now, Dündar Bey... stay away from me.
Devoted women of the Kayi tribe...
and brave men.
We follow a prophet
who would not sleep with a full belly
while his neighbor was hungry.
Our responsibility is a heavy one.
We must help all innocents
without seeing religion or nationality.
Our help will be the hope
of our non-Muslim neighbors.
They will not forget our sacrifice.
God willing,
these donations will strengthen our union.
God willing.
-May God bless you all.
-Amen.
-God bless you.
And you also.
You fool, Dündar!
Doğan Alp died because of you.
His wife suffers.
His child will be fatherless.
You don't deserve anything.
Selamunaleykum, Dündar Bey.
Aleykumselamun, sir.
Come, Dündar Alp. Let's talk a little.
Our prophet tells us that...
if we had not sinned,
God would have destroyed us
and instead created sinning
and repenting servants.
What this means is
that we sin and make mistakes
because we are human.
God is happy that we repent
and take refuge in him.
Sir, what if this mistake caused
the death of an innocent.
What if a pregnant,
crying woman has been left behind?
Dündar Alp, no sin is greater
than God's mercy.
He forgives. He's happy to forgive.
The issue isn't not making mistakes...
it's understanding and not repeating them.
Sir...
I'm so angry with myself.
I can't forgive myself.
You've learned your lesson.
But God does not love
those who go to extremes.
You must obey your brother
and carry out his commands
as best you can.
I'll never stray from my brother's path.
I'll do my best to serve my tribe.
That is the best thing you could do.
May God grant you good fortune.
Amen sir. Amen.
I have to go now. Excuse me.
I like to wander around and enjoy nature.
-Good day, sir.
-Thank you.
Banu Çiçek, my sister.
The people of this tribe
are each a part of the same body.
Just as a wound hurts the whole body,
so one person's problem disturbs us all.
Doğan was your husband and our brother.
But don't forget,
Doğan Alp's sacrifice has placed
a great responsibility upon you.
You must be even stronger now.
How can I be?
How can I overcome this, Halime Sultan?
God wouldn't give responsibility
to someone who couldn't shoulder it.
You sadden us.
We will certainly help you.
You're a woman of this tribe.
How could we abandon you, Banu Çiçek?
I feel your pain
but please forgive Dündar.
He made a mistake and regrets it deeply.
You should forgive him.
Stand firm. See the man.
Hit like this. Let's go!
Who's against you?
-Who's against you?
-You are Bamsi Alp.
The enemy. The enemy!
We are enemies!
Why are you hitting me like I'm a carpet?
When you're hold this sword,
you don't look all kind and sweet
as if it's your lover in front of you.
You look angry. You look angry!
As if you face an infidel.
As if you face an infidel! Go. Go.
Go.
What are you doing? Drop the sword.
No sword for you from now on.
-What are--
-Silence!
Go away and eat something.
Eat honey, drink some syrup.
Carry logs and rocks.
Don't return until you've
made these arms twice as big.
Go now. Go now!
Go.
Brother, what are you doing?
You humiliated him.
I did it for his own good, brother.
Didn't you see him?
He couldn't carry
more than a couple of arrows!
He has to be stronger. He has to eat.
The infidel would eat that one alive,
brother.
All right.
Come on, come on alps!
Brothers, attack as if
it is Vasilius' dogs before you!
As if you face an infidel! Go.
Come on, warriors!
Keep at it.
As if he's an infidel. Keep at it.
The sultan's spy is worrying me, my Bey.
It's been a while since he last came.
And now this unit of soldiers
has arrived, without us knowing about it.
My Bey, I fear he's been compromised.
Then we'll lose our link
with the emperor's palace.
We'll no longer be able to give
information to our Sultan.
Did you get a chance to meet
the Sultan in Konya, Artuk Bey?
No, I didn't, my Bey.
I believe I'll leave this world
without once seeing our Sultan.
My Bey, when I got to the palace
it was unusually quiet.
Someone said our Sultan wasn't there.
I don't know if that was true.
Let's hope for good news.
But everyone spoke highly of him.
The people are always praying for him.
Thank God for him.
We have to help
the merchants in the bazaar.
We have to strengthen the reputation
and the security of the bazaar.
Nobody shall be taxed from now on.
As you command, my Bey.
At a time like this, freeing them from
taxes would relieve them greatly.
Support the merchants
with our gold as well.
Protect them.
I've abolished interest, my Bey.
They'll have all that they need
if you give gold to them too.
If they lose, we lose, Artuk Bey.
But their prayers will
bring us prosperity.
Thank you, my Bey.
Hold on, sir. Hold on. I'll get you out.
Spread out. You go that way.
One of them is injured. Look for blood.
Yes, sir.
Don't worry, sir. I won't let you die.
You'll live. Hold on.
Listen to me.
Go to the Kayi tribe, quickly.
Find Ertuğrul Bey.
Give this to him.
Tell him to hurry before the eye
of the Sultan is blinded.
I bring information which is
very important for the state.
Sir, I can't leave you.
Do as I say.
He must hear that message.
Don't worry, sir.
I'll give my life for this if necessary.
We found this, sir.
It must belong to one of them.
There's blood on it.
Maybe he's dead.
We can't be sure without a body.
Keep looking.
I'll go to Governor Vasilius
to ask for help searching for the spy.
We have to catch them, dead or alive. Go.
Did you leave your room at last, Çolpan?
Not Çolpan.
Ekaterina.
I'm glad you remembered
that you're a noblewoman, Ekaterina.
Whatever it was that
poisoned you in the past...
you must get rid of it, Ekaterina.
You can start with the dagger
with which they stabbed us.
For the waist of a beautiful
woman like you...
a Byzantine dagger would go well.
This dagger will go into the hearts
of our enemies, Governor.
If I don't do it...
the baby inside me will.
Çolpan, are you with child?
Ural's last gift to me.
I'm carrying his child.
That is great news!
I couldn't be any happier
if it was my child.
This child will bring us our vengeance.
How?
When Aliyar and Aslıhan hear
that you're pregnant
they'll have no choice but to show mercy
and take you back into the tribe.
And that mercy will bring about their end.
Welcome.
We have heard a lot about Ertuğrul Bey
through our friends.
We are here to trade in peace.
They call me
Ebu Mansur Muhammed in Aleppo.
Welcome.
You are more than welcome here.
I am Ertuğrul Bey's brother.
My name is Dündar.
Be our guest with your men.
You have come from a long way,
get some rest.
Thank you.
I know that you are at war
with the Tekfur of Karacahisar.
However...
you continue to trade with the Rums.
These supplies will be sent
to the Rum people who need help.
To the Rum people?
I have seen many states in my life.
But you are the only state...
that helps the people of the enemy.
Ertuğrul Bey always gives support
to the indigent people.
It seems Ertuğrul Bey
is not only a great warrior,
but also a very generous man.
This is my mother, Hayme.
And my brother's wife, Halime Sultan.
Ebu Mansur.
He is a merchant from Aleppo, Mother.
Welcome.
So, you are the ones
who made those beautiful rugs
which Europeans
have been rhapsodizing over.
We are using our ancestors’ methods,
that's what makes our rugs so special.
We weave our rugs with passion.
I am here to talk about this.
I want to place an order for many rugs.
In fact...
I will pay half of it right now.
I do not know how many more
generous merchants there are.
Our rugs will please you.
You will not regret this.
But shouldn't we discuss it
with Ertuğrul Bey, Mother?
Sister, I will explain it to my brother.
Don't worry about it.
Fine. Okay.
I am in no hurry.
I am a very patient and wealthy man.
You look familiar to me.
I have traveled to many cities,
and many places.
We must have met somewhere.
Take care of our guests, Son.
Let them rest well.
Günkut, prepare food for our guests.
Take care of their horses too.
Let them rest.
Come with me, Bey.
I will show you the way.
Mother, Dündar Bey,
I feel like I know him from somewhere...
but I couldn't place where.
I have doubts about him.
Neither he nor his men
look like merchants.
They look like royal people.
Kayi Tribe is here.
And Cavdar Tribe is here.
Hanlı Bazaar is in the middle of them.
Right here.
As you said,
if we took the Hanlı Baazar,
we would cut them off.
Ertuğrul would lose his reputation.
Ertuğrul took Hanlı Bazaar
by trickery, anyway.
Ertuğrul...
has become more powerful
thanks to that bazaar.
Now it will be his grave.
The Emperor's guards are here, sir.
Their commander wants to see you.
Let him come right away.
What are the Emperor's guards
doing here, Nikolas?
The Emperor uses them
only for important matters.
It means there is a serious matter.
Tekfur Vasilius,
we need your soldiers' help.
What is the matter, tell me.
At the Emperor's palace,
we have discovered a spy
who is serving Sultan Alaeddin.
I have tracked him down here.
What happened then?
We attacked him
when he met another man this morning.
We had wounded the spy.
However, he managed to escape
with the other guy.
Do you know
who this spy will contact?
No, we do not know.
We will never know
if we cannot catch them.
It may take days to find them.
We have found the spy's bag.
His stuff is here.
Spy's bag...
I know how we can find him.
Nikolas, prepare your best men,
we are setting off.
Yes, sir.
Selamunaleykum.
Aleykumselamun.
Your alps are in very good shape.
They look as strong as a tiger.
They are.
We train all the time.
You know war is around the corner.
We need to be prepared.
Are the other Turk tribes also
as ready for war as the Kayi Tribe?
They are.
At our tribal meetings, Ertuğrul Bey
recommends to the Turkmen Beys
that they should get their Alps ready.
He deals with them personally.
Does Ertuğrul Bey
only care about his Alps?
I've heard that he is
also interested in politics.
You will have to ask him
when he comes back.
Let's talk about rugs.
You sound like
an experienced merchant, Dündar Bey.
Actually, I am not a merchant.
My brother has arrived.
Alps, Ertuğrul Bey is here!
-Welcome, Bey.
-Bey, welcome.
May you never lose a fight!
May you always be strong!
Train well, Alps.
Long live our Bey!
That heathen Vasilius...
is a blood-thirsty man,
and now he summons
new soldiers from Nicaea.
For this reason,
we will continue
to be cautious all the time.
Our unity with the Turk Beys is strong!
Prioritize your trainings.
While our Sultan
is dealing with Mongols in the east,
we will continue to make life here
unbearable for Vasilius.
We will show our sultan
what we are made of!
Come on, Alps,
continue your training
with all your power.
Yes, Bey!
Go on, Alps.
Sir, what I don't understand is
why these spies came here, but not Konya?
There is another one who is
sending messages between Konya and Nicaea.
He is here, in my lands.
Who?
-We will find out.
-How?
We are not the only ones
who are looking for the spy.
The man who is sending messages
to the sultan
must also have gone after the spy.
If we find the spy before they do...
Then we will also find
the traitor in my lands.
Welcome, brother.
Thank you, Dündar.
What is the situation?
Everything is all right, thank God.
Good.
You have been working hard.
You make me proud with your hard work.
Now you deserve to be a Bey and an Alp.
Bey...
May God bless you, Bey.
You have honored me greatly.
I also have good news for you, brother.
Tell me.
A merchant came from Aleppo.
His name is Ebu Mansur.
He has heard of our rugs' fame.
And wants to buy some.
And he paid a lot of gold coins.
Now that's good news.
Where is he now?
He is there, brother.
He was there.
How could he disappear suddenly?
His disappearance means
he didn't want me to see him.
Halime said she knows him from somewhere,
but she couldn't remember where.
We will find out.
Come, brother.
Keep up your good work.
Sir, the dogs smelled something. This way.
You haven't said a single word
since you came back from Emir Sadettin.
You used to ride horses,
train with your sword and go hunting.
Now you are imprisoned in your tent,
like an eagle in a cage.
I wanted to be a drop in the river.
But fate locked me in a water bottle.
I wanted to fly like a bird
in the savannah.
But fate wants me to imprison in a palace.
Look, Sister,
you are the only woman in my family.
I promised my father
I would look after you.
When I look at you...
I see my deceased mother.
And for this reason,
I made you my deputy, Aslıhan.
You don't say it by your tongue,
but I can see it in your eyes.
So, I am asking one more time, Sister.
Do you want to marry him?
I do not want any hostility
between our state and our tribe, brother.
I am ready to sacrifice myself
for our tribe.
No one can force you
into this marriage.
It is too late now, brother.
Do you think Emir Sadettin would just
give up on this marriage?
I will accept my destiny.
You rest assured, Sister.
As long as I live,
no one can force you into this.
I would not use you for politics.
Do not worry about it.
Thank God, I have you, brother.
Amen, Sister.
We will visit Ertuğrul Bey tonight.
Get ready, Aslıhan.
Yes, brother.
Sir, it started to rain,
the traces will be lost.
Hurry, then! Hurry!
Sir, they are hiding in the cave.
We've been dealing with a lot of trouble.
But thank God, anyway.
We aren't going to leave our country.
These lands are enough for all of us.
-Yes, they are.
-Right. It is enough.
Does Ertuğrul Bey
have any involvement with all of this?
I swear to God,
we didn't see anything wrong from him.
He helped us all,
when we were having a hard time.
He just remitted the taxes today.
And he promised he will give
interest-free loans to the merchants.
You want to work with us.
But we can't promise you anything,
since we don't know
what's going to happen.
We do not want to let you down.
Were you going to say something, Aleko?
I was going to ask if you have an order.
Bring meat to my guests.
Bring sherbet to them.
And do not disappoint me.
Yes, Bey.
You go and prepare a good meal,
do not disappoint us.
I will be right with you.
They play politics at the table.
I do not like this man, Dumrul Alp.
He has booked the entire in.
I even couldn't find rooms for all them.
It does not matter, Aleko.
They would never leave Ebu Mansur alone.
They don't look like
they will sleep tonight.
Dumrul Alp,
I fear that Vasilius is behind this.
Do not worry, Aleko.
Our Alp will stay all night long.
And I will go to our tribe, and
inform Ertuğrul Bey about this man.
Bey should know what this man is doing.
Sorry to bother you.
Did we wake you up?
Tell me...
Who is your spy
in Sultan Alaeddin's lands?
Tell me, who are you waiting for?
Speak!
I am waiting for Azrael.
You bastard!
Commander Vasilius, there were two men,
one of them is missing.
Just as I guessed.
The missing spy
will get us the sultan's man.
Get your soldiers ready.
We will ambush them when they come.
In the name of God.
Thank God, we can share the same food now.
May God bless our food.
-Amen.
Amen.
Enjoy your meal.
Thank you.
Our food will be more blessed,
God willing.
A merchant came today.
He has heard about the fame of the rugs
which we made for Europeans.
Thank God.
We are lucky now.
We are starting to solve our problems.
You deserve this, my dear.
God always gives you what you deserve.
We will unite again.
We will weave rugs and earn gold coins.
-God willing.
The rugs' fame traveled fast,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Wonderful, Sister.
Something is not right about this.
I have been thinking about it.
The merchant gave us
a lot of gold coins, Bey.
As a down payment.
Then he vanished into thin air.
He did.
He gave lots of gold coins,
and then vanished into thin air?
It is a good job, Ertuğrul Bey.
However, I wonder who this man is,
where is he coming from?
He said his name was Ebu Mansur.
He comes from Aleppo.
That is what he said to Dündar.
I think I know him from somewhere,
but I couldn't place where.
I hope his intentions are good,
because this job is very important
for both of our tribes.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Dumrul.
Bey, I have come from the inn.
A merchant named Ebu Mansur
has come to the inn.
So, he vanished into thin air,
and then showed up at the inn?
He talked with the merchants.
He talked about trade, and politics.
He kept asking questions.
Asked about their business,
about the situation in the land,
and about Byzantine.
He is a silver-tongued man, Bey.
People pay close attention
to what he says.
He earned everybody's respect
in no time at all.
Thank you, Dumrul.
Thank you.
You keep an eye on him.
Keep watching him.
Yes, Bey.
He is just a merchant
who wants to buy rugs, Ertuğrul Bey.
Why is he asking so many questions?
We will find out, Aliyar Bey.
We will find out.
Easy, Bamsi, you will choke.
Are you in a hurry,
are you going somewhere?
Hafsa Hatun...
Where did you learn to cook like this?
Thanks to Mother Hayme,
she teaches me everything.
Of course, of course she does.
This is Mother Hayme's dish.
Hafsa Hatun, I mean,
you made it delicious, of course.
I wish my brothers could see me like this.
I wish they knew
how happy Bamsi Alp is now.
All the single men would envy me.
I wish...
Now I understand, Bamsi.
You want to go to your brothers.
No, no way.
No way, my love.
I mean, of course,
my brothers want to see me,
but I told them...
I told them Bamsi Alp would never leave
his woman in the tent and go.
Go now.
And tell them
Hafsa Hatun knows your heart.
If her lover
would be happy with his brothers,
then she will be patient
and wait for him to come back.
Okay, then. Good.
Wonderful. My wonderful woman.
Thank God for giving you to me.
Wonderful woman.
I am going then.
My dear,
you look too thoughtful.
Why are you worried?
I am fine. I was thinking about the rugs.
And my marriage.
I felt sad, because I won't be with you.
Do not worry, my dear.
Your marriage is more important.
We can finish the rugs without you.
So... did you set a day for the wedding?
Our sultan has vanished into thin air.
We had to postpone the wedding.
We will marry when Emir Sadettin is here.
Let's hope for the best.
Maybe it is better to postpone it.
-Brother...
-They are like family to us, Aslıhan.
We have nothing to hide from them.
What is happening, Aliyar Bey?
What is the matter?
I told my sister as well, Ertuğrul Bey...
If she doesn't want...
Halime, are you okay?
Lie down here.
Easy.
Mother, my baby is coming.
Go and tell Artuk Bey, my dear, quick.
-Okay.
-My dear.
Bamsi said he'd come,
before we finish eating.
But he has not come yet.
He is just married, Turgut Alp.
And it is not easy to leave your love.
He will come, brother.
I am here, brothers.
My brother is here!
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
You look good.
-You look good, brothers.
-Sit down.
Okay.
I told you, Bamsi
would never leave his brothers alone.
Welcome, brother.
Thank you, brother.
Would I ever leave you alone?
Did you say the same thing to Hafsa Hatun?
You said you wouldn't leave your brothers?
No.
I told Hafsa Hatun,
"There is an impertinent man among Alps,
his name is Günkut,
and he has a big mouth,
I will take care of him first,
and then come back." Come here!
Come here, Günkut.
Come here! Come!
I don't even feel like
getting mad at you.
Do not worry, come.
Come and eat, Günkut, come.
Go on, sit, brother.
Mischief!
This is love, brother.
It makes flowers burst in your heart.
You lose all your worries and anger.
You are right, brother, you are right.
However, brothers I have learned
that there are two kinds of women;
one makes flowers burst in your heart,
and the other one withers your flowers.
You said it well, brother,
but how can we find a woman like that?
How can we understand
which woman gives love
and which gives pain?
My brother, my dear brother...
You will beg God, like this, brother,
and you will pray.
With good intentions, of course.
And then you will find your woman
dropped out of the sky.
Like an apple falls from the tree.
Let's eat.
Enjoy your meal.
You talk about
apples, and flowers, Bamsi, but...
You have come here hungry.
Didn't your wife feed you?
Now, you deserve a good beating, brother.
You deserve a good beating.
Come here, come!
Help me God!
You deserve a good beating. Come here!
In the name of God.
Halime Sultan is not well, Bey.
The birth has started.
But something is not right.
Go and bring the midwifes.
I will bring them.
Hafsa Hatun, prepare some hot water.
We will need it when the midwife comes.
Yes, Artuk Bey.
My dear.
What's the situation, Artuk Bey?
We cannot be hopeless now, sir.
We'll do whatever we can.
However, the baby could be breech.
Sir, this man wants to see you.
He says it's important.
What could it be?
Who are you?
Sir, I was sent by the eye of the Sultan.
Come here.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Let's go.
Bismillah. Here we go.
God help us.
A little more to go.
It'll be over in an instant.
Come on.
Stay calm, all of you.
One more push.
Come on.
Push, Halime Sultan.
It's almost over.
Yes, come on.
Keep pushing, dear.
My dear.
It's almost out, Halime Sultan.
A little more to go.
-Push.
-Halime Sultan.
Just a bit more.
Where is the eye of the sultan?
Why did he send you?
His eye's identity was revealed.
He had to escape from the castle.
Are you serious?
We were ambushed at our
meeting point with the eye.
He was wounded.
I had to hide him in a cave I found.
He's dying.
However, he told me that
he had something important to tell you.
He wants to see you before he dies.
Who were you going to meet?
Where were you taking the information
you gathered at the palace?
Speak.
Go to hell, Vasilius.
Even if you don't tell me now,
I'll find out once he comes
to save you anyway.
Shut your mouth!
Curses be on you, Vasilius.
Damn you and your emperor!
Turgut, prepare your best men.
We've received an important mission.
Yes, sir.
Ertuğrul Bey, I may not be able
to find my way back in the dark.
We wait till morning and the eye dies.
Ertuğrul Bey, daytime
would be better for us than nighttime.
We couldn't find him if we went now.
The sun will rise soon.
Tell Ishak to get ready,
he'll be coming with us.
Our man is injured.
-Yes, sir.
-As you wish, sir.
Ebu Mansur,
I've things to tell you if I may.
I'm listening.
The jackal left
with the rest of its pack today.
He probably got the scent
of game, then.
Which way did they go?
To a place called Nikos Hill.
Once jackals go hunting,
lions can't stand still.
The baby doesn't want to come out easily.
It's breech.
Push, Halime Sultan.
Endure it just a bit more.
Push.
My dear.
Come on. Just a bit more.
Push, my dear.
Keep going, Sister.
Come on Halime Hatun.
Just a bit more.
Come on, my dear.
God help me.
Son.
Why are you awake?
I'm waiting for the baby to be born.
Are you waiting for it too?
As we wait for the sunrise,
we are waiting for that as well.
What if it doesn't come?
Why would that be?
It'll come, just as you did.
Did you wait for me too, Daddy?
Of course we did, Son.
If you want to see the baby soon,
you must go to bed.
Then you'll be able to see it faster.
I want to see my mom.
Not now, Son.
Go on, now.
Come on.
Gunduz.
May I come in, sir?
Come in, Turgut.
The sun will rise any minute now.
All right.
What is the situation, Artuk Bey?
It's not good, sir.
God help her.
Ertuğrul Bey, we can go
to save the man if you'd like.
You can stay with Halime Sultan.
We swore to protect our country.
My baby will come into this world
without me and live freely.
Turgut, prepare the horses.
Yes, sir.
I'm coming in.
Son.
Ertuğrul!
Halime, bear with me.
Endure it.
God will help both you and our baby.
Son, you're getting in the way.
I'll be back, Halime.
No matter what.
Come on, dear.
Push.
Take good care of her, Artuk Bey.
Leave it to me, sir.
We'll do our best.
It'll be all right.
Thank you.
Let us leave.
Halime, just a bit more.
Ebu Mansur, just as you said
the lion went for the hunt.
Which way?
To where the jackal is.
Ebu Mansur.
Where are you going, sir?
Ertuğrul Bey was coming here to see you.
I have enough respect for him
to not make him wait, Dumrul Alp.
I'll be back before he comes.
Tell our men to find out
where that man is going.
It's okay, my dear
Take deep breaths.
Deep breaths, Halime Sultan.
Breathe in, breathe out.
Breathe, Sister.
Breathe out.
God help us.
Ertuğrul.
Dear God!
Heaven and earth, be my witness.
I'll be a father!
Ertuğrul, not in the next winter quarters,
nor in any other place we go,
don't you ever make your son wonder
where you are and cry.
I don't know when I'll die,
or what my fate is.
However,
as long as I'm alive,
know that I'd never
let you or our son suffer.
Never leave our side.
My dear.
Bring hot water.
I'll do it.
Breathe in.
God, don't take my girl and my baby.
God help us.
Here.
Endure it, Sister. Stay strong.
-Bear with it, Sister.
-Here, my dear.
Push.
Keep pushing.
God help us.
Come on.
Come on, dear.
Take deep breaths.
Let Governor Vasilius know.
Ertuğrul and his men are coming.
We'll go on foot from here.
Turgut.
Aliyar Bey.
Be careful.
All right, Ertuğrul Bey.
Right, sir.
Let's go.
Sir, Ertuğrul and his men are coming.
They left their horses
and are climbing up the hill.
Ertuğrul.
So, the spy of the sultan in this land
was Ertuğrul, huh?
He turned out to be strong after all.
He was strong.
But not anymore.
I'll never wipe your blood
off my sword, Ertuğrul.
Nikolas, let's go.
Men! Hide as I instructed you.
Nobody moves without my orders.
Come now, Ertuğrul.
Dear God.
You gave us all kinds of fruits,
budding fruit trees,
and sweet-smelling flowers.
Your existence, your singularity,
your beauty and your perfection
are evident in all that exists.
For the love of all your beautiful names,
please bless us with your guidance.
Oh, God!
You granted sainthood
to the prophet Joseph
who was thrown into a pitch black well.
You saved the prophet Jonah, who fell
into the sea, in the stomach of a fish.
You protected the prophet Muhammad
with spider webs.
We beg for your help
in all our hopelessness.
Please protect those
fighting for you,
and those following your cause.
Don't let them fall prey
to traps set up for them.
Only you can help,
and grant our wishes.
Grace us, God.
For the love of our holy prophet,
hear our prayers and grant us our wishes.
Hear us.
Amen.
Turgut.
Stay here, watch out back.
Yes, sir.
My dear.
Push.
The baby can't breathe.
Push, Halime Sultan.
Push.
Bear it, Sister.
Push, Sister.
Come on.
Come on, dear.
Sister.
Push, Sister.
It's about to come.
We must turn it over.
Come on, Halime Sultan.
Push.
Push, my dear.
Be strong now.
Think about your baby.
Come on.
Please God, don't take them away from us.
My dear.
No!
-Halime.
-Halime, my dear.
Halime.
My dear.
Sir, he's dead.
No.
Can't be.
Sir.
How could they do this to you?
Vasilius.
They found him before us, Ertuğrul Bey.
This is a trap, Aliyar Bey.
A trap.
Men!
Get ready! It's a trap!
What are your orders, Your Highness?
Aliyar Bey.
Aliyar, Brother!
Wait.
Aliyar Bey! Wait, my brother.
We'll get out of here.
Brother.
It's over now.
This is the end of your fame, Ertuğrul.
You can take all the fame.
Martyrdom will suffice for us.
Come on!