Episode 62 will start after 12:40 min.
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY.
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
With the 99 names
of the omnipotent God
who fills our hearts with faith...
Holy God!
Dear God,
demolish the traps
on our way of holy voyage.
Keep us alert in the face of the enemy.
Dear God,
let our weapons be
as mighty as the Zulfiqar
and our hearts be
as brave as Imam Ali's heart.
Don't give the chance
to those who want to
destroy our brotherhood, unity and peace.
We ask for only thy help,
we bow only to thou.
Don't leave us alone, my God.
Praise be to God!
Praise to God!
We've secured the perimeters, sir.
Very well.
Ertuğrul should be here any moment.
As-Salaam-Alaikum.
Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Our sultan sends his regards to you.
He is very pleased with your services.
I heard the dog has become the new vizier.
Sometimes dirty people are needed
for the dirty work.
The state should be clean at all times.
It should cleanse the source of the dirt
in order to prevent us from drowning
in that dirt one day.
No doubt our sultan has a plan.
That's also what I hope.
The sultan has a new task for you.
I'd be honored.
You...
will conquer Karacahisar.
It plays a key role.
If we conquer Karacahisar
then we can take all the Byzantium lands
to Constantinople.
We've gotten rid of the traitors.
Now is the time to conquer.
With God's permission, we'll do our best.
We will handle this
without alerting anyone.
You...
will look as weak as possible.
No one will expect any danger
neither financially nor militarily.
We can handle looking like a tamed sheep.
Nice.
According to the intel from Constantinople
Crusaders are getting prepared
for a new crusade.
They intend to drive us away
from these lands.
And we intend to
make these lands our home.
This one is different, Sir Ertuğrul.
All the enemies joined forces.
Making preparations to attack us
with all the power they have.
Then we Turks will defend our country
until the last drop of our blood.
So...
we will act quick
and barricade their attack.
Appreciated.
That's exactly what we want.
Defense begins on the enemy territory.
Otherwise...
we might lose our homeland.
Now...
listen carefully to what I have to say.
The sultan's spy in Constantinople
will bring a name to you.
This name belongs to...
the spy of the Templars.
The devil himself.
His purpose...
is to pave the way for the crusaders
in our lands.
I know all too well about the sultan's spy
in Constantinople.
We won't be able to conquer Karacahisar
until the Templar spy is dead.
Where will I find him?
Where?
The inn...
Bazaar...
Dündar!
Get that traitor!
Turgut!
What the hell?
Your people attacked.
Not ours, they were Iznik's Templars.
Damn idiots.
My sultan, the spy in Constantinople,
will come to the Bazaar at the inn.
He will reveal
the name of the Templars' leader.
To whom?
Inglorious bastards.
Brother...
He told a man with a covered face
everything you discussed.
Did he reveal our identities?
Stopped talking
when my arrow went through his neck.
Good lad!
You have spared us from big trouble.
We have two different enemies, sir.
First one is those who can be seen,
the other one is the unseen bastards.
It's even better, my lad.
One goes, the other comes.
We won't be out of options.
Our war is on a different level now.
We must be alert at all times here.
They have created games within games.
In order to destroy these traps,
we will do what they do.
Sir, let us cut their tongues
and deliver them
from their lies and traps.
To achieve victory in this holy voyage
we shall now design our own traps
for them.
First, let's bury our martyrs
then we will go for the bazaar
at the inn.
Yes, sir.
"Don't descript those who die
in the pursuit of Allah's way as dead.
On the contrary, they are alive.
Yet, you cannot see them."
THE VILLAGE OF KAYI
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
May you have control
over your body and mind.
Don't look for your daily bread anywhere
but in God's presence.
May you not waste your intelligence
and skills for anything but good.
I give the hand.
I have the end.
May you not hurt a single creature.
May you not have dirt on your hands.
May you not lay eyes on evil.
I'll do all I can to be the remedy,
to be the cure
and to be worthy of my mentor.
Appreciate it, son.
May God help you.
Gündüz!
My brother!
Gündüz! My brother!
Gündüz!
Don't cry, my little lamb, what happened?
My sweetie, don't cry.
Don't cry.
There's blood all over the child's face.
You can't even take care
of a child, Günkut.
Lady Halime, I swear to God
it's not my fault.
My girl, boys grow up
having such experiences.
It's their mothers' duty to straighten
and sharpen these experiences.
If you keep hugging and coddling him
anytime he gets hurt...
then you'll raise a coward,
not a brave man.
You're right, Mother.
Thank you.
My Gündüz will be brave just like his dad
and his uncles.
So İshak's first patient is my Gündüz.
How is the inventory?
I'll start allocation in a moment.
But if Ertuğrul comes with an empty hand
then we'll have a hard time.
You go deal with your tasks,
I will take care of Gündüz.
-Sweetheart...
-Günkut, help her out.
My sweet lamb...
Women with children get in line for flour.
The old and sick should get in that line
for buckwheat.
Come on, hand over your pots.
Next.
Which of my children am I supposed to feed
with only this much flour, Lady Halime?
Patience, sisters.
Just a little more patience.
We've been patiently waiting for months,
still all we get is a pot of flour!
The animals are wasted,
nothing to hunt on the mountains.
We are starving, enough is enough.
What are we supposed to eat?
Where are we supposed to find bread?
Enough is enough.
Is this what we get
for months of suffering?
What did we do wrong?
Enough is enough.
Sir Ertuğrul didn't promise you
a garden of flowers without thorns.
He said that the road would be tough.
He said it'd be a tough ride
for all the travelers.
What is it you are after now?
Lady Halime!
It is Sir Ertuğrul's road
that has put us in this situation.
She is right.
Humor me...
who is the one
that left the tribe to starve?
Come on, who is the one?
Alp Doğan gave his life for Ertuğrul
without hesitation...
and now here you are talking like this.
Know your place, Banu Cicek.
That's all we have
in the inventory for now.
Don't spice things up
so we can eat in peace.
The reluctant ones can leave.
Allah.
Where are we supposed to go?
THE MARKETPLACE
Troubled apostles of Jesus!
Wise exiled-traders of Moses!
Muhammed's first warriors!
The bazaar of Simon is at your service
in order to strengthen you,
fill your pockets with gold
and to rain prosperity over you.
How will you identify sultan's spy
in this crowd, brother?
If your eyes don't recognize
those on your side...
and your heart doesn't know
those who walk with you...
then you have already lost the war.
Sir, let's see who will taste
the rage of our swords here.
Brother...
if you stand still, then it'll be better
for our pockets instead of our swords.
So be it.
Simon, the owner of the bazaar at the inn,
where silk meets with cashmere,
food is fumigated with spices,
households fancied with fabric
awaits you.
Come!
Follow me!
Well, brother,
the voice of that dwarf
is almost equal to that of a bear's.
How come he is able to have such a voice?
I wish we found
some of that in the bazaar.
The one thought of setting up this bazaar
should be feared, brother.
Come on.
How come the idiots in Constantinople
can't hide my identity from the spy!
But they don't know
you are a Templar, Sir Simon.
But they do know we serve the Pope
and the crusaders.
The fault is absolutely
with the Grand Master Benedictus.
They will pay for that.
I will make them pay for that.
I will take this issue
to the high council of Templars,
as soon as possible.
Don't they know
what their stupidity will cost us?
What if our presence from Iznik to Konya
suffers a downfall?
What if Sultan Aladdin's army reach there
before the Crusaders
and conquer those lands?
Damn it!
We couldn't even identify him.
What are we going to do, Sir Simon?
We can figure out everything
if we catch the guy from Constantinople.
The bazaar opens today.
There will be thousands of men.
How will I identify him?
Coming from Constantinople,
Sultan's spy can't be an ordinary man.
He will disguise himself
with a trusted profile.
The best he can do is a knight.
Your wit is frightening, Sir Simon.
Set a trap on the way to the inn.
Have the first knight you see
in your claws.
How old is he?
We have survived a long winter,
and a summer with a temperature of hell.
Our pockets are hungry for gold.
Both my bazaar and inn
will be at your service
until the winds of winter cut our faces.
Of course, only if you have goods to sell
or have gold to purchase goods.
You will find the most precious goods
from Constantinople
to China, on the stands of this bazaar.
If you are the owner,
then I will be responsible
for the safety of your stands
and the goods on your stands.
Right.
Some of you already know,
if not let it be known.
This bazaar belongs to Simon!
May all your pockets be filled with gold.
Sir Simon, Johannes Batakis
is the emperor of the Byzantine
and you are the emperor of this bazaar.
Long live Simon!
My sister, Maria, has made
a grand preparation for you.
Let everyone feast on it.
Long live Simon!
Sir Ertuğrul of the Kayi Tribe...
so you visit bazaars, huh?
Sir Ural from the Cavdar Tatars.
I heard that
the bazaars long to see brave men.
So here we are.
Did you come all the way
just to sell those animal skins?
Let alone myself...
not to anyone in this bazaar...
Just get to know your world, Sir Ertuğrul.
Get to know this world.
Look, people bring a ton of goods
all the way
from China, Venice, India.
You?
Bringing a couple of carcass skins
to a bazaar that is under your nose.
Look at that man.
He makes a fortune every single day,
the likes of which you will never see.
Do you know why?
He puts his mind to work
instead of his sword, that's why.
Be careful though.
You wouldn't even know how
to buy and sell goods.
Huh?
Don't sell those skins for nothing.
Don't go back to the tribe
with empty hands.
Sir Ural...
I got to know many people
who want to give away all their gold
while suffering under my sword.
Yet...
I haven't met a brave man
who would give away his sword
in return of gold.
You are a smart fellow, Sir Ertuğrul.
Look, these men here today
are not chasing after swords or battles.
And you?
You are chasing gold.
Farewell.
Don't forget what I have said.
Be careful.
First wines are on me.
Long live Simon!
Relax.
This is not our guy.
Here comes the degenerate. Be ready.
But, sir, he is a knight.
Not a knight.
He is the spy we're looking for.
Tie his hands and mouth tight.
We need this degenerate alive.
Brother...
this seems like a nice place.
We can sell the skins here.
Let's set the stand here.
Yes, sir.
I wish Doğan was here.
We could have him do the chores.
Here I go.
I will have a look around.
Safeguard the stand.
-Turgut.
-Yes, sir.
You go visit the tradesmen
who sells wheat.
Yes, sir.
Sir Simon, I'm just curious,
what do you do with all the gold?
Curiosity is a good thing, Sir Ural.
As far as I heard, Sir Toktamış is
also curious about your business.
Asking everyone about you.
Accursed bastard.
Looking for his doom.
You can take care of him
when the time is right.
I also have good news for you.
Sultan Aladdin's man,
what was his name...
Sadettin Kobek.
Yes, that one.
I learned this from a tradesman of Konya,
Sadettin has become vizier to the sultan.
So...
that means I have the backup now.
The goods coming from Konya
will be your responsibility now.
You will earn nicely.
If you don't do anything wrong...
you will earn, too.
But if you do...
The man who has great confidence.
Who is he?
I saw him talking to you.
Ertuğrul, son of Süleyman Shah.
Very skilled on the battlefield.
Here to sell a couple of carcass skins.
But it feels like
his eyes are looking for something else.
Help me God.
Let me see the man sent by the sultan.
Spices here, spices here!
Wait. Drowning is too good for you.
We're not done with you.
Speaking would be good for you, son.
Just so you know.
Like a blade on this stone,
you're sharpening my anger.
It's a pity.
If you die, you'll fill your own grave.
I'll be sad for your mourning mother.
So tell me, go on.
Did you destroy our goods?
I've done nothing wrong.
I'm innocent.
My fist won't let go until you
start talking, you disgraceful scum,
I'll show you what happens
when you touch Candar Bey's merchandise.
I'll show you.
Start talking.
Aslıhan.
If the men of the Tatar villages were
as brave as you are,
the wrath of the enemy
would be a blessing to us.
Kutluca.
I left you to Aslıhan's merciful hands,
but...
nothing.
Let's see if my kindness
can get you talking.
Apparently you don't hear so well,
since you didn't...
answer my daughter Aslıhan.
Why is there an ear here...
if it doesn't hear anything?
Let's see...
if this ear hears better.
Tell me, son,
how did our goods come to you?
Who did you work with?
Ural Bey.
What did you say?
-What?
-Your son, Ural Bey.
He planned everything, I'm innocent.
Bey... don't do it.
If he dies, he can't face Ural Bey.
Kutluca, go and tell Ural Bey to come here
at once.
-As you command.
-Right now.
Toktamış,
Aslıhan...
The dark sky...
the desolate soil...
the unfortunate birds...
or any son of Adam...
None will hear of this.
Understood?
-Understood.
-As you command, my Bey.
Ural!
Ural Bey's stew is ready.
Who will take it?
I will.
I love you, Maria.
My heart aches for your love. Tell me yes.
So that I can ask for your hand.
Your head is too heavy for you, Petro.
Go find another dump.
This is your share for now, Ural.
I cooked you a stew myself, Ural Bey.
Appreciate it, Ural Bey.
Maria doesn't serve everybody.
I'm grateful, Maria.
Thank you.
Enjoy it, my Bey.
As you well know, Simon,
power is everything in this land.
And gold is its enforcer.
But...
the gold from a couple of caravans
doesn't do anything.
I want to compete with the giants.
It's time.
Did you say this to your father
Candar Bey as well?
Don't involve my father, Simon.
Wanting to compete with them...
I understand.
However...
this is easier said than done.
How will you do it, when you can't even
make your father listen?
You will see.
Very soon.
Ural Bey, Candar Bey and Toktamış Bey
await you at the shop.
Come quickly.
What for, Kutluca?
You will see soon, my Bey.
I told you Toktamış was trouble.
Toktamış...
If he's like you said,
Toktamış shall...
die by my hand.
Just make a decision.
I'll take care of the rest.
But be careful
that you don't die by your father's hand.
I made a deal with the Reaper, Simon.
He won't visit me until
I have my vengeance.
Do what's necessary.
Let my village...
taste death.
It's time, Maria.
Prepare the sweet syrup
of the black widow.
The prey is trapped, Master Simon.
The scum was disguised as a knight,
just as you guessed.
I took him down.
Batuhan.
Let's be ready for anything.
We might never leave this shop.
If something happens to me,
take Çolpan Hatun away from the village.
Don't worry, my Bey.
Go away, Batuhan.
Your eyes are like glass, Aslıhan.
Only a blind man would not see
what's inside.
What's going on?
My glass eyes have seen betrayal, brother.
Then...
let them see justice as well.
Let them see it
so those beautiful eyes can
give hope to your brother.
Thankfully your mother is dead...
so she can't see this.
Father, what is this?
What do you want from her?
When I look at you
I see her beautiful face.
Thankfully she died young.
I am thankful because
she didn't see your betrayal!
Father...
Don't mention my mother.
Tell me who is slandering my name.
That dog lying there?
What did he say?
My gold wasn't enough,
so you went after the gold of the village?
I haven't stolen from you or the village.
You know the rules of trading
better than I do.
Ever since you made me responsible
for the trade of the village
I've worked day and night
to fill your tent with gold.
This is all I know.
The rest is up to you.
Apparently...
this dog managed to convince
you before dying.
And my punishment is decided.
Believe what you believe.
You...
tell me the punishment, father.
Even if you lost a river's worth of blood
it wouldn't clean your sins, Ural.
I know everything.
This dog told me everything before dying.
How dare you even speak, you scum!
If this dog matters more than I do,
hear my last words.
Whoever spreads
these lies about me
wants to come between father and son.
Take my blood, father.
May you never know peace.
The rest is for you to take, father.
Oh, servant of Jesus almighty
and my dear companion.
I need your strength.
Give me your poison
in the name of the Holy Spirit.
So that every drop of it can be a cure.
Let our enemies drown.
Let them all be damned.
The shadow of Satan is between
your teeth, my little friend Sylvanus.
What do you say?
Should we add some flavor to the food?
My Bey...
They even charge us for opening a booth.
As if it belongs to them.
Who pays to put stuff on the ground, Bey?
We'll have our own booth one day,
Bamsi.
Don't worry.
Now, let's find a trader
and sell our goods.
Still no news, brother?
No doubt we'll meet the one coming from
Constantinople, Dündar.
-Good luck.
-Thanks.
Is Candar Bey here?
Business not going well, Ertuğrul Bey?
And you've been in a fight, Ural Bey.
You said not to fight here.
Also, you've been wounded
for not keeping an eye out.
Salaam alaikum.
-Alaikum salaam, brother.
-Alaikum salaam.
Alaikum salaam.
What's going on?
What are these furs?
Furs, and anything else you want.
Bear, bull, snake, fox, rabbit...
Anything you want.
Mashallah, mashallah.
How much?
What will you pay?
One gold coin per hide.
Hey, trader.
Ever been to a hunt?
No.
Obviously, since you pay so low.
Hunters brave many dangers to hunt these.
What's happening, Aslıhan?
Are you his partner?
I respect the work behind them.
If you lower the price,
they are worth nothing.
What a woman.
Her husband is lucky.
Sir, I will have to treat these goods.
I lose money and time in treating them.
So...
At most, you'll spend one coin per hide.
Two more coins to treat it.
Then you'll sell it for ten.
What do you say?
Is that not enough profit for you?
Alright, tell me your price.
Four gold coins per hide.
Four gold coins?
No way.
Do you want me to go bankrupt?
Four coins.
And one for treating, five coins.
And when you sell it for ten,
you'll be glad.
Don't waste time.
They have a long journey ahead.
Oh, God.
It's fate.
If I didn't need them,
this wouldn't happen.
Just so you know.
Take them down.
Right away.
Aslıhan Hatun.
I wish we'd met you earlier,
so we could've saved time.
Thank you.
My Bey.
These traders are tough.
You know how to break them down.
Thanks.
I've heard that Kayı women are talented.
Bring their carpets here, my Bey.
You'll make a bigger profit.
The drought was extremely hard on us
for years, Aslıhan Hatun.
We couldn't make anything.
The Venetians will be here soon.
They love the products
of the Turkmen villages.
Our carpets are everywhere
in the Venetian and Genoese palaces.
Just so you know.
Sell them something, no matter what.
When will they come?
Very soon, my Bey.
Today or tomorrow.
I'll won't forget this favor
you've done me.
Thank you.
Don't be fooled by their aged appearance.
They're very talented.
They can do anything.
One of them was a palace servant.
You scum.
He's also a...
cook.
And this Armenian
is a mason.
Not for 30,
not for 20,
not for ten,
you can have these slaves for only
five gold coins.
Who will pay five gold coins for
these precious slaves?
Ural Bey?
If you wish, you can have
these slaves for five coins.
Untie that old man.
Run!
If you can outrun my arrow,
you're free.
Run!
He told you to run, he's your new master!
Run.
Run!
Run, save yourself!
If you can't run, you die.
Run, run! Go!
Untie the other.
Brother Ural.
What are you doing?
That's enough.
I told you to run.
Run. Run for your life!
Don't. Don't do this, brother.
-Run.
-Run away.
-Run!
-Brother, don't!
Run! Run!
Step aside, Aslıhan.
Step aside!
Run! Run!
Ertuğrul Bey.
How much for you?
Five coins.
Come with me.
My Bey!
That man will kill me.
Nobody can touch you while I'm here.
Come along.
Ertuğrul...
Dündar.
Give five coins to the slaver
for this man.
That slave is mine, Ertuğrul Bey.
I already bought him.
Then sell him to me.
How much for that slave?
This letter is fake.
Anything else on him?
No, Master Simon.
Only this letter.
So, you want to play.
Then let's play.
Speak, scum.
Where's your tongue?
What else could be expected from a spy
disguised as a knight?
Of course, you're a mute!
Give him to Tristan.
Let him hang.
If we can't understand you,
we'll find someone who we can.
The Turks won't leave their dead.
Whoever he works for
will come to take him.
Master Simon.
Trouble at the bazaar.
You should come.
How much for that slave?
Apparently you sold your hides.
I asked you how much, Ural Bey.
Since we're doing this in a market,
it's fair that I should
barter for a profit.
Ten coins.
Dündar.
Give ten coins to Ural Bey.
-My Bey, what are you doing?
-Dündar.
Brother, that's enough.
Calm down.
Ten coins for an old slave.
I want to dine with this good man.
I hope you won't refuse the invitation of
the sole owner of the bazaar,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll be there with my Alps, Master Simon.
Pleased to hear that, Ertuğrul Bey. Come.
Sit here, Ertuğrul Bey.
What do the brave Alps desire?
Water.
Only water?
If Master Simon hears that
I only offered water to his guests...
he'll be angry.
We only want water.
May you have a long life, brave men.
Thank you.
Maria.
Set the table.
Bring us the drinks first.
That woman can't take her eyes off you,
Turgut Er.
I know, brother.
Mesmerized when you said "water".
Hamza
Okay, Turgut Alp Baş, no more talking.
Simon's bazaar has been here for years.
However...
this is the first time he's seen a man
giving away gold for the life of a slave.
And I have been traveling for years.
It's the first time I've seen
someone murdered for fun.
Your fellow Muslim...
Ural hasn't learned mercy.
If you hadn't intervened,
my men would have stopped him.
The issue isn't his cruelty,
but the organization of your bazaar,
Master Simon.
It's built to oppress the poor.
As a trader,
generosity is a trait I admire.
I'd like to see you more in the bazaar.
We Turks, we like to
give hope to the poor.
I'll be visiting your bazaar.
Now...
I should go.
As you wish.
Brother.
It seems a man has emerged from
the Turkish villages
that you can't buy with gold.
I've sent all their heroes to hell so far.
Hey, folks!
Come here.
Gather!
I said, gather!
Gather and watch what I'm about to do.
Come and see!
What is it, brother?
Do you know this man?
He is our man.
Why wait then? Let's go and rescue him.
Folks!
I'm hanging this thief
for stealing my goods,
to make an example for other thieves.
Know that...
no one can steal
from Tristan the merchant.
Now I'll enjoy his death.
Any objections?
Hang him!
They know he won't talk.
They're using him as bait.
They want me to stand up for him.
What now, brother?
Night is the shelter of believers.
We'll save him tonight.
Hang him!
Hang him! Punish him!
Shame.
Kill him!
No mercy!
Hang him!
Kill him!
Seems like
Ertugrul is still under our feet.
Though your feet are almost gone.
Anyone under my feet
will be six feet under, Master Simon.
There is no other option.
Then it is time to prove it.
My father used to say,
"Since Adam and Eve, no one knows
a sweeter poison than apple."
May he rest in peace.
I always believed that.
Until I found
the shadow of the black widow.
May the shadow of the black widow
bless our people.
Now, let's sweep away all the obstacles
and promote trust in us.
And tonight, as a starter,
the clean and pitiful death of Toktamis
will lead us in the right direction.
The Venetian merchant is arriving soon.
-Are the goods ready?
-Ready, yes.
Never mind the goods, tell me
if the Venetians' sacks of gold are ready.
I don't understand
why you're hiding it all from your father.
With no secrecy, would it be exciting?
And stop prying into everything,
Master Simon.
Bey.
When will Dogan arrive?
When his duty is over, Turgut.
Hacaturyan.
Yes, Bey.
I set you free.
Go wherever you want.
Bey!
Bey, I owe you.
I'll feel humiliated
if I leave without paying my debt.
Well, I have no place to go
and a penny in my pocket.
Bey, if you let me,
I'll come with you and serve you.
Besides, I'm still your slave.
Maybe this old fellow
can find a way to show his gratitude?
Your loyalty
and your blessing
would be more than enough.
From now on, stay as you wish,
you're my guest.
Stay as long as you want.
God bless you, Bey.
Girl.
You're tired, get some rest.
I can't sleep, mother.
I know Ertugrul Bey
will bring us to light from this darkness,
but the men...
they just gave in.
If anyone gets worn out
and decides to leave, then we're doomed.
May I, Halime Sultan?
Come in, Banu Cicek.
You called for me.
Tell me.
Dogan Alp entrusted you to us.
But if he heard your words today...
he'd have done what was necessary.
I stand behind my words.
It's been two summers, Halime Sultan.
Two whole summers
since Ertugrul Bey sent him on his duty.
No word...
Nothing.
My Dogan will not return.
I know it.
Banu Cicek.
When his duty ends...
Dogan Alp will return to his camp.
Then would you be embarrassed
of the words you've spoken?
Ertugrul Bey speaks no words,
Mother Hayme.
No words. Because, I know,
he sent my hero away never to return.
Enough!
I won't let you poison the camp
with your delusions, Banu Cicek.
Control these delusions,
or I will execute you with my own hands.
Anything else, Halime Sultan?
No. You can leave.
Girl.
It's been a while.
Things aren't going well.
This evil heralds salvation.
God willing, mother.
What you reap is what you sow.
So, stand tall.
Now you're the lady of these nomads...
Ertugrul's deputy.
You're the mother of all my kids
in the camp.
Mother.
Mother, Ertugrul Bey is here.
Welcome, Bey.
What is this, Bey?
What the hell?
Is that enough wheat for all of us?
Ertugrul Bey.
We spent days hunting in the mountains.
They became our home.
Is that all the wheat you could buy
with the skins from the hunt?
More will follow, Kara Bey.
Don't you worry.
Let us catch our breath
and we'll talk, be patient.
How much patience do we need, Bey?
We can't take it anymore.
Forgive me!
Who the hell is he?
-It's not one of us, who is he?
-Ertugrul Bey...
saved my life
from the slave market, with gold
he was supposed to spend on wheat.
With our gold...
But...
I'll return this favor.
Ertugrul Bey.
You've been inconvenienced.
I wish you left me there
for him to kill me.
Hacaturyan.
Is this true, Ertugrul Bey?
You wasted our gold on this heathen?
We no longer have patience.
We're perishing on the roads
in the name of the holy war.
But all you say is, "Patience."
We hear no other words.
We want to know what to do.
We want a meeting tonight, Ertugrul Bey.
Since when are you
going after the sustenance?
God's the one who provides it, is He not?
Hacaturyan
is a guest of God.
God's guest comes with ten loaves.
Eats one...
leaves nine.
When did you forget
the Holy Creator's name?
It's not the time for meetings.
Do your share.
I won't let anyone
raise trouble
or agitate the people here.
Our life was not a bed of roses anyway.
This didn't happen
because when we came here.
It's not the time for meetings.
That is my word.
Gunduz.
Father.
My son.
Gunduz.
Heir of my blood.
Son.
Why refuse the meeting?
What are you up to?
Mother...
Gunduz.
My dear, go play inside.
I did not refuse a meeting.
I refused them asking for meetings
and agitating the people
after every little difficulty.
So say this in the meeting.
That's what a bey does.
Hayme Hatun.
I'm the bey of the camp.
I decide when to meet.
Ertugrul Bey, do you hear yourself?
This is not our law.
Why are my orders
being questioned, Halime Sultan?
A Bey's word is final,
isn't that our law?
If I'm the bey of this camp,
I decide.
This is neither the place
to question my judgments...
nor is it your duty.
When it's time...
I'll gather the beys,
and listen to them.
CAVDAR NOMADS CAMP
O King of Kings...
The only one...
The word coming forth
from the Holy Father.
As a benefactor Thou hast now
ineffably sent forth Thy Spirit,
equal in might,
upon the apostles who chant,
Glory to Thy dominion...
O Lord.
Lord, give me strength.
Let me make my enemies
live in hell on earth.
Bey is coming.
Bey...
Gather here.
Toktamis Bey.
Honor my table tonight.
We can talk about the rugs
we'll sell to the Venetians.
We've got
a lot of work to come this winter.
As you wish, Bey.
I am at your command.
Colpan Hatun.
We have guests for dinner.
Prepare accordingly.
Be sure nothing is missing.
Yes, Bey.
Aybuke, begin the preparations.
Yes, Colpan Hatun.
Bey? What happened to your leg?
My father...
He knew everything.
Ural, let me do it.
From now on...
no more rest for anyone.
If I am on a knife edge,
everyone else will be too.
First, you must lose this wrath.
You know a tightened rope
breaks the easiest.
Everyone has an evil eye on you,
so be like a lake...
not a roaring river.
You'll roar, when it's time.
It's not good, Colpan,
that my father learned this.
Not good.
Who do you think he learned this from?
That is...
Toktamis's doing.
His days are numbered.
Tonight at the dinner...
we're going to bury him.
Before Ali Er comes,
we have to send him off.
Or it gets worse for all of us.
That's it.
Your wrath may be like a river, after all.
Flowing slowly, but with power.
Ural Bey will bring peace to these evil
lands. Whoever stands in his way...
will be drowned in your wrath.
This is our time.
Toktamis...
will have his last meal
at my father's table.
So, Toktamis Effendi,
you declare your own kingdom?
You've made your bed, you'll sleep in it.
Get rid of the bulgur.
Not welcome on my table.
That ropy stuff is unworthy for our Bey.
Wheat will be fine.
Yes, Colpan Hatun.
Thank you, Colpan Hatun.
An excellent feast, as always.
Our beys carrying the burden of our camp
deserve the best, Toktamis Bey.
How many rugs are left, Ural?
Enough for the Venetians.
Any discolored,
or poorly crafted, Colpan?
No, Bey.
What about you, Aslihan?
I disliked a few.
The women will work tonight
to get them ready for tomorrow.
Well done, my daughter.
I don't want to hear
that Cavdars deliver poor quality goods.
This is delicious, Colpan Hatun.
Thank you, Toktamis Bey.
This time the enemy will attack
with everything.
So there is no time to lose.
We have to be firm like a castle.
Bey.
An uprising is on the way.
Folks are at the ends of their tethers.
Damn the ungrateful.
Everything is fine when they're full.
When they're hungry, the muttering starts.
Alas!
They've been good for a couple of years,
brother
One good trade would bring hope
to the people, Bey.
I heard the Venetians are coming
to buy some rugs.
Gather all the rugs in the camp,
immediately.
Abdurrahman, Dundar,
this duty is yours until we're back.
Bey, if you let me,
I want to visit all the beys in the camp.
So, they won't be upset
about not having a meeting.
Well thought, Artuk Bey.
Fill them with enthusiasm.
I will.
Bey.
What if Sultan's man dies?
What if we can't find the man
we go in search of?
We have no choice.
Bring him out of that market,
dead or alive, Turgut.
It'll be tough
to get Sultan Aladdin's spy out of that
huge bazaar, Bey.
How will you do that?
Do you know...
how wolves set up an ambush
for their prey, Dundar?
Listen to me closely.
The first thing we'll do...
We'll capture the spy of Sultan Aladdin
who settled in this land.
To catch the big fish...
we will use the circumcised knight
as our bait.
Will he come to that bait, Master Simon?
Not that easily, Philip.
I assume he's smart enough to know
I'm setting a trap for him.
A trap within a trap.
Right.
Don't forget.
We must get him alive. At any cost.
God help us all.
Ertugrul Bey, may I?
Come in, Halime.
Bey, I have some things to say,
if you'll allow me.
Go head, Halime. I'm listening.
Bey, forgive me.
I said inexcusable things.
I was upset by the words of the women
in the camp,
and I made the same mistake,
I acted like them.
I'm sorry.
These lands are surrounded
with fire, Halime.
But...
if we turn to Allah as Ibrahim did,
that fire feels like a bed of roses.
Our duty is
to resign to Allah's will.
With Allah, no sorrow.
We live in hard times.
You have a lot weighing on you, I know.
And that's what made you say those things.
We are off hunting with the Alps tonight.
I hope it will be a good one,
with God's help.
God willing, Bey.
I wish that your arrow hits its prey.
Come home with plentiful supplies.
Amen.
Don't worry about us.
Wolves are the only thing we've not become
and now they will fear us.
Let's see what they come up with.
There's nothing like a noble wolf.
It looks great.
A warrior bears his load on his shoulders,
Bamsi Beyrek.
Aye, brother. Right you are.
A warrior without a woman, Bamsi Beyrek?
Brother Gonkut...
Brother...
I'll chop that tongue out, brother.
Chop that tongue out.
Chief Turgut Alp,
these alps have no manners.
They don't know how to talk to elders.
Salam.
Salam, Bey.
Here, Bey. Your fur is ready.
Good, thanks.
Wolves like the foggy weather.
Come on, warriors.
The war is ours.
The victory is Allah's.
Aslıhan!
Yes, Father.
I see you are distracted, my daughter.
What's on your mind?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Today, he saved an old slave
who was about to die, Father.
He did it by cutting back on the bread
that his village folk needed.
What are you trying to say, daughter?
I believe we have lost our compassion
for quite some time now.
Did you find an answer Aslıhan Hatun?
I did Çolpan Hatun. I did.
When we went after gold and not valor...
that is the day we lost.
What was the matter
you wanted to discuss, Father?
Leave us, Çolpan!
You stay, Aslıhan.
Father!
Çolpan is my wife.
She does not deserve this treatment.
I have things to attend to, Ural Bey.
With your permission.
Because of the embarrassing situation
you put me in today,
I have seen it fit
to take certain precautions.
You still believe the words
of that coward?
You know exactly
what I am going to say, Ural.
What I will tell you, you already know.
Toktamış!
Toktamış?
No!