Episode 86 will start after 12:40 min.
Mother, are you okay?
Dündar didn't come to the wedding.
What else can I say?
Forgive me for what I've done.
What has Bamsi Alp done?
He has set up his tent on the grass
under the sky!
What has he done
to make his beloved happy?
He has made a stallion out of a horse,
a ram out of a sheep.
Did he break hearts?
Did he say anything wrong?
He didn't break a heart
or say anything wrong.
He got married instead!
Off the lovebirds go to the bridal tent
to conclude the marriage!
Then may God make them happy ever after!
Amen!
May God make you happy, brother.
Go, go, go!
Look at this, Bamsi.
It's like I'm in a dream.
They brought many gifts.
You could find anything here.
They sure did. That's how our tribe is.
Our bey on one side,
the people on the other.
They try to do the best they can.
It's our tradition.
And Lady Hafsa, settling down
is a prosperous thing.
Now tell me, do you need anything else?
Don't ask me if I need anything, Bamsi.
Know that whatever makes you happy
makes me happy.
Whatever makes you cry, makes me cry.
How sweetly you talk, my beautiful.
My sweetheart.
And this is how marriage is, right?
Being one instead of two,
sharing the burdens and pleasures.
Our marriage has become a salve
for the pain of you and your loved ones.
You are right.
Our marriage is a beacon of hope
for the people.
And I finally get to be with my beloved.
What else can I ask of God?
Maybe you could ask for a baby, Bamsi?
Lady Hafsa, now....
Now this tent is our home,
let this bed be our heaven.
Amen.
Lady Hafsa, I need to say a prayer.
Don't go anywhere.
You wait here. I'll say a prayer.
Ertuğrul and Aliyar
will both be at the inn tonight
to ensure order.
Their absence will leave
the tribe vulnerable.
What about all the alps who obey Aliyar?
We will wait until they go out hunting
and then strike, Vasilius.
I'll send Aliyar's alps out hunting.
There will be no resistance.
Don't underestimate the tribe, Ural.
Do you think they could accept someone
who they think of as a traitor?
The lives of the people
are precious to them.
Once I've slayed a couple of rebels,
no person will even peek
through their tent.
They'll feel forced to obey me.
I hope you're right, Ural,
because this is your final move.
Either you'll inhale
the breath of life, or...
you'll exhale your last.
That makes two of us.
If you can't stop Ertuğrul with the help
of the Turkish leaders who support me,
it will end badly for both of us.
I doubt the Turkish leaders' loyalties.
They are loyal to me.
They'd be honored to back me up.
Ural Bey, would anyone support you
if not for their own interests?
Go ahead, tell me.
What did you promise to them?
Thank God we could
finally help Bamsi get married.
May God bless you, my bey.
I appreciate it, Turgut.
The company of friends is
what make these events so beautiful.
May God bless you all.
Thank you, my bey.
My bey, may I enter?
Enter, Abdur Rahman.
The Turkmen leaders' messenger
is here, my bey.
Let him in, Abdur Rahman.
Selamunaleykum.
-Aleykumselam
I have a message
from the Turkish leaders, Ertuğrul Bey.
They want to conclude the council
that was interrupted.
They wish for a council meeting
in the bazaar.
Aliyar Bey knows about it, too.
He will be there, my bey.
Thank you.
Let the Turkmen leaders know
that I'd be honored to host them.
This is better, my bey.
We can finish what we've started.
Ensure you take
the necessary precautions anyway.
Have our alps guard
the paths the leaders take.
Vasilius is weak, but we will
take proper precautions anyway.
As you order, my bey.
Tell me, what did you promise to them?
Freedom.
They must decide
between following Ertuğrul's tail
or taking the lead themselves
Do they know that they'll die
if they don't leave my lands
once you have your tribe back?
Of course they do.
I told them.
We'll take our tribes with us
and leave these lands.
We'll leave for richer,
more prosperous lands.
These leaders are dumber than I thought.
I wouldn't do anything
that meant I had to leave the bazaar,
the gold mine or Karacahisar Castle.
You Turks have a great saying.
I learned it from Sadettin.
At this rate,
I'll become fluent in Turkish.
"Way to go!"
Convincing them to leave
with empty hands is a tough thing to do.
Very tough.
What's most important for me is to get rid
of every descendant of Ertuğrul,
take over the Kayi tribe,
and then live in peace.
There is nothing more precious
for me and the Turkmen leaders.
Me and my troops will be waiting for you
somewhere near the tribe.
I'll be the first
to celebrate your victory.
And if, not when, if you fail,
I'll come to help you.
Don't worry.
Then let's secure victory.
Let's do it, Ural Bey. Let's do it.
-Commander.
-Yes, sir.
Be a good host to Lady Çolpan
until I return with Ural Bey.
My wife comes with me!
There will be bloodshed.
She might get hurt.
It's best that she stays at the castle.
If we die, we die together.
I won't let her be a hostage here.
Not a hostage, Ural. A guest.
You'll be reunited with her
as soon as we achieve our victory.
This is better for both of us.
Trust me.
I'll miss this Turk.
No.
Have Lady Çolpan killed
if she does anything wrong.
Yes, sir.
Mother... enough.
You've torn your heart out.
It brings me great pain whenever
I see trouble arise between my boys.
May God deliver them from evil.
Mother, Dündar Bey is
an understanding man.
And Ertuğrul Bey wouldn't let any harm
come to his brother.
He did this to teach Dündar Bey a lesson.
He didn't come to the wedding,
and he's still not here now.
I sent orders to check on his tent.
Still no news.
I hope my fears won't come true.
Hopefully.
May I come in, my bey?
Come in, Kutluca. Come.
My Aliyar Bey, I have something to say.
Go ahead.
For a long time now,
there have been black clouds over us.
Our alps are sad.
I see it in their long faces.
I propose, if you so allow,
that we should go hunting tomorrow.
Let the men fire arrows, swing swords.
What do you think, Kutluca?
The alps are on my mind, too, my bey,
but I couldn't let them leave
due to the current precautions.
Some of the alps can stay and guard
the inn while the rest go hunt, my bey.
And when the first hunters come back,
the rest can go hunt.
Very well. Kutluca, that is my decision.
As you see fit, my bey.
Guard.
My bey, the Tayi leader
appears to be with us.
The situation is good.
We'll see, Kutluca.
I am doubtful of his loyalty,
but what he says about the alps is true.
It is important to maintain the morale
of the alps as they fights these heathens.
Hunting will give them courage.
Go and let them know. Tell them
to hunt quickly and come straight back.
Very well, my bey.
-Kutluca.
-Yes, my bey.
Watch them closely.
Yes, my bey.
Guards.
What's up, mother?
You seem to be in pain.
Your brother's punishment
is too much, son.
Dündar is like a young tree.
He can't be straightened up
if he is broken.
My brother is the son of Suleyman Shah
and you, a strong mother.
He will no doubt learn a lesson
from this shame.
Don't you worry.
He is just a kid.
In his innocence, he followed you
and believed whatever you said.
You practically brought him up.
Mother...
I'm trying to be both a brother
and a bey to Dündar.
I do whatever is the right thing to do.
I treat him just like I would treat
any of my alps in a situation like this.
I can't and won't discriminate.
I do what my father, Suleyman Shah,
taught me to do.
Ertuğrul, I've always been
at your side, son.
Don't let your brother drift away.
I want nothing but to see you
standing shoulder to shoulder as brothers.
May I come in, my bey?
Come in, Abdur Rahman.
My bey, people saw Dündar Bey
leave the tribe on his horse.
Oh, Dündar!
Oh, my son!
How could he do that?
Where could he be going?
Where would he go
at this time, Abdur Rahman?
I checked his tent, my bey.
He left this note.
Your tears will finally stop, my Çolpan.
It's time to be happy.
Now, happiness will be ours
and sadness theirs.
I've always believed in you, my bey.
I knew that my Ural would punish those
who caused us pain.
I believe we'll be welcomed as we deserve
when we get to the tribe tomorrow.
Those who separated us from our tribe
and tent will get what they deserve.
But you won't be coming with me.
Once I take over the tribe,
I'll come here, not to retrieve you,
but to kill Vasilius
and take over the castle.
And then, the scar in your heart
will finally be healed.
So soon? How is that going to happen?
The forces at the castle
are extremely weak right now.
Half of Vasilius' soldiers are dead.
I'm the only one who can
enter the castle as an ally.
With the Turkmen leaders on my side,
it won't be hard to conquer this castle.
And then, you'll be treated as a queen,
both in here and in the tribe.
Since we've been fighting for your cause
you've shown me that leadership
isn't about the sharpest sword,
but about the highest wisdom,
and also that a good soldier isn't just
defined by their courage, but also faith.
But I've come to realize that I'm far away
from understanding these things.
I did something irredeemable
and unforgivable.
I can't look you in the eye,
nor can I look at Banu Çiçek,
whom I made a widow,
or Doğan, whom I made an orphan.
Give me your blessing.
Look after my mother and the tribe.
Oh, my Dündar.
Oh, my brave son.
Ertuğrul, if Dündar became a martyr,
I'd shed tears of joy.
But I can't stand losing him like this.
Do everything you can
to bring Dündar to me.
I won't be able to live with his absence.
Abdur Rahman, send alps after Dündar.
Have them turn every stone if necessary.
Tell them not to return
until Dündar has been found.
As you order, my bey.
May I come in?
Come in, son.
Please, my bey.
Those who seek peace for their own gain
will lose that peace, son.
Peace is only given
to those who embrace one another.
Now, tell me:
what's the cause of your unrest?
My brother Dündar left the tribe
while we were still grieving for Doğan.
My mother is deeply saddened
by the situation.
Important people
have important problems, son.
The weight of your responsibility
is heavy.
You are not one of the people;
you are the one responsible for them.
You dealt this punishment
not for your own gain,
but because it was right.
You did it to uphold justice.
You did the hard thing.
And your brother listened
to his conscience and left the tribe.
It's part of our religion to forgive
those who realize their faults.
When our prophet Muhammad...
emigrated to Medina from Mecca,
he declared that the immigrants
and the local people were brothers.
Every now and then,
there used to be...
some trouble between them.
Mistakes were made.
But they would ask for forgiveness
and try to compensate for their mistakes.
Hopefully, Dündar Bey will also
compensate for his actions
in the best way possible.
The Lord Almighty says in al-Hujurat:
"The believers are but brothers,
so make settlement between them...
and fear God
so that you may receive mercy."
Ertuğrul, my son.
Brothers are like rosary beads.
It's their leader who must align them...
just like the head of the beads.
Now, what you should do is
embrace all your brothers
without discrimination.
Humankind is just like dough.
If you squeeze it too much,
it spills out of your hands
and is wasted.
It's hard to be the responsible one,
the one who manages everything.
That's why the most just leaders
enjoy the best gifts of all
in the afterlife.
May God bless us with the brotherhood
of Muhammad's companions...
and may He remove the obstacles
between us.
May He prevent those who try
to create problems from doing so.
Amen.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Stupid Dündar.
You climbed the mountains
because of your pride.
But you can't eat pride.
So I have to roll up my sleeves.
So help me God.
Let's see.
Our father in the skies...
O Lord almighty.
May you reign over all.
My God,
may you bless us with victory.
It's time, my Çolpan.
Ural, it was a terrible night.
I was having nightmares right up
until the morning.
It'll be the Kayi tribe
who have the nightmares now.
Ural!
I saw you being killed
by a two-headed serpent.
The same thing happened
when I lost my father.
You had bad dreams because
you are full of fear, wife.
Speak of good things, and they happen.
Come on.
Commander, let the guards know that
no one is allowed to enter this castle.
Lock all the doors.
But sir, what about traders?
Let them wait till I come back!
Do not let any traders or even soldiers
enter the castle.
Don't let anyone in until you see me.
-Understood?
-Yes, sir.
Ural.
At last.
So, it's your last day in my castle?
Not really, Vasilius.
I'll come back for my wife.
She is my responsibility. Don't worry.
Thank you for everything, Vasilius.
You have been a good host.
I've felt right at home.
This is a home to anyone
who serves the empire.
My father served as well, Vasilius.
What a terrible fate, huh?
I mean, that of your father.
Some men's fates are written in pain.
In that way, yours is like my father's.
I know it affected you deeply
when Helena left.
Helena's fate
is not intertwined with mine.
She will die, as she deserves.
Just like your father.
Çolpan, what do you think you are doing?
Watch your tongue.
I didn't say enough. I'm sick
of the way that bastard talks to me.
I'm sick of playing nice
so as to not offend my father's killer.
We are almost there.
-Behave!
-Ural.
I have had enough.
I won't rest until I watch that bastard
die painfully.
I'll kill him,
either with your help or without it.
This is not over yet.
We'll talk when I get back.
Hafsa, you are as flawless as a calm sea.
I could watch you day and night.
I'm still trying to get used to my look.
I feel better in these clothes.
I feel like I belonged here
from the beginning.
Right, Lady Hafsa.
We all belong here.
We belong to this soil,
this forest, this sky.
Lady Hafsa...
you weren't able to think clearly
in that castle.
You weren't able to find God.
All you found was darkness and intrigue.
You've summarized my situation
very well, Bamsi.
I felt unsettled there.
Every day was like a bad dream.
I used to find it hard even to breathe.
Oh, Lady Hafsa, you don't understand.
I wasn't able to breathe properly either.
The heaven I was living in
had become a prison for me.
Brother Samsa.
Why is he running like that?
It as if there were a cat in his pants.
Brother Samsa! Brother Samsa!
-Brother.
-Yes, brother.
Where are you going in such a hurry?
There is a council meeting at the inn.
We're heading there with our bey.
A Council meeting, you say?
Things are not well, brother.
Dündar Bey left the tribe.
Also, there is that issue.
I pray to God all ends well.
-Dündar Bey, you say?
-Yes.
All this happened last night?
-Good God. Good God.
Come on, then. Let's go. Duty calls.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
Forgive me, Lady Hafsa.
I have to go.
Of course, Bamsi. Go.
Don't leave Ertuğrul Bey alone.
Good.
You take this.
Good. You are an angel. An angel.
Alright then.
Our path is not that of the weak,
but of the brave.
You are my brother,
but from now on,
you are neither a bey of this tribe...
nor an alp.
-May I come in, Mother?
-Come in, son.
Mother... I know.
I know that you're deeply saddened
by what's happening with Dündar.
It breaks my heart
to see you in so much pain.
Dündar is not only your son,
he's also my brother.
I can't bear the thought
of losing another brother.
Let's give him some time for now.
Give him a chance to come around.
Dündar isn't stupid.
He'll come back to his tribe,
sooner or later.
And if he doesn't?
What if he gets lost in no man's land?
Dündar Bey is a bey of this tribe, Mother.
I could no more
be separated from my brother
than fingers from fingernails.
This is the promise
of the son of Suleyman Shah.
I'll bring Dündar back.
You must stay strong.
I hope so, son. I hope so.
My brother is like an arrow...
released from a bow.
He'll find his way back to his tribe.
Be strong.
I hope so.
Excuse me, Mother.
Let's go, alps!
My Bey! My Bey!
My Bey!
Where are you going without me?
You just got married, Bamsi.
Spend some time with your wife.
You deserve to, after all.
Now, I can't have that, my bey.
How can I relax while Dündar Bey
is missing and there's a council meeting?
We can rest when
we're in our graves, my bey.
-Very well, brother.
-Thank you, my bey.
Let's go, alps!
-Let's go!
-Come on!
Hafsa Hatun, what's going on?
Is there a problem?
-Where is Bamsi?
-There's no problem, Halime Hatun.
Bamsi has gone
to the inn with Ertuğrul Bey.
And I was waiting for you here.
Mother, you don't have to go
to the rug house today, we can handle it.
That wouldn't be appropriate, daughter.
Many mothers have lost their children
in war, yet they still do their chores.
How can I not do mine?
What are you doing here, my girl?
Go to your tent and rest.
Mother Hayme, I'd like
to go to the rug house
and work with the other women,
if you'll let me.
Now that I'm a woman of this tribe,
I need to work and contribute,
isn't that right?
-Whatever you want, my girl.
-Come.
-I'll teach you how to do it.
-That would be great.
If you have a problem,
you know where I am.
Excuse me.
Banu Çiçek Hatun?
When the time comes,
and our tribes go their separate ways,
where will I find you?
Know that...
you'll be always in my heart.
Doğan Alp.
My boy...
It is only you and me.
Everyone went their own way.
You are the only thing
that keeps me going now.
Every morsel I eat,
every breath I take, is for you.
You are my Doğan's gift to me.
It's all right.
No, I won't lose you too.
You'll be born.
You'll be my Doğan.
You'll complete whatever your father...
left incomplete.
Dündar!
You're paying the price
for your mistake now!
You have neither a tribe
nor a home to go back to.
You left your mother in tears.
You are no good to anyone.
So, Ural Bey, you are finally
going back to your tribe?
I've missed the earth, the weather,
the water of this place, so much.
But...
I've missed the taste of victory
even more, Vasilius.
Those bastards!
They're heading to the Cavdar Tribe.
These are blessed days, my bey.
Alps! Good hunting!
Relax. Have fun.
But, when you get back to the tribe,
I want you all alert and ready.
-Understood?
-Yes, Bey.
Go on, then.
You're responsible for security.
Don't worry, my bey.
I'll take good care of the tribe.
Remember,
too much or too little
of anything will ruin everything.
Run away from those two
as if you were running from lions.
Act decisively and appropriately.
Yes, my bey. Thank you.
Come on!
Send a messenger to Cayiralan immediately.
Tell Ural Bey that Aliyar has gone
and the operation can begin.
Yes, my bey.
I smell blood.
There's a smell of blood in the air.
That is the smell
of my enemies, Vasilius.
It is the smell of revenge.
Are you certain you want to go
to your tribe without me?
I could make things easier for you.
Not now, Vasilius.
They won't obey me
if they see you with me.
And afterwards? They'll see me then.
By then I'll be the leader of the tribe.
And maintaining good
relations with my neighbors
will be expected of me.
You are good at politics.
You've learned a great
deal from Emir Sadettin.
So I have.
But there's one thing he'll learn from me.
Everyone pays for their misdeeds.
Let him pass.
Welcome, my bey.
Thank you. So, where are we?
All is well, my bey.
Aliyar Bey went to the inn with the alps.
What about my men?
What about my alps?
They are ready and waiting for you.
Do we have a secure route?
Our alps are standing guard
at the back entrance to the camp.
No one will stop you, my bey.
The time has come.
Let the coup begin.
We've waited so long.
But it'll be worth it.
At last, Ural.
At last, everyone will get
what they deserve.
-My Bey.
-Artuk Bey.
-Welcome, my bey.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
When did you arrive?
Just now, bey.
I came straight to the inn.
I decided to wait for you,
since there's a meeting.
Well done. What's the situation?
I have some important
news for you, my bey.
But it can wait until
after the council meeting.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Aleko. Thank you.
Let's talk while we're waiting
for the other beys, Artuk Bey.
I want to hear what's on your mind.
My bey, all the other beys are here.
They're waiting for you.
They're here already?
Exactly, my bey. I was surprised, too.
They've never arrived so early.
Well, then. Let's meet them.
This way, my bey.
Keep an eye on the tribe.
Let me know of anyone who comes and goes.
Yes, commander.
He's here.
-My beys.
-Welcome, my bey. We're honored.
-The time has come. Is everything ready?
-Just as you ordered.
The swords in the training field
have all been seized.
Our alps are at their posts,
waiting for the signal.
What about Aliyar's men?
We've lured them into a trap.
They've gathered in the tent.
Good. Let's not keep them waiting, huh?
Let's go.
Turkish rugs are known
the world over, due to their tightness
and the vividness of their colors.
You must knot it in such a way
that it's as tough as armor
when it's finished.
But be careful with the patterns.
Now, knot five times to the right
and five times to the left.
Like this.
Come on, you try now.
-Thank you, Halime.
-In the name of God.
If you knot them with your love
nothing will tear your rug.
Thank you, Halime Hatun.
Take the one from the back.
You have skillful hands, Hafsa.
You go on, take your time.
Mother.
I know you're thinking about Dündar Bey.
But you must pull
yourself together, Mother.
I don't want to see you in so much pain.
Neither would Dündar Bey.
I'm telling you, he'll be back soon.
Being a mother
is like sipping at sour milk, my girl.
I hope you never experience
the sort of pain I'm suffering.
Mother, Aslıhan Hatun is coming.
Aslıhan Hatun! Welcome!
Thank God.
-I'm so happy to see you here.
-Welcome.
-Mother.
-Welcome, my girl.
Thank you.
-Welcome, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Thank you.
-Welcome.
-Welcome, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Thank you.
-Welcome.
I've missed you and my home so much.
We missed you, too.
Bring some yogurt for her.
Come and take a seat.
You've come a long way.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
With the 99 names of Allah
who protects and forgives.
Amen.
May our council cause greater good.
-Amen.
The council is honored to host
the leaders of the Turkmen tribes.
Thank you, my bey.
Honorable beys of the Turkmen tribes.
We are ready to implement
the Sultan's orders.
There are no more obstacles in our way.
Vasilius may have wanted
to prevent us from going ahead,
but he has now tasted
the bitterness of defeat.
We heard about your victories,
Ertuğrul Bey. You've made us proud.
You hanged his commanders at his castle.
You made us all proud.
You took revenge on those bastards
who murdered my father.
My tribe and I will
always be at your side.
Your father is an honorable martyr,
who died on the way to the meeting.
It is now your duty to wave his flag.
Vasilius paid a heavy price.
He can't do any more harm to you now.
I hope it is as you say.
A thug like Vasilius won't just sit
in his castle and wait for death.
We don't intend to leave him waiting long.
Neither Vasilius, nor Ural
who took refuge in his castle,
can prevent us uniting.
May I?
Dündar?
Where have you been, brother?
What is this?
We have a problem, brother.
Ural and Vasilius are heading
towards the Cavdar Tribe with soldiers.
What about you, Dündar?
Let us through, alps.
-Who are you?
-The leader of Cavdars.
Ural Bey.
Traitor!
Kutluca!
Don't worry, he'll die too.
Kutluca Alp!
Two alps and a hooded man
just went into Kayitmaz Bey's tent.
They looked like trouble.
This is not good at all.
Let's get over there now.
What's going on here? Ural doesn't
have anything to do with Vasilius.
Something stinks here.
Ural is taking advantage of my absence
to attack me with that bastard Vasilius,
Ertuğrul Bey.
How could they have known
you'd be here, Aliyar Bey?
Council meetings are held in secret.
This meeting is just part of Ural's game.
How come?
What do you mean, Ertuğrul Bey?
There are traitors here among us
who have collaborated with Ural.
Who are they, Ertuğrul Bey?
Your words affect all of us.
If you know something, speak.
It's obvious who they are.
Samsa.
We haven't done anything, Ertuğrul Bey.
Stop! Stop!
Stop! What are you doing? Stop!
We are innocent, Ertuğrul Bey.
It's all lies, Ertuğrul Bey.
We didn't do anything, release us.
-We're innocent, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Stop! What are you doing?
We didn't do anything, Ertuğrul Bey.
This is a slander! A slander!
Forgive us, my bey.
We made a mistake. Forgive us, my bey.
Spare our lives
and we'll tell you everything we know.
You'll be telling it to God.
This is that bastard Ural's last day.
He will not deceive anyone ever again.
My people are in danger, Ertuğrul Bey.
What are we going to do?
Ural will have taken precautions.
So we'll be cautious, too.
Now, listen to me carefully.
Bastards!
I won't let you get
away with this. I won’t!
Go to the inn right away
and tell Aliyar Bey what's happened.
Tell him his beys have been murdered
and that he must come back immediately.
Yes, commander.
Don't let anyone see you,
use a hidden path. Go on!
-Don't worry, sir.
-Go!
What's wrong, Urkmez Bey?
Something's going on. I just saw
Kutluca Alp running to the training field.
-I shouted, but he didn't hear.
-What are you saying, Urkmez Bey?
Enjoying your meal, beys?
Ural Bey!
Well, you've had your fill.
Now it's my turn.
So, revenge actually is sweet.
Ural Bey, everything is ready
at the training field.
Good. The traitorous beys are dead.
Now it's the turn
of those traitorous alps.
Go to the rug house. You know what to do.
Very good. You've finished the job.
God bless your hands.
Thank God it's done.
The women will align the rugs
before they're delivered to the Franks.
I'm so happy you married
Bamsi, Hafsa Hatun.
Your name is as beautiful
as your face and heart.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
As you say, now it's your turn.
Amen.
How are you, my girl?
Was everything all right on your trip?
I'm fine, mother.
I met Emir Sadettin's mother
while I was there.
She liked me, and I liked her.
I left there with good memories.
That's what your tongue says,
but your eyes say otherwise.
I hope there weren't any difficulties.
We weren't expecting you back so soon.
I felt homesick, Mother.
Whenever I went outside
all I wanted was to see
the land of my home and my tribe.
I missed it so much. So, I came back.
There's nowhere quite like home.
But as time goes by, you'll feel your home
is by your beloved one's side.
This is the land of my birth,
Halime Hatun.
That can never change.
People can be only sure of their home.
Brave Turkmen beys.
You know what to do.
We do, Ertuğrul Bey.
There's no turning back from this path.
May God help us, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Amen.
-Thank you, Aliyar Bey.
We either put an end to this wickedness
or we become martyrs together.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, my bey.
-You'll come with us.
I've missed the sound of my sword.
Now it'll be music to my ears.
-May God help us.
-Amen.
Come on, my girl. You've only just
arrived. You should be resting.
We can handle this.
I've been resting for a long time, Mother.
I've missed working. Let me help.
As you wish.
You are precious to us.
Your wellbeing is important.
-Take good care of yourself.
-Thank you.
Halime Hatun.
Why are those alps staring at us?
It looks like they have a problem, Hafsa.
Mother.
Mother Hayme, what's going on?
It's obvious what's going on. Treachery!
Ladies, brave ladies.
We face treachery. On your guard!
Women of Kayi. You will come with us.
What's your problem?
What do you think you're doing,
pointing your swords at women?
Do as I say.
What are you talking about? Stay back!
Be on your way, go on!
You'll do as we say if you want to live.
No mercy will be shown
to those who resist.
Very well, come on then.
Halime, Aslıhan!
Stop, girls.
Whose dogs are you?
Tell me.
Who made you so shameless
that you would point your swords at women?
This is Ural's doing, Mother.
It's obvious.
These are Ural Bey's orders.
Give up your daggers and surrender.
You traitors.
You pig!
Did you really think you could
get away with this, you bastards?
Let me go! Mother!
-Let her go.
-Let her go!
Drop your weapons or I'll kill her.
Aslıhan, my girl.
Mother.
Are we going to surrender, Mother?
Ladies.
We'll wait for Ertuğrul Bey.
Take them prisoner.
Take them to the tent and tie them up.
Let go!
Shame on you.
We need to find Ural.
Let the other alps know.
As you command, Kutluca Alp.
Looking for me, Kutluca?
You bastard!
Traitors! Filth!
You'll get what you deserve.
I've brought what you deserve, Kutluca.
This one's mine. Come.
What happened, Kutluca?
You're on your knees.
I told you. You should've listened to me.
You've killed your brothers.
No betrayal will be left unpunished!
Stay loyal to your traditions.
Well said, Kutluca.
No betrayal will be left unpunished.
And my alps will do
what our traditions demand.
I'd have preferred you
alive to witness my victory.
But we can't keep the hellhounds waiting.
I won't be going alone, Ural.
I bear witness that
there is no god but Allah...
and Muhammad is his messenger.
Get everyone into their tents!
Punish anyone who refuses to obey.
-Go on.
-Yes, my bey.
-My bey.
-Did you take the women to the main tent?
Yes, my bey.
Aslıhan Hatun is there too.
She resisted, my bey.
We had to take her hostage as well.
-How about the people?
-They're resisting, my bey.
Don't worry. I know how to silence them.
Come on!
Shame!
Traitors! Shame!
-Traitors!
-Murderers!
Dogs!
You defy our traditions! Shame!
Go back to your tents!
Shame!
If anyone comes any closer,
we'll kill them.
Disobey and we'll kill you!
Don't make us spill blood!
Do what we tell you!
Get back to your tents!
You've defied tradition! Shame!
Dogs!
Ingratitude!
I have come to save you from tyranny!
I have come to give you back
the greatness you have lost!
You resist instead of obeying us?
We'll never obey you.
Our Bey is Aliyar Bey.
You're the tyrant! You're oppressing
your own people. Traitor!
That's what you get for defying me!
Anyone else want to speak up?
Huh?
When the Cavdars... regain their glory
you'll be ashamed
and will beg for my forgiveness!
Victory is ours, Ural Bey!
May your leadership last forever.
Victory is ours, my Bey.
I've returned with glory
to the tribe I left ashamed.
Thank you, my warriors.
Long live Ural Bey!
Bastard!
My warriors!
Brave men of the Cavdar tribe.
At last, justice will
prevail in our tribe.
Both my father's tent and our tribe
have been reclaimed from the traitors.
Now is the time for vengeance.
Ertuğrul and Aliyar will meet their end.
Only Cavdars may rule this land.
And you... will be the alps who won...
this great victory.
Long live Ural Bey!
It seems that Ural Bey
has taken control of the tribe.
Ural... I hope you don't mess this up.
When Aliyar gets home, there's going to be
a great welcoming feast waiting for him.
Long live Ural Bey!
Bastard!
Bamsi...
Where are you? Where are you, Bamsi?
I told you, Mother.
I told you that as long as that man
remained alive, he'd seek vengeance.
He can't touch us as long as
my Ertuğrul is alive.
My son will save us very soon.
How, Mother?
He doesn't even know we're here.
It's hopeless.
Don't show fear before these dogs!
Our job now is to stall
them until Ertuğrul arrives.
Long live Ural Bey!
It's you who deserves to die, Ural!
Shame on you!
Shame on you, Aslıhan.
You stand with these traitors
instead of with me.
You choose your enemy over your brother.
The path of the crooked man
is never straight, Ural.
You won't get away with this.
Don't worry.
As soon as this is over
I'm sending you to Sadettin.
He'll get what's coming to him too!
He'll find out what
it means to let me down!
Sir, Ertuğrul and Aliyar Bey
are riding towards the tribe.
What did you just say? Ertuğrul?
It seems he's found out about the coup.
The council meeting must have been
cancelled, there's no other explanation.
I, Bey of the Cavdars,
son of Candar Bey, Ural Bey,
swore I'd avenge my father and son.
No one will doubt my honor
when they see me fulfill that oath.
Honor?
What honor do you have, Ural?
As long as Ertuğrul is alive,
all you can do is spread poison with
your tongue like a loose woman.
Just wait, you'll meet your end.
Ertuğrul and Aliyar
have no idea what's coming.
There's nothing anyone
can do to save you now.
So many people have been
saved from you clutches, Ural.
What have you ever
managed to keep hold of? Huh?
Who do you think you are?
What could have made you so arrogant? Huh?
Stop!
I beg you, don't.
You'll be known as a coward
who murders women.
Let them go.
If you're so strong, take on a man.
He won't dare face Ertuğrul.
What do you expect from a man
who sought refuge in his enemy's castle?
Your sword is only good enough for women.
Where's your son? Huh?
Where is he? Have him come save you now.
We'll see if my sword is good
enough for him or not.
If Ertuğrul Bey had known...
he'd have taken your head
a long time ago, Ural.
You're just a traitor who
plots and sets traps.
Traitor?
-Let go!
-Let her go, you dog!
Let me go!
Now you'll see what happens
to those who set sibling against sibling.
Let me go!
My Bamsi, I didn't get enough
time with you, my Bamsi.
-Stop!
-Alps!
Stop!
I swear there is no god but God.
Muhammad is the messenger of God.
Martyrdom...
is an honor for us.
-God is great.
Stop!
I'm ashamed to share
the same blood as you.
Stop. I'm begging you, don't do it.
My enemies deserve death! Death!
Here they come, Mother!
Bamsi!
Ertuğrul!
Stand back!
Since when do Turks
take women as shields
when they ambush men, Ural?
There is no place
for what you call justice,
even among non-believers.
You'll address me as Ural Bey!
I am Bey of this tribe.
Let that be known!
You're nothing in my eyes, Ural!
You're a disgrace, both to my father's
tent and to that sword you hold!
You conspired to take
my title away from me,
and gave it to my brother,
Ertuğrul's puppet.
I claim my birth right.
You hear that? My birth right!
Have you sunk so low
that you're asking my alps
to kill their own Bey, Ural?
Neither our Sultan nor our tribe
will let you get away with this.
Unless the sky falls,
or the ground collapses,
no one can corrupt the Turks' tradition.
You attempted to, Ural.
Now it's time to pay.
Stand back, alps.
You won't only ruin us,
but your brothers
who also live on this land
and your state, too.
If you follow Ural
your destination is obvious.
Surrender... to justice and decency.
Alps!
Kill them!
-Let my daughter go!
-Let me go!
Ertuğrul.
Sir, things aren't going well.
Ertuğrul and his alps must have attacked.
Stupid Ural. He'll lose again.
Sir, Ural Bey has more alps on his side.
Courage wins wars,
not numbers, Commander.
Courage.
Hafsa, Hafsa, Hafsa, Hafsa.
I'll save you, hold on. Hold on.
Stand back. Or I'll kill your woman.
Let her go. Fight like a man.
Your new regime has come
crashing down, Ural.
You've poisoned all of us.
With your ambition and rage,
you've ruined the lives of
many alps, beys and innocents.
And now you hide behind a woman.
How low can you fall, Ural? How low?
Men, my alps, attack!
Ertuğrul!
What are you doing?
I said attack! Attack!
Sir, they've asked for our help.
Ural's life is in danger.
Damn it.
Sir, what do you want us to do?
My son!
Ertuğrul...
I'll end your line, Ertuğrul!
I'll be your worst nightmare!
You and men like you
would make yourselves king
with the crown of betrayal.
I'll take your heads until
each one of you is dead.
God Almighty... I live for vengeance.
Not for bread, water or a husband.
I would sacrifice anything for it.
Bless me with victory.
Praise hell for traitors!
Ural!
We can't win against
the Turks when they are united.
We can't match their strength.
I'll go to the emperor,
ask for more soldiers.
It's obvious we can't stop the Turks with
only the walls of the Karacahisar Castle.
Back to the castle.
Back to the castle!
I have nobody, Lord.
Nobody but you.
There can be no mercy!
Only rage!
God, give me strength.
I won't come to you until
I get my revenge, Father!
Come now, Vasilius!
Taste my poison!
-Mother!
-Dündar!
Ertuğrul!
Bamsi!
My brave warrior.
May you suffer for your sins, brother.
My son.
You came home, sister.
Our home is ruined, brother.
We'll turn this place
into a paradise, Aslıhan.
It's all over. Over.
We have seen
what is true and what is false.
We've known the good and the bad.
We've seen which tree was rotten.
We have been wounded.
But we've learned well.
If a day comes
when our names are but history...
our deeds forgotten...
our ancestors forgotten...
know that that day comes only
because we have forgotten this treachery
and climbed the same rotten tree.
That is the day...
we dishonor our word...
and give up.
That is the day we defy tradition
and yield before the infidel.
Never fear.
Our honorable blood
keeps tradition strong
and keeps our banners flying high.
As long as this blood flows in our veins,
wherever we step is our home...
wherever our voice is heard
is our motherland.
God is great!
God is great! God is great!