Episode 91 will start after 12:40 min.
May God spare me a life
without your love.
May God never let us part, dear.
I'm coming in.
Welcome, sir.
Thank you, Turgut.
Come, let's eat together.
Thank you.
Go ahead, sir.
Thank you, Turgut.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
You're good at axe swinging,
but even better at cooking.
Thank you, sir.
I learned to paddle my own canoe.
I know your yearning for Aykiz
is still there.
However,
if she could talk, don't you think that
she'd lament
about the way you are?
It's my destiny to be alone, sir.
I have no other wish but to serve
for our cause
as long as I'm alive.
Turgut, a man needs to be a man first.
He needs a woman that'll
keep him company.
And a son that'll be the hope of his home.
What would become of an alp
serving our cause in misery?
However, if he serves with love
and walks with love, I know he'll do well.
And you know that, too.
I know, sir.
However...
my heart's become like a desert.
It's time for that desert
to grow forests, Turgut.
How do you mean, sir?
I want you to marry.
Brother.
Conqueror of battle fields.
I'm left to face the harshest of battles.
And I don't know which one
is easier to handle.
May I come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
Come in, please, Ameer Almighty.
I wanted to see you.
I hope you have time for me.
If our state's ameer wants to see
the Cavdar Bey, who am I to refuse?
I came here
to see my fiancée Aslıhan,
not the Cavdar Bey Aslıhan.
Then you shouldn't have come,
Ameer Almighty.
Aslıhan...
You don't care about me.
But don't you care about your father?
Don't you care about his promise to me?
We made a promise to each other.
I promised him that I would protect you,
and care for you till I die.
And he promised me
that Aslıhan was going to be my wife,
God willing.
He said, "God willing."
I gave a promise to my brother, too.
I said, "I will never leave my tribe
without a leader."
Then why do you refuse me?
I am the Ameer of Seljuk Empire.
Let us revive your tribe together.
Let me do my best.
We don't need anybody's help,
Ameer Almighty.
Thank you very much.
All right.
Enough with the kindness.
You probably don't know
how serious this is, Aslıhan.
What would happen to your tribe
when you refuse me?
Did you think about that?
Bey...
you know that I would die for you
a thousand times.
But I cannot do that.
It would ruin not only me,
but also the woman who will be my wife.
How can I make her happy...
with my broken heart?
You have come out alive
from a lot of fights, Turgut.
You will face this great challenge, too,
God willing.
But, bey...
who would accept to be my companion...
at this great challenge?
Aslıhan Hatun.
How is that possible, bey?
What about Ameer Sadettin?
Aslıhan Hatun does not want to
marry Ameer Sadettin.
And we can't force her into marriage,
since she is like a sister to me.
It is our duty to marry her
to a decent man.
And I think you are that decent man.
Bey...
while my love for Aykiz
is still tearing my heart out,
how can I love Aslıhan Hatun?
I don't want to do her an injustice.
You will love her over time, Turgut.
You would suit each other perfectly.
Your broken hearts
will be whole over time.
But, Aslıhan Hatun
would never leave her tribe, bey.
She does not want to leave her tribe.
Do you want me to leave mine?
I want to unite our tribes, Turgut.
Together we win.
Divided we fall.
This marriage would be good
for the unity of our tribes.
I know, it is hard for you.
However,
you will overcome these difficulties.
Thank you, bey, thank you.
For our descendants...
for our traditions...
and for the sake of our tribes' hopes...
I will put out my heart's fire
with my tears.
Whatever you wish, bey.
Thank you, Turgut.
You must keep your promise,
Aslıhan Hatun.
You made a promise to me.
By breaking your promise,
you are ruining not only mine,
but also your reputation.
You still don't understand this?
You are enslaved by your desire,
Ameer Almighty.
You do not think about anything
but pride and reputation.
There is nothing more important
than pride and reputation!
And as a woman
who let down Ameer Sadettin
you will not find any man
who would be brave enough to marry you.
Aslıhan, if you leave me you will wither
like a lonely flower.
You would decay here.
You refused everything
for your tribe.
Childless, alone,
and hopeless.
You should never forget this:
I am your destiny...
now.
I only care about my tribe.
And I'm not afraid of dying alone at all.
Hereafter, I am the Cavdar Bey Aslıhan,
not your fiancée Aslıhan!
I am breaking off...
the engagement.
My destiny is to grow old in my tribe,
and die in my tribe.
You should know that.
When...
you end up as a beautiful
but lonely woman...
because of your pride...
you will regret this.
But it will be too late.
Think about this.
Think about what you just lost,
and what you will...
lose.
What is it, Son?
You wanted to see us.
I hope everything is all right.
Everything is all right, Mother. Sit down.
I want to marry Aslıhan Hatun
to a decent man from our tribe.
That sounds good, Son.
But what will Aslıhan say about this?
Since she talked to you
about Ameer Sadettin,
it means she wants our help with that.
Who do you have in mind, bey?
Turgut Alp.
Bey...
how are you going to put out
the fire of love in Turgut Alp?
Will this fire ever stop burning?
Would Aslıhan Hatun agree to this,
if she knew Turgut Alp's old wounds?
You can't find happiness,
without suffering first, Halime Sultan.
And both Turgut and Aslıhan
can stand this suffering.
I talked with Turgut.
He accepts my offer, if Aslıhan Hatun...
says yes.
Bey, what about Ameer Sadettin?
Would he accept this?
He will be on their backs.
He won't let them live their lives.
Ameer Sadettin
cannot do much harm to them.
And we will always stand by them.
If he tries to hurt them,
I will stand against him.
And Turgut is a strong man,
he can deal with Ameer Sadettin's tricks.
I want you to go
and talk to Aslıhan Hatun.
If she accepts this,
we should take care of this
as soon as possible.
Marriage is a great thing, Son.
If Aslıhan Hatun accepts, too...
we would fulfill Aliyar Bey's dying wish.
We would protect both his tribe,
and his sister from any instigation.
God willing, Mother.
God willing.
With this marriage,
we will connect our tribes
politically, too.
This is very important
for our tribes' future.
The Emperor wants us
to make an agreement with the Turks.
He says, raise the taxes
and give them what they want.
And he sent Commander Ares
to conduct the negotiations.
Commander Ares...
The Emperor made the right decision
by sending a great commander like him.
We could have fought, we could have won.
Most of our soldiers are dead.
If we summoned new troops,
Ertuğrul would have killed them, too.
We could have lost.
We would have died with honor.
As Vasilius did.
Vasilius died for nothing,
because of his temper and greed.
Remember, we will have our honor,
as long as we have this castle standing.
So, you have a voice in the castle,
now, Ekaterina.
You have managed to convince
the Emperor, too.
Justice is served now, thank God.
The Emperor does nothing for our state,
and now he gives a woman
so much authority.
You are underestimating
a woman like me, Nikolas.
You should know that,
if you stand against me one day,
no one can protect you from me.
Who do you think you are to threaten me?
May I come in, sir?
Come in!
Sir, there's a Turk here.
He says he is a messenger for Sultan.
Let him come in.
Soldiers!
They're starting to come at us
like vultures.
Come to your senses.
Choose your side right.
Or you will pay for it.
Seeing you in our nomad tent
and hosting you here is a great honor.
Thank you, my dear.
We are here
as the messengers for Ertuğrul Bey.
We have something to say.
I hope nothing is wrong.
You are like a daughter to me, my dear.
And like a sister to Ertuğrul Bey.
Your trouble is our trouble.
We cannot close our eyes to
you being forced into a marriage.
May God bless you for that.
However, Ameer Sadettin
will not leave me alone.
I could not talk him out of it.
I broke off the engagement, I told him
to his face this isn't going to happen...
but he doesn't look like he will give up.
Men have pride.
They cannot accept defeat.
They would fight for their love.
However, if one of the sides
is not happy about it,
life would be miserable.
It is, Mother.
Life is miserable for me already.
Everyday feels like a nightmare.
Then, my dear,
there is only one way out of this.
Ameer Sadettin finds you alone.
He finds you hopeless.
He does not care about anybody, Mother.
A jackal only fears a lion, my dear.
I know how you can save yourself from him.
You need a lion
that will love you, protect you,
look out for you,
and stand against Ameer Sadettin,
and say, "Aslıhan is my wife now.
You will stay away from her."
So, my dear,
Ertuğrul Bey thinks that the only way
to save you from Ameer Sadettin
would be marrying you to someone else.
Mother Hayme,
who would dare to marry me
after Ameer Sadettin?
Someone who will protect you,
someone who will devote his life to you,
and that brave man is...
Turgut Alp, my dear.
Ertuğrul Bey thinks
that you would suit each other perfectly.
Of course,
you need to give your consent, too.
Artuk Bey...
what do you want?
I want to talk with
the commander of the castle.
We're listening to you.
I am not going to talk to you,
Çolpan Hatun.
My name is Ekaterina.
And you will talk with
Commander Nikolas and I.
You have heard her.
Now talk, Turk.
Sultan of the Seljuk Sultanate,
Alaeddin Kayqubad, commands that...
hereafter, Karacahisar Castle
will be home of justice, not cruelty.
If you turn the castle over to us,
your lives will be spared,
and we will let your soldiers
go back to Nicaea safe and sound.
Otherwise,
we will level the castle to the ground,
and kill each and every one of you!
The ones who resist will suffer the rage
of our Sultan and his army.
This is our first and last call.
It is up to you to obey the call.
Or you will face the consequences.
Sultan, I have
some important news from Konya.
What is it, Aziz?
The Ayyubid army.
They are heading towards
our borders, Sultan.
They're taking
advantage of Mongol attacks,
and want to subvert my state.
Bring Ameer Sadettin
and Ertuğrul Bey to me.
Yes, Sultan.
Tell your sultan,
we are ready for an agreement.
Our Emperor will send Commander Ares
to conduct the negotiations.
We believe
we can solve our problems in peace.
Sultan's commands are clear.
He will decide whether
he will make an agreement with you.
I am sure your Sultan will not refuse
a profitable agreement like this.
We will live in peace,
without losing anybody anymore.
Otherwise, he will
level the castle to the ground.
And everybody would find peace then.
We do not fear you.
This is not over yet.
We will speak the language
that you understand.
Mother Hayme,
before anything else,
I broke up with Ameer Sadettin,
because I don't want to leave my tribe.
He is a bad-tempered man,
but if it wasn't for my tribe,
I would have hidden the distress
and accept my destiny.
What about Turgut Alp,
would he agree to come to my tribe?
Ertuğrul Bey has talked with Turgut.
He is a self-sacrificing person like you,
who considers what's best for his tribe.
And he agreed to live here
in Cavdar Tribe.
God bless him for that.
Not every man would make such a sacrifice.
That's why Ertuğrul Bey thinks
that you would suit each other perfectly.
You both live for the same cause,
and you only care about your tribes.
Look, my dear...
you will need someone like him
on this sacred road.
Marriage is based upon self-sacrifice.
If you combine your love
with self-sacrifice,
you will have peace in your lives.
I only seek peace, Mother.
Turgut Alp is a brave, chivalrous man.
He fought together with my brother.
Ertuğrul Bey's companion
cannot be a bad man.
That's why we are asking you
to think about this, Aslıhan Hatun.
If you give your consent,
we will make this happen.
There is no time for thinking, Halime.
I am having nightmares every night.
Ertuğrul Bey must have thought carefully.
If Turgut Alp will be staying at my tribe,
I give my consent for this marriage.
Then we will come to visit you tonight,
if it is okay with you, my dear.
We do it properly.
We do it in accordance with
our traditions and our religion.
You are welcome, Mother.
You would honor my nomad tent.
We will send Abdur Rahman to the khan
to give Ertuğrul Bey the good news.
We need to go now.
Mother...
-Good luck with it.
-God willing.
Sultan will send Ameer Sadettin
for the negotiations.
And Ertuğrul.
What is on your mind, Nikolas?
They will not come out alive from here.
Do you hear what you are saying?
We cannot have Ertuğrul vulnerable again.
You cannot do that.
I want Ertuğrul and Ameer Sadettin dead,
more than you do.
But, no. Not like this.
If you do this, Sultan will
level the castle to the ground.
Do you think I care?
What are you going to do when Ares comes?
He would never let you do that.
I will kill him too, if necessary.
I am the commander of this castle.
May I come in, sir?
Commander Ares is entering the castle
with his soldiers, sir.
Let's not keep the great commander
of the Emperor waiting.
Bey, I brought you a message
from Mother Hayme.
Tell me, Abdur Rahman.
Mother Hayme said everything is fine,
and you will go to visit tonight.
Thank you, Abdur Rahman.
Bey, what visit is this?
It is an auspicious visit, Bamsi.
Oh. An auspicious visit.
Good. Who is getting married, bey?
Turgut.
My God! My brother Turgut?
Bey, tell me more.
How did this happen? Who is the girl?
Bamsi, come with me.
I will tell you everything.
Okay, brother.
You are responsible for my suffering.
You have poisoned Aslıhan.
She broke her father's promise to me.
Aslıhan Hatun made a decision,
and everybody
needs to respect her decision.
What about Candar Bey's decision?
Why are you not following
an elder's order?
Why are you not following my decision?
Why are you creating difficulties
for this marriage, Ertuğrul?
Ameer Almighty, if we are going to
call each other to account
for the things that have happened to us...
you'll take the blame for that.
You are wrong on this, Ertuğrul.
You have involved with this personally.
You got inside Aslıhan's head purposely.
What is essential
is getting inside your lover's heart.
Come on, brother, tell me.
What is this all about?
Who is this girl? Is she from our tribe?
Or from another tribe?
From a near tribe, or a far one?
Tell me. Tell me, brother, Go on.
You won't let me get a word in, Bamsi.
Oh. Brother, I'm just excited
because of all this joy.
Oh, dear.
Brother, tell me. Who is this girl? Go on.
The women Ertuğrul Bey wants me
to marry with...
Yes, brother?
...is Aslıhan Hatun.
Bamsi?
Bamsi, recover yourself!
Brother, did I hear right?
Did you say Aslıhan Hatun?
Yes. I said Aslıhan Hatun.
Brother, isn't Aslıhan Hatun
engaged to Ameer Sadettin?
Aslıhan doesn't want him.
She said she would never leave her tribe.
She made a promise to
the deceased Aliyar Bey.
Right. Ameer Sadettin will take her away
from her tribe, for sure.
And Aslıhan Hatun doesn't want that.
Her tribe would be without a leader then.
And Ertuğrul Bey wants her to stay
for the future of Cavdar Tribe.
And he wants me to marry her,
so Ameer Sadettin will get off her back,
and our tribes will be united.
Good.
My brother!
My dear brother!
My brother is getting married!
My dear brother.
I am feeling on top of the world now,
because of you, brother!
Take it easy, Bamsi. We didn't ask for
the girl's hand. She hasn't said yes yet.
What are you saying, brother?
Is there a manlier man than you?
Brother, you would suit Aslıhan Hatun,
and she would suit you, too.
Let's hope for the best.
God willing!
Amen.
But, brother... We...
Since we will go to visit her tonight,
we need to get ready. Get up!
-Get up, brother.
-Stop it, Bamsi. What are you doing?
Brother, first,
we need to put you in order.
And we will start by tidying your hair.
Can't you see?
Your hair looks like a real mess.
I will take care of this.
Ameer Sadettin, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sultan wants to see you.
Come. I have been waiting for you.
I got the news from Konya
that I have been waiting for.
The Ayyubid army
is heading towards our borders.
The Ayyubid's greed
will give the Mongols
the opportunity they've been looking for.
Ogeday's scattered troops
will take this opportunity
and attack our state's inner walls.
You were the one
who faced the Mongols' advance guards
at our border, Ertuğrul Bey.
You know them well, too.
And you are right.
When they get the chance
their troops will come,
not to plunder, but to demolish my state.
War is inevitable, Sultan.
We have to launch a campaign
against them, with our army.
It is not about war, Ameer Sadettin.
When the time comes, The Ayyubid
will taste my sword,
as my many enemies have before.
It is about the situation
which the Islamic world is in.
Not only Islamic states,
but even the smallest emirates
are killing each other
with their unabated greed.
Until we unite them,
both Mongol and the Crusader raids
will continue to strike us, Sultan.
We will never drop Islam's justice flag
to the ground, Ertuğrul Bey.
With God's permission...
this flag will always be in the air.
The ones who will stop
the Mongol and the Crusaders’ atrocity
are the brave men
who will fight under the Islam flag.
As long as our state is enduring...
and our beys are as brave and fair as you.
It is almost done...
We are about to finish.
Just wait, brother.
It is done, brother.
Now, you are ready to go.
Now you look like you are going to
visit a woman, not going to war.
You look wonderful. Wonderful!
See it for yourself.
Look, brother.
-Bamsi, what did you do?
-What?
What is this?
-You look excellent, brother.
-You call this excellent?
It looks like a goat licked it.
Why are you getting mad, brother?
It worked for me.
Hafsa Hatun liked me because of this.
It is not about your hair, brother,
it is your heart.
Hafsa Hatun likes your heart.
Good. You are right about this, brother.
You are right. Good. However...
However, brother, a real man
is the one who is heartsick,
and his hair is slicked.
And brother, when Aslıhan Hatun
sees you like this,
she will be thunderstruck.
Sure, she will be thunderstruck.
Good, then.
Brother, we didn't dress you yet.
Let's dress you, then.
Stop, brother. Stop.
Please stop.
I can take care of it. Okay?
Okay.
Good. You take care of it.
You do that.
No!
Not this one, brother.
Not this shirt. Drop this.
Brother, are you going to migrate
to a colder place with that one?
No, brother. No.
You should wear something thinner.
Drop that, brother. Drop it.
Tell me! What should I wear?
I will show you.
Not this one. Not this one, either.
Sultan, Artuk Bey is here.
Let him come in.
Sultan, I delivered your message
to Karacahisar Castle.
Emperor sent a commander
with full authorization.
They invite your envoys to the castle
for peace negotiations tomorrow.
You have honored our castle,
Commander Ares.
Do you know what honor means
for a soldier, Nikolas?
Commander Ares...
It means to live with loyalty,
and die for his commander.
I heard you left Vasilius for dead.
I could not leave the castle defenseless,
when Vasilius left
it was ambushed by Ertuğrul, sir.
I live to die with honor.
If I made a mistake,
I am ready to pay the price.
Vasilius paid that price
with his blood, Nikolas.
I am ready to die for you,
and for our Emperor.
May God forgive his sins.
A castle without a commander
is like a ruin!
But a ruin with a commander...
is stronger than Byzantine's walls!
When a soldier
leave his commander for dead,
it means he also
hands over the castle to the enemy!
Now take this disloyal man's body here.
I don't want him to soil the memory
of the soldiers who died for the Emperor.
Are you Ekaterina?
Yes, it is me.
Come with me. We need to talk.
My Sultan, the emperor
will agree to anything
except surrendering the castle.
It's clear that he'll accept our terms,
no matter how harsh.
My Sultan, this might be for the best.
Vasilius' death, your presence here,
and your army heading this way
have obviously intimidated
the emperor, my Sultan.
It's time to stem the poison
which flows from this fortress.
They are evidently afraid,
but in the current situation,
I believe it would be best to force
them to seek peace.
-Continue, Sadettin.
-My Sultan...
the demands on our army
will be considerable
during the campaign against the Ayyubids,
and this way, we can achieve victory
without risking a single soldier.
In addition, the taxes
we will force them to pay
can be used to strengthen our state.
My Sultan... gold can't
compensate for treachery.
As long as Karacahisar Castle is under
their rule, victory will not be ours.
You're right, Ertuğrul Bey.
We will not rest easy
until we have uprooted this evil.
The most pressing issue
is how we address the Ayyubid violations.
My Sultan, if we divide our army,
we cannot win both wars.
If we merely subject them
to the heavy taxes Emir Sadettin suggests,
we're giving them time
to regroup, my Sultan.
They're weak, my Sultan.
This is our chance. Our only chance.
We'll not give them time to
heal their wounds, Ertuğrul Bey.
We'll stop them regaining their strength.
I have the utmost faith in the Turk Beys,
your valiant alps
and, most of all, in you.
We will agree to a deal for now.
And when the time comes,
we will drain the swamp.
With your permission,
I'd like to go to the castle
to negotiate the agreement, my Sultan.
In that case, I don't think any agreement
should be limited to taxes, my Sultan.
We need to make it clear to the emperor
that they cannot take so much
as a breath in these lands
without our permission.
If you'll allow it,
as your chief bey of the frontier,
I too would like to go to the castle.
Very good. Very good.
I have no doubt that you will both
carry out this duty
to the best of your abilities.
Lion.
My brother, no woman who sees you
will know what hit her.
Her heart will flutter like a bird.
She will frolic in the fields
like a young horse.
Bless my brother! Bless him!
-Thank you, brother.
-Bless you.
My dear brother.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome
Turgut Alp?
Brother, you know how I told you
that they wouldn't know what hit them?
Look at him.
Speak, Günküt.
Brother Günküt, why are you
staring like a fox that's seen a rabbit?
I was looking at Turgut Alp, bless him.
Well, don't.
You'll cast the evil eye on him.
I said bless him, brother.
You said that to Brother Dumrul, too,
when he dressed up like our sultan,
and he barely made it out alive!
-What is it, Günküt?
-Ertuğrul Bey says we must leave.
All right.
Well then, it's time.
Come on, now. Come on, brother.
May God lead your way.
Bless him, bless him.
You saved our state from disaster.
If Nikolas had defeated you...
he'd have been able to kill the Turks
that had come to make a deal.
You should've known
that I'd never have allowed that.
The letter said you would arrive tomorrow.
The fact that you arrived early shows that
you understand exactly what's going on.
Because of him, the Sultan's army
and the Turk tribes
would have raided the castle.
And you would have lost the privileges
the Emperor granted you.
Ertuğrul took everything I had from me.
Nobody wants him to die as much as I,
or for the Turk tribes to go back
to the hell they came from as much as I.
I swore an oath that
I'd die for our emperor.
Paying them huge amounts in taxes
is hardly a retaliation, is it, Ekaterina?
All I know is that the Turks will
never stop clamoring for blood.
I never believed they would,
nor did our emperor.
As powerful a commander as yourself
surely wouldn't fall for that.
I understand now why Vasilius
had so much confidence in you.
I carry the fruit of his love in my loins.
I would give my life
and that of my child for the Emperor.
You impressed our emperor greatly
with your letter, Ekaterina.
You persuaded him that we could only
get rid of the Turks with your help.
I am prepared to do anything for our state
and my father's holy legacy.
I would very much like to believe
that you are strong enough to drive
your poisonous dagger into the heart of
the Turks when the time comes, Ekaterina.
Believe me, Commander Ares,
for those forced to share this land
with the Turks, you are our last hope.
May God protect you.
Ertuğrul... He is not an easy man to kill.
You know that better than anyone.
The Crusaders, Vasilius,
your late husband Ural...
-You know everything.
-I know my enemies, Ertuğrul best of all.
And more than you might think.
I have my eye on you, Ekaterina.
I look forward to seeing
what you can do. Now go.
I have matters to discuss
with my commanders.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
spare me from the cowardly enemy
and the betrayal of those
who seem like friends.
If I am to die, let it be in victory
over the Turks, and not in defeat.
Amen.
-Greetings.
You give honor to my tent, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Welcome, Mother Hayme.
-Thank you, my girl.
Halime.
Welcome to you too, Turgut Alp.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
Come, you must be tired.
Let us eat and relax.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Just as we break this bread together,
so we have shared in joy and sorrow too.
We have forged a strong bond
between the two tribes.
Now, it is my wish
for this bond to be strengthened
through blood ties
so we can travel a new and better path.
Anything which benefits our tribes
is most welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Quite so, my girl.
That's why our minds are easy.
We will leave your tent
in good faith, God willing.
Thank you.
Aslıhan Hatun... you and Turgut Alp
are like sister and brother to me.
You know why we are here.
On the one hand, there is you,
whom Aliyar Bey entrusted to my care.
And on the other,
there is the prosperity of our tribes.
Aslıhan Hatun, it is my wish
that you and Turgut Alp marry.
Whatever is in your heart,
say it freely, Aslıhan Hatun.
I have but one intention, and that is to
protect my tribe and my brother's legacy.
God willing, I would like to
fill my tent with my children,
raise a son, and continue my lineage.
Do you have anything to say, Turgut Alp?
We fought many a battle
side by side with Aliyar Bey.
We never once yielded to the enemy when
with the valiant alps of the Cavdar Tribe.
Our sole intent... was to never sway
from the road of holy jihad.
As the Kayi Tribe is my home...
so too is the Cavdar Tribe.
Dedicating your life to your children...
to your home and to your woman...
is the duty of a man.
I would happily dedicate myself
to he who dedicates himself
to my tribe, Ertuğrul Bey.
Enjoy, my Sultan.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
The archers that attacked
Ertuğrul Bey and his alps...
Still nothing? Still no word?
Everywhere we look
is only dead ends, my Sultan.
We've tried to get information,
but it's hard.
The treachery runs deep, Sadettin.
The treachery runs deep.
If I don't triumph, the traitors who have
infiltrated the veins of our state will.
Our overriding duty is to maintain order
preserve the state, my Sultan.
As soon as we return from the campaign,
I will take more precautions, God willing.
However...
there is something that worries me.
What?
The Mongolian threat.
The Mongols won't stay quiet
while you're away. That's obvious.
I believe it's imperative that we
take precautions against them.
What are you thinking, Sadettin?
I must give him his due.
Ertuğrul Bey is exactly
the right man for this.
He's spent more time fighting
the Mongols than any of us.
He got rid of that troublemaker Noyan.
Who knows the Mongols best?
Who of your beys
understands their tongue most clearly?
Ertuğrul Bey.
You're right, Sadettin.
You're right.
However, in Ertuğrul Bey's absence...
I fear our western frontier
will be vulnerable.
Then, if you see fit, I will stay
and do my best to serve you from here.
I hope I will be able to fill his shoes.
I'll discuss it with
Ertuğrul Bey, tomorrow.
The unity of the Turk tribes
is of the utmost importance.
You must have understood why Aslıhan Hatun
wanted to remain the head of her tribe.
-My Sultan?
-Aslıhan Hatun
quite naturally wants to stay
as the head of her tribe
and preserve Candar Bey's lineage.
She is the hope of her tribe.
Don't take that away from them, Sadettin.
-My Sultan--
-I have no doubt
that you will make
this sacrifice for our state.
Thank you.
Sister Aslıhan.
We spoke plainly.
We didn't hurt or get hurt.
By the command of God...
and the word of the Prophet...
we would like you to marry Turgut Alp.
Do you consent?
I have the utmost trust in you
and Turgut Alp, Ertuğrul Bey.
I consent.
May God bless you.
Be with God.
Be with God, my son.
May God grant you lasting peace.
May your children be loyal
to your beliefs, your law and your tribe,
and may they make you happy.
-Amen.
May your sons prosper
and your lineage grow.
May God unite you as one.
If anyone should cast
the evil eye upon your tent...
my tent would go up in flames, too.
If the whole world rose up against you,
they would taste my wrath.
I want you to be married quickly.
I wish this marriage to cast a veil
over evil eyes and shield your tent.
May your happiness
and your lineage be eternal.
-Amen.
Amen.
From this moment forth,
I am not your fiancé Aslıhan,
but Aslıhan, bey of the Cavdars.
Our engagement is over
My fate will be to grow old in my tribe
and die with my tribe.
Aslıhan...
You have sent me to hell.
Eminence, there is word of Aslıhan Hatun.
Tell me.
Ertuğrul Bey, Hayme Hatun,
Halime Hatun and Turgut Alp
have visited the Cavdar Tribe.
Interesting.
-What for?
-We don't know, Your Eminence.
Leave.
What are you up to now, Ertuğrul?
Surely you will be gone soon, Ertuğrul.
You'll leave, taking your tricks
and the trouble you caused me with you.
When you are fighting your campaign...
my reign will begin.
My war will begin.
All right then.
-Here you go, brother.
-Thank you, brother.
Here you go, brother.
Thank you, brother.
Brothers, my brother Turgut's
good fortune has made all of us happy.
I thought I'd give a feast
in my brother's honor.
Hafsa made this wonderful food
with her own hands.
-Brother?
-Yeah?
We are going to eat weeds
like goats. Weeds.
Hush, Kader. Hush.
There was no need, brother.
God bless you.
-Thank you for your trouble, Hafsa Hatun.
-Brothers!
Eat first, and then say what you will.
Bamsi...
I wish I could have made fish.
We used to eat lots of fish,
but it's hard to find around here.
Don't worry, Hafsa Baci.
We'll eat whatever God offers.
We will.
Thank you.
There we are. All right.
In Nicaea we would enhance
our food with various herbs.
They are both delicious
and good for the digestion.
I put a lot of spices into the stew.
It's not like the one you make.
I hope you like it.
Come on.
-Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Here you go, brother.
Bismillah.
I've never eaten
such delicious stew before.
Really brother, what have
we been eating up till now?
-I'm glad you like it. Bamsi?
-Yeah?
I'd like to go see Banu Çiçek for a while.
You should tend to everyone.
Don't worry. I can
take care of my brothers.
Off you go.
Enjoy your meal.
Thank you.
Hey! You're going to choke, slow down.
Brother, what kind of food is this?
You are so lucky.
Well, brother, you all know my appetite.
This is what I needed all along.
These spices make the food
taste very different.
Yeah. No need to worry
about it being left for the goats!
You're not so different
to a goat yourself, Brother Günküt.
Brothers, God created
man in various forms.
Each people has its own food,
its own way of baking bread.
Brothers, we should experience these foods
and remember them.
I wonder what happened to Turgut Alp.
I hope everything turned out well for him.
Brother, if Ertuğrul Bey was involved,
no other outcome is possible.
It is done.
Now, we have one last thing to do.
What is that, brother?
We make for Karacahisar Castle, brother.
We ride in the morning.
Eat, eat.
So good.
You eat like a goat. Like a goat, Günküt!
You eat like a goat!
An empire can only stand
so much belittlement.
You believed them to be a mere tribe
and took for granted an enemy
that grew in power before your very eyes.
I don't know who makes me angrier,
my foolish friend or my cunning enemy.
Ertuğrul Bey,
come to my castle in search of victory.
Be arrogant. Show weakness.
Prepare your own end.
Commander Ares, Emir Sadettin
and Ertuğrul Bey have arrived.
Guards!
Ertuğrul Bey.
-Emir Sadettin, welcome.
-Thank you.
Your reputation precedes you,
Ertuğrul Bey. You are a valiant warrior.
-We meet at last.
-I do not fight...
to further my reputation, but for justice.
You must have heard that too.
Although we are enemies, we fight for
the same thing ultimately, Ertuğrul Bey.
Justice.
I always respect a chivalrous enemy,
and you are one of them.
Our objectives are night and day, Ares.
What you consider just, I consider cruel.
And I trample cruelty under my feet.
See, that's another thing
we have in common.
Ruthlessness against the cruel.
We will get along well.
Emir Sadettin, there is much talk of you
at Nicaea. Your cunning is legendary.
How nice. You must know then that I'm not
likely to walk out of here empty-handed.
-Show our guests the way.
-No need, Ares.
I have been here many times before.
In order to stay with my tribe
and serve it until the end of my days,
I have broken off my engagement
to Emir Sadettin.
And to further our bond
with the Kayi tribe
and become blood relatives,
I have decided to marry Turgut Alp.
I hope this marriage will
be for the best for both tribes.
May God make it so.
-I hope it will be good.
-Thank you.
Please tell the tribe of my decision.
Let everyone know that from this moment,
Turgut Alp is my betrothed.
There is a long road ahead of us
and many things to do.
We have come to hear Nicaea's offer.
In the name of the Seljuks,
Emir Sadettin...
bey of the Kayi tribe,
and chief frontier bey of the Seljuks,
Ertuğrul Bey...
I am authorized to speak
in the name of our emperor.
Ekaterina is entitled to attend, by the
privilege awarded to her by our emperor.
We are here to negotiate
for the mutual benefit of both sides.
The outcome is obvious.
Make your offer quickly.
Our offer will protect
both your soldiers and ours.
The emperor in Nicaea
is ready to pay for peace.
Our empire will pay
the following tribute to the Seljuk State.
Each year, 150,000 gold coins,
200,000 silver...
and a cut of the trade routes.
The war will end,
and our peoples will live in peace.
As long as peace is maintained,
the tribute will continue to be paid.
Very good.
I know how generous
the emperor in Nicaea is.
And you should know how forgiving
our Sultan Alâeddin Keykubat is.
In return for your tribute,
your lives will be spared.
You will be allowed
to remain in the castle.
We have a deal, then.
That was your offer, Ares.
We haven't discussed it yet.
What do you mean, Ertuğrul Bey?
You may be able to convince
the Latins with a handful of gold...
but we did not come here for a tribute.
What is your demand?
Every year, you will pay 300,000 in gold
and 400,000 in silver to the Seljuk State.
The gates of the castle will be open
to all Turks and Muslims.
No taxes or interest will be applied
to Muslims trading at the castle.
All trade routes will be under
the management of the Turkmen tribes.
There will be a limit on the number
of soldiers stationed at the castle.
We will specify how many.
The Turks and Muslims
who live and trade in the castle
will be under the protection
of the Seljuk State.
We cannot accept these terms. You have
not come to negotiate, but to invade.
Ertuğrul Bey...
What you are asking for
is the surrender of the castle.
You have exhausted our patience.
Either you accept our demands, or...
we will melt the iron mountain,
make the sky tremble...
and lay waste to your castle.
Wait.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Your demands are too harsh.
Give us a few days to decide.
I will be back soon.
Make your decision quickly.
Door!
He's insane!
He's lost his mind!
He thinks we're helpless.
He's forcing us.
If we want to keep the castle,
we have no other choice.
Have can we give all that?
What authority would we have left?
First, we pay, Ekaterina.
Then we wait.
What is the meaning of this?
What are you trying to do?
We came here to negotiate.
I am negotiating.
You're not trying to negotiate.
You're trying to ruin everything!
What you're asking for
is nothing short of the entire castle.
That's what I intended, Your Eminence.
What if they refuse, Ertuğrul?
We will lose the ransom!
Then we'll come back
with our sultan's army.
We will take the castle.
Is our sultan's army not heading
east to fight the Ayyubis?
Don't you know that?
I do, Emir Sadettin. But they don't.
They think our armies
are moving towards their borders.
If we walk out with just the gold,
we will lose.
So, you wish to pursue
the answer in politics?
But don't forget, Ertuğrul.
If this thing falls apart because of you,
because of your stubbornness...
you will pay the price.
I came here at the price of a great
many things, Emir Sadettin.
It is time to get what's due to me.
I hope it's worth it.
I hope so.
Halime Sultan, I am so happy.
I hope Turgut Alp and Aslıhan's wedding
can take place very soon.
-I hope so too.
-It will be good for both of them.
Turgut Alp has kept to himself
for so long now.
I hope they will be good for each other.
Love makes the lover beautiful,
more amenable.
It brings peace to the heart
and blesses the home.
That is true, Halime Sultan.
I found that out through experience.
I hope all our unmarried men
find that out too.
Hopefully.
Bamsi was often worried about Turgut Alp.
He used to run off to be with him.
He couldn't stand him being all alone.
Now, he won't be able to
even if he still wanted to, Hafsa.
Turgut Alp will move to the Cavdar Tribe.
No matter. The Cavdar Tribe is so near.
In the end, our hearts are unified.
They are.
Ladies, we have a huge task ahead of us.
We have a wedding to prepare for.
We can do it together.
I saw how you helped each other
during my wedding. I was envious.
God willing, I'll be able to help
in the same way this time.
We will ensure it goes
off without a hitch.
People will bring
whatever they have to offer.
Ladies, I suggest we help with
Aslıhan Hatun's dowry too.
She's been through a lot.
She won't have had any time
to prepare anything herself.
-Right.
-You are right.
Just standing next to her will help.
-Come on, then. We have a lot to do.
-Come on.
Bismillah.
Your demands will batter our empire
both materially and morally, but...
our desire for peace is total.
You've gotten
what you wanted, Ertuğrul Bey.
Every demand?
Every single one.
But I do have something to ask of you.
All you may ask for is your life.
If you do everything
we say without delay...
we will honor your wish.
Ertuğrul Bey... I understand your anger.
Many warriors on both sides
fell in this war.
But if the terms of this agreement
aren't followed, there will be many more.
What is it you ask for?
Trust.
I ask you to trust me.
Everyone you saw as your foe has fallen.
Simon, the governor, Vasilius.
None took into account the one thing
sharper than the sword: honor.
I give you my hand in friendship.
If honor is what you prize,
you ride under the wrong banner.
I have no trust.
Not in you,
nor anyone associated with you.
But know that I will not be dishonest.
If you are cruel...
I will turn against you.
Cruelty is the armor of cowards,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I came into this world naked
and will leave it naked.
You have a month
to abide by the terms of the agreement.
It will be done, Emir Sadettin.
I will personally ensure we meet the terms
of the agreement and your wishes.
May it be good.
I hope it is.
Don't make the mistake Vasilius made
and try to play games.
We are in this situation because Vasilius
underestimated you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Rest assured I will not
make the same mistake.
The agreement must be broken at once.
I don't know how long I can take this.
Even Emir Sadettin found it hard
to believe we agreed to the terms.
It's too much, even for them.
We're going to break it
without handing over a single gold coin.
My brave father...
I accepted whatever you said...
so as not to oppose you.
But my brother Ural poisoned you.
Now, I will do my utmost to stay loyal
to my brother Aliyar's legacy,
and preserve the tribe
you fought so hard to establish.
I agreed to marry that man...
to stay loyal to your memories...
and ensure our tribes remain united.
I know if my brother Aliyar was here
he would support the decision I made.
However...
I will need your forgiveness, Father.
These are significant
concessions, my Sultan.
This is a victory.
Money alone
will not enough to relieve those
Muslims who are suffering, Sadettin.
We fight in the name of God's justice,
not for gold. Don't you know that?
And the emperor will no doubt
break the agreement
the moment he believes
we are in any way weakened.
It isn't only the Nicaea Empire,
the whole world is waiting
for us to be wounded.
Gold will be no use to us
when they appear on our borders.
There is cruelty
in every corner of the world.
That's the reason why our march
to the east is so necessary, my Sultan.
Our state is capable of handling
both the Mongols and the Ayyubid Dynasty.
May God make you victorious
on your campaign, my Sultan.
On our campaign, Ertuğrul Bey.
I want you to join the war, too.
I am entrusting to you and your warriors
the defence of our eastern borders
when I march against the Ayyubid Dynasty.
You will repel any possible
attacks by the Mongols
while I'm away dealing with the Ayyubids.
As you command, my Sultan.
They shall not pass.
But... have no fear
for what you leave behind.
Emir Sadettin will take care
of these lands until we return.
As you command, my Sultan.
Until Ertuğrul Bey comes back,
these lands will be safe in my hands.
I'll inform the Turk tribes
and gather our best alps, my Sultan.
They will be honored to fight
under your banner.
I have no doubts about the loyalty
and competence of our brave warriors.
Our country will rise up
upon the shoulders of these brave men.
Take all necessary precautions
and prepare your men, Ertuğrul Bey.
Yes, my Sultan.
We will meet them on Kurt Hill...
and make our way from there
to our eastern borders.
Ertuğrul Bey...
In the time I have known you,
you have never disappointed me.
I believe appointing you as margrave
was the right decision
and one that will benefit our state.
May your cunning
be as sharp as your sword.
May our unity last forever
and may our army be victorious.
Amen.
May God help you in your endeavors.
Henceforth, I entrust you with
the responsibility to make decisions.
I will never forget this day.
The concessions we were forced to make
because of the stupidity of a commander
have taught me something important.
Never underestimate your enemy,
and always fight honorably.
Those responsible are
buried in the ground now.
It's we who have to suffer
the consequences.
The Turks have stopped for now, Ekaterina.
But you should hurry.
Your emperor chose you for a task.
Remember, your rights were
granted to you for this purpose.
We are not the only ones
who want Ertuğrul dead.
We'll do it together.
Choose your allies carefully.
Remember... If Ertuğrul doesn't die
you lose all your privileges.
I've already lost what's important.
I have nothing to fear
and nothing to lose.
The problem of Karacahisar Castle
has been dealt with.
Thanks to the agreement we struck
Karacahisar is no longer a threat to us.
God bless your efforts, son.
You deserve this victory.
God bless you in your battles.
Thank you, Mother.
May God watch over you, my Bey.
May your victories be everlasting.
But there is something even
more pressing we have to deal with.
What is it, son?
You've only just got back.
Who else is there to oppose you?
Mother, the Ayyubids' army
is marching towards our borders.
It's a threat to our state.
Our Sultan is marching to meet them.
He wants the Turkmen tribes
to act as the front line
along the eastern borders
while he is away.
What are you saying, my Bey?
We promised to endure any pain
and hardship for our state, Halime Hatun.
-Turgut.
-Yes, my Bey.
Send Gunkut, Samsa, Dumrul
and Abdurrahman to the Turkmen tribes.
Have them gather their best alps.
You go to the Cavdar Tribe.
Take some of Aslıhan Hatun's alps.
We rendezvous at Kurt Hill tomorrow.
We will have to postpone your marriage.
-Let Aslıhan Hatun know.
-As you command, my Bey.
Dundar Bey, you will act as Bey
of the tribe in my absence.
Artuk Bey... you will be coming with me.
As you command, my Bey.
I want you by my side not just for your
bravery but because of your experience.
I'd die for you, my Bey.
Brother... I wish I could come
and fight alongside you.
The tribe needs a bey, Dundar,
you know that.
-The tribe is your responsibility.
-Have no fear on that score, my Bey.
Dear God...
-What is this, Eminence?
-Out!
What do you think you are doing?
You have already made a fool of me
and now you distract
our sultan at this
vital time with this matter?
I have nothing to hide from anyone.
Our sultan wanted to know about it.
The place for it is right here.
It cannot leave here.
Are you going to keep on
humiliating me, Aslihan?
I'm not trying to humiliate anyone!
Do not think to take your anger out on me!
You convinced our sultan and sought to...
use him against me, right?
So, what will you do
when our sultan marches away?
You didn't know, did you?
And what about Ertuğrul?
He was supposed to protect you, right?
Alas, he is also marching away.
And... no one knows if or
when they'll ever come back.
May God aid our warriors in their battles.
I don't fear anyone but God.
I have never looked to anyone for support
except for God's holy support--
I made you an offer,
and it's still on the table.
Stop being stubborn
and just choose a bey for your tribe.
Let me help you.
Let me conclude our marriage.
There is no such thing as
"our marriage", Eminence.
Ertuğrul Bey, with God's help,
had Turgut Alp ask for my hand.
And you said?
Turgut Alp and I are to be married.
If he marches to war,
then I will wait for him to return.
And you should give up on this delusion.
You don't realize what you're saying.
You...
You don't realize what you are saying!
God, please protect me and my loved ones
from this man's rage.
Eminence!
-Are you all right? Healer!
-Stop!
I don't need anyone.
Listen to me, Cabir...
Send a messenger
to Karacahisar Castle at once.
Yes, sir.
-To whom, exactly?
-To Ekaterina.
The message will be
Ertuğrul's death sentence.
-May I come in?
-Come in, son.
-Greetings.
As you know, at our sultan's invitation,
we are to march to the east.
You know, it's time for war.
I'm here to ask for your prayers
and your blessings.
Those who carry good intentions
will secure a good outcome, son.
Our prayers are with you.
If I have blessings to give,
you have them.
We've made many memories
over the years we've spent together.
You should give me your blessings, too.
Of course, you have my blessings.
God does not leave alone those
who embrace his cause, son.
You want to wave
the glorious flag of Islam
in every corner of the world.
You aim to provide justice
and eliminate cruelty.
God will certainly be on your side.
God says in the story of The Heifer,
"Fighting has been enjoined upon you
while it is hateful to you.
But perhaps you hate a thing
and it is good for you;
and perhaps you love a thing
and it is bad for you.
And God Knows, while you know not."
Our prophet trusted only in God
when he was travelling to Medina.
And God did not leave him alone.
He protected him
with the web of a spider.
You too should count on God's help.
Your march will shine like a beacon
of hope to the oppressed.
You'll be the protector
of innocent children,
crying mothers and the poor.
Be a servant to your holy cause
so that you may be glorious.
But remember, son, it is being a servant
of God which is itself glorious.
Use your power to frighten only the cruel.
To provide hope to the oppressed.
To spread justice in the world.
To rise against cruelty.
And always remember these verses
from The Family of Imran.
"Our Lord, let not our hearts deviate
after You have guided us,
and grant us from your mercy.
Indeed, you are the bestower."
May you have good fortune
and may God help you
in all your endeavors, Ertuğrul Bey.
God bless you.
Bamsi.
How will my heart
endure your absence, Bamsi?
I'll be left incomplete when you leave.
You'll get used to it.
You'll endure it. I'll go
and come back before you know it.
It's hard to get used to it, Bamsi.
There seems always to be a battle.
When you leave in the morning
I know you'll be back
in the evening and I wait for you.
This time no one knows
when you'll be back.
How can I bear it?
My beloved Hafsa... My beloved.
Please don't be sad.
Come here, come, my Hafsa...
Come here.
Hafsa, I know our being apart is hard.
But we will be together again soon.
My Hafsa, barbarians are on our borders.
If we don't force them back
many innocents will die.
Patience is a sour thing,
but its fruit is sweet.
Bamsi, what if something happens to you?
I can't live without you.
I have no one else, Bamsi.
Don't talk like that.
Would I ever leave you alone?
I'll be back before you know it.
Please don't worry.
-My lady, may I enter?
-Yes.
My lady, a messenger brought this.
He wouldn't say who it's from.
Ertuğrul will be on Kurt Hill tomorrow.
Have him experience hell on that hill.
Emir Sadettin.
I know it's you.
May I come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
Come in, Kirca.
Welcome, Turgut Alp.
-Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Please sit.
Thank you. But I have
something important to say.
Our Sultan has marched his army
against the Ayyubids.
The alps of the Turk tribes
will act as an advance guard
under Ertuğrul Bey's
command against the Mongols.
We would like the alps of the Cavdar Tribe
to join us if you will permit it.
The wishes of our Sultan and of
Ertuğrul Bey are orders I live to fulfil.
I had the warriors get ready
as soon as I heard about the march.
When did you learn about the march?
Emir Sadettin told me.
He has a loose tongue.
I hope he didn't say anything
to upset you.
Don't worry. His words can't upset me.
Put your mind at rest.
Very well.
Ertuğrul Bey says we should
postpone our wedding ceremony,
if you agree to it.
Ertuğrul Bey thought correctly.
We'll do what's required
when you come back.
Then if you will excuse me,
I'd like to check on the warriors.
Kirca will show you the way.
Guards!
Sir, news has arrived
from our scouts at the inn.
The sultan is on his way
to Konya with his army.
You can leave.
So, the sultan took a big
bite out of us and left.
Isn't that what we wanted?
I won't get what I want
until Ertuğrul dies, Ekaterina.
I will deliver Ertuğrul's head to you
without disrupting the peace.
Without disrupting the peace... how?
The time has come.
Ertuğrul will go to Kurt Hill
near Konya tomorrow.
Right after the sultan...
What are they up to?
It's up to you to find out.
Just as it's up to you to
send Ertuğrul straight to hell.
You will be his executioner.
How did you find out about this?
I was told of it by someone I trust.
How do we know your contact
is trustworthy?
Because he wants Ertuğrul dead
more than anyone.
Who?
You'll know who they are
when you finally learn to trust me.
May I come in, Aslıhan Hatun?
Come in, Turgut Alp.
I've been expecting you.
I had a guest tent made ready for you.
You should rest tonight.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun. Thank you.
I talked to the alps. They are
as sharp as a sword and just as brave.
They're all excited at the prospect
of fighting alongside Ertuğrul Bey.
I understand their enthusiasm,
they'll be with their brothers once more
and fighting alongside them.
I chose unmarried warriors.
If anything should happen to them
they will leave no wives behind,
waiting for their return.
Except for you.
It's been a long time
since someone waited for me.
I know very well what it's like
to wait and then to lose.
But you made the right decision.
We'll be on our way first thing tomorrow.
-Excuse me.
-Turgut Alp.
This dagger is for you.
I'd like you to have it.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
This dagger... will remind me
someone is waiting for me.
I'm grateful.
Guards!
My boy!
I hope you come back safe and sound.
May God help you and protect you.
Come back safe and sound. God bless you.
Protect each other.
My Halime...
Whenever you send me into battle
with tears in your eyes,
I leave a part of me here.
I can't think straight.
I'm strong,
but my heart is soft, Ertuğrul.
Don't you understand? I'm in love.
I'll miss you.
I'll cry, I'll wait,
but I'll stay patient.
May my tears be your comrades.
May my love be your shield.
May the blue skies be your friend
and the brown soil your companion.
Share your secrets with them
until I come back.
If you listen to the wind...
you'll hear me.
The rain will pour my love for you.
My Halime.
I entrust my children and my home to you.
You are the bearer of life, a mother.
You are the beloved one.
You are God's gift to me.
Be patient and stay strong.
May God protect you, Ertuğrul.
I know he will protect you.
He will send you back to my arms.
Father, I'm ready!
Mother, we're going on a march.
Who will protect your mother
if you come with me?
Who will protect our tribe?
I talked to the alps,
they will protect it.
No, you've not to leave your mother alone.
You are to lead the tribe while I'm away.
When will we go
and fight together, Father?
We'll go to war together
when Savci has grown up.
May God deliver you from evil, Halime.
Gündüz.
Come back safe to us.
-Thank you, my boy.
-Protect my sons.
May God protect our sons.
Come on, brother.
-May God help you.
-Come back...
-May you be victorious.
-Amen.
Dear God, protect these brave men
fighting for your cause.
Spare them for their
families and children.
Live long, brave warriors.
-May God help you.
-Come back safe and sound.
May God protect our Ertuğrul Bey.
To the parents who send their sons...
to be martyrs, if that's what it takes,
know this...
God sees everything
and he is aware of your sacrifice.
We live to spread the justice of God.
We know our dying
is to come together with God.
But we will live.
For God, for the state.
For our traditions.
If we live, our state lives.
If we live, our traditions live.
If we live, our tribe lives.
We will oppress the sound of cruelty.
We will make those brutes
kneel before our swords.
Our faith will shake the earth.
We have one arrow for every heathen
and a thousand warriors
to protect us from their one arrow.
We are Turks.
We have been never afraid.
And we will not ever be afraid.
We will not!
-We will not give up!
-We will succeed!
-Allahuakbar!
Allahuakbar!
Allahuakbar! Allahuakbar!
-Take care of the tribe, Dundar.
-May God protect you, brother.
Thank you.
I have such a brave son
that even the skies envy me.
I have such a brave son...
that I can't give enough blessings to you.
You deserve more than I can give.
Go on, son. Go.
Go on if our state is to live on,
if the enemy are not to walk
upon the soil of our state,
if our flag is to wave freely. Go on, son.
Be a martyr if that's what it takes.
We won't shed a single tear
even if our hearts cry a river.
Mother, pray for me.
Your prayers will be my shield.
-Come back safe.
-May God watch over you.
Come on, Alps! A battle awaits us!
Brave warriors of Cavdar tribe,
I know each one of you volunteered
to go on this march.
I have no doubt that the warriors
of the Cavdar tribe will act bravely
under the command of Ertuğrul Bey.
Many other Turk tribes
will accompany you in this march
and victory will bring power
for our state and honor to our tribe.
May God bless us in this battle.
Amen!
Amen.
I will pray for you,
I will pray that you come back
to your loved ones as soon as possible.
Turgut, Master Alp,
I entrust these brave warriors to you.
They are first entrusted to God,
and second to Ertuğrul Bey, Aslıhan Hatun.
Alps!
My Bey, this looks like
the work of bandits.
They ambushed these poor people.
There are wounded people here, my Bey.
Let me have a look at them.
Keep on your guard. Alps!
Take both sides of the road.
Ready your bows!
-Be careful, Bamsi.
-Yes, my Bey.
Artuk Bey!
Show your face, you bastard.
I will make you pay
for what you've done to my warriors.
I bear witness...
that there is no god but God,
and that Muhammad is his messenger...