Episode 88 will start after 12:32 min.
This is the end of your fame, Ertuğrul.
You can take all the fame.
Martyrdom will suffice for us.
Come on!
Where are these arrows coming from?
Attack!
Sultan!
Who are they, Nikolas?
They have more men than us,
we will lose. Let's go.
We won't lose! Attack!
Just a bit more, Halime Sultan.
Keep pushing.
-A bit more.
-Breathe.
Push.
Push, Halime.
-Come on.
Congratulations, Halime.
Dear God!
-Thank God.
-Congratulations, Halime Sultan.
He's a boy.
God bless.
God bless him.
My love.
God bless.
How sweet!
Surrender, Ertuğrul.
There's no way out.
We only surrender to God, Vasilius.
To the last of our breath.
Ertuğrul!
This is just the beginning.
Aliyar Bey! Brother!
Brother!
We must retreat, Vasilius.
No. Either he dies, or I die.
For our cause, Vasilius. Come on.
Come on.
You are coming with me.
Ishak!
Abdur Rahman, Bamsi. Come with me.
I love you so much, my baby boy.
Look at those silky hands.
That heavenly smell.
Healthy and beautiful.
God bless you.
Come on, hop in to your mother's arms.
God bless.
May God let him grow with his parents.
Here, take him.
I love you so much, my baby boy.
Mother.
Has Ertuğrul returned yet?
He will, my dear. Be patient.
Don't worry.
Okay.
Please God, I beg you.
Let him return safe and sound
and see his son.
Amen.
Please protect him
and his friends from the evil doers.
Amen.
Let's be strong now.
They will surely come back.
I hope so.
-Hopefully, my dear.
-Hopefully.
Aliyar Bey, open your eyes.
Aliyar Bey.
He's alive.
Put more pressure on it.
Sir.
He's lost too much blood,
and his wound is deep.
The bastard got away.
Turgut.
Slowly.
Easy.
You've gone through worse than this.
Come on.
God bless you, Your Highness.
If it weren't for you--
Ebu Mansur, Ertuğrul Bey.
Call me that for now.
We aided you, but God saved you.
We'll talk at the camp.
Yes, sir.
Ishak.
We're going back to the camp.
Carry the wounded.
-Come on, brother.
-Come on.
-Don't be rough.
-Up.
Help.
God bless.
Such a healthy boy.
May he live with his mother and father.
Amen.
Amen. Thank you, dear.
Next is Banu Çiçek, God willing.
Hopefully.
Thank God you are with us, Mother Hayme.
My first grandson.
Come here, look who is here.
Gündüz.
Is this my brother?
I need soldiers. Let me have a look.
Look.
Let me make my brother a sword.
You take care of him now.
Okay.
As little as he may be,
he's already acting all high and mighty.
May God never let them suffer.
Amen.
Ertuğrul Bey will be overjoyed to see him.
Mother.
Is there any news from them?
When will they come back?
After I lost my father,
I can't bear more of this pain.
May God let them get back safely.
Do not tempt fate, dear.
What could it be?
Nothing bad, I hope.
Please God, protect my children.
It's Aliyar Bey.
Aliyar Bey is wounded.
Who did this?
Make way.
-Aliyar!
Oh, my God!
-Brother!
-Son.
Please, open your eyes, brother.
Artuk Bey!
Don't leave me alone.
-Brother.
-Make way.
Brother.
-Take him to the healing tent.
-Right away.
Ishak, you take care
of the wounded. Hurry up!
-Get him up.
-Up.
-Be quick about it.
-Don't rock it.
Don't be rough.
How is Halime Sultan, Mother?
You have a beautiful and healthy son.
Halime is okay, too.
Go and see your wife.
Ertuğrul...
Don't get up, Halime.
Thank God you are back.
Welcome back.
Thank you.
Son.
My son.
My baby son.
You and our son have been
on my mind the entire time, Halime.
Now that I have seen you're well,
I'd die a happy man.
And I've been waiting for you
to come back, Ertuğrul.
I prayed to God to let you
see our son.
Sometimes, we must leave
our loved ones behind for the cause.
Ertuğrul, you are following God's cause.
Now that you are back alive and well,
that's good enough.
What happened?
You look sad.
Vasilius.
He found out where we were going.
We fell into his trap.
If it weren't for Ebu Mansur,
we'd have been done for.
Ebu Mansur? Who is that?
I told you before that I knew about him.
But how did it turn out like this?
Aliyar Bey...
is wounded.
He's badly hurt.
How many times has it been Nikolas?
Just how many times?
How many more times are we going to
return with dead bodies
when instead we should be
taking Ertuğrul's head?
How many times?
-Sir.
-What?
Apologies,
there is a messenger from Nicaea.
He said he had information
that he could only tell you.
A letter from the emperor for you, sir.
Leave.
God damn the emperor
and his cursed letter!
It all changed when he arrived.
We wouldn't have lost if
it weren't for him.
You could have taken...
Ertuğrul's life.
Ebu Mansur.
He's supposedly a merchant.
But his real identity is a mystery.
I don't know who he is,
but it's obvious what he is not.
He's not a merchant,
but a warrior.
Is there even a soldier here
that fights as well as him?
He's not from around here, Nikolas.
They were the sultan's men.
They're coming to take my fort.
An advance party.
There'll be more if we don't stop them.
Then, the one called Ebu Mansur
must be one of the best commanders
of the sultan.
No, more than a commander.
Someone more important
and with more power.
But who?
-We'll find out.
-How?
We don't even know where he is.
Where could a man wearing
merchant clothes stay?
At Hanlı Bazaar, of course.
Send two men after him
and watch him right away.
Read this, sir.
Sultan Alaeddin, huh?
In disguise amongst commoners.
What's the meaning of this?
We now know Ebu Mansur's identity,
that is what it means.
That man...
Is that even possible?
How brazen would he have to be?
He'd never risk his life coming
all the way here.
-You are wrong, Vasilius.
-He would.
Sultan Alaeddin
first wants to see the place
he'd like to conquer.
He has done it before.
But now,
we must make sure it's him.
But how?
Is there anyone that would recognize him?
Yes, Nikolas.
There's someone.
We are honored to have you, Your Highness.
Come.
Sit with Ebu Mansur.
Ertuğrul Bey, I wish I didn't have to
show up on such a dreary day.
How is Aliyar Bey?
He's in a bad condition, Your Highness.
I hope to God that he recovers quickly.
I hope so.
Never lose your hope.
On the other hand,
the good news is that you have a son.
I have one more son, Your Highness.
May God...
let him grow up to be a gallant warrior
such as yourself.
Amen.
Ertuğrul Bey.
What happened at the inn?
Tell me everything.
Your eye in Nicaea...
was exposed, Your Highness.
He was on the run
from the emperor's soldiers.
He had something very important
to tell you.
However,
Vasilius found him
before us and killed him.
Could you find out
what he was going to tell me?
He sent me this seal with his comrade.
Ertuğrul Bey.
There's a traitor from the government
in the Sultan's castle.
You must tell our Sultan quickly.
They tried to take my life twice.
I suspected there was
a traitor in my castle.
Now I have no more doubts.
They're attacking our country
from the east and west.
As if that wasn't enough,
we have a traitor now?
If that's how it is,
then it's dangerous
for you to be here, Your Highness.
I am the real threat here,
for my enemies, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll find out who is the traitor
in my castle, sooner or later.
However,
the real issue today is...
Karacahisar Castle.
The fate of the Turkmen Tribes
rests on your decision, Your Highness.
We tried to protect the peace
as per your orders.
However, we lost many men.
War is now inevitable.
I came here to see Karacahisar Castle
with my own eyes
and give my final decision, Ertuğrul Bey.
I've talked to many men
as Merchant Ebu Mansur
for the last five days.
My armies are preparing for war
in the east.
Before I join my armies,
I'd like to consult you,
my finest bey...
that knows these lands.
Be my guest at the marquee, Your Highness.
We must keep this secret, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'd like to stay at the inn
with the guards.
But I'm worried about
Aliyar Bey's condition.
I'll stay with your tribe tonight.
However, not at your marquee,
but in the guest tent.
I don't want to attract any attention.
Gone!
Slipped from our grasp!
Killed our brothers!
They got Aliyar Bey as well.
Aliyar Bey is still alive, Bamsi.
Don't lose hope.
If Ebu Mansur had not made it...
we would have died.
Who is that merchant?
Are you not curious?
You are right, brother.
I've never seen a merchant
that fought so well.
My brothers.
If you ask me,
he is no merchant.
He's not just clever, but strong as well.
His speaks softly, but his mind is sharp.
We spoke before the rug deal briefly.
He's both knowledgeable,
and a decent man.
Yeah.
All their shots hit the mark, too.
Apparently, trading is not
their only occupation.
They are all brave warriors.
Ertuğrul Bey was stunned
to see Ebu Mansur.
There must be an underlying reason
as to why he respects him so much.
Come on, brothers. Dress your wounds.
And then...
pray for Aliyar Bey.
Sir.
Bismillah.
Brother.
I beg you.
Artuk Bey, please tell me
that he's going to live.
He's the only one that...
holds together our tattered tribe.
If something happens to him,
all this blood...
and these tears will have been in vain.
His condition is bad, Aslıhan Hatun.
Be prepared, anything could happen.
But don't lose hope.
Aliyar Bey shielded me
with his body in the battle.
He cared about you...
much more than he cared
about himself, Ertuğrul Bey.
He wouldn't stop to think...
even if he had a thousand lives.
It's the same...
for me as well.
It's your duty
to hold your tribe together...
until he recovers and comes back,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Aliyar Bey chose you
as his representative.
Don't let all the blood spilled
be in vain.
You've been badly hurt,
and gone through a lot.
Be a leader,
and give hope to your people.
Look out for your tribe, Aslıhan Hatun.
If something happens to him,
what do we do, Ertuğrul Bey?
All our beys are dead.
Our soldiers are run-down
with all the betrayals.
The tribe's been awash with our own blood.
I'll pray to God that he doesn't take
this brave man from us.
And if it did happen...
know that...
I, Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah,
will always be on your side,
along with my tribe.
Men!
Enough of this. Why are you all sulking?
Pull yourselves together.
Even the women caring for their husbands
and mothers waiting for their sons
are stronger than you.
Snap out of it!
Turgut Commander,
you know how Aliyar Bey is.
We couldn't even
protect Ertuğrul Bey at the inn.
God forbid.
What if something happened to our bey?
I feel ashamed as an alp.
My brothers.
We all fought well.
We took down most of them.
That dog Vasilius...
turned his tail and ran, right?
Yes, indeed.
He ran away, the bastard.
To hell with him.
He ran away with his tail
between his legs like the coward he is.
Do you remember what happened
when we were taking Hafsa Hatun
to her father, the governor?
What happened?
That dog Vasilius ambushed us.
Who came to our help then?
Woah!
We're being attacked!
-For God!
For God!
Helena!
Aliyar Bey.
He came like the wind
and saved us all.
And then vanished into thin air.
Yeah. He knew what
Ural would do and was prepared.
He risked his life for us.
Who helped Ertuğrul Bey
every single time
that we were in trouble?
Aliyar Bey. He always came as a godsend.
Yes, he did, my brother.
Indeed he did.
With his sword,
he always fought bravely
beside Ertuğrul Bey,
as a worthy soldier
of our prophet Ali, right?
Yes, he did.
He did, indeed.
But if it wasn't for Ebu Mansur
we'd be in trouble.
Yes, if it weren't for him,
both tribes would be left without a bey.
Right. Then, how could we have explained
it to our bey and Aslıhan Hatun?
However, my brothers,
just as Aliyar Bey reached out for us,
Ebu Mansur came as a godsend, too.
Now you are talking, brother.
Ebu Mansur came just in time, thank God!
God did not leave us alone on the path
of Ertuğrul Bey's cause, again.
Right, brother.
In the past, it was Aliyar Bey.
And now it was Ebu Mansur.
We got one step closer
to his cause, brothers.
With God's permission,
we have nothing to be
ashamed of as alps.
Turgut is right, my men.
From now on,
we can't be upset by such things.
Now what befalls us is to take revenge.
Our revenge will be so brutal
that even the soil will spit back
the blood of those bastards.
They will not find a place
to rest their dead bodies.
The arrow
has already left the bow.
Unless we find that dog Vasilius,
and avenge our brother Doğan,
as well as the blood
of all the other men we lost,
we can't stop. Understand?
May we never stop until
we take their revenge.
Brothers, this will be such a war
that with Ertuğrul Bey on our right,
and Aliyar Bey on our left,
we will make the heavens tremble
with the sound of our swords.
This will be such a war that
our dead will rise
from their graves in respect.
Our brother Doğan
will fight alongside us, brothers.
God bless you all!
Allahu akbar!
Ekaterina, it's me.
We must talk.
Come in, Vasilius.
Now that you are home,
you look even more dazzling.
We age too fast, Vasilius.
Time flies away.
And we are still empty-handed.
That's not true at all.
What happened?
Aliyar.
Is he dead or what?
Maybe not, but he won't live long
with those wounds.
Ertuğrul was supposed to share his fate,
but somebody turned up
and saved him along with his men.
Who was it?
It's on you to find out who.
Ural...
said you went to Konya
with him some time ago.
Did you see Sultan Alaeddin then?
What does Sultan Alaeddin have to do
with this?
Did you or did you not?
It's true that I went to Konya
with Candar Bey and Ural Bey.
We attended the circumcision feast
of the Sultan's son,
Izzettin Kilij Arslan.
I saw him there once.
We are together...
in this great task,
for our great cause, right, Ekaterina?
There's something I need you to do.
You must go to the Public Market.
Disguise yourself and notice
who comes and goes.
You must find someone called Ebu Mansur.
See if that Ebu Mansur is
Sultan Alaeddin.
Is he here?
I hope he is, Ekaterina.
If so, we'll get rid of
a lot of our troubles.
Only you can do this job.
And I presume
it won't prove too hard for you.
Leave it to me, Vasilius.
I'll do anything for revenge.
Anything at all.
That's what I'm afraid of, Ekaterina.
Don't be like me.
Control your anger.
You have yet to see
your worst fears, Vasilius.
And your worst nightmare.
I'm done for.
I'm done for, Hafsa Hatun.
Your wound isn't too deep, Bamsi.
But maybe you should have
Artuk Bey check it.
No, I don't mean that, Hafsa Hatun.
It's the treacherous enemy
that disturbs me,
not this small wound.
I wish
that disgusting Vasilius
had hurt me and not Aliyar Bey.
God willing, Aliyar Bey
will return to his tribe safe and sound.
God will not let Vasilius go unpunished,
with all that he's done.
You will take revenge for all of us,
with Ertuğrul Bey.
I hope so, Hafsa Hatun.
Bamsi, you are the hope
of all those oppressed in this land.
My people will be on our side, too.
However,
we must first take
that dog's head, just like Ural.
Sooner or later,
he will pay for what he did.
May God
let me live till the day
I see him get what he deserves.
Hafsa Hatun.
Amen, my love.
I can see the anger in your eyes just
as I can feel your pain, Ertuğrul Bey.
Vasilius used Ural to stain
the Cavdar tribe with blood.
He lured many of the Turk tribes'
bravest warriors to his cause.
And now, Aliyar...
He must be avenged, my sultan.
Taking Vasilius' head
or Karacahisar Castle
would not prove difficult for our army.
But if I take the castle,
both the Crusaders
and the emperor will get involved.
As I have understood,
from my discussions
with the people when I was going
by the name of Ebu Mansur,
you've managed to conquer the hearts
of both Muslims and non-Muslims alike.
I have upheld the duty bestowed
upon us by God, my Sultan.
I have carried out
your orders for our state.
I know you want to secure
the western border, my sultan.
When you have gone to war,
we will carry out your orders
and keep this area secure.
Speak frankly, Ertuğrul Bey.
We're capable of taking Karacahisar Castle
and sending Vasilius' head to the emperor.
You need only believe in
the unity of the Turkish beys
as you believe in me.
You're telling me you can take
Karacahisar without an army?
Not only can we take it, my sultan,
we can keep the land surrounding
it secure afterwards too.
I know the weaknesses
of the emperor in Nicaea.
I'm also aware of the greed
of the Latins in Constantinople.
Do you think you can manage to keep
the peace with only your alps?
We've been training our alps
like an army for some time now.
I have my best alps training them.
Not a day goes by without them training.
The emperor has sent his best men
to drive us from these lands.
You managed to kill them all
and enter the castle.
You rescued your brother Dündar
from the hands of Vasilius.
More have been sent, elite soldiers.
Their intention is obvious, my sultan.
But I am still convinced
I can take Karacahisar Castle.
My brave warrior...
He won't be long now.
When he comes with that
beautiful face...
I'll see you once again.
May I come in?
Of course, Mother.
No, no, sit down. Sit down.
I wanted to see you before I went to bed.
How are you?
I'm fine, thank you, Mother.
Halime Sultan has had her baby.
I have everything I need.
At last.
Soon you too will have your baby
in your arms, God willing.
Doğan's child will run around and play
with my own grandchildren one day.
He'll ride horses
and wield swords, God willing.
God willing, Mother.
They will be alps worthy of their fathers,
and of their ancestors.
God willing.
I hope he'll be born soon.
I want to entrust Doğan's
child to you and Ertuğrul Bey.
What do you mean by that, Banu Çiçek?
We set out to claim these lands
for our children, Mother Hayme.
We lost so many along the way.
Doğan was martyred close to Ertuğrul Bey.
Aliyar Bey fights for his life.
Those who are holding swords
will consider martyrdom in this fight.
The motherland awaits us.
Man or woman, it doesn't matter.
-Daughter, now you--
-My child is for you,
my life is for God,
and my sword is for Ertuğrul Bey
to look after, Mother.
I don't want other mothers to cry,
so until Karacahisar Castle
comes down on Vasilius
I won't so much as smell my child.
Look, dear...
Doğan left you in our care.
Doğan was my son.
And you're my daughter.
I think of you and Halime the same way.
Ertuğrul will make Vasilius pay,
one way or another.
But your duty...
is to look after your child.
My mother.
Brother.
You were away from us for so long.
Even when you came home you couldn't rest.
You protected me after Father died.
If you go too, I won't have anybody.
Please don't leave me.
Artuk Bey, his hand moved!
God the healer! God the healer!
Aliyar Bey, can you hear me?
Sister.
Brother!
Call Ertuğrul Bey for me.
-Ishak, get Ertuğrul Bey here, quickly.
-Right away.
At last. Praise God.
Vasilius has spent a lot of time
fortifying the castle walls.
He's preparing it for war.
But all he's done is wall himself in
with the anger he feels for me.
Any reputation he had among his own
people has been tarnished and lost.
With patience and cunning,
I can take the head of Vasilius,
trapped as he is
by his own rage and folly.
I'll raise our glorious flag
above the walls of Karacahisar Castle.
You can leave with your army
and with your mind at ease, my sultan.
May I enter?
Go on.
Ertuğrul Bey, do we have
your permission to enter?
Come in, Mother.
We wanted to show
our gratitude to Ebu Mansur.
I am humbled.
We were just passing by.
You saved our men. God bless you.
Thank you. What are their names?
My eldest son is Gündüz.
We haven't named the baby yet.
My father, Suleyman Shah,
wanted him to be called Savci.
But I'd like you to name him.
I would be honored.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
There is no god but God.
Muhammad is the Messenger of God.
Hasten to the prayer.
Hasten to the salvation.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
God is the only god.
Your name is Savci.
Your ancestor Suleyman Shah gave you
your name. God grant you a long life.
-Amen.
Amen.
May the angels above...
and the servants below
know that from now on...
your name is Savci.
-May I enter, my bey?
-Come in, Ishak.
-Salaam-Alaikum.
-Alaikum-Salaam.
My bey, Aliyar Bey is awake.
He wants to see you.
At last!
At last.
Allahu akbar.
Peace of God be upon you.
I lived as a traveler in this world.
Thank God that my fate was to...
be martyred fighting for his cause.
Brother!
Brother...
Ertuğrul Bey...
Aliyar Bey?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Come closer.
Let me see you one last time.
There's something I must say.
Don't waste your energy, Aliyar Bey.
It's time to leave this life...
behind, Ertuğrul Bey.
My sister and my tribe...
are yours to look after.
You have to take Karacahisar...
and avenge our...
fallen warriors.
Ertuğrul Bey...
Give me your blessing.
Aliyar Bey...
I'm so glad to have been able to fight
by the side of a warrior like you.
I'll continue down our path,
never resting.
Both your will and your requests
are written on my heart.
But don't give up.
Don't leave me alone on this journey.
You'll be all right.
Brother! Brother!
Artuk Bey! Artuk Bey, help him!
Brother, no!
There is no god but God...
and Muhammad is the Messenger...
and the servant of God.
Oh God.
No! Brother, please!
No! No!
No!
We have delivered to your peace
our warriors who died
for our faith and country.
Give them peace, God.
Grant your people patience, God.
Heal our wounded quickly, God.
Deliver us from all kinds of enemies,
within or beyond,
who would disturb our faith,
state and nation.
Grant victory to our noble resistance
as it fights for justice
and righteousness, God.
For the sake of our martyrs
please accept our prayers.
Grant them safe passage to heaven, God.
You grant justice.
You are the all-powerful.
Amen. Amen.
Ve selamun alel murselin
velhamdulillahi rabbil alemin.
Al Fatiha.
Salaam-Alaikum, sir.
Alaikum-Salaam.
Ertuğrul Bey awaits you.
Let's go, Abdurrahman.
Let us carry out our last
duty to our martyrs.
Mother.
I'll come too.
-Daughter.
-I must be there for Aslıhan.
Brother.
You were my life.
You were more than my life.
My brave brother.
Avenge my brother, Ertuğrul Bey.
The alps of my tribe
are at your command.
As am I.
I swear that I will drown Vasilius
in the blood of our martyrs.
Look after the Cavdar tribe,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Stay strong.
Stay strong so that the people
and the alps can share in your strength.
Now...
it's time to unite to carry out
Aliyar Bey's final wishes.
Brother.
Aliyar Bey...
is with God, my sultan.
May he rest in peace.
Amen.
You didn't hesitate to risk
your lives for my state.
You lost many.
Aliyar Bey has also
been martyred for my state.
I must avenge him, Ertuğrul Bey.
The emperor is the snake
and Vasilius is its venom.
The head of the snake must be cut off.
We would gladly sacrifice our lives
for our state, my sultan.
Your words and what I have seen of you,
what I know of your deeds in these lands,
have already convinced me, Ertuğrul Bey.
You succeeded in uniting
the Turk tribes.
This united force must
now take Karacahisar.
Call a council before I return to Konya.
I want to see the beys myself
so that I may declare you their leader.
I know that you will avenge our martyrs.
When Karacahisar is conquered,
I will grant you these lands.
The territory of the glorious Kayi
will be a land of justice
for Turk tribes and non-Muslims alike.
May God not give you shame
in this endeavor.
Amen.
The Quran will be our guide,
Alaeddin Keykubat Khan, our sultan,
and Oghuz Han, our ancestor.
May Allah help and protect us.
Our lives are lived for your state.
May God not give us shame
before our martyrs.
Ertuğrul , Aliyar, Aslıhan.
Let me see the day they all die, God.
Let me accomplish my final duty
in this castle in which I'm entombed.
Let me kill that dog, Vasilius.
May my hands be covered
with his dirty blood.
After that, even hell will be
heaven for me.
-Salaam-Alaikum.
-Alaikum-Salaam.
Alaikum-Salaam.
Al Fatiha, for the soul of our martyr.
I seek refuge in God from
the cursed Satan.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Our prophet says that
seeing the angel of death is worse than
being pierced by a thousand swords.
But there is no death for believers.
Death is merely a migration for them.
And when a believer is martyred
he will not be questioned.
We all knew Aliyar Bey when he was alive.
We are all witness to the fact that
he was a good Muslim and a fair Bey.
May God grant us martyrdom,
may he allow us to
give our lives for him.
Amen.
-Amen.
If a land is to be a motherland,
it needs sacrifice.
Our sacrifice is the blood
of our many martyrs.
God, do not let the descendants
of the martyrs who settled here
leave your path.
-Amen.
Amen.
Make our descendants responsible,
and make them good Muslims.
Amen.
-Amen.
I'm ready to go.
You were wasted on the Turks, Ekaterina.
I'll be whoever I want to be.
I'm doing what's necessary.
You're doing even more.
You're going to find out
who Ebu Mansur is.
And if he's Alaeddin?
Then we'll have a treasure.
-Sir.
-Speak.
I have news that you should hear.
Speak!
Our scouts say a convoy left
the Kayi tribe for the Cavdar tribe.
They're transporting a coffin on a cart.
I told you he wouldn't live long.
May you suffer, Aliyar.
This is only a fraction of the pain
we're going to make them feel, Ekaterina.
A fraction.
I won't stop until there's nobody
left to mourn them.
That cart will not stay empty.
One will die before another is mourned.
-You're so--
-So angry, Vasilius.
I refuse to show mercy
to anyone who has hurt me.
Get on with it, then.
Allahu akbar.
There is no god but God.
Allahu akbar. There is no god but God.
Welcome, emir.
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
Aliyar Bey has died.
They went to the Cavdar tribe to bury him.
We're going to the Cavdar tribe.
God is great. God is great.
There is no god but God.
May you rest in heaven.
-We won't forget him.
-Rest in peace.
Rest in peace, Aliyar Bey,
rest in peace, Aliyar Bey.
God bless you.
Honorable men, women and warriors
of the Cavdar tribe.
Aliyar Bey
led his life honorably,
for his faith, integrity and tribe.
He did not hesitate to give his life...
as a brave warrior should.
He has left behind much wisdom
which will illuminate your path.
It is yours now.
Do not forget him.
It's up to you to keep his memory alive.
Remember him.
Do not tarnish his memory.
He was your Bey and my brother.
A mother, a father.
He was a great man who would
shoulder any burden asked of him.
My brother has done
his work in this world.
And he now rests in peace.
It is our duty to continue that work.
We will stand tall.
We will protect our tribe, our honor
and our traditions as he would have done.
Our mourning will be short
but our pain will never fade.
Let it be known that our tribe
will not remain leaderless.
Until a new Bey is elected,
I will uphold my brother's legacy.
We came from God
and we will return to him.
Yes?
Sir, Ekaterina managed
to get a message to our soldiers.
Tell me.
Emir Sadettin was at Hanli bazaar.
But he left quickly.
Emir Sadettin?
So you came, Emir Sadettin.
We're not quite done with you yet.
They've made their intentions
obvious by coming one by one.
War.
I'll give you a most bloody war.
My condolences.
-Thank you, Emir.
God bless you, Emir.
I seek refuge in God
from the cursed Satan.
In the name of God.
To the prayers for God.
To witness his Messenger.
To pray for the deceased.
God is great.
Peace of God be upon you.
Did you give your blessings to Aliyar Bey?
Bless him!
Did you?
-And God bless you.
-Amen.
Mother, where is my brother?
He's asleep, Gunduz, be quiet.
The baby looks nothing like me.
Dear boy, come here.
You looked like that too when you
were a baby. Then you grew up.
You became a big brother.
He's only a baby right now.
You've to look after
your brother from now on.
I'm training the alps,
I can't look after him.
You're right, I know.
And you're training them really well.
Put your brother among the alps too,
so that you can both serve
in the ranks of your father.
As long as he swears fealty to me.
Come here. My little bey.
Son of the bey of the beys.
Uncle Alaeddin?
Halime Hatun?
Are you well?
You were far away, what happened?
No, I'm fine.
I just remembered something.
You're tired.
Go and rest. I'll look after the baby.
Thank you, Hafsa.
But I'm fine, don't worry.
He loved to learn.
He didn't see mother or father.
Only knowledge. Only school.
He spent most of his life far away.
When he came back home,
he left this world quickly.
Daughter, we all came from God
and we'll all return to him.
Aliyar Bey went straight to heaven,
according to Islamic ethics.
No doubt about that, Mother Hayme.
I'll walk in his footsteps from now on.
I'll look after his legacy.
I'll stand tall at the head of my tribe.
His friends are my friends,
his enemies are my enemies.
That's my daughter.
We'll always support you.
Ertugrul is your brother too, from now on.
And Halime your sister.
If you agree...
please think of me
as your mother, daughter.
My sweet daughter. My sweet daughter.
God bless you.
Don't ever leave us, Mother.
The day I met Aliyar Bey,
I saw what a big heart he had.
Ertugrul Bey managed
to unite the Turk tribes,
thanks to Aliyar Bey.
May he rest in peace.
I know I'm not alone
thanks to you and Ertugrul Bey.
My tribe and our honor are yours.
May I come in?
Please come in, Emir.
I'm so sorry for your loss, dear.
I'll leave you alone.
Please do.
Hayme Hatun.
Bismillah.
Sit down, Aslihan. Sit down.
My condolences.
May God grant you patience.
Even through all this pain,
you still manage to stand tall.
This is a great comfort to me.
The way you conducted yourself
when that traitor Ural returned
showed me how brave you are, but I
saw today how strong you are too.
Ural is where he belongs, Emir.
As for Aliyar Bey,
he gave his authority of the tribe to me.
Of course, of course.
You should perform this duty
until the council elects a new Bey.
I don't intend to abandon my tribe
after the council has voted.
The Cavdar tribe will always be my home.
Do you realise
what you're saying, Aslihan?
I do, Emir.
When I agreed to be your wife
to satisfy my father's wishes,
I had two brothers.
I trusted them.
Now one is martyred, the other killed.
I won't leave my tribe until
my brother is avenged.
Know that I would die for my tribe too.
Pain has dulled your senses,
Aslihan Hatun.
You promised to be my wife
and dedicate your life to me.
You promised. Remember that.
Forgive me, Emir. My decision is final.
What makes you think you, a woman,
is capable of leading your tribe?
If Mother Hayme has done it before,
so I am capable of doing it now.
And I will have Ertugrul Bey by my side.
Ertugrul.
Ertugrul?
My decision is final.
A glorious Emir like you will easily find
a more suitable woman than me.
Now, if you'll allow me,
I'd like to mourn my brother in peace,
at least for a day.
It is my priority now to discuss
with Ertugrul Bey by what means
he and I can avenge my brother.
I know you are speaking out of grief.
The pain will lessen with time.
You'll see the mistake you've made.
I'll wait for you, Aslihan.
No matter how long it takes. I'll wait.
You'll see.
Excuse me.
If Ebu Mansur really is Sultan Alaeddin,
you can see now how Ekaterina
could change the fate of our country,
can't you Nikolas?
I don't doubt it.
Ekaterina is capable of securing
you a great victory.
I'm so pleased Ekaterina
has found the right path.
You revived a woman left without hope.
Her only mistake was believing in a Turk.
She has found the holy path now.
Smart woman.
Smart women can be dangerous.
I know that only too well, Nikolas.
Only too well.
That's why I keep her close.
You could keep her closer.
She's of noble birth.
When the day comes, she'd be worthy
of a governor set to become emperor.
-Greetings.
Greetings, brothers.
I'm sorry for your loss, brother.
Sorry for your loss, brothers.
-Thank you.
-Thank you both.
Come, sit.
Brothers.
Candar Bey is gone.
The dog Ural Bey is also gone.
Our beys lie slaughtered.
Now, we are alone.
The great Cavdar tribe is leaderless.
It'll be very hard for us to regroup.
Brother...
Brothers...
We are as one.
Aliyar Bey was our bey as well.
Ertugrul Bey is our bey. Don't lose hope.
It's more complicated
than that, Bamsi Alp.
The bey of a tribe is its everything.
A beyless tribe cannot be.
-Greetings, Alps.
-Greetings.
Sir, you honor us.
Please.
Death brings joy to the deceased,
but pain to those left behind.
However, there should be
no sadness for martyrs.
Sir, we purged out tribe of traitors
and we stood united,
we had peace.
But now our bey and leader is gone.
What do we do now?
My children...
All this wasn't created in a day.
A great cause requires great sacrifice.
In the first years of Islam
we lost many of our leaders.
The Battles of Badr and Uhud,
and the Battle of the Trench.
Many people like Hamza,
Ja’far ibn Abi Talib, Ammar ibn Yasir,
and Yasir ibn Amir
were martyred for the cause.
War and death never ceased.
You have accepted the jihad for God
as a pillar of Islam.
But, do not forget this.
The distance the arrow travels
depends on how far it is pulled back.
Every time the enemy attacks you
and causes you pain,
you become stronger.
Our Prophet, peace be upon him,
when he passed away,
some Muslims lost hope.
Asap couldn't believe he had died,
he couldn't take on the responsibility.
But the cause of God had to go on,
the banner of Islam
still had to be carried.
So, Abu Bakr went to our prophet,
covered his face,
and faced the companions.
Abu Bakr said that,
whoever believes in Muhammad,
peace be upon him,
know that he's in heaven.
Whoever prays to and serves God,
know that God is immortal.
Then he recited these verses from
the surah Ali Imran.
"Muhammad is but a messenger.
Other messengers have
passed on before him.
So if he was to die or be killed...
would you turn back
and no longer believe?
He who turns back...
cannot harm God.
But God will reward the grateful."
Ashap was shaken by these words
and they regained hope.
They adopted the cause of Islam.
So Islam was spread throughout the world.
Gave hope to innocents, fear to tyrants.
Holy God has said in the surah Ali Imran,
"So, do not weaken.
Do not grieve.
And you will be superior
if you are true believers."
We need brave men like Ali
and those who will uphold his legacy,
like Hussein.
The Ummah awaits salvation.
Humanity awaits service.
Now, you must fight for tomorrow.
Yesterday you were led by Aliyar Bey.
Today, by Ertugrul Bey.
Now, you must...
keep the cause of your Bey alive,
unite and follow the path of the union.
Mother, welcome.
Thank you, dear.
Is he asleep? God bless him.
We carried out our last duty.
Aliyar was like a son to me.
Seeing him with Ertugrul
used to make me so happy.
He was a brother to Ertugrul
and a son to me.
Death only brings joy
to the martyr, Mother.
But it's hard on the ones left behind.
This sad heart has said
goodbye to many warriors.
Now I realize that...
Aliyar had a special place in my heart.
Death is inevitable.
Aliyar Bey was blessed with martyrdom.
You're right, dear. You're right.
-May God grant him rest.
-Amen.
Mother, was Ebu Mansur at the funeral?
He was, dear.
Ertugrul never left his side.
Do you still doubt him?
Mother, this Ebu Mansur is no
ordinary merchant.
I've remembered who he is.
Who is he?
Sultan Alaeddin.
Do you know what you're saying, Halime?
-Are you sure?
-Yes, Mother, I'm sure.
I saw Uncle Alaeddin
before he became Sultan.
That's how I know.
Were you expecting Emir Sadettin,
my Sultan?
No.
But it's good he's here.
He should know of my decision
concerning your new duty.
When I return, I'll leave
Sadettin here to support you.
My Sultan.
What brings you here, Sadettin?
My marriage to Aslihan Hatun, my Sultan.
But her father's death,
and now Aliyar Bey...
It's good that you're here.
That you came in time
for Aliyar Bey's funeral.
Also, after talking over some
matters with Ertugrul Bey,
I've come to a decision.
A decision you should be told about.
I hope it's good news, my Sultan.
Ertugrul Bey is now
the chief Bey of my state.
He will govern these lands.
It's an honor for me to serve
my state and nation, my Sultan.