Episode 85 will start after 12:30 min.
They welcome us.
We will respond
in the language they understand.
Where is Commander Angelos?
Who are you?
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
God is life!
Dumrul, take us to the dungeon!
Turgut!
Come with me.
Abdurrahman, come with me.
Aliyar, the courtyard is yours.
Aliyar Bey!
God is life!
Stake out the area.
Make sure it's safe.
Go.
Now is the time, Bamsı.
Let's attack.
Cihan...
which of you...
Which of you burns up inside like me?
We'll wait.
We'll wait, brother.
Let them spread out like cattle...
then we'll hunt them
while they're off guard.
I'll save you, Helena.
I'll save you from them.
Archers to the wall.
Don't let any of them into the courtyard.
Come on my brave men.
We'll make hell of this courtyard.
-God is great!
God is great!
Which way, Dumrul?
Didn't you memorize the way?
I saw some drunken soldiers
and they taught me the way, my bey.
We go this way.
Good.
Come on now.
Come and we'll see how thick your neck is.
What's that noise?
There is a battle outside.
Do they train?
Train?
The infidel's sword is only pulled out
in fear of his life.
If the men are afraid in their own fort,
that isn't good news.
Ertuğrul Bey.
He raids the fort.
Don't come out.
What are you talking about?
How can Ertuğrul raid the fort
in broad daylight?
They slaughtered
the secret military unit from Nicaea.
They entered in disguise.
Let go of me.
How did Ertuğrul...
know about the secret military unit?
Keep this door locked.
No matter what happens
don't open it, understand?
I know why Ertuğrul is here.
Ural! Don't do it, Ural!
They'll kill you too.
I will not give up Dündar.
I'll kill them both.
Move aside hatun, move!
-I'm going to take a walk.
-Let me accompany you.
-Ne need, I want to be alone.
-But, my lady...
I said no need.
What don't you understand?
-We can't let her go alone.
-I'll go after her.
You follow.
Some of you stay here.
You come too.
Helena is making her way to us.
Leave the jackals with her to me.
You take care of the bastards here.
Come on alps, come on brothers.
Come on brothers.
Raid, run!
Run!
So, they sent me a dog like you...
So, you want to be my Azrael...
My bey, this way!
I'm here brother.
Don't let them near the prisoner.
Kill them.
I'm here, my bey!
Dündar, are you hurt?
Why did you come here?
I should have died here.
Dündar, you should know that
we never leave our men behind.
So many died for my sake, brother.
I don't deserve to live.
This is no time to be
feeling sorry for yourself.
We will settle this back at the tribe.
-Sir!
-Take Dündar away.
There are too many, sir.
Do as I say, Dumrul!
Sir!
-Where's the prisoner?
-They took him away.
Don't let them escape!
Follow them!
Come on, sir.
Dündar.
Are you all right, brother?
I betrayed my brother.
I should have died.
Head for the drain in the wall.
Come on, sir.
Ertuğrul!
I know where they are.
Follow me.
This way, sir.
Wounded first. Hurry!
Vasilius must be close, sir.
He should be here any minute now.
If Bamsi managed to get
Helena out as well,
we will bury Vasilius
alive in his fort, sir.
The next time I come here,
I'll raise our flag, Turgut.
And hang his lifeless body
on the walls of this fort.
I hope so, sir.
Come on, sir.
Once I get to the camp,
I'll behead Acar and his daughter.
It won't soothe our pain,
but there will be fewer scumbags
on this earth.
I'd like to execute them
at my tribe to make an example
of them, Aliyar Bey.
Bring them to me, along with Teo.
Well said, sir. Let's do that.
Sir, you go on ahead.
I'll close the hole and catch up to you.
All right, Turgut.
Helena!
Where are you?
Answer me!
Helena!
Miss, why are you running
away from us? Why are you here?
You insolent fool!
Stop pestering her!
Bamsi!
Come at me!
I knew you'd come.
Helena, hold on.
Hold on.
Wait, what are you doing?
How could I leave you
to the hands of these savages?
How could I let you marry that bastard?
I can't thank you enough.
Once more you saved my life, Bamsi.
No, don't mention it.
However,
I wish
I could have saved
my brother Doğan's life as well.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I appreciate it, Helena.
Thank God you are alive.
-What about Dündar Bey?
-Oh, yes.
Don't worry,
Ertuğrul Bey went to save him.
He will definitely get him back.
My brothers!
Let's go back to our tribe, come on!
Helena, let's go.
Come with me.
God damn!
They got away.
Quick, follow them.
Quick! Find them
before they get your governor.
They closed off the hole with a rock.
What do you mean?
We can't follow them from here.
Where does this tunnel go?
To the other end of the fort.
We can't catch up.
Ertuğrul.
I'll obliterate you all.
Your mother,
your wife,
your children...
I'll make you watch them die.
I'll kill you all!
God.
Help my children and make it...
easy for them.
Grant them victory.
Please, protect my children.
Mother.
Since you won't come inside,
take this cushion.
Here.
Thanks, dear.
How hard it is to wait on tenterhooks.
I'm just too anxious, Mother.
Your son
is with you right now.
Once he grows up,
flourishes,
and starts riding his horse,
you will then understand
what it means to be a mother.
You will know the grief
and fear of losing a child.
That stud
will kick not the ground, but
your very heart.
You will keep your mouth closed
and watch...
as your son bolts out to war.
I have lived all this, dear.
I did.
I'm a mother.
I sealed my lips.
My pain doesn't seep out.
However, I'm dying inside.
May God
protect our children
from ever parting ways.
Amen.
How is Banu Çiçek holding up?
Are you checking on her?
She's the same, Mother.
Brought her food, didn't touch it.
No.
That's not good.
She's still pregnant,
she'll hurt the baby.
You have to make sure she eats something.
Banu Çiçek may grieve today,
but she'll let it pass tomorrow.
God has blessed her
with the patience of a mother.
The real issue is Dündar.
It's Dündar that keeps me
brooding over.
The thought of my sons
arguing with each other
is eating away at my heart.
What if Ertuğrul doesn't forgive Dündar?
Help me for the love of God.
I'm dying.
Commander...
Commander!
How did this happen?
How did they get in?
They came in disguised as our soldiers.
Your regent thought they were
the unit sent from Nicaea,
and welcomed them with military honors.
A fort that embraces its enemies.
A fort that doesn't
know its enemies!
A fort that's full of soldiers
cut down as the clumsy cowards they are!
What's this fort?
What kind of empire is this?
Where is the regent commander?
He died, sir.
We followed them to the drain hole.
But they got away.
Ertuğrul!
Damn you!
Wherever you are, to hell with you!
They won't run again, Vasilius.
They won't run again.
Damn!
God damn!
For once...
Be damned!
Why is it always me?
Why?
Be damned!
God...
I am stuck in this dead end,
so I'm begging you...
spare me my children.
Grant my children
that I relinquished for jihad
with victory.
Please God, help us.
Mother Hayme!
May I enter?
Bamsi.
Bamsi!
Mother.
I brought you a guest.
We have a guest.
Come in, Helena.
Mother Hayme, would you accept
this unexpected visitor?
Welcome, my dear.
I can't thank you enough.
You saved me from that monster.
I'm happy to see you here
safe and sound, my dear.
I'm so sorry
for Foreman Haçaturyan and Doğan Alp.
With all my heart, I believe
that Ertuğrul Bey will save Dündar Bey.
Of course, my dear.
He will.
He'll make them pay
for all they have done.
Vasilius and that Ural,
blinded by their ambitions,
are the only ones responsible.
My dear.
There's a time for everything.
But you should rest now.
You went through a lot.
You are our family now.
If you so wish,
this could be your permanent home.
I have no one else left
other than you, Mother Hayme.
This tribe is my home.
Vasilius.
Where is my cousin Helena?
Why didn't you bring her here?
I sent my men after her,
they should be here soon.
At this point I just hope she is okay.
She will be okay.
Sir.
This man
has something to tell you.
Sir...
Helena is...
What about Helena?
The Turks, sir.
They attacked us at the place
while we were waiting with Helena.
And?
They took her, sir.
Helena fled from us.
She went with the Turks of her own accord.
Everyone but me died, sir.
I got here as fast as I could to tell you.
By Gods, sir, don't kill me please.
A commander dropped his sword.
Helena...
So, you were the traitor, then?
From the very beginning...
it was you.
Traitor.
Since the very beginning... it was you?
A traitor?
You were the...
traitor?
Since the beginning...
you were the traitor?
You?
You were the traitor?
Since...
the very beginning?
Traitor.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Mother.
Our men are on their way.
God.
Hear my prayers.
Don't make me go through
the pain of losing a child again.
Bismillah.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Mother.
Thank God!
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Mother.
Son!
Son.
Thank God!
Now that you got him safely back,
I couldn't be happier, son.
You brought hope to our marquee.
Thank God for
giving me a son like you.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Mother.
Forgive me, sister.
Forgive me.
When Doğan's body
is cold as snowy peaks,
and he's lying under the ground,
would it ever be possible
for Doğan to see his child?
Would it ever be possible for him
to come back to my tent again?
Tell me, Dündar Bey.
What do you want to hear?
Brave men of Kayi!
Sisters and brothers that
without a second thought,
sent their sons and husbands to war
for our cause.
We brought victory to our tribe.
Thank God
there were no martyrs today.
However,
we are still grief-stricken.
We won't stop until
we raise our flags in Karacahisar,
or possibly,
until we collapse that viper's nest
around our enemies.
May God
help us prevail in our cause,
or possibly, grant us martyrdom.
Amen!
Allahu akbar!
The ignoble bey
of my noble tribe, Acar.
I have good news for you.
We saved Dündar Bey.
You know what's left now?
You and your betrayal.
I betrayed no one.
Your daughter Günyeli
confessed everything.
Told me everything you plotted together.
She told me how you rushed
to tell Ural about Dündar Bey.
Lies.
Just how much did you torture her
to convince her to side with you?
My daughter would never
say something like that.
You are a cruel man, Aliyar Bey.
A cruel man.
Acar.
You'll die tomorrow.
Kutluca!
Now that I know
both my sons are alive...
this old woman can die in peace.
God bless you, son.
Amen, Mother.
My dear son.
How could they hurt you?
How on earth did this
happen to you, Dündar?
I deserved it, Mother.
I deserved it.
I made a mistake.
And I was paid back in kind.
Doğan Alp died because of me.
I can't redeem myself.
I didn't listen to Halime.
I didn't listen to my big brother.
Sir, may I enter?
Come in, Bamsi.
Sir.
Welcome, Helena.
Happy to see you here.
I appreciate all that you've
done for me, Ertuğrul Bey.
You were entrusted to us, Helena.
We couldn't let you marry
someone you hate.
Just tell us.
We will take you wherever you want.
I feel at home here.
I'd like to stay here if you'd let me.
If that's what you want,
then this is your tribe now.
Your home.
And you are my sister.
My mother is your mother.
Consider Halime as your sister.
Governor Vasilius.
What's this silence about?
What?
Are you giving up already?
She sold me out.
She crossed me.
She ran off with the Turks.
She ran off with the enemy...
With the backstabbers...
Vasilius, calm your nerves.
You are overlooking something.
The unit coming from Nicaea.
Helena must have told Ertuğrul
that they were on the way.
Maybe it's better that she ran away.
I didn't tell Helena
there was a unit coming here.
Then, just like how you have spies here,
there must be spies in the castle
of your emperor in Nicaea.
I know, Ural.
They are everywhere!
Damn it!
I just want to split
all the traitors in two!
I want their blood.
I want to skin them alive.
They probably acted against you
in the hope that you'd retaliate.
You won't go after them.
Now is my time to shine.
Your desire for blood will be satisfied.
Everything is ready.
I've organized the other beys.
They will hold off Ertuğrul and Aliyar
at the inn
under the pretense of a meeting.
And I'll go take back my tribe.
-And then...
-And then what?
And then I'll deal with
Ertuğrul and Aliyar.
And of course, Helena.
Once I get back my tribe,
I'll kill Aliyar
along with Ertuğrul first,
and then deal with Helena.
Then, do as you like.
Bring Helena to me.
Everything is planned, but...
But what?
What is it, Ural?
If there happens to be unexpected
resistance from the tribe,
I'll need your men to support me.
I trust my beys and soldiers.
However, I'd like to make sure...
it will all go smoothly.
I just want to know
that I have your support.
Go and reclaim your tribe.
You have my full support.
Go.
I heard Günyeli Hatun snitched.
If Acar Bey talks as well,
Aliyar Bey will cut us all down.
This can't go on.
We trusted Ural Bey.
We have been waiting
in fear for so long.
How long is it going to keep going?
Why don't we end this already?
Are we waiting for Ertuğrul
to execute us all?
-May I enter?
-Come in.
I brought a letter from Ural Bey.
What does it say?
"I know you have been waiting
for a long time for this,
but the moment has come for slaughter.
With the sunrise, bathe in the blood
of those who have dared
tarnish the honor of my tribe."
Slaughter?
Are we going to revolt?
He wants us to unite with
the other Turkmen beys
and slaughter everyone
once he lures
Ertuğrul and Aliyar Bey
to the Hanlı Bazaar.
He says we'll blindside them
when they have no leaders.
What if we botch it?
What if Acar Bey snitches on us?
Then we won't wait until sunrise
and we'll fight
till our dying breaths.
Acar Bey is an honorable man.
He won't die an ignoble death
by snitching on us.
Go sharpen your swords
instead of whining like a dog.
Did you forget for what cause
we devoted ourselves?
Ural Bey is right.
We must unite now
and take what's rightfully ours.
We will take what's ours.
Whatever Ural Bey says in his letter,
we will follow his instruction.
Your brother trusted you with his life
and you let him down, Dündar.
You let Doğan die because of
your fantasies about that woman.
Doğan, who was always so brave...
Big brother.
Everything you say
is true.
I wish you'd left me at the fort
-so I could just die.
-No!
Don't say that.
For God's sake.
You are my brother, Dündar.
How could I let them kill you?
Two wrongs don't make a right.
Your conscience will be your judge.
You're yet to realize
the importance of our cause.
You don't realize your responsibilities
as a bey.
You showed weakness and put us
through worse hell than our enemies have.
Enough, son.
Say no more.
I can't bear seeing you two like this.
This pain wrecked us all.
I've had enough.
He's right, though, Mother.
I don't deserve to be a bey for my tribe.
I've done more harm than good.
I have no excuses.
-In the future--
-You have no future here, Dündar.
We can't show weakness in our cause,
we need real men.
You may be my brother.
But from now on,
you are not a bey, nor an alp
of our tribe.
Here, sit.
My God.
Don't test me with my children.
Help me, God.
Help me bear this pain.
Please.
Mother, be patient.
Turgut.
Brother.
I see Doğan
as I look at the food.
You mean the fried meat?
Sure, why not?
Fried meat.
As I look at it,
I'm reminded of the times
we carried sheep with him.
It's my win!
No, I won!
-I got here first.
-No, I got here first!
I passed the line first!
It's my win!
I won!
He wouldn't stop boasting about that.
Even the sheep would outrun him
if he would let it go.
But he wouldn't budge.
He was always arguing with us.
However,
when he declared his love
to Banu Çiçek...
That night, he was sitting
by the campfire,
brooding like a dove, just like this.
I went and asked him what he was up to.
I'm going to ask Banu Çiçek to marry me.
But I'm not quite sure how.
Like this, brother.
Smitten by your love,
my yearning for you
will reduce me to ashes.
Not bad.
I am smitten by your love,
and yearning for you
will reduce me to ashes.
What else should I say?
You should go on like this.
Like this...
Your gaze pierced my heart like an arrow.
Into the well that is your beauty,
I fell like the prophet Joseph.
I feel like a dry leaf floating
through the desert.
How do you know all of this?
It's not so much me
as the one that makes me say it all.
I was smitten by your love.
Yearning for you...
He went ahead and said to Banu Çiçek
what I had prepared.
Çiçek Hatun.
I was smitten by your love.
Your gaze somehow
pierced right through my heart.
You are a deep well and I fell inside you.
You are like a desert
and I got lost within you.
What's all this gibberish, Doğan Alp?
I'm not quite sure myself.
Curses, Bamsi!
Whatever!
Here goes!
I'm not good at beautiful phrases,
Çiçek Hatun.
Banu Çiçek.
Be my wife.
Please accept me as your husband.
If that's what you want...
then allow me to
give you my life
and bring peace to your heart.
I'll make your tent my palace,
and you my safe haven.
Your troubles are my food,
happiness is my sun.
And my life is your life.
Doğan Alp?
And when she accepted,
you should have seen him.
He froze like a deer before a hunter.
And he came to his senses
after getting slapped on the cheek.
Thank God.
Did I just...
Wait, I don't get it.
You said yes because I asked you
to be my wife, right?
Indeed I did.
So I asked you to be my wife,
and you accepted, am I right?
You said yes, you'll be my wife.
Correct, Doğan Alp.
Then let me go tell Ertuğrul Bey
so that we can go and ask
Tuğtekin Bey for your hand in marriage.
Sure.
My God!
Poor Doğan.
Brother.
From now on,
all we can do is to think of Doğan
as our flag and let it fly.
It's our duty to pierce the armor
of the heathens with that flag, brother.
To pierce their hearts.
Helena Hatun.
May I enter?
Come in, Bamsi.
Bismillah.
Hi.
He...
Helena Hatun, I...
I came to ask if you need anything.
Thanks, Bamsi.
They are treating me well.
Sure, of course they will.
You are one of us now.
One of our women.
Helena Hatun...
I need to tell you something.
Yes, Bamsi?
Helena Hatun...
you know me.
They call me the mountain bear.
However,
even this mountain bear has a heart.
And it keeps beating
and beating and beating.
And it keeps on beating.
Don't laugh, Helena Hatun.
It's already hard enough
to express my feelings.
Sorry, Bamsi.
I'm so excited
I don't know what to do with myself.
All right, then. Let me keep going.
Helena Hatun,
what I'm trying to say is that...
In the huge heart
of this huge man,
it is you whom he cherishes.
And your love...
This love is what keeps me alive, Helena.
Now, what I mean to say is that...
Come to this mountain bear,
and if you so wish,
be my wedded wife.
I...
I want you to
never stop laughing, Bamsi.
I want us to laugh together.
I can't live without you.
I...
I want to be your wife, too.
I want to be by your side all my life.
Be by my side, then!
I'll be by your side as well.
Sure, why not? Of course
we will be side by side.
Be by my side all your life...
Let's live side by side.
Stand by my side.
Helena...
I'll never let you leave my side.
I will never let you go, Helena.
I mean I'll have to go when there is war.
I will fight, and you will be
weaving rugs here.
However, you'll always be by my side.
I'll never let you go.
Why are they beating the drums?
Did they find out about us?
Bamsi!
This is different.
Different. What could it be?
Let me check it out.
I'll never let you go.
Drums are beating.
Traitors!
Kill the traitors!
Kill them!
Traitors! Traitors!
I brought them, sir.
Thank you, Aliyar Bey.
Die, you scum!
Banu Çiçek!
Calm down.
Do you want to go?
I want to see, Halime Hatun.
Let me go, I'll just watch.
I want to watch her die.
I'm no traitor.
You can't do this to me.
We have procedures.
There is law. Let us go.
Father, you must do something!
Bastard!
You bastard!
-Sir!
Showing mercy to the traitors means
betraying those
who have been hurt by them.
Burn in hell, Aliyar.
You betrayed your father.
You betrayed your brother.
You betrayed our traditions.
Burn in Hell!
We are at war with the heathens.
We have enemies that dare
tarnish our honor,
our belief,
and our traditions.
We can't turn a blind eye
to the traitors among us.
Now,
justice is served,
and the culprits eliminated.
Dad!
Forgive me, sir!
I was fooled by my father.
I beg you.
You trampled on my dignity.
Forgiving you now
would be unhuman.
They got what they deserved.
Burn in Hell.
All evil shall be brought to justice.
I said I'd let you know
every time I killed your men.
The unit coming from Nicaea...
is no more.
The soldiers at your castle...
are no more.
I piled them all up, Teo.
And now,
it's time to raise our flags.
We took down a thousand for one.
Now, we are victorious,
and the traitors defeated.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Long live Aliyar Bey!
Send Ertuğrul and Aliyar a letter.
Tell them that
Ural Bey is
trying to trick you
into taking his side.
Tell them that it's time to unite
and take measure.
Ertuğrul Bey and Aliyar Bey
suspect that we meet you in secret.
What if they distrust our words?
Then,
tell him that Ural is threatening to
attack our tribes with the help
of Vasilius and his men.
Spring has come.
Tell him that you will have to
leave this cursed land
along with your tribes.
They can't afford for three tribes
to leave right now.
Then what?
Then, while you hold them off at the inn,
I'll reclaim my tribe.
Since there'll be no one to resist,
we will settle it without any bloodshed.
What about Vasilius?
Will you keep working with that heathen
after you take back your tribe?
By staying at that heathen's fort,
am I betraying my tribe
and our traditions?
Is this what you mean?
Vasilius already fell into my trap.
He thinks that
I'll take you and leave these lands.
I'd never walk out on the Hanlı Bazaar,
or the riches of Karacahisar.
You should all know this.
Conquering Karacahisar is
not an easy feat, is it?
I've already conquered his fort.
The gates of the fort are wide open.
And about Vasilius,
Ertuğrul dealt with
the emperor's reinforcements.
Vasilius is trapped in his fort.
He has no strength left to fight
and protect his fort.
Once we conquer the fort,
the Sultan will acknowledge us.
We will hold all the riches
and trade routes.
The real fight begins now, Aliyar Bey.
Everyone will show their true colors.
All the beys that sided with Ural
are shaking with fear.
We showed them how it will end for them.
But you are right.
They'll go on a rampage now.
They'll plot a coupe.
They will attack desperately.
Ural will even add Vasilius' support
to his forces.
Plotters are not just within, Aliyar Bey.
My men are keeping watch
day and night, sir.
-Kutluca.
-Yes, sir.
Tighten the security.
Let our people know.
Anything could happen now.
They must be alert.
If anybody sees or hears something
they should let you know.
Yes, sir.
Take care, sir.
You too, Aliyar Bey.
Have a safe journey.
We have one last mission, everybody.
Let's go.
Did you get my letter?
Yes, sir.
All the beys and soldiers
are ready to die for you.
You've proven that you are
worthy beys of my father, Candar Bey.
However,
Acar Bey is...
What about him?
We got news from loyal soldiers.
They executed him along with his daughter.
They killed Teo as well.
Acar Bey died honorably
and didn't denounce any of us.
As long as I have honorable men
such as Acar Bey,
let alone Ertuğrul,
not even Karacahisar
could stand against me.
His and my brother's oppression
of my tribe will come to an end.
It's time we took
all the riches.
After we conquer Karacahisar
we will raid all the villages,
each one bigger than the last,
until we reach Nicaea.
We will get all the riches
while also getting a taste of their blood.
We avenged you, Doğan.
God rest your soul.
Rest in peace.
We will protect
your memory, your wife,
and your child, brother.
That's true, brother.
Don't you worry about it.
This mountain bear
will take care of your child.
I'll raise him to be a fine man.
I'll teach him to use dual swords.
Don't you worry.
Bey.
-Thank you, Hatun.
-Enjoy.
-Mother.
-Thank you, my dear girl.
Enjoy.
They got what they deserved.
The execution of Günyeli
and Acar has taught a lesson
to the traitors left behind.
Doubt does not suit us, I know.
God made my heart ache so much
over Günyeli,
that I couldn't keep quiet.
You sensed everything correctly
with your beautiful heart, my dear.
You were right all along.
People are capable of anything.
I wish we could suss out a person's
personality by looking at their face.
Bey.
Bey, may I come in?
Come in, Bamsi.
Come in, dear. Come.
On this bitter day,
you're our consolation.
What is it that you're trying to say
but can't, Bamsi?
Bey, I've been trying
to think of how to say it,
but I couldn't find a way.
That's why I won't beat around the bush.
Bey, if you and Mother Hayme allow it,
I'd like to tie the knot
with Helena Hatun.
What do you think about this,
Helena Hatun?
I'd like to leave these sad days behind,
to be Bamsi's companion for life,
to be a consolation for the pain
he feels for the brother he lost.
Such nice words, dear.
Such a good thing will be a consolation
to all of us in these bitter times.
May God make your home into a heaven.
If you wish to unite,
all I can do is
wish you a fruitful marriage.
God bless you, Bey.
God bless you.
Thank you, Bey.
Don't ever upset Helena Hatun, Bamsi.
And you, Helena Hatun,
be the cure to all of Bamsi's problems.
Bey... Bey, I could never upset her.
I could never upset her.
As long as we have you, we can
scale every mountain, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Helena Hatun.
Go on then.
Be quick and prepare.
Let's do this in the evening.
Good things should be done right away.
Good. Thank you, Bey.
All right. As you wish, Bey.
As you wish. Bey...
Mother Hayme.
-Congratulations, dear.
-God bless my brother!
Thank you, Bey.
Helena...
-Mother.
-Bamsi.
Congratulations, son.
Thank you, Mother. Thank you.
Sister.
We should go. We're going.
They executed Teo.
They took Helena from you...
but they took my father and my child
from me.
They killed your best soldier...
but they killed my most loyal bey.
They murdered Acar Bey.
They will pay a heavy price for this.
We'll see, Ural Bey.
This will be my last move.
When I go to the village tomorrow,
I will kill every single one
of those beys who opposed me!
I will kill off every alp that resists me!
Then...
I will keep the promise I made.
What promise?
When I raid the village,
Ertuğrul’s mother and wife
will be at the rug shop.
Revenge!
Sweet revenge.
A taste so sweet
that you can't get enough...
even if you eat until you burst.
Do you want me to tell you…
what will happen if you don't succeed?
I...
will have to flip the chessboard over.
If you can't make it,
I will burn down
every single village in these lands.
I will kill off everyone.
I fear your anger, Vasilius.
I know what you're capable of.
I will not allow my tribe or the other
Turkmen tribes to stay in these lands.
However, when I go into my village
to fight for the last time,
I need to know you are behind me.
I will get this done without you needing
to get your hands dirty.
Instead of Ertuğrul,
it is I who will be in front of you.
I'll stand behind you.
Sword in hand,
my soldiers beside me.
Amen.
I'm coming in.
Seeing you like this hurts me, Mother.
And seeing Dündar so helpless
and so full of shame pains me, son.
If anyone in my tribe
revealed that kind of weakness,
they would've faced
the same punishment, Mother.
Bamsi, Turgut, Banu Çiçek,
and many alps...
are turning away from him.
He is ashamed.
If I privilege him
for being Suleyman Shah's son,
how will I look the people of my tribe
in the face?
Ertuğrul, son, he is still so young.
He is too proud to pay this price.
Banu Çiçek and her child paid
the price for my brother's weakness.
Dündar took Doğan away
from us, from his comrades.
Ertuğrul, you place such a heavy burden
on Dündar's back...
that he doesn't know
what to do underneath it.
I took away the burden
that he didn't deserve.
I did it so that he could face himself.
I wanted him to know what it is to be
a bey worthy of Suleyman Shah's tribe.
When you left Sungurtekin, Gündoğdu,
and your many brothers behind,
who was with you, son, huh?
You've forgotten about those days so fast.
He must face his shame.
This will improve his character.
When he proves himself,
he'll go back to being an alp and a bey.
That's all I'm going to say.
It's time for you to be
the solution to our problems.
Let's go to Bamsi Alp's wedding.
Look at my brother!
You look so handsome, brother!
Brothers, no wonder Helena Hatun
fell for this brave man.
Right.
How wonderful it is
that God put you two together.
Be very happy.
Thank you, brothers, thank you.
I wish you the same good fortune.
Amen.
Now that you have your lover,
you won't ever see us.
Günkut, you're being tactless.
But I won't get mad at you tonight.
He's right, brother.
Your weapons aren't
your only companions anymore.
From now on,
we'll see you only during wars.
But... But don't say that, brothers.
Don't say that.
My love for my weapons is boundless.
This is different.
Besides, I love my brothers...
as much as I love my woman.
Brothers, I feel rejuvenated.
So, brother, is Bamsi Beyrek
even stronger now?
Brother, I'm even more eager
to cut off the heads of heretics!
Look at you!
-Bless you!
-Thank you.
Brother.
This jawshan is
our wedding present to you.
Put this around your neck
and never take it off.
May God protect you from sharp swords,
evil eyes, and bitter words, brother.
Amen.
From now on,
I will never take this off my neck.
Never.
My brothers.
My brave brothers.
May God never...
May God never let us part again. Never.
-Amen.
-Brother.
My lion-hearted brother.
Bless you.
Bless you all.
Come on, brother. It's time.
It's time.
It's time to go now. Come on.
Look at the bride, look at her
She's got henna on her hand
Don't say anything to her
Or she'll go back to her home
Her door has henna on it
She's an angel in her heart
Oh bride, God bless your henna
May all your life be sweet
Look at the bride, look at her
She's got henna on her hand
Bless you, Helena.
You look so beautiful.
Yes, bless her.
You've helped me a lot.
I am grateful to you.
I can't thank you enough.
We've liked you from the start.
From now on, we'll experience
the good moments together in our village.
Together, we'll welcome the spring.
Together, we'll say goodbye to the winter.
I hope so.
From now on, I'll weave rugs
in the workshop, just like you do,
as I wait for my man.
I'll share in your pain and your joy.
Don't say anything to her
Or she'll go back to her home
Thank you.
Her door has henna on it
She is an angel in her heart
Oh bride, God bless your henna
May all your life be sweet
Give me your hand, dear.
Don't say anything to her
Or she'll go back to her home
Don't be afraid. This is henna.
We apply it on our soldiers and women
so that they sacrifice themselves for God
and dedicate their lives to each other.
Look at the bride, look at her
She's got henna on her hand
Don't say anything to her
In the name of God.
The henna is kneaded with love...
respect, compassion and loyalty.
Look at the bride, look at her
She's got henna on her hand
Don't say anything to her
Or she'll go back to her home
The henna is applied on our palms...
but its meaning
is inscribed on our hearts.
Oh bride, God bless your henna
May all your life be sweet
I don't know why, but I feel like crying.
I can't explain it, but I'm both happy...
and sad.
You're crying, but you keep going.
That's tradition.
You're one of us now.
That's why you are so affected.
Don't say anything to her
Or she'll go back to her home
Her door has henna on it
May your home be fruitful...
and peaceful.
May all your life be sweet
God bless your henna.
-Amen.
May God protect you
from evil eyes, bitter words,
troubles and disasters.
May you have many babies.
May your lineage go on forever.
-Halime, dear.
-Give it to me, Mother. Let me put it on.
May your ears never hear a bad word.
May you never endure grief.
May everyone who looks at you
see the good in your heart.
May you never glimpse an evil eye, dear.
May you never endure any pain.
May your tongue taste only sweetness.
May your home never see cruelty.
May your heart be ever in comfort.
I'm so glad I met you.
I'm glad I'm here.
I want to learn everything
about you and your traditions.
Everything.
From now on, Bamsi Alp is
both your man and your companion, dear.
He'll teach you everything he knows.
And you'll be his first student.
Go on now. It's time.
Come.
Wait a minute, my dear Çolpan.
Allow me to gaze on your beautiful face...
one last time.
Why are you speaking
as though you're giving up, Bey?
Everything is ready.
It's time, my dear Çolpan.
I will come to this castle again,
not as a parasite,
but as the bey of the Cavdar Tribe.
I'll come back as a powerful,
free man and take you away.
For me, what is important
is your life, Bey.
Whatever happens, come back alive.
Oh, my dear Çolpan...
If you only knew what I was going through.
Since I was separated from my tribe,
I've felt like I was living in hell.
Am I even alive now?
All these years, I served my tribe.
And then I got stuck in this stone castle.
Do you think it's easy for the son
of a bey to go through all this?
Now, I have two roads before me.
I'll either get what I deserve,
or I'll die and keep my honor.
God forbid, Bey.
If you die, I'll die with you.
Don't worry.
We'll be fine.
We'll take care of this
with the support of Vasilius and my beys.
I made a promise, Çolpan.
Our bloodline will go on, but...
Ertuğrul's will end.
Then it'll be this castle's turn.
Your father's castle
will become your husband's castle.
I hope so, Bey.
I want my kids to run around and grow up
in this castle, just like I did.
One of the things that pleases God most
is a couple being joined together
in holy matrimony.
As our great prophet once said,
one person is just a half, and only
becomes whole after getting married.
Before His Holiness
married His daughter, Fatıma, to Ali,
He summoned them before Him
and said,
"Ali, I will marry you to my daughter,
but only if you'll be a slave to her.
Fatıma, I will marry you to Ali,
but only if you'll be a concubine to him."
They applied this philosophy
to their lives.
And that marriage
set an example to all humanity.
I hope your marriage will be built
upon this philosophy, too.
Amen.
Yes, dear.
Sir, these people have embraced me.
They didn't let me feel the absence
of my parents.
They looked after me like a sister
without questioning my religion or nation.
From now on, I wish for your religion,
glorious Islam, to be my religion.
If you see fit, I want to become
a Muslim before the wedding
and then get married.
Our mighty God says in Surah Ali İmran,
"You treated them softly.
If you were mean and cold-hearted,
no doubt, they would all leave your side."
Happy are the people
who acted according to the holy word...
and happy are you
who has decided to be Muslim.
Now, repeat what I say.
May God bless you for it.
Amen.
Now, we need to give you a name that will
help you arrive at the right path.
Let your name be Hafsa Hatun
from now on.
May God make you neighbors
with our prophet and his blessed wife,
whose name you just took, in heaven.
-Amen.
Amen.
Ertuğrul Bey, you secured
your victory by winning hearts, too.
You helped a person find the right path.
This is the most beautiful victory
in God's eyes.
Such a victory could
only belong to the bey of beys.
My little... sweet...
traitorous lover.
I'm grateful to you.
You've reminded me
why I hadn't loved a woman
in all this time.
I'm grateful to you...
because you've reminded me
why I've encased my heart in iron,
just like this body.
You've reminded me
why I will never love anyone.
Why I hate women.
Why I hate them.
You will... die... with those Turks.
I will kill you, too,
like I killed your father.
Commander!
Lock up this room.
Nobody must ever get inside.
Do you understand me?
Yes, sir.
Everyone must keep their hands open.
Don't put them together.
We ask forgiveness for all our sins.
Hafsa Hatun, daughter of Andros.
Do you take Bamsi, son of Altuğ,
as your husband...
in return for ten gold dirhams?
I do.
-Do you?
-I do.
Do you?
I do.
Bamsi, son of Altuğ.
Do you take Hafsa,
daughter of Andros, as your wife,
in return for the gold you promised?
I do.
-Do you?
-I do.
Do you?
I do.
Witnesses, do you witness this?
We do.
I now pronounce you man and wife
in front of everyone here.
May God bless your marriage.
Amen.
Dear God... we witness the marriage
of these two children of ours.
May you witness it, too.
Dear God, bless this marriage.
Amen.
Grant this couple peace, love,
and stability in their marriage.
Amen.
Dear God, grant this couple
what Adam and Eve had;
what Mohammed, the Great Prophet
and Mother Hatice had;
what Ali and Fatıma had:
intimacy, patience and affection.
Amen.
Dear God, grant this couple
faithful sons and daughters,
long lives and food in abundance.
Amen.
Dear God, in this world and the next,
grant us goodness,
beauty and blessings.
Amen.
And protect us from suffering by fire.
Bey.
-May God grant you happiness, brother.
-Thank you, Bey.
Brother.
May you be happy, brother.
Thank you, brother. Thank you.
May you be happy.
-Mother.
-Son.
I hope you'll be very happy.
Mother.
May God grant you happiness.
May God grant you happiness, Bamsi Alp.
Bless you, ma'am.
Bless you.
Dear...
I hope you'll be very happy.
Be happy.
Thank you, sister. Thank you.
Mother, are you okay?
Dündar didn't come to the wedding.
What else can I say?
Forgive me for what I've done.
What has Bamsi Alp done?
He has set up his tent on the grass
under the sky!
What has he done
to make his beloved happy?
He has made a stallion out of a horse,
a ram out of a sheep.
Did he break hearts?
Did he say anything wrong?
He didn't break a heart
or say anything wrong.
He got married instead!
Off the lovebirds go to the bridal tent
to conclude the marriage!
Then may God make them happy ever after!
Amen!
May God make you happy, brother.
Go, go, go!