Episode 68 will start after 12:12 min.
I come in peace, Ertuğrul Bey.
I've found out who made the attempt
on your family's lives and on my market.
I'm handing her over to you.
What did you want from my baby!
We'll find out. We'll find out.
If you tell them, I'll kill you.
If you don't, you'll live. Got it?
Ural Bey.
It's against our tradition to harm people,
especially women,
no matter how guilty they appear,
without a trial.
I know, Ertuğrul Bey.
I couldn't restrain myself.
My apologies.
-Abdurrahman!
-Yes, sir.
Take her to the tent.
Up!
Maria says she saw this woman
talking to Francisco.
If you knew who the culprits were,
why didn't you talk before now, Simon?
I took action as soon
as I found out about it.
You Turks wouldn't believe a Christian
even if he told the truth, anyway.
We Turks trust any valiant man.
I hope you don't let this opportunity
slip through your fingers, Ertuğrul Bey.
Ural Bey.
Bey.
I saw them dragging Amanda through the
market and followed them. What happened?
Ertuğrul took her in for interrogation.
-If she talks, we're done for.
-Don't worry, she won't.
I'll kill her if she does.
But Simon...
His time is up. I've had enough of him.
I'm going to kill him.
Who did this to our people?
Who is behind those bandits?
Talk.
Even a child would know you have
more enemies than friends here.
Bey, don't let this devil talk anymore.
You have a point.
Our enemies are many.
While friends are few in this lion’s den.
But if you could give us
just one name, it'd suffice.
I told Aliyar Bey all I know.
If you knew about Francisco,
then you must also know who he worked for.
Speak, you snake!
If you don't tell us who
was responsible,
you'll not leave here alive,
do you understand?
I...
I said I suspected Francisco.
And you were right.
Now,
tell us who Francisco worked for.
Who do you suspect? Tell us.
Simon.
Simon is a clever man.
He knows we'd take his head
if he were to touch our women.
You asked me who I suspected,
and I told you.
If he did do it, why on earth
would he hand you over to us?
Simon...
Who else?
His sister Maria...
She said she saw you
and Francisco talking at your stall.
All are welcome at my stall, sir.
I can't choose my customers.
Do you suspect everyone that comes
to your stall might be bandits?
I said it could be Simon, sir.
So why would he hand you over to us?
To put himself in the clear.
I did you a favor, sir.
Again with the favors.
Why are you letting her speak?
She will talk, Halime Hatun.
She will talk.
She will tell us who was behind it.
Or else she'll spend the rest of her life
in the cage.
Sir...
Brother!
Get off me! Get off!
Let me kill her!
-She tried to kill my sister!
-Brother.
Stop!
Ural!
-Abdurrahman.
-Yes, sir.
Take her to the cage.
Yes, sir.
Up!
That sly woman won't talk
just because you lock her up.
What do you suggest?
We can't torture a woman
to make her talk, can we?
I'll deal with
her interrogation personally.
I'll let you know as soon as
I find out something.
I hope you can make that snake talk.
May God protect you.
-We'll await your news.
-Candar Bey.
I forgot to tell you.
Tomorrow evening, we are going
to gather to mark the safe return
of our women and my son.
You are very welcome.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey. Thank you.
We keep talking about our traditions.
But when push comes to shove,
we forget about them.
We made our move.
Let's see how Ural deals with it.
Ural and his wife were panicking.
You should've seen their faces.
Now the game begins.
We deserve a feast, right?
Look at them, Philip.
Our lands have been invaded by
a bunch of shepherds and their goats.
And now they're riding
their horses before us.
How did we lose to them?
How?
Innkeeper Simon...
He wouldn't give his dying father
so much as a cup of water.
Why would he do us this favor?
She's right, sir.
The devil never helps
without expecting something in return.
What's Simon's objective, son?
And more importantly,
what will our next move be?
I'm going to set Amanda free.
If you set a dog free, it'll surely
go running back to its master.
Talk!
-Who's behind it?
-I'm innocent.
I just wanted to help...
Did you really think I'd believe that?
Who's behind the bandit?
Who made you do it?
I've told you all I know.
I've got time.
Speak whenever you feel like it.
We got our Bey and our women
back safe and sound.
Thank God.
If only Tugtekin Bey and Gokce Hatun
could have made it back alive as well...
I still have nightmares about it.
I can't forget that damn day.
Sir!
I miss my master, brother.
They've become martyrs, brother.
Such an honor...
May God allow us as honorable a death.
Amen, brother.
She'll talk, sir, she'll talk.
I'll make her talk before sunset.
I'm innocent. Believe me, please.
I know you're innocent, woman.
Sir?
She's telling the truth.
How can you believe her?
Because she's telling the truth.
Amanda is innocent. Simon is behind it.
They came in so suddenly
and dragged me here, sir.
I didn't understand what was happening.
It's Simon.
He thought no one would suspect him
if he was the one to give you up.
You are free to go.
Halime Sultan will send you away.
Ertuğrul Bey...
You are a just and brave man.
CAVDAR TRIBE
Foals grow, steeds rest.
Sons grow, elders rest.
This is how I've always wanted you to be.
When my time is up
and I leave this transitory life behind,
I don't want to have any regrets.
I want to know that my sons act in unison.
Rest assured, Father.
We live for our tribe.
We work to glorify our tribe.
I didn't believe them when they said
my brother's sword was like a dragon.
Then I saw it. And believed.
Like Ertuğrul Bey says,
if it weren't for Ural, we wouldn't
have been able to save our women.
What were you talking about
with Emir Sadettin, son?
You didn't tell me.
Emir Sadettin Köpek is going to give
the lands up to Enguruk to us.
Son,
I've known the man for over 30 years.
We fought together in Harput.
The Emir Kopek I know
would never give away his land.
But he'd take land.
His rule doesn't extend beyond
the walls of Konya Palace.
He needs us here.
That hand...
toppled the great Celaleddin Karatay.
The Emir hides his intentions
even from himself.
We're talking about the man
who is right below the Sultan.
I don't know his intentions.
But if the Seljuks want to
get a hold of these lands,
they'll need our tribe.
Emir Sadettin Köpek has no choice
but to support us!
Which tribe has more men than us, Father?
-Son--
-Father.
We need a lifeline
in these fierce currents.
Emir Sadettin Köpek
is going to provide us with it.
Prepare the horses,
I'll collapse the inn around Simon.
Yes, sir.
Simon showed his last hand.
First the knife, and now this.
One of us has to die, it's the only way.
How will you explain this to your father?
I'll tell him that...
I found out it was Simon
that killed Toktamış.
Besides, Maria prepared the poison,
and the evidence is there.
I'll have him believe me.
One of us dies.
There's no time to lose.
KAYI TRIBE
We owe her the lives of all our sons.
Tend to our guest, Halime Sultan.
I understand. Here.
I'm overjoyed to see you alive and well.
Apologies for not believing you.
Thanks to you, I got my son back as well.
May God be with you.
Let's head to the healing tent
and have Ishak tend to your wounds.
Thank you, I'm alright.
It'd be best if I left now.
Wouldn't you like to drink a cup of ayran
while we prepare the horse?
Come.
Kaya.
Take three alps with you.
Follow Amanda.
Yes, sir.
You'll go to the market.
Tell me if you see Turgut.
I want to know every step Amanda takes.
Yes, sir.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, sir?
Prepare 20 men.
-I'll talk to them before the meeting.
-As you wish, sir.
I'm coming too, brother.
Think I got rusty, boy?
Of course you're coming.
You are an alp.
You must come.
Why did they let her go?
They freed her.
Let's go.
Go back now.
Sir.
Men!
Aktolgali.
In peace, you're my brother,
in war, my comrade.
Half the time...
we breeze through the Steppes.
The rest of the time...
we put an end to our foes.
We drank from every spring.
We set foot on every piece of land.
We hunted every game there is.
I miss those carefree days.
Who knew it'd be this hard?
I shoulder the holy mission
I received from my father,
Suleyman Shah.
The enemy are hard on our backs.
Enough of this mess that
rusted my sword, Aktolgali.
I've come to miss enemies
that I could fight properly.
Now,
I must steel my nerves,
and with my foes as the hammer,
I must get stronger
with every hit, and become sharp enough
to cut their throats.
Now, my sword shall become my path,
Mother Earth, my blanket,
and the heavens, my confidant.
Bask in my glory, Aktolgali.
I, Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah,
before taking my revenge,
before I light up the hopes of my people,
before I do right by my tribe,
shall not die.
PUBLIC MARKET
Come, sit with us, Bartalmay.
I'd hate to offend you, Master Simon.
I'm overjoyed today. Come, eat with us.
To what do I owe this honor, Master Simon?
We owe it to the war Ertuğrul shall soon
wage on the Cavdars.
The Kayis might be a small tribe,
but Ertuğrul's men will not yield
to the Cavdars easily.
Who wants them to yield, anyway?
Let the lot of them wipe
each other off the face of the world.
We'll keep trading with both tribes.
Amanda.
At last she was good for something.
Speaking of trades,
excuse me, Master Simon.
I shall head for the market.
Goodbye, Merchant Hasan.
-Check out my colorful clothes!
-Spice seller is here.
Come, see my silk clothes.
How much is it?
-Take...
-Right away, sir.
Beautiful clothes.
Boy, can you give me a hand?
Spice seller is here.
Who wants some spice?
What's it, Samsa?
Ertuğrul Bey let Amanda go.
He wants to know who she
works with, and why.
If she comes here to talk to anyone
he said he wanted to know.
Okay.
You're back early.
-Turgut...
-What about Turgut?
Met with an alp from Kayis.
Ertuğrul let Amanda go, apparently.
And she's being followed.
He had Turgut watch Amanda.
And you said you'd know
if he left the room, huh?
He's been playing us
from the very beginning!
Did his bed keep you that warm?
So we were ambushed by him as well.
Damn it!
Turgut knows everything.
The secret passage, the letter Sadettin
Kopek sent us, everything!
It's all upside down again!
Allow me to...
Ertuğrul was a step ahead of us.
So it was thanks to Turgut.
We'll be in danger as long as
that traitor lives, Master Simon.
Allow me to
cut out his heart and give it to you.
No, Philip.
I'll have Turgut do one last thing for us.
He'll kill Ertuğrul.
It's obvious that
she's waiting for someone.
Ural.
Ural Bey.
What are you out here for?
How did you get away?
I didn't, he let me go.
He was fooled by our plan.
Come with me.
Come here.
You fool!
Ertuğrul used you as bait.
Would he let you go if he didn't know
you'd come to me?
No, Ural. He thinks it was Simon.
Let him.
I'm not leaving it to chance.
Batuhan!
Ertuğrul must have sent men
to follow her.
No one can know Amanda came
to see me. Send your men to search around.
Let's go back to the settlement.
There they are!
Don't let them go!
You wait here.
Let's go!
My brothers!
It's done. Don't leave our dead behind.
Be quick.
-We got rid of them, sir.
-Good.
Get ready, we'll be at the inn
when the sun sets.
God, give me strength!
Oh, how I love you, my darling.
God answered our prayers.
He spared us our son.
What would I do if something
happened to you?
Don't think about it, Halime Sultan.
What would our son do without you?
I wouldn't know.
I've never heard you say that, though.
Besides, it's common practice among men
to find a second wife.
I know my wife well enough
to know when she's implying something.
I'm not implying anything.
Why would I do that?
If I disappeared,
you'd just get another woman,
and have her nurture Gündüz.
Did you think I'd say this?
Who knows?
However, you seem to be enjoying
the idea of it.
They say a man
can survive the strike of his enemy,
but not the cruelty of his wife.
Who knows?
Maybe you'll even get a woman
while I'm alive and well.
After all, women from other tribes
are eyeing you.
Expect no charity from the strangers.
Lean on support from no one but
your own kin.
Only death may part those
of the same blood.
I have decided.
I'll have Aslıhan bind us
with the Kayi inseparably.
Well thought, father.
I'm sure my sister would be happy to marry
a brave
and valiant warrior
from the Kayi Tribe.
I'll talk this over with Aslıhan.
Who will you have her marry, father?
Dündar Bey?
No, Ertuğrul Bey.
What?
Yes, with Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul is a true Kayi.
Father, alright, but...
Ertuğrul Bey is already married.
Not to mention his children.
I know.
His first wife is the niece
of Sultan Alaeddin.
My sister...
Do you think she'd accept that?
I'll talk to her.
However...
Ertuğrul Bey is no ordinary man.
It's up to you, father.
However,
Dündar Bey is a son of
Suleyman Shah as well.
He's not married either.
They call Dündar a bey
because Ertuğrul is a bey.
Ertuğrul is much too young.
He'll be the head of the Kayi
for years to come.
We can't wait for Dündar to be the head
of Kayis to get a hold of their tribe.
It's up to you, father.
However...
what would my brother say?
It's no secret that they don't
get along well.
With this marriage,
Ural shall obtain the glory and power
he's been after.
I'm sure he'll support the idea.
Still no news from Amanda?
Let's hope she was dumb enough
to go to Ural.
Ural would kill her.
What's important is that Ertuğrul
finds out who she meets.
That's all that matters.
Batuhan.
Hold the door with your men.
Let no one in.
Amanda is dead.
Found with three other bodies.
Looks like Kayi soldiers,
Master Simon.
Ural...
It's your last supper, Simon.
Eat. Don't die hungry.
Such an emotional man you are, Ural.
What were you lead to believe again, huh?
Did you think you could make us fight
with Ertuğrul by giving him
Amanda?
How could I make Ertuğrul
fight you by giving him Amanda?
I don't understand.
Enough!
Hold!
His Highness Abu Nakkas.
I hope I'm not interrupting
as you kill each other.
Get out.
-What's this, Maria?
-Come with me.
While you are fighting among yourselves
Sultan Alaeddin is planning on
allowing Ertuğrul to rule
the lands as far as Engurek.
While Karacahisar and the keep
are still in the hands of the Byzantines?
The Sultan
is not aware how big of a mistake
he's making.
Ertuğrul is but a speck of dust, sir.
However strong he might be,
he can't possibly imagine
invading Karacahisar with
a mere 400 tents.
Ertuğrul
is but a pebble
among these huge rocks.
Even a pebble could defeat a man,
as they say.
You keep making wrong decisions, Ural.
Instead of going after futile things,
strive to become the head of your tribe.
There will be time for that, sir.
I'll soon take over the Cavdar tribe.
At this rate, you'll soon
take your last breath.
The Seljuks
and I need
strong tribe leaders.
The man that stands before me,
unable to lead his tribe,
dares to expect to rule these vast lands?
Simon.
You'll do what I say.
Or else Ertuğrul
will bury you alive along with
your precious market.
And you'll roll with it.
Rest assured, sir.
I've already signed his death warrant.
Why is Batuhan here?
I thought Simon owned the inn.
I don't want you to get hurt.
Ural Bey is here.
Just another fight over money.
Don't leave this room.
-Did you let the alps know, Artuk Bey?
-They are awaiting your orders, sir.
-Sir.
-What is it, Abdur Rahman?
Sir.
Kaya.
Son!
Lad! Son!
Lad!
Son!
Son.
I bear witness that
there is no god but Allah
and that Muhammad is
his servant and messenger.
Kaya!
Lad.
Who did this to you?
Who?
Kaya.
Kaya!
Sir, Ural Bey gets little done,
but hurls abuse constantly.
He'd have killed Ertuğrul
many times over, if it was up to him.
I hope you don't end up like him.
Don't you worry, sir.
You'll hear of his death
by tomorrow if you stay here.
It's not that I'm asking for
the death of a Turkmen bey.
However, there is no predicting
who meets the grim reaper.
All I care about is
the safety of the Seljuks,
the comfort and fortune of my people.
Every emir would want
that everything in his country
is resolved quietly and discreetly.
Quietly.
Discreetly.
Your death will be quiet
and discreet, Ertuğrul Bey.
Quiet.
Discreet.
The Sultan must know about
the spy at the palace.
Give this letter to Alfonso, Philip.
He leaves tomorrow.
Alfonso.
Kaya Alp paid for what he heard.
That woman, Amanda,
must have met her maker...
since they left no witnesses.
God has witnessed it all, Artuk Bey.
The one behind all this
will be sure to meet my blade.
Salaam alaikum.
-Alaikum salaam.
I seek refuge in Allah
from the cursed Satan
In the name of Allah
The beneficent, the merciful
By the wise Qur'an
Your people are the messengers
On a straight path
This is a revelation of the Exalted
In Might, the Merciful
That you may warn them
Whose forefathers were not warned
So they are unaware
Permission, father.
Come here, my daughter.
Sit down.
You wonder why I have called for you,
no doubt.
I still remember...
how I was mesmerized
when your late mother
handed you to me for the first time.
After two sons,
when I held you
it was as if
a baby chick...
so fragile...
so tender...
Time flows like water.
And one day...
that bird takes flight
and leaves the nest.
What I want to say is...
I have decided that
it's time for you to fly
and find your own nest.
It will be as you decide,
Father.
Traditionally...
it's you who decides
whether or not to marry
the one I choose.
I'm your father.
Not your owner.
Our rules don't force you.
I only want
the best,
for you...
for my sweet little girl.
In short,
and if you accept,
I wish to betroth you to Ertuğrul Bey
of the Kayi tribe.
My wish is to marry...
your sister Aslıhan to Ertuğrul Bey.
We were discussing.
And what does Aslıhan
have to say about this?
Father will decide.
Ertuğrul Bey is a godsend for you.
I only hope your heart wishes the same,
my daughter.
If you ask me,
you made a good decision, father.
Ertuğrul Bey...
Small village but a big reputation.
Excuse me, father.
If you also approve...
may God let this happen.
Inshallah.
After Emir Saadettin...
Ertuğrul's support for us means nothing.
But, one more friend and one less enemy.
Everyone serves their purpose,
Ural.
You only met the Emir yesterday.
I know his whole past.
We have no friends but each other.
If Ertuğrul Bey agrees
to marry your sister,
this will be huge for the Cavdars.
Let's hope
that Ertuğrul agrees
to marry Aslıhan then.
The time of death has come for those
who wish to put out the holy flame.
I have come to take
the cold breath of death.
Loyal servants of Christ.
My silent friends.
Give me the breath of Hell.
Let it all smell of death.
Oh, children of fire!
Hear the children of Olympos!
I'm sending you a sibling.
With a poisonous smoke.
There's nothing to be ashamed of, Aslıhan.
Marriage is the dream of all women.
Of course it is.
I know what worries you.
Being the second wife confuses you.
You have nothing to worry about.
You're the young and firm one.
Let Halime Hatun worry about herself.
What will happen when her man marries
a young and beautiful girl?
I have seen
with my own eyes what a warrior she is.
I know how loyal she is to her Bey
and her son.
She'll fight you for a day,
or two.
But she will accept you eventually.
But don't forget,
if Ertuğrul Bey agrees,
Halime Hatun will accept as well.
Would you accept it?
As long as you agree,
she will too eventually.
It's not like she'll go against
Ertuğrul Bey.
In the name of Allah,
the most merciful, the most gracious.
And they had made their plot,
but Allah had seen their plot.
There will be only torment
for them and their plots.
Even if their plan had been sufficient
to do away with the mountains.
When those infidels were
plotting to hold you,
kill you, exile you,
or torment you.
When they were plotting,
Allah was plotting against them as well.
It is known that
Allah only plots for the best.
They have cheated.
Allah has done away with their plots.
And Allah is the best
of planners.
I'm apart from everything except Allah.
Come together,
plot all your plots against me.
Do not delay.
Oh, Allah, you speak so true, so well.
My Allah,
may you spoil the plots
against your warriors.
Make them victorious.
Amen.
Allah is great.
Peace and mercy of Allah be with you.
Bismillâhirrahmânirrahîm.
For the souls of our martyrs,
Al Fatiha.
Brave sons of Kayi.
Today...
we buried...
another brave warrior.
Witness it.
Kaya Alp is a martyr.
Our cause is just,
our path is hard,
our enemy is treacherous.
Kaya Alp.
Despite the treachery of the enemy
he has been buried with honor.
Inshallah.
We will be buried the same way.
As my ancestor Oghuz was buried.
As Çagri Bey was buried.
As Tugrul Bey was buried.
As my father, Suleyman Shah was buried.
They
went to war saluting the sunrise.
Everywhere they went, they left a mark,
a home behind them,
and a holy cause for the future.
What makes this soil honorable...
is their blood.
Now is the time
to honor
this dirty land
with the blood of our fallen.
Allah is great!
This box holds Turgut's loyalty.
And this loyalty will bring
the death of Ertuğrul.
And we will lose a beloved brother
for this cause.
But God will reward Alfonso in Heaven.
Where to, Turgut Alp?
I wish to visit
the villages to see the Alps
I haven't seen for some time.
Of course.
You're used to going on horseback.
Obviously, you're bored.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Tell Simon.
Goodbye, Turgut.
The Holy Spirit blesses you, Alfonso.
Look at Aslıhan, my Bey.
She's really worried.
She wants it too,
but she's shy about Halime Hatun.
This will be discussed this evening.
Father will discuss it with Ertuğrul.
But,
I don't know if Ertuğrul
will live long enough
to give an answer.
What does that mean?
My poor sister.
She'll lose her beloved
before the marriage.
Everything has changed.
How will this happen?
Just like Toktamiş.
Actually,
Ertuğrul's death
will be worse than Toktamiş' death.
Ertuğrul will get what's coming to him.
What are you doing here, Turgut?
Simon sent me.
I'll carry the letter.
Go back to the inn.
Only a knight can carry the letter.
Simon wouldn't trust you with that.
Enough.
Here's the inn.
One front door.
Another door near the barn.
Two doors.
There'll be 30 to 40 men
with everyone included.
There's 20 of us.
My Bey.
We'll count them before killing them.
Any mistake at all,
Bamsi will have to answer for it.
I'll answer with my life, my Bey.
We'll sacrifice everything for you,
my Bey.
I know, Bamsi, I know.
However,
Kayi tribe, we don't need dead warriors.
We need you alive.
Thank you, my Bey.
Scouts will go first.
They'll leave no stone unturned.
When we're here,
at the crossroads...
you will prepare.
Archers will be on both sides.
Unless I order it,
nobody
will leave their place.
-Understood?
-As you command, my Bey.
By the way...
I want that devil Simon alive.
We have a lot to learn from him.
Inshallah, we'll fight under
the banners of Gündüz Bey one day.
Brother, even now he'd fight better
than you.
He's right, Doğan.
Isn't he?
Anything you say is true.
If we wish to have a village
when Gündüz becomes Bey,
we'll take precautions now.
We'll cleanse our land of serpents,
parasites, jackals,
and pigs, so...
Gündüz's sword can conquer us new lands.
Long live our Bey,
long live our family!
Inshallah, Allah will grant us those days
as well.
-Amen.
Inshallah.
It will happen as long as we don't
hand our land to that vicious infidel
and his scum.
Doubting this means hopelessness.
Hopelessness is a sin.
We are Alps.
We'll give our lives
but not our hope.
Our ancestors said,
"A Turkish baby is a wolf.
Where he steps, he conquers."
Ask your questions now.
Otherwise,
after the council
when everyone is asleep,
we'll move in for the ambush.
My Bey.
Our guests are here.
Thanks, Abdurrahman.
May we be victorious.
Welcome, Candar Bey.
You have honored our village.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
The honor is all ours.
How is your son?
He's well, thank God.
Welcome to you as well.
Come now.
Welcome again.
You've honored our council.
The ones saved
are not foreigners,
they're one with us.
The honor is ours, Ertuğrul Bey.
Our lives are saved.
Now we'll cut off the head of the snake.
Hasn't that girl spoken yet?
I waited to hear news but...
I let her go, Candar Bey.
Forgive me,
Ertuğrul Bey.
But why?
She is innocent.
She only knows what she told Aliyar Bey.
We were saved thanks to that.
We don't know who's who anymore,
Ertuğrul Bey.
We don't know who to trust.
From every angle comes a threat.
Let them come, Candar Bey.
We'll threaten them all.
My Bey.
My Bey,
Master Haçaturyan wants to see you.
Let him see Artuk Bey.
As you command.
We have neither
a lead
nor a witness, Ertuğrul Bey.
One way or another
whoever is behind this,
I will find out
where they live
and make them regret it.
Thank you.
Despite our differences,
when it comes to
our villages and our existence,
know that we support you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Ural speaks the truth, Ertuğrul Bey.
He just forgot one thing.
We aren't two villages anymore.
One village.
Moreover, we are one family
with shared interests.
My Bey.
-With permission.
-Speak, Master Haçaturyan.
What's wrong, Master Haçaturyan?
My Bey, I know
you told me not to come to the village.
But I had to.
The river
was so generous that
I filled a bag in no time.
But protecting the gold is hard.
I wanted to let you know
and give you the gold.
Thank you, Master Haçaturyan.
You did well.
Ertuğrul Bey will be very happy.
Our coffers will be full of gold
thanks to you.
My Bey,
it was thanks to you and God.
I am a mere mediator.
Master Haçaturyan, keep working.
Don't come to the village
unless necessary.
Get your provisions quickly
and go back to the cave.
Don't worry, Artuk Bey.
We'll be back soon, son.
Our suffering will end soon.
Let's find out
who that spy in the Sultan's palace is.
Calm down, son.
It seems you want to go back
even more than I do.
But we still have time.
This letter will allow us to return.
About Turgut...
You didn't deserve those words.
Forgive me.
You did a lot.
Without you he would be dead.
I wish I had let him die.
He will die.
I promise you, sister.
You will kill him.
But first, he will kill Ertuğrul.
Welcome, Turgut Alp.
Thank you, brother.
Now, go tell Ertuğrul Bey
that there's an urgent issue.
I have to see him now.
-Go.
-Thank you.
This is my father Suleyman Shah's sword.
Damascus steel.
What makes a sword valuable
is the hand that holds it.
Look...
My father Ginal Bey left this.
This is Damascus steel too.
Inshallah, we'll leave these to our sons.
So this is the sword
of Suleyman Shah,
which bled many infidels from
Khorasan to Damascus.
May I, Ertuğrul Bey?
Yes.
Really sharp.
Obviously, a masterpiece.
A sword twice quenched is a real sword.
The iron twice quenched becomes strong.
Becomes firm.
Here, Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey.
I've discussed with my sons.
I have good news.
I would like to see you personally
after the council.
My Ertuğrul Bey.
The table is ready, come.
Come, sir.
In the name of Allah.
Thanks to Allah who gave us this food.
-Amen.
Come along. Enjoy it.
Permission, my Bey?
My Bey.
You know we have guests,
Abdurrahman.
I didn't mean to disturb
but it's important.
Excuse me, Candar Bey.
Of course, Ertuğrul Bey.
My Bey.
My brave brother.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, my Bey.
What's that letter?
From Simon.
To his spy at Sultan Alaaddin’s palace.
Well done, Turgut.
Knowledge is power.
Thank you, my Bey.
We'll attack after the council.
It's been a while
since I heard something that good.
Now, excuse me,
I should get back before they notice.
Godspeed, Turgut.
Thank you, my Bey.
We met Abu Nakkash, his wish is clear.
Make Sultan Alaaddin incapable of ruling
and then overthrow him.
For this, he needs chaos
and disorder.
When Ertuğrul makes Amanda speak,
I can't even imagine Ural's demise.
Ural...
Thank you, dear.
It was delicious.
Glad you liked it.
I'm sorry, Candar Bey.
No worries, Ertuğrul Bey.
I hope it's nothing important.
Nothing important.
Nothing.
Come now.
From now on
may our councils,
our weddings
and our funerals be one.
Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul Bey.
Ural, Aliyar!
Ertuğrul.
-Mother.
-Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-My Bey.
No! Brother!
Brother!
-Ertuğrul.
-Brother!
Ertuğrul!