Episode 67 will start after 12:19 min.
I trusted you.
And you got us both ambushed, fool!
He is alive!
-He is alive.
-Oh, he is alive.
He is alive!
Take him to Artuk Bey right away.
At once!
Let the Candars know the situation.
-Tell I'm after the bandits.
-As you order, my Bey.
My Bey.
Let me go with you.
You'll slow me down, Hasan.
Go to the bazaar, let them know.
May God protect you, my Bey.
-Come on!
-Go on!
Brothers!
How did the Sultan's spy know
you were coming here, Simon? How?
I'll find him, blessed vizier.
Have no worries.
No.
This partnership is valuable.
Too valuable
to let your weakness destroy it.
I have offered a partnership
in which you win too.
And what did you do?
You are not even capable
of finding the Sultan's spy.
-I will find him but--
-Silence!
Don't interrupt me!
As if!
Sultan's spy is Ertuğrul!
Right...
Do you expect him
to confess before you understand?
Damn it!
I suspected him from the beginning.
But what did you do?
Nothing...
Ertuğrul is working day and night
to conquer Karacahisar Castle.
If he conquers it...
no one will be able to stop Alaeddin.
So that's why you want to help us.
You don't want Sultan Alaeddin
to get stronger.
So you want to replace him.
Or are you trying to replace him
with someone of your choosing?
Oh, Köpek.
If you talk to me like this again...
I will rip your lungs out
and feed them to the dogs.
You do your task.
Keep your nose out of the rest.
Go!
Don't let them get away.
Bamsi!
-Bamsi!
-I'm fine.
Go ahead! Come on, don't stop!
Brothers, let's head back to the tribe.
You go, brothers.
I won't return to the tribe
without Ertuğrul Bey's permission.
Brother, you won't make it back
if we leave you here like this.
Brother...
How...
How will we able to look
Ertuğrul Bey's in the face?
We weren't able to reveal
the spy's identity.
-You go.
-Brother...
Do you think Ertuğrul Bey would leave you
in such condition?
We won't do any good to the tribe
if we are dead.
Come on, brothers.
Come on.
Come on, brother.
Let go!
Gunduz! My boy!
How could you do that?
What did you want from him?
What was it?
Keep...
Keep your hopes up, Lady Halime.
Put yourself together.
You are strong.
Don't let these bastards enjoy your pain.
Don't tell me you let him escape!
Send men after them!
Don't come back without finding him!
Look at you.
You can't even protect yourself.
My Lady.
My Banu Çiçek!
Hang in there, my brother.
We're not there yet.
Çiçek!
Comrade Doğan!
Brother Doğan!
Hang in there, brother!
Hang in there.
-Brother.
-Yes?
What is it, brother?
If...
If something happens to me...
Nothing will happen, brother.
We'll get to the tribe
and Artuk Bey will take care of you.
Right! You'll be fine, my brother. Right!
Brother Doğan!
Brother!
Doğan!! Brother!
Brother! Brother Doğan!
Brother!
Doğan!
-Stir it. Don't let it come together.
-Okay.
Beautiful.
They say this place is bitterly cold.
This marmalade will comfort our soldiers.
God willing, my lady.
It's thickened up.
Time to put it in the pots.
Stir it up.
People! Let me through!
What is it, Gunkut? What's wrong?
Speak, my boy.
Bandits.
They intercepted our sisters, Mother.
Do you hear what you're saying?
Halime? Gündüz?
There's no news of them.
Ertuğrul Bey went after them on his own.
Horses! Gather round!
Make way, come on!
Artuk Bey, Ishak Bey, please help!
Gündüz! Gündüz! Gündüz!
My sweetheart.
God!
Open your eyes!
My dear boy!
Oh my dear boy!
Artuk Bey.
Let's get Gündüz Bey to the tent.
By God...
In the name of God...
Banu Çiçek,
go to the healing tent at once.
Ishak will take care of your wound.
In the name of God...
Let me go.
Gündüz.
Gündüz!
Make way!
Ishak Bey! Ishak Bey!
Ishak Bey!
Doğan is wounded, Ishak Bey.
-Doğan.
-No.
Doğan!
My Doğan.
My Doğan, my Bey.
Doğan, my brave heart.
Doğan, open your eyes. Doğan?
Open your eyes. My Doğan!
Please open your eyes.
Doğan.
My God!
Don't make me suffer anymore!
Don't make me suffer anymore, my God!
My God!
Open your eyes, Doğan!
Open your eyes, my brave heart!
-My Doğan, who did this to you?
-We have to take him right away.
Help me, sisters.
-Come on. We need to take him right away.
-Make way, people!
Make way!
Let us through!
-Make way!
-Let us through!
Make way.
THE CAVDAR TRIBE
How could this happen?
Who would dare do this?
What about my daughter?
Where is Aslıhan?
How is she?
Speak up, man!
Bandits.
They abducted Sultan Halime...
as well as Lady Aslıhan!.
My daughter...
Aslıhan!
Ertuğrul Bey... went after them, sir.
He wanted you to know.
-Kutluca!
-Yes, sir.
Gather the scout Alps at once.
-They are to go after them immediately!
-Right away, sir.
Kutluca, take this Alp
so that his wounds can be seen to.
As you wish, sir. Come.
Come.
Guards.
Aslıhan...
Where is Ural?
He went to Konya, Father. Auntie said so.
What business does Ural have in Konya
while the devil is attacking us here?
I wouldn't know, Father.
He said he was meeting someone important.
Guards!
He's coming.
Nobody move.
Why don't we just
finish him off here, Francisco?
This is supposed to look like
a simple ransom.
Our employer wants it that way.
Also, the ransom will make us rich.
I bear witness
that there is no god but Allah...
and Muhammed is the messenger.
You are as brave as they say, Ertuğrul.
Where are the women?
They are safe until I get what I want.
What do you want, you bastard?
A thousand gold coins.
You'll come alone.
No one is to secretly follow you.
Or I will murder the women.
If you harm them, I'll skin you alive.
Tomorrow, when the sun reaches its zenith,
you'll bring the gold here.
My men will take you to me.
Tell Halime Sultan that Gündüz is alive.
And that I'll kill
whoever did this to him.
HANLI BAZAAR
How did the Sultan's spy
know our location?
How was he there
when I met Vizier Saadettin?
Maybe there is an informer among us.
The four people who knew about it
swore an oath. Who do you mean?
He refers to Turgut, Master Simon.
-Yes.
-It's not possible.
He works all day long.
I watch him constantly.
Even if he had got out, he wouldn't
have been able to enter the temple.
He doesn't even know the place.
We can't be sure of anything, Maria.
Anything!
-Master Simon.
-What is it, Petrus!
The Kayi women have been
attacked by bandits.
What?
I saw the raid with my own eyes.
It's Francisco's doing.
I know him well.
He's not so stupid as
to abduct Ertuğrul's wife
and the daughter of Candar Bey alone.
Someone else is behind it.
Who do you suspect, Master Simon?
It's obvious that Ural has a hand in this.
If Ertuğrul finds out the truth,
all hell will break loose.
It's time to spark a war
between those two tribes.
We have to prove Ural is behind this.
Maria, go to Turgut at once.
He can accompany me to the tribe.
-To the tribe?
-Yes.
Let's find out
if Philip's suspicion is justified.
We'll see.
There's something I need to tell you.
Something I think you'll want to know.
The women who were coming
to the bazaar have been attacked.
Halime and Lady Aslıhan were abducted.
I'm not at all surprised.
Ertuğrul has failed once again
to protect his loved ones.
His son Gündüz was mortally wounded, too.
Ertuğrul has got what he deserved.
But I'm sorry for his son.
Simon is going to the tribe soon.
You are a conscientious man.
You can go with him if you like.
At least--
I don't want to see Ertuğrul's face.
Still, I think you'd better go.
If you go, there's no risk
of us offending Ertuğrul Bey.
You are right.
My anger towards him
shouldn't hinder your brother's work.
I don't want him to think badly of Simon
because of me.
Stay strong.
Degenerate scum! I'll kill you!
Come to your senses, woman!
What do you think you can do?
What are you going to do?
Kill me too?
You've already taken my son's life.
I don't care if you kill me too.
So you want to be reunited with your son?
Then behave so that I let you live.
Is my son alive? Does he live?
You'll never find out...
if you do such a stupid thing again.
You bastard!
I swear I'll be the one
to take your life. I swear to God!
Tie them up!
Let me go!
How is my son, Artuk Bey?
I've done what I can, sir.
The rest is up to God.
God willing, when he opens
his eyes and talks again,
the danger will have passed.
I'll wait for you in the tent, sir.
Thank you.
Son, what's going on?
Is there any news of Halime?
They've demanded 1,000 gold coins
to release them both tomorrow.
They continue their attacks...
upon us, like a plague.
Upon our households...
upon our women and children...
Who are they, son? Who?
This place is infested
with treacherous bastards.
Whether one or all...
Whoever did this, I will find them.
And rip their lungs out.
Sir. Candar Bey and Aliyar Bey are here.
Thank you.
May you recover swiftly, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Candar Bey.
I hope we all recover quickly from this.
Please, take a seat.
How... can something
like this have happened?
They have no business with our women!
They're holding them for ransom.
They've demanded
1,000 gold coins for them.
If that's the case...
I'm willing to pay the whole amount.
It's not just about the gold, Candar Bey.
What else then, sir?
No bandits are so stupid
as to openly challenge
the two most powerful tribes in the land.
First, let's pay the ransom
and save our women.
Then, we hunt them down and crush them,
and learn their true intention.
Ertuğrul Bey... let me do this.
We at least owe you that much, thank you.
Kutluca.
What if the true intention...
is to get the gold and kill you, Bey?
I'd give it a try
if I were them, Aliyar Bey.
They know well...
that if they leave me alive...
I will take their lives.
I don't see Ural Bey here.
He went to Konya. He'll be back tomorrow.
You are just in time to share my meal.
I prepared it myself.
I rubbed it in dried cherries
before roasting.
I know what refined tastes
you have, Vizier.
But there's something
I'd like you to know.
Your hostility towards Ertuğrul...
has got to the point that it risks
harming both our interests.
What do you mean, blessed Vizier?
Ertuğrul's worth in our Sultan's eyes
is greater than you can imagine.
All I know is how troublesome he is.
Since he arrived, no one
has enjoyed a moment of peace.
I want Ertuğrul to meet his doom
as much as you do.
But things have their own way
of coming to pass.
If you don't resolve matters
quietly and smoothly,
they'll get worse.
Especially now that
the Sultan has decided to...
conquer Karacahisar Castle.
After the conquest, who do you think
he'll leave to rule over these lands?
Ertuğrul.
You are soon to be
the leader of the Cavdars,
so you have to learn
to contain your anger.
-Your brother Aliyar...
-What about him?
I heard your father
prefers to put him in charge of things.
Aliyar on one hand,
Ertuğrul on the other.
It'll be hard for you.
But don't worry.
I want to see you as the Bey of Cavdars
and Head of the Principality.
I'm ready to do whatever you want me
to do, blessed Vizier.
The Cavdars are the largest
tribe in the area.
It'll be in everyone's interests
for a brave Bey like you
to lead such a tribe.
So...
Until you hear from me again, you'll
end your hostility towards Ertuğrul.
You'll act like a friend to him.
As you command, blessed Emir.
Very well. Very well.
Come on then...
Let's feast.
Innkeeper Simon and Turgut Alp are here.
Ertuğrul Bey, Candar Bey.
I heard what happened.
I'll do everything I can to help.
My men are at your command.
I appreciate that, Innkeeper Simon.
I could ask Karacahisar's governor
for help, if necessary.
He would send his soldiers.
The more of us there are, the better
our chances of finding the women.
We...
will deal with this matter ourselves,
Master Simon.
Why are you here, Turgut?
Merely to extend my good wishes.
Go on your way, Turgut.
I have nothing to say to you.
None of this would have happened
if you'd gone after the men
who attacked our Alps in the first place.
Don't say another word, Turgut.
I understand.
You are in great pain, Ertuğrul Bey.
I am deeply sorry
about Halime Sultan and Gündüz.
But...
you are the reason all this has happened.
They doubt my intentions, Bey.
Never come here again, Turgut.
I'll let this one go...
because of the years we spent together.
But...
if it happens again
you'll pay dearly for it.
Turgut.
Turgut!
I'm used to betrayal, Simon.
We have enemies rather than friends.
I'm leaving. Stay sharp.
Halime Sultan.
We have to get out of here.
You are right, Aslıhan. And we will.
We should help each other.
The ropes are tight.
We'll have to loosen them first.
Do your best.
I have seen so many summers.
I waited so many winters.
I ate if I found food.
If not, I went hungry.
I've traveled many roads.
You were never there.
Was love supposed to be like this?
We were supposed...
to be together on happy and on sad days.
He was killed on the battlefield, I said.
He got captured, I said.
He forgot me, I said.
No one ever had any news.
You disappeared, my Doğan.
You disappeared from me.
You left me all alone.
Not only was I captured.
I fought on many battlefields.
I slept on the earth.
With nothing to cover myself.
I got so cold.
Then I was roasted under the sun.
Spent many hungry days.
Yet, I came back to you, my flower.
You'll leave again once you're healed.
Leave me all alone once again.
Tell me, my Doğan.
What kind of life is this?
My lips are sealed, Lady Çiçek.
I can't explain it to anyone but my Bey.
But...
I won't truly be healed
until I have you by my side.
I kept my promise.
The birds are in the cage.
Now it's your turn, Amanda.
What's up, Hasan?
Who are you hunting?
Francisco went into Amanda's shop.
Ural...
So, you used Amanda.
You're not done yet, Francisco.
You've to kill them all
when Ertuğrul brings the ransom.
Then, you are to forget everything.
Do you think me some sort of fool?
Tell me... who's behind this?
Did you really think I'd do
a job like this for such a low price?
Who's behind it?
Speak up or I'll gut you.
Speak!
U...
Ural Bey. Son of Candar Bey.
This just got a lot bigger.
Tell your Bey, the price just doubled.
Or I'll cut his head off too.
We have to find out what they're saying.
We will, now.
My God,
you giveth and you taketh.
Do not take my child.
Do not test me
with the grief of losing a child.
Amen.
Dündar...
You will lead the tribe while I am gone.
-If something happens to me--
-Brother...
God forbid, brother.
What would we do without you?
Dündar Bey, son of Suleyman Shah.
A bey is never afraid.
He protects his tribe, no matter what.
If something happens to me,
responsibility falls to you.
Don't worry about us, brother.
If Suleyman Shah was alive...
he would be very proud of you both.
Go to it.
We have work to do.
We have striven to make things better
and now this malice...
We are being tested, Ertuğrul Bey.
We can rest when we die, Candar Bey.
We can find a way.
You must have a plan, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let us join you in it.
Such a treacherous man
would do anything for gold, Aliyar Bey.
He wants me to come alone.
Otherwise, our women will be at risk.
You must have some idea
of their whereabouts, Bey.
Let us go there ahead of you and hide.
They won't see us.
It's too dangerous, Aliyar Bey.
I met them at Akkozak Road.
I don't know where their hideout is.
They'll post lookouts everywhere
before I get there.
If we knew where they were
holding the women, then maybe...
We can't stand by and do nothing, Bey.
I'll go to the bazaar tomorrow morning.
I'll ask everyone who this bastard is
and where he might be hiding.
For your woman, for my daughter,
you risked your life, Ertuğrul Bey.
I will not forget this favor.
Thank you, Candar Bey.
I have the gold, Bey.
I'll take my leave, Ertuğrul Bey.
May God help you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Candar Bey.
Why is Ural absent?
What is he doing in Konya?
We have to learn the answers
to these questions, Dündar.
Magnificent.
Brother. Greetings.
-Greetings, brother.
-Greetings, brothers.
You look good, brother.
Recover quickly, brother.
You have cheated death, thank God.
May God heal you soon.
Thank you, brothers.
How is your wound, Samsa?
My wound is fine, brother. But...
I am disappointed
I didn't fulfil my duty.
Hey... Why the long faces?
When did we ever leave
our duty unfulfilled?
That's not our only concern, Bamsi.
Halime Sultan and Aslıhan Hatun
are at the mercy of a bandit.
I understood you well, brothers.
Just... Just hear me out, brothers.
Listen to me.
Brothers,
once upon a time, there was a tiger
which kept attacking the Turk tribes.
It attacked every herd,
killed every shepherd.
People were thinking
"What are we going to do?"
Then Khan heard of the situation.
Khan. Khan was bursting with anger.
He said, "When my people
are suffering attacks by this tiger,
how can I still call myself a Khan?"
He sent 20 Alps along with
his best man to the nomad camping side.
Khan also had a son.
He went to his father and said,
"Father, let me go there too.
Let me go, so I can show the world
that I am a worthy son,
Father."
Brothers, Khan's son was strong.
But he was also very young.
His father said,
"Son, I know you are excited,
but your time has not come yet."
Unwillingly, his son had to accept that.
Brothers, while Khan's 20 Alps and his
best man were searching for the tiger,
they suddenly heard a great roar!
Before they even saw it,
the tiger had torn the 20 Alps to pieces!
And when the tiger was
about to kill Khan's best man too...
Khan's son appeared and throttled
the tiger with his bare hands!
That mighty tiger, brothers,
died at the hands of that brave man!
So, brothers, from that day on,
that brave man went by the name of Tunga.
This is the story of our ancestor,
Er Tunga Alp.
Brothers. Our ancestors were wolves!
Our Bey is just like
his ancestor Alp Er Tunga,
ready to stand against the whole world!
Brothers, even though times have changed,
even though years have passed,
that blood is the same blood, brothers!
Family is the same family, brothers!
We have known lots of brave men,
brothers, and have many legends.
Now is the time for Ertuğrul Bey
to write his own legend.
May God strengthen Ertuğrul Bey.
-Amen!
May God give him and we Alps
many more victories!
-Amen.
Amen.
Brothers...
Brothers, I hope one day...
people will tell
the legend of Ertuğrul Bey.
Amen.
-Amen.
Amen, brothers. Amen.
Ertuğrul is a very dangerous man.
And he is not stupid.
He'll come alone tomorrow, as I said.
But we'll take precautions anyway.
You, take four men with you
and wait for Ertuğrul at Akkozak.
The rest will hide.
If he doesn't come alone, kill them all.
And kill the women, too.
The enemies within...
and the enemies without did not allow us
a single moment of peace, Aslıhan.
First, my father...
then my brother...
and now my Gündüz.
I still remember the day I told Ertuğrul
I was pregnant as if it was yesterday.
I'm pregnant, Ertuğrul.
We will have a baby.
Praise God!
The blue sky and the dark ground,
witness me!
I will be a father!
Keep calm, it's too soon for this!
How can I be calm, my darling?
Our whole tribe has been
looking forward to this news.
Gündüz will have a sibling, Bey.
I'm pregnant. We will have another child,
God willing.
Praise God!
They say fate will protect
a man from his death.
If God allows it, you will meet
Gündüz again.
God willing, Aslıhan Hatun.
God willing.
We couldn't hear what they were saying.
But it's obvious they did this together.
Just as I guessed.
Ural was behind this, too.
So, Ural has been using
Amanda to spy on us.
I'll make her pay for this.
There is going to be a lot of bloodshed.
When Ertuğrul learns what's happened,
he'll do anything to kill Ural.
He will not let the killer of his wife
and son live.
Nor will Candar allow it.
When we give Amanda to Ertuğrul Bey,
the rest will be easy.
What if Amanda refuses
to tell Ertuğrul what she knows?
We will do what is necessary.
Right, Maria?
I can make her
sing like a bird, Master Simon.
Petrus, keep an eye on Amanda's stall.
Ural is bound to go there
in order to find out what's happening.
We can trust Turgut.
I saw it today with my own eyes.
I will use him when war
breaks out between the tribes.
Don't push him. Do you understand?
Yes, Master Simon.
My God, please protect my bey, my tribe...
and all the people I love.
Do not take Gündüz from us.
Allow the safe return of Halime Sultan.
Do not test us through
our loved ones anymore, God.
God, bless the souls of my Alps,
may they rest in peace.
Help me see the day I take my revenge
on the traitors who killed my Alps.
God, do not take my life
before I avenge them.
Amen.
Although we worship differently,
our prayers are the same, Turgut.
I hope God will answer
all of your prayers.
Thank you, Maria.
I am waiting for the day He does.
My only aim in life...
is to take my revenge...
so that I may start breathing
with peace again.
I live only for this.
I am keenly awaiting that day too.
When you are able to ease
your suffering and be happy again...
that day, I will be happy, too.
You should have
a better reunion than this.
Our real reunion will be the day
our tribe finds peace.
You are right, Doğan.
We cannot be happy
when our tribe is in misery.
May I come in?
Sit tight, brother.
You have a lot to talk about. Excuse me.
I said some terrible things to you...
but it was only because I was
so worried about Doğan.
Please forgive me.
Thank you for risking your life
when they attacked.
We cannot thank you enough.
Bey,
Karacahisar Castle is okay now.
I know its every detail:
how many entrances it has,
how many exits it has,
where the guards stand,
I know everything.
They are in my pocket, and in my mind.
You have discovered so much for us.
Such information will be crucial
at the time of conquest, Doğan.
Now, get well soon.
That day has not yet come.
I wish we could come with you, Bey.
Yes, Bey.
We can't stand to see you go alone.
God is with us, brothers.
-Give me your blessing.
-I give you my blessing, Bey.
Brother...
-Don't be scared. It's me.
-Ural Bey!
I wanted to talk to you inside
because I don't want anybody to see me.
Are you okay? What's happening?
Did Francisco come?
Yes, he did. He kidnapped Aslıhan
and Halime, just like you said.
And he gave your message to Ertuğrul Bey.
He said, "If you don't bring
1,000 gold coins, I will kill them both."
Good.
Ertuğrul doesn't have that sort of money,
so he'll either go
with his Alps and fight,
or my father will give him
the 1,000 gold coins.
It doesn't matter which.
He'll still fall into Francisco's trap.
Francisco's men are strong fighters
who've fought with the Crusader Army.
Ertuğrul will die there.
-However, we have a problem, Bey.
-What is it?
Francisco broke the agreement.
He wants double the amount.
Did you expect anything less
from a bandit?
Listen to me.
If he finds out it was me who
planned this, I'll cut your throat.
Don't worry, Bey. He won't.
Why are you still worried?
I am going to save Ertuğrul, his wife,
and my sister from that bandit.
What do you mean, Bey?
I'll explain later.
But I have missed you so much.
I want to spend the night with you.
My God,
I am in great trouble.
I seek your refuge.
Deliver me from this cruel plot.
My God, I know that with every difficulty,
there is relief.
Help me save my wife
from those brutal bandits.
Help me send those
who hurt my wife to hell.
Give me victory over my enemy.
Amen.
Halime.
My wife.
My precious.
My only love.
How can I sleep here when
you are at the mercy of a bandit?
How can I sit here while
you wait for me in tears?
My darling one.
If your beautiful eyes fill with tears,
I would be a thunderstorm.
Without you, my tent is a dungeon
and my bed is an enemy to me.
I cannot live here like this anymore.
Son, my dear son.
You were born at a time
when the world is full of corrupt men.
Villains will always be after you.
You are not destined to obey them
or to kneel at their feet someday.
We are Turks, son.
We are the brave fighters of the steppe.
Finding without losing,
taking without deserving,
dying without fighting is forbidden to us.
In the name of God,
most gracious, most merciful.
Have we not expanded thee thy breast?
And removed from thee thy burden,
which weighed down thy back?
And exalted for thee thy mention?
So, verily, with every difficulty,
there is relief.
Yes. Verily, with every difficulty
Therefore, when thou art free,
still labor hard.
And to thy Lord...
turn thy attention.
In the name of God,
most gracious, most merciful.
Verily we have granted thee
a manifest victory.
That God may forgive thee thy faults
of the past and those to follow.
Fulfil his favor to thee
and guide thee on the straight path.
And that God may help thee
with powerful help.
It is he who placed tranquility
into the hearts of the believers
that they may add faith to their faith.
For to God belong the forces
of the heavens and the earth.
And God is...
full of knowledge and wisdom.
That he may admit the men and women
who believe...
to gardens beneath which rivers flow
to dwell therein for aye
and remove their ills from them.
And that is, in the sight of God,
the highest achievement.
And that he may punish the hypocrites,
men and women,
and the polytheist men and women,
who hold an evil opinion of God.
On them is a round of evil.
The wrath of God is on them.
He has cursed them
and prepared hell for them.
And evil is it as a destination.
For to God belong the forces
of the heavens and the earth.
And God is exalted in power.
And full of wisdom.
Undoubtedly,
God is omniscient, all aware.
God!
Undoubtedly,
God is omniscient, all aware.
May God heal you soon.
Amen.
You will be better by the time
your mother returns, Gündüz.
Give me your blessing.
I give you my blessing.
My son.
May God keep you from envious eyes,
evil tongues...
and sharp swords.
Amen.
Return quickly to me, God willing.
Thanks to the powerful women
of the Kayi and Cavdar tribes,
to these gold coins
I will today add 1,000 more.
Do you think you'll be
able to spend that gold?
I have known many people
that would do anything for gold,
who died the moment they got their wish,
without touching a single coin.
You will choke to death
on those gold coins.
Francisco will live like a king
on Ertuğrul Bey's gold.
-But you--
-Do you really think
you will walk away
from Ertuğrul Bey alive?
I am sure about it.
Because I know that
a dead man cannot hurt a living one.
Ertuğrul is walking into a trap
he will not get out of alive.
Stupid Turk.
He believes I'll let you and he go
once I get my hands on the gold.
But...
each of you will die
while gazing into each other's eyes.
I swear on my God,
my banner and my sword.
Thank God, I am on a holy duty.
If I turn back from this path I have taken
for my forefather Oguz's great generation,
may I be slain by my own sword,
like wheat in the field.
May the blue sky tear,
may the brave ground sink.
May my forefather Oguz,
my blessed tribe, sue me in the next life.
On this path I have taken,
may Hizir accompany me
and may Ali be by my side.
May the journey be ours,
and the victory God's.
Bey, I questioned everyone in the bazaar,
as per your orders.
But no one could answer my questions.
Nobody knows anything.
Go back to the tribe, Kutluca.
Yes, Bey.
My God, I call on you
with the prayers of Ali.
You are the greatest, you are omnipotent,
and you oppress all kinds of evil.
Save us from this trouble, God.
Bey...
I heard about what happened.
I'm very sorry.
I have prayed to our saints for them.
Thank you, Hatun.
Even though both tribes are suffering,
I saw that the women came to work.
Ertuğrul Bey is the most determined man
I have ever seen. He never gives up.
I understood this
the first day he came here.
-Thank you.
-Bey!
I have to tell you something.
What is it, woman? Speak.
I think I know who kidnapped them.
Who?
There is a Catalan warrior
who goes by the name Francisco.
He doesn't come to the bazaar very often
as he and Simon are sworn enemies.
What does he have to do with
the kidnapping of our women?
Spit it out, woman!
The day the rug house launched,
I met Francisco.
He asked me lots of questions
about Halime and Aslıhan Hatun.
I got scared and came back to my stall.
Where can I find him? Tell me!
One of his bandits
sometimes comes to my shop.
I overheard him saying they have
a camp out at Aya Nikolas rocks.
But Bey, you didn't hear
this from me, right?
Hey, Aliyar. What's the rush?
-Bandits have kidnapped our women.
-What?
Aslıhan and Halime Sultan were kidnapped,
but I've discovered where they are.
We have to go there now, brother.
Ertuğrul went there alone
to pay the ransom and save the women.
Then we should tell Batuhan
to get the Alps ready.
There's no time, brother!
We'll go together then. Come on.
Real mastery is being able to stare
your enemy in the eye
while resisting the urge to draw
your sword until the moment is right.
There is a proper time for everything.
It is the enemy who renders you brave.
Ertuğrul Bey.
You came.
I said I would.
And the gold?
Come with me.
Leave the horse here.
They're coming.
Not now, wait.
Bring them.
Ertuğrul
First, let Halime and Aslıhan Sultan go.
Why the hurry, Ertuğrul Bey?
Francisco would like you
to be together, not to leave.
Either in this world, or the next.
Kill them.
I'm here, Ertuğrul!
Ertuğrul
For God!
Come on!
I told you I'd be your death.
Take it! Take it!
Eat them till they choke you,
eat the coins for which you killed my son!
Halime. Halime!
-Halime.
-Ertuğrul
Is my Gündüz alive? Does our son live?
He's alive. He'll get better
once he sees you.
Thank God!
Ertuğrul.
Ertuğrul., let's go home, come on.
Let's go. Let's go.
Thank God for giving me
two brave brothers.
This has been hard on you, Halime Sultan.
-I'll get the horses.
-Thank you.
If it hadn't been for you,
things could have been much worse.
May God keep us united,
and our tribes protected from suffering.
Amen, thank you.
Nothing compares to fighting
side by side with a brave man.
This is an honorable day.
Thank you, Ural Bey. Thank you.
-Maria, honey.
-Did you bring it?
Of course.
-How is it?
-Very nice.
I've never smelled
such a beautiful fragrance.
I'm sure Turgut will love it too.
You're blushing now.
Did somebody confess
her feelings last night?
No reason to be embarrassed, sweetie.
That scent will turn Turgut into a beast
and you into a Greek goddess.
I can see your true colors now, Amanda.
Now we can start the war.
People are coming.
Look!
Ertuğrul Bey is coming. Thank god!
Thank god he's coming.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Gündüz.
Aslıhan!
Father...
Gündüz...
-Halime!
-Gündüz...
Mother...
How is my son's condition, Artuk Bey?
My sweet girl... Don't lose hope.
Gündüz! I can't take it,
don't do this to me, son.
Come back to me.
I beg you, open your eyes.
I owe you her life, Ertuğrul Bey.
God bless you.
I couldn't have done it
if it hadn't been for Aliyar and Ural Bey.
My brother is innocent, Father.
We brought the bandits into line.
We killed them all.
Your sons did you proud, Father.
We managed to unite.
Gündüz!
Open your eyes, my darling, I beg you.
Don't leave us.
Don't do this to me, Gündüz!
Ertuğrul! Ertuğrul, say something.
Please, anything.
Tell me Gündüz will be well again.
Tell me that our son will live,
tell me something, Ertuğrul!
Tell me nothing is going to happen
to our son, Ertuğrul.
I can't take this.
I can't bear it, Ertuğrul.
Please, say something.
I beg you, say something, Ertuğrul!
I can't live like this.
Please, say something.
Mother.
Son?
My darling? Gündüz!
Gündüz!
Son, I'm here, dear.
My son. Are you really awake?
Dad, when will you get me a real sword?
My son! I was so scared, darling!
When the time is right, son.
When the time is right.
Thank heavens.
Thank God.
Thank god for sparing my grandson.
Ertuğrul.
Sir...
Innkeeper Simon is here.
He has a tied-up woman with him.
He wants to see you.
The man you went to meet in Konya...
Who was it?
Father, I'll tell you everything.
But now is not the time.
I asked you something.
Give me a name.
Emir Sadettin Köpek.
Father...
If you still think I was behind this,
you can ask the emir
whether or not if I was with him.
I bring good news from him.
How is Gündüz, sir?
He'll recover, God willing.
He has opened his eyes, Candar Bey.
Abdurrahman told me Simon came
to see me with a tied-up woman.
Let's see what he has to say.
I come in peace, Ertuğrul Bey.
I've found out who made the attempt
on your family's lives and on my market.
I'm handing her over to you.