Episode 66 will start after 12:34 min.
What happened to your foot, Philip?
You're limping.
The work of an arrogant drunk.
I suppose you put him in his place.
A Bey's skill lies in
knowing if the devil is coming from
the right side or the left side.
I am Suleyman Shah's son Ertuğrul!
I want all the world to know...
that any fool who
hankers after what's mine...
will pay the penalty.
Take this bastard away.
Simon.
Thieves run wild here
and you're completely unaware of it.
Sometimes the dagger comes from
the place you trust the most, Ertuğrul.
You couldn't protect
your rugs against thieves.
You owe money to the French.
We're here to agree business
which might give bread to everyone.
But I see you are still wounded.
If we sit down at that table and...
shake hands, I believe that will
salve the wounds each of us bear.
There's no point dragging this on,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Simon.
I have no wish to offend a kind man
like yourself, nor a Bey like Aliyar.
Go ahead Ertuğrul Bey,
be the guest of honor at my table.
I told Simon everything
you discussed and agreed
with Candar Bey, Ertuğrul Bey.
What do you want, Simon?
Firstly, please forgive me for the
unpleasant incident that just occurred.
Let's disregard it.
And hope that it protects us from
further such wickedness.
All right.
I like to gather
business partners together
and have them shake hands.
The demands you and Candar Bey make
seem very reasonable to me.
I see that...
both sides are in agreement.
All we can say is "good luck."
And that, from now on...
my brother will take care
of business such as this.
What do we do now, Bey?
We'll show them who Ural is.
Turgut Alp.
How are the wounds
inflicted by your Ertuğrul Bey?
My wounds are fine.
But he's not my Bey anymore...
he's your partner.
It is you who must now
worry about being wounded.
What do you mean?
He's like the wolf
which has its claws in its prey...
he won't let go before
he gets a bite of its flesh.
When he goes hunting,
he never comes back empty handed.
And if he's out hunting with his pack...
there won't be any prey left.
Speak more clearly.
What I'm saying is...
be careful, Ural Bey.
You'll live to regret knowing him,
just like me.
I'd like to have a long talk
with you some time,
and hear more about your experiences.
Sure.
I live here now. I'll be waiting.
I stood up against the Pope's
scoundrels who vandalized Constantinople
and the many barbarians
who came from the North.
I lost my son, my wife,
and many men to this cause.
I established this bazaar with everything
I had left, Ertuğrul Bey.
I saw that the most difficult thing...
is to have brave and honest men
beside you that you can trust.
I've crossed many lands with my people.
I've seen every trick,
I've seen every act of treachery.
I could make a castle
with the enemy heads I've decapitated.
What I learned was
you couldn't trust anyone in those lands.
That's why my men will protect
the women in the bazaar.
I wouldn't want that burden anyway.
You Turks love fighting
as much as we love gold.
You get the battles... we get the gold.
One day, you'll wish
you had a sword at your side,
instead of pouches full of gold.
Let's not disrupt the peace, Ertuğrul Bey.
Let's enjoy the agreement.
Maria, let's get the table ready.
But don't bring wine.
We don't want to offend
our Muslim guests.
Ural Bey is a little upset about this,
am I right, Aliyar Bey?
I doubt it.
Ural Bey is skilled at trading.
He'll use his knowledge.
I see you're feasting before you
have paid your debt, Ertuğrul Bey.
My debt is still valid, Ricardo.
You can't come to my inn
and question my guests, Ricardo.
You want your gold?
Philip, give him his gold.
Your account is closed, Ricardo.
Now you owe me, Ertuğrul Bey.
You can pay me when
the rug house starts to make money.
Thank you.
I know for a fact that, sooner or later,
you'll rule not just this market,
but the whole of Bithynia.
I too believe that day will come, Amanda.
And I'll take you into my harem.
We won't have to meet
in secret anymore.
Now, find me the warrior
you praised so highly.
It's time I overcame these obstacles
and get rid of them, one by one.
Including the man I call my brother.
He's a threat to the tribe, sir.
I'm afraid he'll get in your way.
Do as I say.
My plan to win is
a massive undertaking, Amanda.
But you'll profit from it
like never before.
What do you need?
The women of Kayi
will not make it to the bazaar that day.
Let's see who Ertuğrul's wrath
is actually going to hurt.
No one can know I was behind this.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
But... what do I get in return?
Come on.
I see you've recovered well, Turgut Alp.
Thanks to God.
As long as I have the help of my friends,
my wounds heal
and my heart rests assured.
If your wounds have healed,
it's high time you came back.
I'm not coming back.
Until you spill the blood
of those cowardly ambushers...
every breath I take is a curse.
There's a right time for everything.
In the past,
if we were ambushed,
the Ertuğrul Bey I knew
would kill to avenge us.
But now...
Ertuğrul Bey designates the time
for everything.
From now on...
you rule...
and I hunt, Ertuğrul Bey.
Recover quickly.
And come to your senses.
Know that I'll avenge our sons.
Come, Bamsi.
Simon seemed impressed by you, sir.
He even paid your debt.
Simon wouldn't shoulder
anyone's responsibility.
He must be after something.
Let's wait and see what he does
to get his gold back from me.
My father was right.
I've got a lot to learn from you, sir.
Thank you.
Don't mention it, Aliyar Bey.
Your brother Ural...
He wasn't pleased.
It's up to you to deal with him.
My brother is unpredictable.
But my father has him
under control, don't worry.
I should get back
so that I can tell Father.
All right, give him my regards.
Thank you, sir.
Safe travels.
Ertuğrul Bey.
-Greetings.
I'd like to visit your settlement
to trade, with your permission.
You are most welcome, Merchant Hasan.
But I doubt our settlement
will satisfy you.
I'll be content with whatever, sir.
I want to buy milk, meat,
and cheese, not goods.
You are welcome anytime, Hasan.
Thank you, sir. God bless you.
Godspeed.
We must speak now.
Where are you going?
I must find out.
I must.
Ertuğrul will bring his men
on the pretext of protecting his women.
Isn't it dangerous for them
to be living with us like a cancer, Simon?
I do not believe Ertuğrul
is the sultan's spy.
I need him and his men
if I'm going to accomplish my mission.
We must gain his trust.
We are few in number.
I must pit the Turks,
Armenians and Greeks
against each other.
I needed two things to achieve this end,
and I got them both.
The passion of Ural
and the bravery of Ertuğrul.
If we pit them against each other,
our army will have an easier time.
When should I depart, Master Simon?
Head for the island of Lesbos.
As you wish, sir.
Go in good faith, Knight Tristan.
Maria, did we get the news
I've been waiting for from Konya?
We're looking forward to the dove, still.
My father taught me to share...
my food with my kin first.
And look what you did.
You can't prosper if
you don't share, brother.
Without sharing what you have,
you can't make friends or allies.
Did you go to Damascus to learn
these fancy words?
You permit our food
to be made a present
of to that questionable fellow.
Father prevented the catastrophe
you almost caused, brother.
What if Ertuğrul Bey
had found out it was you
who killed his Alps?
Through his decisions,
our father secured us a brave supporter.
Brother.
Don't you dare hurt us
with another mistake.
Pity. Such a pity!
We'll pay for your stupidity together.
Are you so blind?
Why do you carry this grudge
against Ertuğrul, brother?
Ertuğrul's wormed his way close to us.
Soon, he'll rush our tribe
with the few men he has left.
He'll get stronger.
Then he'll rule over this realm.
How can you not see this?
If he rightfully deserves it,
he shall rule.
May God let us not stray
from his just path.
For unity is only possible
through justice.
If there is a speck of doubt in that,
it'll be the end of us, brother.
The end.
And then you'll have neither a tribe...
nor your traditions left.
KAYI TRIBE
I'm relieved to hear
our Alps will provide security...
to our women at the marketplace.
Thank you, Mother.
We scared Simon a bit.
But that's all right.
If you scare your enemy once,
you can then win wars without a fight.
When will these games end?
I suspect Simon is John the Baptist,
Halime Sultan.
However, until we find out
who is behind him, and to what end,
we can't move on.
If Simon is the Crusaders' spy as you say
he'll want to go after Doğan,
who he believes is the Sultan's spy.
When he does, we'll do what's necessary.
With respect sir, it feels that
there's no end in sight to these games.
They will end, Halime Sultan.
They will end.
The day we establish our own nation,
the day our flag flies
over our heads, they will end.
God is merely preparing us
for more sophisticated games.
My hope increases the more
I see these tricks being played.
How so, sir?
There is nobody between here
and Iznik who could stop us.
If we could just get Karacahisar,
we can rush over to Sogut...
and raise our own flag there.
Why in Sogut, sir?
Sogut is the center
of everything, Artuk Bey.
He who rules Sogut rules the future.
Our light shall light
the darkness of the night.
As long as we don't fall into disarray.
As long as we don't become desperate.
What about Turgut Alp, sir?
He's invaluable to us.
He's our commander.
Yet he sides with the enemy.
If he's the man I know he must be
playing a game, Artuk Bey.
Or I'd have had his life
right there and then.
I can overlook anything, Artuk Bey.
But not betrayal.
HANLI BAZAAR
I want you to know that you
are not a burden on me, or on my brother.
You stayed by my side
for days on end, Maria...
but I have no wish
to burden you any longer.
I must leave no later than tomorrow.
Where will you go?
You turned your back on your tribe,
you have no one.
Don't worry, I can fend for myself.
I spoke to my brother.
He said you could work for him,
if you wanted to.
He needs a good warrior
such as yourself.
Maria...
I'm a warrior.
An Alp.
It's all I know.
How could I be of use to
a great merchant like Simon?
There are bandits everywhere.
They keep extorting us.
Problems occur when we make collections.
Bandits that have found out
we've been collecting raid us.
They steal our gold, murder our men.
So, in short, trade is a war
in and of itself, Maria Hatun.
Please stay.
I don't want you to get hurt.
I appreciate the sentiment.
I shall stay a while longer.
My brother will be very happy.
Let me go tell him.
Good night.
So, this is the doorway to Hell
you've been using.
Master Simon, the news you were
expecting from Konya has come.
-It's Ebu Nakkas.
-What does he say?
He says it's time.
He's waiting for you at the usual place.
-What about Turgut?
-He agreed to work for you.
Good. You and Philip shall train him.
Tomorrow, he joins the first collection.
-Learn the ropes.
-As you wish, Master Simon.
The spy in Konya is Ebu Nakkas.
Who is he? Who?
CAVDAR TRIBE
Thank you, sister.
In the name of God...
Here, my son.
Here, my girl.
Bismillah.
We must win over Ertuğrul Bey...
and become stronger,
that's the only way forward for us.
The path to China from Constantinople
passes through these lands, Father.
If we rule over these lands
we rule over the gold,
and thus, dominate everything.
All we need is stability.
These lands will be free of disorder
thanks to you, Father.
You are right.
Only we can provide stability.
However, we must first ensure
unity among ourselves.
Much depends on you two.
Don't take your eyes off Ural,
or his wife, Çolpan.
Any mistake they make could be
disastrous and lead to our destruction.
Don't worry, Father.
We'll do whatever is necessary.
-Sir, may I enter?
-Come in, Batuhan.
-You called for me, sir?
-Tell me, Batuhan.
Is your master Ural Bey
up to anything?
You tied his hand and foot, sir.
I'm watching him.
When he makes a mistake
you know what to do.
I'll tell you first, sir.
Go now.
Batuhan.
If you forget my words...
I'll cut your ears off.
First, he used Batuhan's knife.
Then, he made a deal with Ertuğrul.
Simon is behind all of this.
He's a merchant, sir.
His god is gold, his prayers, trade.
-Why would he do it?
-I'll find out, Çolpan. I will find out.
Keep your eyes open at the bazaar.
I need to know every step
Halime and Aslıhan take.
Don't worry.
They won't take a step
in the market without me knowing.
May I enter, sir?
Come in, Batuhan.
You know what to do?
Depart at sunrise.
-Amanda is waiting.
-Yes, sir.
What did my father say?
If I ignore his words
and not inform on you
he'll cut my ears off, sir.
Batuhan.
You're not afraid of him, are you?
Sir, you took me in
when I lost my parents.
You brought me up as a warrior.
I was trained to give my life for you.
And I shall die only for you.
I'll not forget your devotion, Batuhan.
Let me see.
Thanks, here.
If you're playing tricks on me,
I'll carve your eyes out, Amanda.
There's 100 gold coins inside.
What's this for?
Down payment for what you are about to do.
You'll receive 200 more afterwards.
I'd like to know who I'm serving.
Let's say an influential client.
I can't disclose his identity.
If I don't get my money,
I'll find you, Amanda.
You know where to find me
if you don't get paid.
What do I have to do?
Come with me.
Here is how you get your gold.
I hate Turks.
That's why you were chosen for this.
Welcome, Halime Sultan.
May this be fruitful for all.
Thank you. We too hope
everything goes well, Aslıhan Hatun.
They want you to...
kidnap Aslıhan Hatun and Halime Sultan.
Who are they?
Aslıhan Hatun is the daughter
of Cavdar Bey.
Halime Sultan is the wife
of Ertuğrul, Bey of Kayis.
The niece of Sultan Alaeddin?
The very same.
I hope our partnership proves fruitful.
If the wishes are sincere,
the outcome shall prove positive.
-Come in, everyone.
-Go on, women.
It's up to you, Francisco.
Find out how many guards there are
and which routes they take.
And prevent them from
coming to the market tomorrow.
Circle the weaving house.
Don't let anyone in.
Go. Go. Wonderful!
It should be done tomorrow.
-Banu Cicek Hatun.
-Yes.
Are you responsible for
the weaving house as well?
-Of course, Bamsi Bey.
-Praise be.
I have a matter to attend to.
Then I'll be back.
Go, get it done. Don't worry about us.
-Right.
-Go on.
Bismillah.
The women are ready, Halime Sultan.
Earnest women of Cavdar
and Kayi tribes...
From now on, the rugs, our very own work,
will reach the whole world.
And if it's blessed,
it shall bring us a fortune.
As long as we work together,
these looms won't lie idle,
and our tribes will know no hunger.
God willing.
It's time we worked as one, and honestly.
May God honor his name,
and bestow us with prosperity.
Amen.
Aslıhan and Çolpan Hatun will
deal with any problems you might have.
-Congratulations on our first day here.
-Amen.
Get to work now.
Just like her husband, Ertuğrul.
Courage is in their blood, it seems.
And you and your husband keep losing.
The war has just begun, Maria.
You don't know the Turks yet.
I heard that
you are about to fall for a Turk.
Yes.
I wouldn't believe
the things you tell me...
unless I convert.
Welcome.
May I know who our guest is?
I'm Maria, the sister
of the owner of this bazaar.
I'd like to invite you brave women
who have brought life to this market
over for dinner.
I'd like to welcome you to the market
on behalf of Innkeeper Simon
and the other merchants.
Greetings, brother.
Turgut, brother.
You must miss the food of your home.
I brought you food from home.
There is only food for heathens here.
Enough.
Leave me alone.
Brother, what's wrong with you?
How long will you keep running?
Brother, I miss fighting with you,
back to back.
Riding horse with you until they tremble.
Everything was great when
we were still together with our brothers.
When they were still alive
and not buried six feet under.
Turgut, brother!
You made a fool out of a Kayis...
in front of this scum.
You deserve a whipping now.
Go away, Bamsi! Go away!
Fight! Fight!
Fight!
Let me go!
-Let me go! You scum!
-Enough!
I won't tolerate
fighting in my inn, Bamsi.
Turgut works for us now.
Stop causing trouble.
Turgut, join the collections
with Maria and Philip.
Apparently, Kayis won't leave you alone
unless they see that you work for us.
You serve this scum now?
Pity, you were a brave man.
Right, brother. Right.
You were trying to tell me something,
but this half-wit Bamsi didn't get it.
Good man.
Well done, my brother.
Thank you for your kind offer, Lady Maria.
We always come here prepared,
but then, it is against our traditions
to refuse anything offered to us.
But we must first set up our stands
and put everything in order.
Very well, Lady Halime.
I'll be at the inn if you need anything.
Good luck.
Lady Aslıhan, Lady Çolpan.
We need to assign the patterns
to the women.
You're right, Lady Halime.
But we need to discuss what happens next.
This is our opportunity
to get our beautiful Turkish patterns
into palaces all over the world.
Our customers are Franks, Lady Aslıhan.
They don't like Turkish designs.
Let them get used to it.
It'll get them used to seeing us.
We will conquer their palaces
with our rugs for now,
then our brave men like Ertuğrul Bey
can conquer them with their swords.
Let's leave them do their work.
And we'll do ours.
The patterns need to be ready tomorrow.
If we work through the night
we'll have them ready easily enough.
I need to leave early,
there is a council meeting tonight.
If you wish,
Lady Aslıhan can go with you.
Then you can work through the night.
We do need to have those goods ready.
She is more than welcome.
My father doesn't know about it.
I can't, I'm sorry.
I'll let him know, Aslıhan.
We need to work day and night
if we're going to get the goods ready.
We'll be a lot quicker if
we prepare the patterns tonight.
Right, Lady Halime?
You are right, Lady Çolpan.
Very well, then. The Kayi tribe
will host sister Aslıhan tonight.
And who knows,
maybe a good fellow from the tribe
will see Lady Aslıhan and fall for her.
What's up, Bamsi Alp?
Still haven't given up on Turgut?
I have. I have given up on that traitor.
I don't care about him.
He is a donkey.
You can have him,
do what you want with him.
I'll take my leave.
I knew my brother wouldn't turn on us.
Yeah...
I got a little dizzy
after that punch, though.
But it's okay.
His hand is a like a rock, bless him.
Yeah! Ertuğrul Bey
will be very happy with this news.
Grand Master,
Ebu Nakkas has contacted me.
The long-awaited moment is coming.
I'm putting into action a plan to set the
Turks in the region against each other.
I will expect your orders.
Ertuğrul Bey, I thank God
for granting me the opportunity
to repay my debt to you
before taking my life.
The sand in the riverbed
is rich with gold.
The gold was unaffected by the storm
because it is heavier
than both rock and sand.
It resisted the tide.
It remains hidden amongst
the sand on the river bed.
Our task is to remove it
and carefully sift through the sand.
There is a cave on the banks of the river.
I would like to sift
the sand in that cave.
It'd be safer that way.
Do I have your permission?
Do what you think best, master.
Get that gold ready to fill our pockets.
As you command, Ertuğrul Bey.
But the river is deeper
and the current stronger than I thought.
We'll need some tools.
Get whatever you need from the bazaar.
But make haste.
The council is meeting tonight.
Yes, sir.
My Bey. My Ertuğrul Bey.
Come in, Bamsi, what is it?
My Bey. I went to see Turgut.
It seems that he was faking everything.
He hit me pretty hard, but I'm okay.
Bey, look. Look what he hid in here.
It's an encrypted message, Bey.
But I trust that, with this tool,
it will be easy enough to decipher.
I told you I knew my alp.
This letter
leaves me in no doubt
that Simon is John the Baptist.
This was a productive day, Lady Halime.
We've already made a lot of progress.
You're right.
The women of the tribe are good at this.
Sorry to interrupt your chit-chat.
But the women are tired.
And we should be on the road.
Let's call it a day, Lady Çolpan.
We can continue tomorrow.
Let's get things ready so that
we can get on the road before dark.
I'll let your father know that you'll be
with the Kayi Tribe tonight, Aslıhan.
Don't worry about that.
We have some hard work
ahead of us tonight.
I don't want to be a burden on you.
Nonsense, it will be an honor.
Dedicated women of our tribes,
thank you for your efforts.
You have done fine work
stitching the patterns of our ancestors.
Now it's time to go home.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
We'll take care of it if you like it.
Let's have a look at that one.
The scent of pine doesn't suit you,
my lady.
The doors and windows of the church
I used to attend were made of pine.
This scent took me back to those days.
I haven't visited a church
since my marriage.
May God forgive me.
Scent is a very powerful
stimulant, my lady.
I'd suggest this one for you.
Give it a try.
-What is it?
-Musk.
It's found in the skin of the male deer.
It is a scent for the evening.
It is preferred by women
who want to impress their men.
What are you doing here, wife?
I like to smell good for my Bey.
That's all.
My Ural.
What are you doing here?
Doing what a Bey does at the bazaar.
The sun is about to set.
Why are you not yet on the road?
We're leaving now, brother.
I have something to say to you.
Go ahead Aslıhan, what is it?
I am going to stay the night with
the Kayi tribe as a guest of Lady Halime.
We need to keep working
to get the goods ready for tomorrow.
Of course, Aslıhan.
We are now fraternal tribes.
They are like our family.
My Bey, Lady Aslıhan...
-If she's with that caravan--
-Batuhan.
If she is with them,
then no one will suspect us.
Oh my.
That man is still alive?
I thought he was dead.
He has a life debt to me.
How do you know him?
He used to be a fine master
when it came to gold.
When my father was a governor
he offered to extract gold for him.
My father didn't accept.
Gold?
Ertuğrul must have a plan
if he has set that man free.
Batuhan.
Find out what he's doing at the market.
What he buys or sells.
Find out.
So, Ertuğrul Bey...
We'll find out your intentions eventually.
Çolpan, don't be late.
We have things to do tonight.
I've never seen anything like this before.
But I'm certain I'll be able
to figure it out tonight.
I'm worried about the situation
my people are in, Artuk Bey.
He must have taken this secretly.
We need to get it back where
it was before it's missed. So hurry up.
Don't worry, Bey. I'll do my best.
-Good luck.
-Thank you, Bey.
Bey, these men have built
their lives on cheating.
Cheating is death to valor, Ishak.
They think they can manipulate people into
doing what they want with these traps.
What should we do in the face
of such traps, my Bey?
By sticking to justice, sincerity,
honesty, our values and our companions,
we can break all these traps, Ishak.
Well said, Bey.
My God, make our work fruitful.
Help Mohammed's followers, my God.
Let us be at peace with each other.
Disarm the traps set against us.
Don't let our lawful livelihood be soiled
with that which is forbidden.
-May God accept your prayers.
-Amen, Bey.
-How is business?
-Thank God, not bad.
I'm satisfied with today's income.
We make our earnings by following
the ways of the blessed Muhammed.
And we are happy to see traders like you
who make their earnings in halal ways.
Yes, you can be happy, Bey.
Yes, you can be happy...
yet you do business
with a Christian like Simon.
Yet we gave you the skins we had.
And I'm grateful, Bey.
But be wary of Simon.
-Why?
-Simon is after you.
He seeks to ally himself with us
so that he can grow stronger.
He's the sort of man who gives one
and wants ten back in return.
Haven't you just described all traders?
Simon doesn't just get what he wants...
he destroys his allies, too.
I just wanted to warn you, Bey.
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah....
buries his enemies deep in the ground.
Thank you.
My Bey, Lady Aslıhan has come with us.
There is some work that needs to be done.
Very well, Lady Halime.
We are to have a feast tonight.
You are fortunate, Lady Aslıhan.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you for hosting me.
Come now. We have things to do.
Welcome to our tribe, Lady Aslıhan.
Please.
Since I was a child,
I've done everything I could
to make him love me.
But he...
has always treated me like a stepson.
He is so cruel that he is incapable
of genuinely loving any of his children.
It's not you.
It is me, my Çolpan. Only me.
He trusts Aliyar completely. Aslıhan, too.
He doesn't care that I exist.
I've suffered so much
because of this tribe.
He seems not to care
about the hardship I've endured.
He made
Aliyar responsible for the business...
while he lost his mind in books.
Don't worry, my Bey.
Tomorrow's raid will bring
everyone to their senses.
First, he'll lose Halime.
Then... his beloved daughter Aslıhan.
Once we've taken control of the rug house,
it'll be Aliyar's turn.
Once the things clouding
my father's mind are taken away
he'll learn to trust me.
And if he doesn't?
Then...
it'll be his turn.
Which female servants were working
on the day Toktamis Bey died, Kutluca?
There were a lot of them, Bey.
Aybuke was in charge.
Where is this Aybüke?
Lady Çolpan sent her on an errand, Bey.
She hasn't been around for a while.
We need to find Aybüke, Kutluca.
Don't worry, Bey.
I'll find whatever hole she's hiding in.
Take a seat, Father.
What's wrong, Father?
Why have you come here at this late hour?
-It's Aslıhan, son.
-Has something happened to her?
No, not yet.
But... she can't go on like this.
Aslıhan has been rebellious
ever since she was a young girl.
Her honest and compassionate nature...
has sometimes got her into difficulties.
She'd never listen to me...
no matter how often I tried.
She has always followed the path
she considered to be right.
Everyone admired her beauty.
All these years...
I never wanted her to be married.
Do you want her married now, Father?
-Yes.
-Do you have someone in mind?
I don't want her to go far away.
She'll find peace
by the side of a brave and strong Bey.
The Kayi tribe is our neighbor.
I say she'd make a fine bride...
for the tribe of Kayi.
He who says "be" and it is done...
He who fills our hearts with faith,
with the almighty God's 99 names.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
We have been through hard times,
but thankfully we've come
to earn our daily bread.
Hopefully from now on,
our tribe will enjoy brighter days.
May God make our peace
and blessings everlasting.
Amen.
Enjoy your meal.
Thanks, brother.
Bey...
May I?
Go ahead, Ishak.
Bey, this is in Latin.
Are you sure, Ishak?
Ebu...
Nakkas...
will relieve...
the Weeping Rock's suffering...
on the first day...
of...
the...
new month.
How do you know Latin, Ishak?
My Sheik Ibn-ul Arabi
wanted me to learn it.
He said it might be useful
when the time comes.
Hey, my lion. My lion!
We've figured out the wretch.
-Let's tell the Bey, huh?
-Let's do it, Bey.
So, Ozan.
Go ahead and cleanse our souls.
Hay hay
Here I am on the mountain top
Summer is behind, winter is ahead
Winter is ahead
So it trembles in the lake
Oh, words fall short
Oh, hay!
I am at my wit's end
Let's send the foe to his glory
To his glory, to his glory
Down the road, to Ayvaz
Ride at full gallop
Hey!
Hay hay!
There's no cure, I will go blind
Let me marry Pasha's sister
Pasha's sister
Draw your sword
Behead the foe
Aslıhan, my girl, it's time
for you to get married.
The opportunity hasn't yet arisen.
I will do as my elders see appropriate.
Opportunity can co-exist
with your intentions, my girl.
If you have a young valiant man
in your heart
the opportunity
will present itself to you.
You just need to have the intention.
Ask for a good man to take your hand.
My mother is right, Lady Aslıhan.
Keep your intentions good.
Then God will provide you
with someone to love.
Let's find a brave fellow
from our tribe for you.
There's no cure, I will go blind
Let me marry Pasha's sister
Draw your sword
Behead the foe
Hey!
Ishak deciphered the heathen's code, Bey.
The situation is more complicated
than we thought.
There's a spy in the sultan's palace.
Simon will meet with the spy,
Ebu Nakkas, in the palace.
So, the treachery has made its way
all the way to the sultan's palace.
We need to learn his identity.
Simon is going to meet the spy
at the Weeping Rock, Bey.
We can learn it there.
Take this back to Turgut, Dundar.
He'll tell you if he has
discovered any new information.
Tell Dumrul to go
to the Weeping Rock at once.
Have him check the environment.
Observe the location.
As you command, Bey.
Dogan will go to the Weeping Rock
and find out who this villain is.
We won't be able to protect the sultan...
or these lands
if we fail to discover his identity.
What do you expect Ebu Nakkas will propose
at the Weeping Rock, Master Simon?
Nakkas won't make an offer
which isn't to his advantage.
Whatever he proposes,
there'll be some benefit in it for him.
The real question is...
what's in it for us?
The sultan's spy will probably be there.
I'll take the necessary precautions.
My dear friend Philip...
what would we do without you?
I want you to know
how much we appreciate your services.
Right, Maria?
The oldest worker at the inn!
How is business Cazgir?
Business is how you want it to be.
Let me know if anything is wrong
so that I can make it right.
This is exactly the kind of loyalty
and intelligence I look for.
My dear brother Cazgir.
Take the day off, enjoy yourself.
Drink all the wine you want.
You deserve it.
I don't drink while working, Simon.
And I don't stop working
till closing time.
His wisdom is too great
to fit into his physical shape.
Appearances can be deceptive.
You shouldn't trust anyone
without first knowing them very well.
Look who's here.
You must be hungry.
Have them prepare a meal for Turgut Bey.
So, Turgut Alp. You are one of us, now.
How did collecting go?
I hope it wasn't difficult for you.
No, it wasn't.
I gave the gold to Philip.
You didn't mention that, Philip.
There was no time, Simon.
Anyway. Tomorrow will be a tough day.
Enjoy your meal.
And he is one day older...
He spends his whole day trying
to become just like his father.
His hand was never
without its wooden sword.
Such a son is certainly worthy
of Ertuğrul Bey.
I was going to suggest we have...
the Seljuk emblem on the larger rugs.
Maybe we can add images of birds
and the tree of life around the sides.
-That'd be beautiful.
-And the earth-colored ones...
can have the Kayi emblem on them.
Images of wolves... or wolf prints.
It'll be very fitting.
Maybe we can add eagles
at the corners as well.
What will we use as a dye?
Let's use buckthorn berries.
And barberry for the yellow.
The flannel plant for green.
I've seen some near here.
Yes, but using the whole plant
would alter the tone of the green.
It'll be a better green
if we use only the leaves.
Very well, Halime Sultan.
I can see the outcome
before we've even started, thanks to you.
I remember the day
Lady Halime first came to the tribe.
Lady Selcan and I could hardly
believe the things she suggested.
But she somehow made it possible...
by using all different herbs,
and produced a variety of colors
we'd never even seen before.
And that's not all.
She came into our lives
just as my Suleyman Shah and I...
were coming to terms with the idea that
Ertuğrul couldn't be tamed
and would never give us grandchildren.
I'm really glad she has.
I hope God gives other mothers
a daughter-in-law like her.
Mother...
Amen.
May God never take you from our side.
My girl...
I also hope God gives you someone
to embrace and love dearly.
A brave and decent man.
Amen, Mother Hayme.
-Welcome, son.
-Thank you, Mother.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you, wife.
Excuse me.
As we must wake before the sun rises,
I'd better go to sleep.
Goodnight.
Have you put your business
in order, Lady Aslıhan?
Thanks to Lady Halime...
we are already halfway
towards finishing them.
-Goodnight.
Forgive me, God.
What am I thinking of?
What's going through my mind?
Get him out of my heart, God.
Don't exhaust me
with this incurable heartache.
You seem as tense as a bow, Halime Sultan.
Is something bothering you?
I just want to do my job
in the best possible manner, my Bey.
Thank God I have no other worries.
Why, then, do I see
your beautiful brow so furrowed
whenever you look at Lady Aslihan, Halime?
Do you have something to tell me?
Let me know.
Mom...
Water.
Of course, my Gunduz.
I'm not worried, my Bey. I'm fine.
There you go, my boy.
Good morning, Simon.
You too, Turgut Alp.
I'm not an Alp anymore.
You will always be
a brave warrior in my eyes.
What's up?
Taking a long road?
You could say that.
I'm going to see an old friend of mine.
I can accompany you if you wish.
Thanks. I must go by myself.
I heard you did very well yesterday.
Take the day off.
We'll have a lot to talk about
when I return.
Very well.
Bamsi. Don't you dare disappoint me,
you grizzly bear.
Don't you do that.
Take this one, too.
If I have your permission,
I'll be on my way.
I hope your trade went well, Hasan.
Thanks to God.
It was profitable for both parties.
Appreciate it.
You can come to my tribe
any time you wish.
You don't need permission.
Thank you, my Bey.
I appreciate it.
-Peace to you.
-Very well.
Dad!
Dad. Let me go to the bazaar with mom.
-Do you really want to?
-Yes.
Very well, then.
Take good care of your mom.
Come and give a hug to this lady.
Safe travels.
Thanks, my Bey.
-Mom.
-My girl...
May God protect you.
-Thanks, Mother.
-Go on, then.
All good, ladies?
My Bey.
Dumrul is back from the mission.
Artuk Bey and Dundar Bey
are waiting for you at their tent.
Very well.
I want those two women alive.
I will make all of you pay
if anything happens to them.
Go to your positions.
What have you learned, Dumrul?
The Weeping Rock is surrounded
by trees, my Bey.
It is sacred to the Greeks.
They visit this place on their holy days.
But why this place?
No one goes there on the other days
because it is such an eerie place.
It's a good place
to hold a secret meeting.
We'll have them surrounded
if we get to the road now.
No, Dundar.
We may well fall into a trap.
What's on your mind, my Bey?
You shouldn't get into a hole
if you don't know how to get out, Dundar.
They won't go
to the Weeping Rock unguarded.
After all, it is obvious that
they are expecting the spy from Konya.
My Bey... How will we get there?
By taking a road
no one will predict, Bamsi.
We shall take this stream.
We'll not only get to the hornet's nest
via this stream
but we'll also escape up it
if anything bad happens.
Now listen to me carefully.
Explain to Doğan
everything that I explain to you.
We'll take this stream.
Coming down to the stream,
some of the Alps will go into the woods.
I'm sure some of their men
will be positioned here.
Where are the women of the tribe?
On their way.
They'll be here soon.
What are you thinking, my Bey?
None of this would be happening
if it wasn't for Toktamış Bey.
That damned old man ruined everything
by breaking his promise to my father.
First Aliyar,
then Ertuğrul,
and finally, Simon's hypocrisy.
They'll all going to get
what they deserve, my Bey.
So long as you stand your ground.
Nobody's wife will be allowed to step
into the rug house
for which we've fought.
The partnership is over
before it even begins.
Ladies, Alps...
Let's stop here and take a little rest.
Bismillah.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Come here.
Come here, take a seat.
Thank you, Banu Çiçek.
Appreciate it.
Right.
Thank God.
Roads tire people out.
But the tiredness can be forgotten
if the destination
is a warm home.
-No, thanks.
-There you go.
My sweetheart.
You are very fortunate, Lady Halime.
Thank God, I am.
But nothing is easy, Lady Aslihan.
We have paid a high price
to build our relationship.
So why are you not married yet?
We talked about it yesterday.
I can help you marry someone
from the Kayi tribe, if you like.
Since my mother passed away,
I've never left my brother and dad alone.
I've taken good care of them.
Even if I were to marry someone
I doubt my dad would allow me
to meet anyone outside our tribe.
I see.
Come on, ladies. Let's be on our way.
Let's go.
Take these, too.
Watch the kids.
Kids, come on.
Alps!
Hide the children! Hide them!
Ladies, be on guard!
Jesus Christ!
What the hell?
Go!
Gündüz!
Everyone surrender!
Or every woman will die,
starting with the wife of your Bey.
Take them away.
Gündüz.
My lion.
Someone is coming!
Who is he, my Bey?
Hasan the trader.
My Bey...
Bandits attacked the women
going to the rug house.
I rode my horse here to tell you
as soon as I saw.
Gunkut, go to the tribe at once.
Tell them what’s happened and get help.
As you order, my Bey.
Bamsi, you know what to do.
Yes, my Bey. Very well.
-Oh, God!
-Come on.
-Go!
Come on, comrade!
What do you want, Dundar?
How many times do I have to tell you
I'm not coming back to the tribe?
It was mentioned but I didn't believe it.
So it is true!
Brave Alp of our tribe, Turgut,
betrayed his Bey and his tribe, huh?
If there is a betrayal,
I'm not the one guilty, Dündar.
Shame on you, Turgut Alp.
Shame on you!
Where is your Bey, brother?
He couldn't come, brother.
What is it? Did something bad happen?
Show your evil face already.
My dear friend.
I'm really happy to see you again.
All the borders will be subject
to a change.
We are now ready.
If you give me what I want
then we will both win.
What would you have us do?
Show your evil face already.
Brother!
Is there a problem?
Bandits attacked our women
on their way to the rug house.
But brother...
our Bey has assigned this mission to us.
Come on, brother.
Let's take them down. Come on.
That's as far as you get,
Sultan Aladdin's rats.
-God is righteous!
-So God help me!
Gündüz!
My Bey. They abducted Lady Halime
and Lady Aslihan. We couldn't stop them.
My Bey...
Gündüz!