Episode 64 will start after 12:52 min.
Sir, with your permission,
this man wants to see you.
His name is Philip.
He says he works with the innkeeper Simon.
You may speak, Philip.
Ertuğrul Bey, I bring you
Master Simon's regards.
Received. So, what's wrong?
On the way to Constantinople,
the Alps that were escorting your rugs...
they were attacked.
What, did he say attacked?
No!
Unbelievable.
How is that possible?
We must take revenge.
Silence! Can't you see Bey is talking?
Unfortunately, all your Alps were killed.
Except their commander, Turgut.
Master Simon sends his condolences.
You...
-What are you talking about?
-Bamsi!
Bamsi.
Where is Turgut?
At the inn, sir. They're trying to
keep him alive until you arrive.
Only he knows who did it.
It'd be in your interest to go there.
Sir, give me the order
to prepare to depart.
Ishak, you stay here.
-Ertuğrul Bey.
-Abdurrahman!
-Sir.
-Tell Artuk Bey...
he comes to the inn with me.
-Yes, sir.
-Son, what's going on?
We'll see, Mother.
You deal with the families
of the dead Alps.
Don't leave them alone.
Let them know
that the blood of our martyrs
will be avenged.
Bamsi. Let's go.
Yes, sir.
First Doğan Alp,
and now Turgut Alp as well, huh?
Let's see how this turns out.
Banu Çiçek!
Listen...
Everybody is already exhausted.
Do not open that damn mouth of yours
and rub salt into their wounds.
Got it?
One day...
-I will either kill my own blood, or--
-Father.
Don't talk like that.
There's no other way, son.
You'll invite Ertuğrul, personally.
Have you thought this through, Father?
Summoning Ertuğrul Bey and his family
will only fan the flames.
You said that Ertuğrul is a wise man.
But if he realizes that my brother
was the culprit...
You know what happened at the market.
That's why I'm inviting him,
so that he doesn't suspect Ural.
And I'm sending you, my own blood,
to ensure he can't decline.
Then what?
Do you think he won't suspect?
When he comes...
we'll give them a feast.
We'll tell them we heard what happened,
that we are sorry for them,
and that we are here
if he needs our support.
Also, that we're ready
to give him our men
when he goes looking for the killers.
Otherwise, either Ural,
or Ertuğrul will die.
We cannot prevent this, son.
Whatever the cost
I can't allow my son to be killed,
despite his treachery.
We'll convince Ertuğrul
and gain his trust.
When Ertuğrul Bey
learns that it was my brother...
-He will want revenge.
-Then...
we'll have to kill Ertuğrul Bey.
It won't be easy, Father.
So many would have to die on both sides.
The peace between our tribes
will be replaced with conflict.
Aliyar, go now,
and bring Ertuğrul Bey here at all costs.
Off you go, my son.
Guards!
HANLI MARKET
I've done all I can.
Anything more will require a doctor.
-Will he live?
-It won't be easy,
there's no one here
to care of him properly.
If Turgut survives to tell
Ertuğrul that it was Batuhan
the tribes will fight,
which will work to our advantage.
What if he dies?
I'm not about to leave it
in the hands of the devil.
Anton, make sure that Ertuğrul
receives Batuhan's knife today.
Give this knife to two of your
most trusted men.
Have them wait for Ertuğrul
at the Blind Spring.
When Ertuğrul comes,
have them tell him
that this knife belongs to Batuhan.
Yes, Master Simon.
Neither Ertuğrul nor Ural can know
we were involved in this.
-Make haste.
-Yes, sir.
And I shall have Ural and Ricardo
sit at the table they knocked down.
Filthy Turk! Not only did I lose
two of my best men...
I also lost 300 gold coins.
You are at fault
for trusting Ertuğrul Bey, Ricardo.
And you paid for it. That's all.
Ural Bey, don't push me.
My fellow Beys, stop arguing.
What's done is done.
Let us look forward.
Turgut might survive
and we can find out who did this.
Right, Ural Bey?
Whether he speaks or not
is of no concern to me.
All I care about is business.
Ertuğrul Bey, you promised
you'd make sure my rugs
arrived at Constantinople safely.
What happened? Tell me.
One of my men is hurt.
I must see him, we'll talk later.
Listen to me, Turk!
You owe me 300 gold coins.
Or I'll make you pay for it.
I'm Ertuğrul, the Bey of Kayi Tribe,
son of Suleyman Shah.
I keep my promises.
You'll get your gold back.
Ertuğrul Bey, I heard what happened.
You may be my rival
in the marketplace,
but I'm sorry for your loss.
You can be sure that I'll do
what I can for you, Ertuğrul Bey.
I shall not forget this favor,
Simon Efendi.
Where is my alp?
My sister Maria is taking care of him.
Don't worry.
Philip, escort Ertuğrul Bey
to Turgut Alp's quarters.
I'll visit you after
I put my affairs in order.
Let's go.
That was the price
of your cunning, Ricardo.
If we don't talk soon,
it's going to cost us dearly.
Even if doomsday is upon us,
business continues.
Gold coins still flow in.
It's the way the world turns, right, Ural?
Turgut, brother!
How could they do this to you?
-Excuse me, I'm the doctor.
-Of course.
Sword cuts in his arms and back.
But the worst one is in his abdomen.
There's no damage to his vital organs,
but he has lost a lot of blood.
I was a nurse
during the crusade in Palestine.
I'd like to help if I can.
Bring me more clean cloth.
Get some hot water as well.
Get a fire going quickly
so that we can burn his wound.
-Who found him?
-I did, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Where did you find him?
-Near Karacahisar Keep.
What were you doing there, woman?
We had collections to fetch from Tekfur.
As I said, I saw them on the road.
Are you sure my other Alps were dead?
As I said, I was a nurse.
I can tell the dead
from the living at least.
She's right, sir.
Her actions were justifiable.
Where are my other Alps?
My brother Simon had them brought in
to protect them from animals.
They are outside the inn, on a cart.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
You can go, sir.
I can handle it from here.
Give me the cloth, dear.
Your goods were burned.
Will you go back to Venice empty handed?
Ural Bey's offer is still on,
three gold coins per rug.
Also, to ensure they arrive
in Constantinople safe and sound,
my Alps and Ural Bey's men
will escort the caravan.
You'll be in safe hands.
What about the money I gave to Ertuğrul?
I'll deal with it.
I can make the collection for you.
If you'd like me to, that is.
I'm out of options.
The ship is setting sail
to Venice in three days.
We must get going, now.
Are you in, Ural Bey?
-Yes.
-Good.
With that matter dealt with, we can now
talk about our deal of 1,500 rugs.
Did you say 1,500?
Ricardo wants 1,500 rugs by spring.
He trusted me with it.
I'll carry the ball in Ricardo's stead.
I'll also take my cut.
If you are okay with it,
we can talk about it more later.
At last, we'll make profit from it all.
Bey...
Sir, my heart can't take it anymore.
We trained these men with Turgut.
We taught them how to hold a sword,
to use a bow, to ride a horse.
Sir,
they were loved by their families.
Now they rest here.
And Turgut is fighting for his life.
We'll find
whoever pulled this dirty trick on us.
We'll give them
the most terrible of deaths.
Whoever did this can't be human,
Ertuğrul Bey.
They're so low
that they'd murder men for rugs.
It's my duty as well as yours to make
sure they pay for what they've done.
They've blackened
the reputation of my marketplace.
What else do you know, Simon?
According to Maria, they came in numbers.
Many of their men died too.
She said it was a bloodbath.
Who are they? Do you know anything else?
-Where are the bodies of the murderers?
-They didn't leave the bodies behind.
They took their men with them,
and burned the rugs.
-Then they are not thieves.
-Right.
It seems somebody
holds a grudge against you.
Don't be suspicious of Ural,
he was in his tent last night.
His brother Aliyar will tell you the same.
He's not so low as to do something
of this caliber.
And even if he did,
make no mistake, his father Candar Bey
would kill him before you could.
That is Ertuğrul,
and beside him is Bamsi Alp.
What about that
inauspicious looking merchant?
That'd be Simon Efendi.
The owner of the market and the inn.
You may go. I can handle the rest.
-How is he, Artuk Bey?
-Maria looked after Turgut well.
If she hadn't acted when she did,
he'd have died a long ago.
The rest is up to our God.
All I know is that we can't take him
back to our tent just yet.
If we moved him an inch
it'd mean his death.
I'll take care of him, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll be sure to treat him
as if he was my own brother.
Bamsi, stay with Turgut.
We can't trust anyone here.
Not that woman, not the guards.
Sure thing, sir.
What if John the Baptist
is at the inn, sir?
If John the Baptist is Simon,
he'll want to gain our trust.
It means he must doubt me as well.
If I leave Turgut here
it'll make him think that I trust him.
We'll keep playing this game
until one of us finds out
who the other really is.
What about those who attacked
our horses?
We'll go after them, Bamsi.
You'll go after the slaver Tristan.
He'll take us
to John the Baptist for sure.
Bamsi Alp will stay with Turgut.
I'd like to pay you for the room
and your services.
There's no need.
I'm equally responsible
for what you've been through.
Turgut Alp is an honored guest of mine,
as well as Maria's.
Just like Bamsi Alp.
Don't worry.
So be it.
Bamsi, Turgut is in your hands.
Yes, sir. Yes.
Aykiz.
Aykiz?
Will he live?
He will live.
This Artuk man...
He's the best doctor I've ever seen.
Good. I want him to live, anyway.
I must make sure Ertuğrul
is Aladdin's guard dog.
I need Turgut to reveal
Ertuğrul's true colors.
We must keep him here,
whatever the cost.
You will offer yourself
to him if you must.
Make sure he falls for you,
so that I get what I want.
Don't worry, Master Simon.
Philip, come with me. We must talk.
Let's see who this Aykiz is.
Brave Turk!
Help me take off his clothes.
Don't worry, I won't bite him.
Repent, repent!
-What do you want?
-Stop!
I didn't mean anything by it, sir.
A man came up to me and gave me gold.
-What did he want?
-He said, "Tell Ertuğrul Bey
that if he wants to find out the truth,
he should go to Blind Spring."
Go.
Thank you, sir.
What is this pus festering in every line
and wrinkle of this market?
-You are obviously being led into a trap.
-They don't want to kill me,
they want to get me
to confront those who killed my Alps.
What will you do?
If I want to find out the truth,
I have to go.
Sir, what happened?
Kutluca, we can't allow Ertuğrul
to find out the truth.
We can't have our tribes
fighting each other.
Listen to me.
Are you sure Turgut didn't see you?
It was dark, sir. And my face was covered.
He couldn't possibly have seen me.
Good. We can't leave this to chance.
We can't allow Turgut to live.
He can't leave that inn alive.
There is a problem, sir.
What?
My knife, sir. I can't find my knife.
I must've dropped it during the attack.
What did you say, Batuhan?
If Ertuğrul finds it,
he will hunt you down. You fool!
-Go back and look for it.
-I did, sir, but it wasn't there.
-I must've dropped it somewhere else.
-Let's hope you're right, Batuhan.
Let's hope you're right.
Take our martyrs back to the tent,
Artuk Bey. Prepare them for the funeral.
-I'll catch up with you.
-Let me come with you, sir.
I won't be alone, Artuk Bey.
I'll go with my Alps.
May God be with you, sir.
How is your Commander Turgut,
Ertuğrul Bey?
He's pulling through somehow, Ural Bey.
Artuk Bey's proficiency as a doctor
precedes him.
All we can do is wish
him a fast recovery.
-Thank you.
-But I'm warning you, Ertuğrul Bey.
These lands are nothing like
the land we came from, the steppes.
Earning our lives as merchants
is not like hunting down men with swords.
I told you it wouldn't be easy.
The men running this marketplace
are worse than the Mongolian assholes.
Don't meddle in things
you don't understand.
This market makes a man feel
like a fish out of water.
Know your limits.
Thank god we haven't had to kneel
for gold yet, Ural Bey.
Looting is against our tradition as well.
We may not be good merchants
such as yourself, but we will take...
the heads of those looters,
whoever they might be.
Beware, this land is also home to us.
Nobody should labor under the illusion
that we are going anywhere.
Ural, I brought the fragrance
Colpan Hatun asked for.
You aren't jealous of my wife
by any chance, are you?
My dear sir,
I know you have such a huge heart
that we could both fit within it.
My present looks good on you.
Go to the inn some time. Talk to Maria.
-And don't leave Turgut alone.
-Don't worry, sir.
My son, who did this to you?
How could they do this to you?
My son!
Dad?
Let me see my dad! Dad!
I want to see my dad!
-Let me see my dad!
-Come here.
Come here, son.
Your dad wouldn't like you to
remember him like this.
His blood is like holy water to me now,
Mother Hayme. Let me see him.
All right. When the time comes, you will.
My love!
How could they do this to you?
How?
Come here.
Avenge our sons, Halime Hatun.
We can't let them trample on us
because we are weak and few.
That's right, they must pay!
We must avenge them!
Let's make them pay!
-We should avenge them!
We can't let them die for nothing!
Ertuğrul Bey is already
hunting the ones responsible for this.
You all know that Ertuğrul Bey
will not return empty handed.
That lowly scum will choke
on the blood they have spilled.
Brave sons and daughters of Kayi!
Artuk Bey is right.
Ertuğrul Bey has gone after
those who have made us suffer.
Five of our sons have died.
We'd forgotten this kind of pain.
But it also means that
we have reached the destination
Ertuğrul Bey promised us
way before we settled here.
That is the reason they are attacking us
like rabid dogs.
Now,
we must do what's right for our martyrs.
We must grieve solemnly, befitting
of our Oguz ancestors, as we wait for him.
Ertuğrul Bey keeps his promises.
We shall grieve
until we avenge our brothers.
Ertuğrul Bey wants the bodies
prepared for burial.
He said he will make it to the funeral
come hell or high water.
-Abdurrahman.
-Yes, Halime Sultan.
Begin the preparations for burial.
When Ertuğrul Bey returns
we will see what scoundrel laid this trap,
and to what end.
And then do what's necessary.
As you wish, Halime Sultan.
You represented your husband well
at this painful time.
You dealt with the problem
and soothed their pain.
Still, my heart aches, Mother.
I know.
We are the women of this camp.
Even when we grieve,
we must keep a smile on our faces.
Our words must give them hope.
Even if this camp burns to the ground
the whole world will witness us
unleash our anger.
Let's go.
THE VILLAGE OF ÇAVDAR
Aslıhan Hatun, your late mother
established this carpet weaving house.
You helped it prosper and grow famous,
how can you quit it now?
Why did you leave it to Çolpan Hatun?
How could she know what we do?
Don't leave us, we all support you.
-Please, don't leave us.
-Don't leave us.
This is the order of Candar Bey.
From now on this house is consigned
firstly to Çolpan Hatun, and then to you.
Skilled women of Cavdar!
The hope in your eyes
and the thrill in your hearts tells me
that you have heard the order
of Candar Bey.
From now on,
I will lead you and this house.
What's done is done.
We must look forward.
We got a lot of work to do.
We must weave new rugs.
My man, Ural Bey, will sell our rugs
all over the whole world.
Does anybody have anything to say?
What's done is done, Çolpan Hatun.
It's our duty to congratulate you.
Everyone, go back to work then.
We have visitors coming
tomorrow night, Aslıhan Hatun.
Candar Bey wants you to
begin the preparations.
He wants us to serve our visitors
and their families in a fitting manner.
And who might this visitor be?
Ertuğrul Bey, apparently.
I'm looking forward to getting to know
the man who impressed you so much.
What are you talking about, Çolpan Hatun?
Why would I care about him?
That wasn't what you said
at your father's table.
You talked at length
about Ertuğrul's mercifulness,
the way he saved that Armenian man...
It was the impression I got.
I couldn't care less what you think.
He's a married man, with a child.
If Ertuğrul Bey gets to
Korpinar before me
there will be hell to come.
May God help me prevent this trouble.
Don't let those that want
brother to kill brother run amok.
Grant me the strength and courage
of your beloved Prophet Ali
so that I can put an end
to it before it begins.
God, even if what awaits me is a trap,
help me overcome it.
You helped me become a bey,
trusted me with all those lives.
Don't let me die before I find those
who took the lives of my men.
Don't you worry, sir.
I won't disappoint you.
-Who might you be?
-Ertuğrul Bey sent me.
He said you had something to tell him.
That you'd tell him the truth.
So let's hear what you have to say.
He's lying, Ertuğrul Bey
was supposed to come alone.
-How did he know we were here?
-Let's find out.
Tell me...
how do you know it was Batuhan
who attacked Ertuğrul Bey's caravan?
Who are you? How do you know that?
Ertuğrul Bey would never believe
anything men like you might tell him.
So you must have proof.
Give it to me,
and then get out of my sight.
What were you
going to give Ertuğrul Bey?
-Are you guys all right?
-Sir, go on. We're okay.
It seems that somebody wants to get
to Korpinar before us.
What was it? Speak!
Knife.
Batuhan!
I never thought a Turk fighter like you
would weep for his friend.
If you were in his stead
would he come and weep for you?
-No.
-What would he do?
First, he'd find out who did it.
Then he'd weep for me.
What would he do
when he found the thieves?
He'd grab whatever was at hand,
his axe, his bow, doesn't matter what,
then he'd make them pay.
Not that I'd know.
What I can be sure of,
is that he'd make them pay for it
before he came to me.
And then come to your bedside
and pray and weep for you?
Yeah. Turgut is not just the head of alps,
he also has a tortured soul.
More so than any of us.
Everything you just told me
about Turgut Alp I already knew.
-What? How could you know?
-I see a man that knows how to love.
He kept calling for Aykiz in his sleep.
Was she his fiancée or his wife?
His wife.
Where is she now?
She's lying in the ground now.
Awaiting her man's arrival.
Amanda!
Stop annoying the man.
He's already in pain.
Bamsi, I've always liked
strong men like you.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable!
Amanda, when did you get back?
I came back from Nicaea this morning.
-Who is this good-looking Turk?
-Turgut.
Head of the Alps of Kayis.
Go Turgut!
Go!
Faster, Turgut! Come on!
Come on!
-I won! I won!
-I won!
-I crossed the line first.
-No, I crossed it first, are you blind?
-Ask Aykiz.
-She's your fiancée, I'm not asking her.
Bamsi, my man!
Dogan, where are you?
Where did you go?
Are you alive?
Did you fall off the face of the earth?
Unbelievable!
Brother, come and see
the state Turgut is in.
Come and see the state I'm in.
Brother, we are now at the mercy
of our greatest enemies, women!
I'll make you pay for the dead horse.
I gave you gold to buy me
a good horse.
And what did you do?
I asked you a question!
You spent it all on wine and women
and bought a sick horse!
If you don't find a good horse
before we leave,
I'm going to make you suffer.
You'll die of hunger.
This is your last chance.
Are you all right?
Why does he treat you like a dog?
If I don't find him a horse,
I'll not just be a dog,
I'll be a dead dog.
Don't succumb to hopelessness yet.
Come, let's eat,
and think about what we can do.
Come on.
What's wrong?
-Where are you guys going anyway?
-I'll tell you.
Maria, do you think this poor man in love
will live to see the morning?
I'll wait by his side till morning.
If he lives, he lives.
If he does get better, he'd suit you.
What would I do with a Muslim man, Amanda?
Love sees no religions.
He may even find Jesus
and the one true path of Christianity.
Poor man.
From the scars of torture on his body
I can see his life
has been full of hardships.
Who could be so brutal?
Who knows?
Only the Mongols could commit
such horrendous torture.
And also...
those wretched ones.
-Who?
-The Templars.
May the devil take the lot of them!
Vandals that didn't get their share
of our Lord's mercy.
I must get back to my store.
I'll come back tonight.
I've news from Nicaea.
We can talk more later.
Did you bring me
the fragrance I asked for?
Wait a while. I'll prepare it
and bring it with me tonight.
It might just bring Turgut to his senses,
and make him fall for you.
I'll be looking forward to it.
KAYI CAMP
There must be a reason
he left Turgut there.
You know Ertuğrul would never
turn his back on his men.
If he left Turgut there,
it must be for a fight.
Mother, what are you talking about?
Turgut is battling for his life.
How can he fight in that state?
The closer we get to our goal
the more they will attack us
like rabid dogs.
It's just as you said, you can't fight
these rabid dogs with swords.
If you can't outsmart your opponent
you'll never win the war.
Who knows?
Maybe Ertuğrul is doing
what the cuckoos do.
Cuckoo birds?
Cuckoos secretly lay their eggs
in other bird's nests.
Do you know why?
So that it holds on tight to life
when it hatches.
-May I come in, Halime Hatun?
-Come, Rahman.
The bodies are ready for burial.
Ertuğrul Bey has not yet come, however.
If he said he would come, then he will.
We should bury them
before it gets dark, Mother.
Let's go, then.
My god!
You said you killed them all.
We did kill all of them.
And we burned their rugs.
I killed Turgut myself.
Brother...
what have you done?
If you plotted Toktamis Bey's
death as well...
May God prevent me from going mad!
Hello, sir.
Hello.
I'd like to get to Kayi's settlement.
Do you know the way?
-Who do you want to see there?
-I have news for Ertuğrul Bey.
From whom?
-Why do you want to know, sir?
-Because I am Ertuğrul.
And who are you?
I'm the son of Candar Bey,
the Bey of Cavdar Turks.
The name is Aliyar.
What did you want to tell me?
Candar Bey would like to invite
you and your family to dinner.
My men were killed.
We are grieving.
Give your father my thanks.
-Some other time.
-Bey.
That's the reason
you should accept his offer.
To ensure there is not a speck of doubt
left in you.
Ural Bey...
Where was he last night?
At the village, sir.
Me, my father, my sister Aslıhan
and my brother's wife sat down and ate.
We talked.
I've been away studying in Damascus.
I've only just returned home.
They didn't let me down, thankfully.
Bey...
I know you took a client from my brother.
I understand your suspicions.
But know that it wasn't my brother
who did this.
Is that the reason
for your father's invitation?
To reassure and soothe me?
He was meaning to invite you
before this mishap, sir.
He respects you deeply.
That's why he sent me,
his son, and not an alp.
Just like everybody else, he knows
how great a warrior you are. He does.
Tell him I'll be his guest tomorrow.
Thank you, sir.
Batuhan's knife is gone.
Ertuğrul didn't know about it,
so couldn't have been the one who took it.
-Who, then?
-Only Petrus can answer that question.
-Tell him to attend the ritual tonight.
-As you wish, Master Simon.
Pray for the souls of our martyrs!
Mother, Ertuğrul hasn't come back yet.
He will, surely.
There he is!
I see five graves.
The graves of five brave men.
They are our first martyrs in these lands.
Know this, they will not be the last.
Today, we grieve.
We are burying five good men.
Until we claim these lands
as rightfully ours,
every battle is going to be filled
with such treachery.
We will suffer more with each passing day.
We will not yield to the treachery
of our enemies, not in a thousand years!
We will not allow these two realms
to turn us to dust.
I know you will never turn
your backs on me,
even if all our sons and men perish.
We're heading into the most treacherous
and evil battle the world has ever seen.
Losing is not an option for us.
This land, like every other land,
belongs to God Almighty.
We have overcome all kinds of trouble.
Now we'll put down our roots in this land.
Let me say this in front of our martyrs.
May God let me be a martyr
in a war which could last
a thousand years or more.
-Amine!
-May God help us keep to our path!
-Amen!
Allahu Akbar!
May I come in, sir?
Come.
I couldn't find the knife, sir.
An alp that loses his weapon
is no alp at all! You fool!
Get out of my sight!
Were you looking for this, brother?
It still bears the blood
of the Kayi alps you murdered.
Clean this knife well.
Clean it, as if to clean
your filthy conscience.
Brother...
Aliyar!
How many more times will you slander me?
What do you want? I've had enough!
Aliyar, stop talking in circles.
Tell me what you know.
My father and I both know very well
what you're up to, brother.
Brother Aliyar!
Get back! Get back!
Whoa!
My brother, we sent you away
to educate yourself,
but you've returned a fierce Mongol!
Don't come anywhere near me, brother.
We know what you're up to.
What the hell do you know?
Ural! Aliyar!
Come to my tent, right now!
I've had enough, Father!
Do you believe his words as well?
How long do I have to put up
with their attempts to smear my name?
What's happening here?
Tell me what you know.
Is there anything I know
which you don't already?
Father!
I know what you've been up to, Ural.
I also know you cannot be redeemed.
You are the biggest
threat to our survival.
If you weren't my first child
with your late mother
I'd have killed you long ago.
-Father--
-Aliyar saved your life.
Not just yours,
those of many of our men, too.
Do you know why?
Because he found Batuhan's knife
and stopped Ertuğrul
getting his hands on it.
Ertuğrul is not a fool like you, Ural.
Pray that I succeed in convincing him
that you are innocent.
When they arrive, you will serve them,
along with your impudent wife.
You will show them respect.
Do you understand?
Brother...
Guards.
-Father...
-Aliyar, leave me alone.
Guards!
The same people who killed our Alps
got to Korpinar before we did.
They followed us to the bazaar.
The degenerates were right behind us.
Clearly, he is afraid of the consequences
of revealing the truth.
Being afraid is no good
in the face of the death.
My God, please deliver me
from spilling Muslim blood.
What are you saying, sir?
I'm suspicious of Candaroglu Ural Bey.
Unfortunately, nothing else is possible.
He didn't take it well
when we sold our rugs.
He's never wanted us on these lands.
I hope Ural Bey is not so contemptible
that he would spill the blood
of Muslims for a few coins, sir.
That's not all. Candar Bey was
desperate to invite us to his tent,
he even got his son to invite us.
That and Ural Bey's threats towards me...
If that's the case,
many will die from both tribes.
There will be fierce battles ahead.
If Candar Bey doesn't sacrifice his son,
we're not strong enough to fight them.
We will find a way, Artuk Bey.
Then we will shake the tree by its roots.
If Candar Bey fails to deliver justice,
we will rip the tree out.
-One more, brother?
-Sure.
Here you go, brother.
You are quite a drinker, Bamsi.
And still standing, like a pillar.
My late father was a hardened drinker too.
He could drink three pints
without any sort of bother.
-Three?
-Yes.
Three it is, but never mind the numbers.
Now tell me something.
You bought my horse, where are you
headed with your master?
-The island of Lesbos.
-Lesbos?
Man, where is that?
Get on a ship in Constantinople.
Okay.
Go through the Dardanelles.
So I do, brother.
-Go straight ahead.
-I'm going straight ahead.
-Keep going for a while.
-I am, brother.
So I keep going, I've been through
these Dardanelles. Then where am I?
Lesbos, for God's sake.
-It's an island.
-An island.
It's a huge island.
-A huge island.
-Yes.
Pirates take the slaves they've captured
in the Mediterranean to Lesbos.
And Master Tristan...
goes to Cunda, across the island,
-buys the best slaves...
-He does.
...brings them to the bazaar
and sells them.
-Get it now?
-I do, man. I do.
Dardanelles, Lesbos, Cunda.
-Cunda, Lesbos...
-Dardanelles.
Pour us one more!
-One more glass of wine.
-Yes, one more.
There you go.
Take care.
Dardanelles, Lesbos, Cunda. Dardanelles...
Lesbos, Cunda.
Dardanelles, Lesbos, Cunda.
-Are they downstairs, John the Baptist?
-They are waiting for you, sir.
Here we go, sir.
Mentor Nicola D'artagnan.
Welcome to the residence of your loyal
guards, Mentor Nicola D'artagnan.
May God bless you all.
John the Baptist, as you'll have guessed,
I'm here because of Ertuğrul.
Everything you need to know
about him is written here.
Mentor Petruccio
of the crusader region of Antakya
wrote it himself.
After Mentor Petruccio
was killed by Ertuğrul,
a young knight salvaged this book
from the Turks and brought it to us.
The very last lines were written
by that brave knight.
-Is he also the killer of Titus?
-Yes.
-The war has begun, John the Baptist.
-What do you require of me?
Ertuğrul's presence here
cannot be a coincidence.
I want you to kill him immediately.
Petrus, my dear boy!
Welcome, Mentor D'artagnan.
It was a relative of Ural...
who took the dagger and killed our men.
-Aslihan?
-No.
Aliyar.
Everywhere is surrounded
by a mighty fog.
One does not simply see
or hear the other.
The war between life and death,
conscience and gold,
purity and corruption, continues.
And we are in the middle of it, sir.
People are trading
and laughing with each other,
while digging each other's graves.
On one side, there are the Crusaders
who set Constantinople alight.
On another, the emperor
who fled from the Byzantium.
And finally, the Turks,
who want to make these lands their home.
Don't forget the bandits,
vandals, pirates...
The local people of these lands
are crying their eyes out.
This is a complex war, sir.
As you said, it's a war between
existence and extinction.
We will make our way out
of this blinding fog.
We will draw our swords
only once, Artuk Bey.
God willing, sir.
And once we do, these lands
will meet with justice and freedom.
Is this the reason you accepted
Candar Bey's invitation, sir?
Everything begins
in the tent of Candar Bey, Lady Halime,
and ends under the soft light of the inn.
We have to figure our way out of this fog
without making a mistake.
That's why we accepted
Candar Bey's invitation.
So you want to play, Aliyar.
The one thing more dangerous than
a brave enemy who knows how to fight
is an enemy who is smart enough
to see and take control of the game.
The game we set was taken down.
Damn it!
I will chop off your head.
What should we do now, Master Simon?
We will give the murderers
of those Alps to Ertuğrul Bey.
No matter what it takes, the two Muslim
tribes must fight each other.
The blood of your own kin is cursed.
No one can stem it once it's spilled.
Right.
You are right, Master Simon, but we lost
our only leverage against Ural.
You are wrong, dear Petrus.
Our greatest leverage
is the ambition of Ural.
This ambition will be the end
of him and of his tribe.
Aliyar is trying to stop
the war his own way.
But it has already begun.
Esselamu aleykum ve rahmetullah.
My God,
please forgive my sins.
I raised Ural.
I took good care of him. I thought
he was the great hope of the Cavdars.
Now, I'm afraid my tribe
will pay the price for my sins.
Help me kill the demon
inside my son, God.
I won't forget this favor, Lady Aslihan,
it is much appreciated.
Bey of the Kayis.
A brave man.
Fought and won many battles.
A true gentleman.
Thank you, Lady Aslihan.
Enough is enough.
Tell me everything, Lady Aslihan.
No matter how much you, my father
and Ural try,
-you won't be able to hide the truth.
-What do you mean, Aslihan?
We know very well
who killed Ertuğrul Bey's Alps.
Lady!
How did you arrive at that conclusion?
It was Ural and you know it.
Ural is my husband and your brother.
Save the speech, Lady Colpan.
Ural is bringing us closer to our doom.
As his wife, you should take care of it.
That's all I have to say.
Liar! You can't blame Ural Bey.
If I hear you speak any more lies
about him you'll pay dearly for it.
And that's all I have to say.
I've prepared the gifts
we'll take tomorrow.
These are fine gifts.
Small, but valuable.
The most valuable thing...
is to be a guest in his tent
with my wife and mother.
Only if they understand its value.
With all your suspicions about Ural Bey...
I have no doubts about Candar Bey,
Aliyar or Lady Aslihan.
-Who is Lady Aslihan?
-Candar Bey's daughter.
She helped sell the rugs.
Is that so?
She must be a very kind woman.
Your wound is worse.
It'll heal.
Before it does, those who wounded me
will pay for what they've done.
I don't doubt that, sir.
But how did Aliyar acquire
the dagger of Batuhan?
Before long, I will figure out...
who is behind this.
Simon's sister found Turgut, right?
-What is her name?
-Maria.
What if she found the dagger?
-Then it was Simon.
-What's done is done, sir.
Candar Bey is watching every step
you take, every move you make.
As if all this wasn't enough,
he appointed Aliyar to protect me.
And Aslihan knows everything.
The situation has gotten out of control.
What are you implying, my Çolpan?
It's high time we took control
of the tribe and the bazaar.
Simon and your father
won't put up with you for much longer.
Aslihan and Aliyar will see to that.
I can't let that happen. No.
I will crush whoever stands in my way.
-Don't you know that, my Çolpan?
-What about your father?
Will you crush him, too?
Do you doubt me, my Colpan?
Of course not. Never.
Get up!
We have business with you.
-Selamun aleykum.
-Aleykum selam.
I can't even look at your...
or at the faces of these young Alps, sir.
It wasn't gold that kept us here
for a thousand years, Hacaturyan.
And it never will be.
We follow God's path.
Our destination is clear.
This old head of mine
didn't show me the right way.
But if I go once more,
I can find the right path.
Give me one more chance, sir.
That's enough, craftsman Hacaturyan.
Go and rest.
If you want to pay your debt to me,
go and lead a peaceful life in my tribe.
Share your wisdom with the young,
so that they may have the most
valuable asset in the world: a profession.
-Do you understand?
-I do, sir.
Brother, Abdurrahman told us
what happened. How is Turgut Alp?
He will get better, with God's permission.
We are to be guests of Candar Bey.
The tribe is yours to protect.
Are these the men who killed the Kayi Alps
and burned the rugs?
Yes, sir.
Is that all of them?
We alone will know what Ural did, right?
Yes, sir.
Are you man enough
to keep such a secret, Batuhan?
I am, sir.
We will see, we will see.
What will you do now?
I will tell you every single
step Ural Bey takes, sir.
Have no doubts, Mentor Nicola.
Ertuğrul will die.
You'll pay a grand price if you
delay this mission, John the Baptist.
I can't understand why
you're so afraid of a Turk.
You don't know him. You'll understand
more once you've read the book.
If I kill him, I'll never know
if he is the Sultan's spy.
I need more time.
Until Easter then, Simon.
If Ertuğrul isn't dead by then,
the council will send someone else here.
As you wish, Mentor Nicola.
Saadeddin Kopek will be here soon.
Don't forget, he'll be your closest ally.
You both have the same enemy.
Sultan Alaaddin.
The only reason you have such
an important mission at this young age
is my trust in you.
Don't let me down
in the eyes of the council.
They are coming.
Here he comes with his family.
Yes, the tribe of Kayi.
-Abdurrahman.
-Yes, sir.
As I said, stay sharp.
Keep a close watch of Ural and Batuhan.
Don't worry, sir.
-Welcome.
-Welcome, sir.
Where is Ural, Lady Çolpan?
Must have important business, sir.
Brave Alps of Cavdar!
-Selamun aleykum.
-Aleykum selam.
Welcome to my home, Ertuğrul Bey.
We are honored to have you here.
The honor is mine, Candar Bey.
Lady Hayme, my mother.
Lady Halime, my wife.
Our loyal doctor, Artuk Bey.
Welcome, all of you. Aliyar, my son...
Aslihan, my daughter...
Lady Çolpan, wife of Ural Bey.
He will be here soon.
Go ahead, come in.
Ertuğrul Bey
and his family have arrived, sir.
Very well.
-What happened with the old man?
-Just like you said, sir.
He killed the men
with whom we raided the Kayi caravan.
Is that all? What else?
He wants to know every move you make.
Good, then you'll tell him everything.
Let's not keep the guests waiting.
Come on.
Thank you.
No peace or trade is possible
where bandits roam free.
I assure you I'll do all I can to help
when you go after those bandits,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I want you to know that we are sorry
for your martyrs, Ertuğrul Bey.
We can't find peace or prosperity
in these unclaimed lands.
Order can be provided by a certain man,
Aliyar Bey. Sultan Alaaddin.
Who has the duty until that holy day
comes and our flag dances in the wind?
It's our duty...
to stop the bandits and restore order.
We have to protect our religion,
honor and goods
until that day comes.
-Selamun aleykum.
-Aleykum selam.
Do I have your permission, sir?
Go ahead, Ural Bey, sit.
Welcome.
Thank you.
-I was waiting for you.
-Really, sir?
Ertuğrul Bey says it's our duty
to restore order in these lands.
And to stop the bandits.
I wish to make a pact with this brave
and honorable Bey and live in peace.
That's why I wanted to take
the first step.
The Venetians want 1,500 rugs from us.
It's almost impossible to deliver
such an order until spring.
But if the skilled ladies
of the two tribes join forces,
then I say everyone will win.
What are you saying, sir?
As a token of our friendship,
I offer business to the Kayis.
I have already said what's on my mind.
The important thing now is
to find out what's on Ertuğrul Bey's mind.