Episode 65 will start after 12:34 min.
The Venetians want 1,500 rugs from us.
It's almost impossible to deliver
such an order until spring.
But if the skilled ladies
of the two tribes join forces,
then I say everyone will win.
What are you saying, sir?
As a token of our friendship,
I offer business to the Kayis.
I have already said what's on my mind.
The important thing now is
to find out what's on Ertuğrul Bey's mind.
First of all, you honor us, Candar Bey.
We believe prosperity comes from God.
We can at best appreciate the middleman.
Before giving a response,
I'd like to discuss it with my family.
I value their opinions.
You are right, Ertuğrul Bey.
This partnership would affect
both the men and the women of each tribe.
I don't want anything to spoil my hosting
you and your family here tonight.
We'll see what the new day holds for us.
HANLI BAZAAR
-Do I have your permission, Master Simon?
-Come, Petrus.
-Everything is ready for the ceremony.
-I'm coming, Petrus.
Candar Bey is hosting Ertuğrul
and his family tonight.
Wise old man Candar.
So he figured out Ural
was the one who led the raid.
He's trying to end the war
before it even begins.
We'll soon see what comes of it.
This business has come to us
in our time of need.
But there is something
I've been wondering about.
Why are they offering it to us?
No gazelle runs to its hunter, Mother.
Candar Bey has his reasons.
It's payment for our Alps' blood.
Our two tribes are not at war,
why would they pay the price?
Who benefits from our rugs being burned?
And who makes a loss?
I suspect it was Ural Bey
who burned our rugs and killed our Alps.
We think Candar Bey is trying
to put out the fire set alight by his son
to prevent Ertuğrul Bey
going after him, Lady Hayme.
If it was indeed Ural Bey
who had our Alps murdered,
then he must pay for it.
And if Candar Bey knows what he has done
but chooses to go this way...
then we must stay sharp.
Mother, everything points to Ural,
but we don't have any proof.
We'll stay silent until we can prove it.
Keep in mind that
these lands are dangerous.
Ertuğrul Bey, if you accept this offer,
let me and my mother manage it.
We can't leave the management
of the rug house to Colpan and Ural.
You will manage the rug house,
Sultan Halime.
That will be our only condition.
I will make them pay
for what they have done.
I put so much effort into getting
this business from the French traders.
Why, Father? Why?
So, that you can just give our
earnings away to some newcomer?
The tribe of Cavdar has got to this point
not by increasing its enemies,
but by decreasing them.
Father, you can't be sure
the Kayis are our friends or our enemies.
You talk about the power of Cavdar,
but all you're doing
is spoiling a bunch of peasants.
Let's deal with the situation properly.
We have the power for it.
I too know what we're capable of.
This partnership is necessary
for the sake of both tribes.
I don't want to hear any objections.
Aliyar,
you will manage this.
As you wish, sir.
Ural will help you.
Sir, who will manage the rug house,
the women of the tribes?
We'll talk about that tomorrow.
Let's wait until they
accept our offer first.
That's all I have to say.
I can't understand why the old man
has suddenly decided on
making this partnership, brother.
The most important thing is that Father
has made a fair and just decision, right?
I hope there aren't any ulterior motives.
Calm down, husband.
This way, everyone
will reveal their thoughts.
You'll find out who is an enemy
and who is an ally.
The price of that will be too high
for me, Lady Colpan.
I can't stand sharing our gold
with a half-wit like Ertuğrul.
But do you know what's worse?
I've never seen...
my father look so afraid.
What is he afraid of?
Of war. Of spilling blood.
He used to make the earth tremble,
but now...
he's too afraid to do what must be done.
How will we prevent this partnership?
We won't... Simon will prevent it.
Why would Simon do such a thing?
Simon...
always thinks of rebels like Ertuğrul...
as potential threats.
When he learns
Ertuğrul is involved in this...
he won't give him a place to rest in
his bazaar, let alone a stand.
He'll choose me!
This book contains very
valuable intelligence.
It was written by Mentor Petruccio
of the crusader region of Antakya.
Before Mentor Petruccio died,
he left us crucial information
about Ertuğrul.
He is brave, courageous,
god-fearing and religious...
He seems a worthy rival,
as noble as a templar.
But that is not enough.
We will be the ones
to complete this book.
There are two things we don't know.
Does Ertuğrul obey Sultan Alaaddin,
and if he does, is he the spy?
We'll find out tomorrow.
Disciple Tristan.
Step forward.
From now on, you are a knight.
And as a knight, your first mission
is to sacrifice yourself if that is
what's required to take down Ertuğrul.
In the name of the Father...
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
I declare you a knight.
I'll be loyal to you always, Master Simon.
He knows you caught
and exposed the spy in the bazaar.
He will certainly come after you
on the way to Lesbos.
He'll try to catch you and get you to talk
in order to learn about me.
I'm absolutely sure of it.
By setting this trap, we'll know for sure
whether Ertuğrul is actually the spy.
Knight Philip will accompany you
in your first mission.
May God protect you.
Let the ceremony begin.
The rug house can be built here
and the rugs made by our tribe.
But both sides
will want to have it in their tribe.
-What's the solution, sir?
-The answer is obvious, Artuk Bey.
The most appropriate
place is... the bazaar.
It has a critical role to play.
What are you thinking, sir?
The bazaar is the cradle of filth.
We can't clean the filth without going in.
We'll get to the source of the filth.
That's a very wise decision, sir.
Well said.
Sir? May I?
Come on in, Bamsi.
-I have news for you, sir.
-Take a seat, tell me.
Where is the trader heading?
Sir, the trader is going
to Lesbos tomorrow...
in order to buy slaves.
Then, let's give him a brand-new slave.
They will use the trader as a bait.
They want to lure
the Sultan's spy into the trap.
Then we will tear that trap apart, sir,
have no fear on that score.
No, Bamsi.
We're going to give them what they want.
Sir?
We're going to let them capture you?
Not me, Bamsi. The spy who'll replace me.
That will confuse John the Baptist.
He believes Ertuğrul Bey is the spy.
I see, I see.
You're suggesting they catch me
so that I can mess them up.
Not you, Bamsi.
Then who?
Go to the bazaar. He will find you.
This is where we meticulously
handcraft our rugs.
Our girls and women are very hardworking.
Each of them is a master craftswoman.
May God reward your efforts, my girl.
I heard you run this place.
You are clearly a woman of many skills.
Aslihan used to take care of this place
until she revealed her brother's business
to Ertuğrul.
This is not the place, Lady Colpan.
Watch your words
when you are with our guests.
What's the problem, my girl?
Whatever Ertuğrul has to deal with
is also our concern.
Lady Aslihan told him about the deal
between Ural and the Venetians.
Ertuğrul Bey made them a better
offer and sold them his rugs instead.
That is the nature of trade, Lady Colpan.
Certain skills are required.
My words alone are not enough.
Of course, it requires some skills.
But a good partner...
would ease the burden.
When Ertuğrul Bey makes his decision
we'll be partners not rivals.
You can tell him whatever you want then.
Hold your sword tight
and don't use the strength in your arm,
use the strength in your heart.
-Selamunaleykum, Bey.
-Aleykumselam, Aliyar Bey.
All my life, I have searched for wisdom.
I hope you have found
what you were looking for, Aliyar Bey.
Imam Ali says;
"There are two infinite things;
one is knowledge, the other is wisdom."
My search continues.
In these lands...
there is nothing but blood, sir.
Blood.
The men of these lands must be brutal,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Or else...
they're food for the worms.
Got to keep yourself trained.
But you should be merciful while training,
Ural Bey.
There is no place for mercy
in fighting, Ertuğrul Bey,
else you'll give your enemy
the chance to stab you in the back.
Then try to make friends, Ural Bey.
Friends...?
There comes a time
when even your brother leaves you.
You of all people should know that.
Ertuğrul Bey.
We are ready.
Excuse me, Bey.
I'll go check on the preparations.
Very well, Aliyar Bey.
I heard Lady Aslihan
got into trouble for your sake.
Her father demoted her
because she told you about the Venetians.
Are you sad because
Lady Aslihan got demoted
or because she told me
about the Venetians?
No, my husband. May she live long.
Thanks to her we sold our rugs.
But I wish I'd known about it.
So that I could have
thanked her in person.
Then have no worries. You'll have
plenty of time to talk to each other.
Thanks, thanks!
Come here! Come here, kid!
Come here, kid! Come here!
Don't run! Damn!
Going after a kid for a piece of ham?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
It's not about the ham, it's about
the kid thinking he can steal from me.
I might believe that if I didn't know you.
I told you that big belly of yours
would get you into trouble, you half-wit.
Hold your horses. Don't.
Come with me.
My comrade.
My dearest friend.
What have they done to you?
You've turned into a beggar.
Looks good on you.
So, how is work?
Manage to earn a couple of coins?
I wish. No one listens to
their consciences anymore.
I'm just glad not to get beaten up.
I see you are healthy.
You've got bigger.
Bigger? No, my friend, no.
We weren't even able
to eat properly until yesterday.
Ertuğrul Bey managed
to sell the rugs, thank God.
I know, brother.
I know about everything.
You really thought I was a beggar?
I'm always in contact with Ertuğrul Bey.
My brother, my comrade.
Welcome back, my brother!
Anytime I find myself in pain...
I look out the window, too.
It's like a horseman
from some far-off land...
will come and take me away from here,
take me away from all the pain.
I've prepared some medicinal tea for you.
It'll ease your pain.
Thank you.
They won't be able to come...
those I wait for.
They all...
lie deep in the ground, now.
I only see my own painful end...
when I look out the window.
You and I look at the same place
and see the same thing.
I could show you my dreams...
if you wanted to see them.
I have been living
in other people's dreams.
That's why I'm in this mess right now.
From now on,
I will see my own dreams...
even if they turn into nightmares.
Selamunaleykum. Well...
May I, brother?
Aleykumselam, Bamsi.
If you are here
to talk about your tribe...
you should know that
I haven't changed my mind.
What happened to you, brother?
Did the sword of the heathen
rip through your soul
as well as your body?
It wasn't the heathen's sword
that ripped through my soul...
It was Ertuğrul Bey.
We lost our loved ones...
because of the decisions he made.
I still grieve for my girl.
Not only that...
we left our home,
and our loved ones behind.
Despite everything,
we stood by his side,
even when his own brother didn't.
And what did he do?
He made us bait, to sell his goods.
He risks our lives so he can make money,
just like he risks them when we fight.
Ertuğrul Bey is neither a skilled
trader nor a good warrior.
Brother...
Do you hear what you are saying?
Brother, what have they done to you?
Have they poisoned your mind?
These words don't belong to you.
I will burn this inn down
if you have poisoned my comrade.
Enough!
Enough.
I'm in my right mind.
More so than ever.
From now on...
there is only one way for me.
And it's my own way.
You can have... the way of Ertuğrul Bey.
We...
will not deviate from his way.
We made a promise.
A promise.
You have broken that promise, brother.
You have gone against its principles.
The shame of that
should be enough for you.
I'll take my leave now.
Bamsi Alp.
Bamsi Alp, wait.
I'm so sorry.
But you should try to understand Turgut.
Just like you, he's been through a lot.
Maybe you should listen to him?
Actually, actually maybe
his tongue should be torn out!
Sometimes violence isn't the solution,
Bamsi Alp.
Instead of cutting out his tongue, why
don't you tell him what you want to hear?
I'll cut his tongue off first,
then it's down to you whether you use it
to get him to talk or to cook it.
We prefer to cook venison.
Would you like to have some?
I've already had my fill. I have.
Get out of my way if you don't
want to have some of me.
Funny fellow.
I see Turgut has lost his loyalty.
Loyalty for a Turk
is more precious than food.
An Alp who swears loyalty to no one
is like a body without a soul.
But Turgut has been here before.
He has lost his loyalty before.
But then he went back to his tribe.
We read that in the Mentor's book.
Do you think Turgut is playing with us?
He is a Turk.
Turks don't turn their backs
on their leaders easily.
You should get more intimate
in order to find out.
Do whatever is necessary,
but don't fall in love.
He is nothing more
than prey to me, brother.
Let's hope Turgut Alp really has
turned his back on his master.
Then we can draw new paths for him.
And if he is lying...
then we will chop his head off.
We considered your offer
and have decided to accept it, Candar Bey.
We hope it will be good for both tribes.
But we have some conditions.
I hope it'll be good for both tribes, too.
What are your conditions?
You should deal with
the financial side of things,
as you are the more experienced trader.
We suggest it would be appropriate
to conduct our business in the bazaar,
because of the effort involved
in transporting the goods to the bazaar.
The rugs should be designed
and sold in the bazaar.
You are right, Ertuğrul Bey.
There is a considerable distance
between our two tribes.
It makes sense to meet
at a midway point.
We also suggest that Lady Halime
takes charge of the rug house.
She will lead the way for the women.
Deal, Ertuğrul Bey.
My daughter Aslihan
and my daughter-in-law Lady Colpan
will help Lady Halime any way they can.
My son Aliyar is an educated man.
I trust his honesty more than anything.
It'd be appropriate for him
to deal with the trade.
I have no doubts about Aliyar Bey.
So, all there is left to do
is to find a place in the bazaar.
My son Ural...
will talk to the owner Simon
and take care of it.
Ural, go to the bazaar with Aliyar
first thing in the morning.
Have Aliyar meet with Simon
and inform him of our decision.
Tell him we'd like to have a place
where we can set up the rug house.
What if Simon doesn't agree?
Simon is a trader, son.
All he cares about is money.
Do as I say and leave the rest.
-Best wishes.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
May God make our earnings
fortunate and blessed.
-Amen.
May God help both our tribes.
-Al Fatiha.
Get lost, Comrade Bamsi.
You know what to do.
Got any change, sir?
Any change you give to the man in need...
will find its way back to you.
Wait for it.
Beggar.
Don't disturb the masters
or you'll get a beating.
May God protect you, little master.
Don't interfere with God's business.
He wouldn't ask you who to protect.
Get lost before I beat you up.
Do I have your permission, Artuk Bey?
Please, Aliyar Bey.
Permission is God's to give.
This tongue belongs to a certain
someone who died recently.
But I have some doubts about it.
With your knowledge of medicine,
can you find out if he was poisoned?
I can try, Aliyar Bey. I can try.
But who was this unfortunate person?
He was a poor soul.
I have things to do in the bazaar.
Then I will come visit your tent.
If you manage
to get this tongue to speak...
you can tell me everything then.
Very well.
Ertuğrul Bey, may our partnership
be fruitful for both our tribes.
Amen.
Unity means power, Candar Bey.
Now it's time for us to work.
Don't worry.
Aliyar and Ural will talk
to Simon and handle everything.
I have no doubts, Candar Bey.
Lady Aslihan and Lady Halime
will also do their best.
But... don't be angry with her,
because of the deal with the Venetians.
Our earnings and paths are the same.
We must be leaving.
Thank you for hosting us.
Safe travels.
May God protect you.
We will always be glad to host you here.
You have my blessings.
And you have mine.
We're leaving with a heavy heart.
May your tribe be happy
and our friendship eternal.
Ertuğrul Bey is a brave
and decent man, Father.
This partnership will be good
for both tribes.
As long as you contain Ural,
it will be good.
Take care of him.
It's time you got to work
on your part of the deal.
Brother, we need to go.
I'm ready, Aliyar.
It's you who's fooling around.
Sir.
The Alp whose leg was broken
during training is not doing well.
His leg is swollen.
We don't know what to do.
These Alps seem to be weak.
It's just his leg, just get him fixed.
Where is he, Batuhan?
I'll take a look.
Aliyar.
We have a meeting with Simon.
Let's not be late.
He is our Alp, brother.
Simon can wait.
Kutluca.
Batuhan.
Now it's your turn, Simon.
Are you trying to make
a fool of me, Batuhan?
Nothing's wrong with this man!
He was groaning, sir.
He thought he was going to die.
Batuhan.
Go get my horse.
You're dead now, you brute!
And you were supposed to ambush us, huh?
You need eyes in the back of your head.
I could teach you a thing or two.
If I'd had all my wits about me,
I'd have had your head
before you even pulled your sword.
Though I've got to admit, it'd be
hard to spot you, considering your height.
What, are you still
thinking about those sausages?
What sausages are you talking about?
I'm too exhausted
to even think about food.
Turgut keeps talking in his sleep.
-What's wrong with him?
-I don't understand the things he says.
He speaks very harshly about Ertuğrul Bey.
It's as if our brave Turgut is gone,
and a man filled with hate
has replaced him.
Is that what you think?
-How could he speak like that?
-And yet he does.
While looking me right in the eye.
If it was anybody else, I'd have
jabbed him in the chest with these swords.
I would know, brother.
There's no bringing him back.
That's not possible, brother.
It's the pain in his heart speaking.
How could I tell Ertuğrul Bey
what he said to me?
I can't bring myself to tell him.
Someone's coming.
Come to me.
I'll wreak my anger on you.
Your cooking smells great as usual, Maria.
But tasty food is not enough
to win a man's heart.
You're spouting nonsense again, Amanda.
I'm talking about Turgut.
I see you've become very close.
-And here I was thinking--
-You have it wrong, whatever it is.
Turgut is but a guest.
Turgut! Why are you walking around?
-I'm fine.
-Are you?
I got hungry.
You're covered in wounds,
and yet you say you're all right.
Get back to bed.
I'll bring you some food.
I'm telling you, woman, I'm fine.
I'm sorry.
It's all this worry gnawing away at the
back of my mind, I can't bear it.
I'll go mad if I stay in that room.
It's obvious you wouldn't be happy
with the way things are.
You are an Alp, after all.
You two should eat together.
Don't even think about saying no.
You're stuck with Maria till you recover.
You owe her your life.
You must not let it happen, Simon.
Aliyar will come asking
for a space to sell his rugs.
My father supports Ertuğrul Bey now.
You must stop him.
Or we won't have an agreement.
It was you who breached our agreement
when the Europeans came,
or did you forget that?
That was different.
I need my father's trust.
Not the cleverness of Ertuğrul Bey.
You don't know Ertuğrul.
If he were to come here,
it'd be the end of us.
It's you who doesn't know Ertuğrul.
Right now, you're seeing red.
Yet you dare tell me what to do...
Let's see what Ertuğrul
has to say when he comes.
Ertuğrul wasn't kind enough to come.
But Aliyar should be here soon.
You must tell him that the deal
with Ertuğrul is off.
And that'll be an end to it,
Simon.
You must be Turgut Alp.
-And you are?
-Aliyar, son of Candar Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey was our guest.
He spoke very highly of you.
I thought I should come and wish you well.
He dares play the guest
instead of finding those...
who did this to me and my Alps?
We should expect nothing of him, it seems.
I must get my strength back
and find those responsible myself.
I've been meaning to talk to you,
Innkeeper Simon.
Yes, Turgut Alp.
I will remember the favor
you and your sister have done me
until the day I die.
I'll find whoever
is responsible and avenge you.
You can be sure of it, Turgut Alp.
-Let me know when you find them.
-I will, Turgut Alp.
I wish you a swift recovery, Turgut.
-I see you are better.
-Thanks.
Turgut wanted to come here
on his own, brother.
So, you really are getting better.
Thanks to Maria Hatun.
Will you be going back soon?
I was the commander of the Alps there.
I'm not going anywhere until I find
the ones responsible for their deaths.
Excuse me.
Turgut is a dangerous man.
He's made up his mind
that he's going to get his revenge.
I wouldn't want to be in their shoes.
My brother, Aliyar.
Let's take a breather here.
Attack!
You still have some time until
you're all out of breath. Speak.
Who brought the knight
to the market?
Who was it?
Let's see who the dog of the Sultan is.
Damn, it isn't Ertuğrul.
Working with such a wise man as you will
undoubtedly be lucrative for our bazaar.
Thank you.
I take it my brother has already told you
Candar and Ertuğrul Bey's demands.
I would have liked to have
been present during that conversation
but alas I had to see a wounded Alp.
I'm sorry about your Alp, Aliyar Bey.
Ural Bey passed on your request.
As I said, my father trusted
Aliyar with this duty.
I'm only here to introduce him to you.
I know you've been business partners
for a long time. You trust each other.
But both tribes agreed to this.
If we are to do this
quickly and honorably,
we'll do it our way.
I'm but a merchant, after all.
Profit is all I care about.
On the other hand,
Ural Bey has a point.
I don't know Ertuğrul Bey well.
I'd like to hear what he has to say.
I'm sure we could come
to an agreement if he joined us here.
We were expecting Ertuğrul,
and instead we got some random Turk
Master Simon won't like this.
There, look. He's coming around.
Identify yourself, Turk!
Your worst nightmare.
You? Don't make me laugh.
It'll be the sweetest of dreams
to see your blood slowly spill.
Give my regards to John the Baptist.
How do you know about him?
Tell him that I'll turn his world
upside down soon.
That bazaar will be
the grave of the lot of you.
You won't be able to get away
with just hiding your faces.
I know the lot of you.
I know all about you people.
I know every breath, every step you take.
I’m not going to stop till I bury you
in this land that you've turned into hell.
Kill him.
Charge!
Tristan, wait.
They got away, Doğan Alp.
-Are we not following them?
-No, brother.
They'll tell their masters that
Ertuğrul Bey isn't the spy.
-That's what we want them to do.
-What?
Bamsi will explain.
Brother, he's never going to understand!
You didn't even try, Bamsi Alp!
My brother with
the most exceptional mustache.
I'm just teasing you.
Don't get worked up, now.
Praise be, my brother.
Are you all right, brother?
Stop it, I'm not going to die
from a punch or two.
You great bear!
I haven't heard such
sweet words in a while, brother.
-Say it again.
-You great bear!
What do we do now, brother?
They got away.
-Our mission here is done.
-You think so?
Of course, brother. That pig
Tristan will tell his masters everything.
Get to work before sunset, brothers.
Ertuğrul Bey is waiting for you.
Yes, sir.
-Brother.
-Yes?
How is my wife?
-You're not troubling her, are you?
-She is safe, brother.
Don't worry about her,
Cicek Hatun is well.
I hope you two are back together soon.
I hope so too, brother.
I do hope so.
What will you do now?
I live in the mountains, brother.
I will lie low for a while.
May God help us, brother.
Come here, brother.
-Thank you, my brothers.
-Don't mention it.
Come on.
My dear Halime.
We haven't had the chance
to talk together in a long while.
That's why I wanted to go
alone, without my mother.
Why are you looking away, Halime?
It feels like we've been getting in
and out of trouble constantly lately.
I felt a thrill at being alone with you
like this, I guess. That's why.
The things which separate us,
distance, life, time,
are nothing before a loving heart.
They only strengthen our love.
-Ertuğrul, I must tell you something.
-Yes, Halime.
Our son, Gunduz...
Has something happened to our son?
He'll soon have a sibling, Bey.
I'm pregnant.
We'll have another child, if God permits.
Yes!
Thank God, Halime.
With this news,
there's nothing in the whole world
that could trouble me now.
We came to trouble you, brave warrior.
And what might that news be?
Let us rejoice, as well.
Halime.
Whenever you tell me that
you're pregnant,
something bad always happens.
All our children
come with their own quirks.
This one comes with some common bandits.
What do you want, you impertinent fools?
Who are you?
We are the soldiers
of Ertuğrul Bey of the Kayis.
We rule around here. Give us your gold.
What are you laughing at?
Are you deaf? I said Ertuğrul Bey.
Do you want to die?
Give us your gold and we'll let you live.
Don't move or I'll kill you.
So, you are Ertuğrul Bey's soldiers?
You must know him well, then.
You heard us, he trained us personally.
Let's see how well I trained you.
Look at me, scum!
I'm not going to dirty my hand with
your blood on this most perfect of days.
But if you rob anyone else in my name
and I get to hear about it,
I'll hunt you down.
And if I hunt you,
I'll not rest until I have your head.
Got it?
And so our reputation grows.
Our sons will bring us even greater honor.
I hope so.
Don't let anyone know about it just yet.
When the right time comes,
we'll give them the news together.
As you see fit.
Come on, let's go.
God!
Let my people grow and prosper!
KAYI CAMP
-Hello.
-Welcome, Ishak. Come in.
I brought the partridges.
What are they for, Artuk Bey?
They will tell us if there was
any poison in the deceased's blood.
In the name of God...
Who does that tongue belong to?
Do you have any idea, sir?
-Ertuğrul Bey will know.
-And you?
No, I don't know. But...
according to Ertuğrul Bey,
Aliyar Bey doesn't believe that
Toktamış Bey would have attempted
to kill Candar Bey and his family
if he were in his right mind.
Right, sir.
Nevertheless,
I wonder what our holy book
has to say about cutting
a dead man's tongue.
In such conflicting cases,
Maturidi of Samarkand says
"We must follow the minds enlightened
with the light of Islam,
so that we will not stray
from the path of Islam and rationality,
and lose our way in the dark."
Well said, sir.
-Greetings.
-Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
-Thank you, Dundar.
I'd like to return this seat, this tent,
and the honor of our settlement to you,
as per your orders.
-Do you agree to it, beys?
-Yes, sir.
Thank you, Dundar.
How is the waterway coming along?
I saw the works on my way back.
Dündar Bey has given us orders
as to how to continue.
We'll take advantage of the hill and
its slope and fill this place with water.
How much time do you need?
It'll be done in three days.
The women of our settlement
won't have to walk so far for water.
What about the sheep pen? Winter's here.
We'll get it done soon.
We'll have it ready before winter
lays waste to our animals.
We're doing it without cutting down
any young trees, as per your orders.
If God permits.
Beys, you may leave.
-Did something happen in my absence?
-It's all under control, brother.
But I couldn't refuse Foreman Haçaturyan.
I sent him to look for the gold mine
with Samsa and Kaya Alp.
He'd have died of grief otherwise.
Well done.
-I hope he finds what he's looking for.
-With God's permission.
We're not going to get lost
while looking for this gold, are we?
Trust me, Samsa Alp.
I know this place
like the back of my hand.
I can smell the gold.
It's close.
I didn't know it had a smell.
If you know how,
not only can you smell and hear it,
you can also see its bright light.
Kaya, he's right.
I can smell partridge
when one is in range of my bow.
Now we're speaking the same language.
You've tried so hard,
I hope you do find it.
Foreman Haçaturyan, the gold hunter.
I have to, my son.
I owe Ertuğrul Bey my life. Not just that,
I own him a debt of honor too.
I could never repay that,
even if I do find gold.
But at least I'll be of use to people.
Gold! Gold!
Thank God! I knew it was here!
Gold!
-Yes!
Thank God, I knew it was here.
Gold!
God bless you!
Ertuğrul Bey will be very happy.
-What're we waiting for, then? Let's go.
-Let's go!
-Bey, Aliyar Bey is here.
-Show him in, Abdurrahman.
Welcome to my settlement, Aliyar Bey.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Come, sit.
I talked to Innkeeper Simon.
Did he accept the offer?
He said he would discuss it
if you joined us there tomorrow.
What do you think, Aliyar Bey?
It is a good idea
to have a discussion first.
Simon is a merchant, after all.
He wants to make sure
his business is in safe hands.
What about Ural Bey?
What does he say?
It's obvious, after all, that he only
accepted because Candar Bey forced him to.
My brother Ural won't make
any more mistakes, sir.
I'll be overseeing the matter.
With my sister, Aslihan. Rest assured.
All right, Aliyar Bey.
-Greetings.
-Come, sit, Artuk Bey.
-Welcome, Aliyar Bey.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Were you able to find out
what I asked of you?
Yes, Aliyar Bey, indeed we did.
Ishak, bring it here.
Here, sir.
I believe Ertuğrul Bey
is familiar with this matter.
Yes, I am. Artuk Bey told me everything.
Such a pity. Whose tongue is it?
It relates to a dispute I stumbled upon
on my way back from Konya.
They asked for my help
but I studied astronomy,
mathematics and Islamic law.
What help could I be?
But I believe we can settle it
with Artuk Bey's knowledge of such things.
So, what did you learn?
I fed one of the partridges
the chemical I found in the tongue.
What happened to the other bird?
The chemical made the partridge
go berserk. It killed the other bird.
I've never witnessed such a thing.
Partridges are such peaceful beasts.
It turned into a wounded lion
in the blink of an eye.
After killing the other partridge,
it died, fluttering.
The chemical made it ecstatic,
then drove it insane.
Whatever it is, this poison hurts both
the host and the people around him,
Aliyar Bey.
Here, sir.
If you could bury the tongue
with the dead--
Don't worry, Ishak.
I'll do what's right.
I understand, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
As I said,
I'll be at the inn tomorrow morning.
-Excuse me, sir.
-Thank you, Ishak.
What do you think, sir?
Clearly someone poisoned Toktamış Bey.
Could it have been Ural Bey?
Once again, we see that
there are but two people we can trust.
Aliyar Bey and Aslıhan Hatun.
What about Candar Bey?
Candar Bey will do anything
for the good of his tribe.
Including going against the law
and all reason.
That's why we'll never reach
an understanding with Candar Bey.
I see, sir.
How does this end, Mother?
We haven't been this fortunate
for a long while.
This means we can finally breathe easy.
Though...
There is...
an inexpressible anxiety
within you, isn't there?
Indeed, Mother.
Ertuğrul Bey doesn't trust Ural Bey
or Candar Bey.
He chooses his words so carefully,
you've seen that.
Well, what about Aliyar?
-Aslihan?
-Mother.
Aren't they the children
of the same father?
What if a situation escalates
and gets out of control in the future?
What would we do then?
Would Aliyar and Aslihan walk over
their father and brother to save us?
And that woman, Aslihan...
What about her?
Why did she ignore the interests
of her own people
and tell Ertuğrul Bey
about the French traders?
When it came to light, she continued
to go against her own father over it.
There's also that woman called Çolpan.
She's got cruel eyes.
But don't forget that they're
going to help you in the rug house.
Whatever you want
they'll do what's necessary.
We're only after our daily bread.
We'll go to the bazaar every day
and weave rugs.
What comes after that is up to God
and Ertuğrul Bey.
As we rode our horses to the West...
I saw how much the world order
has changed.
The only thing that rules the East
and the West is gold, Turgut.
They buried our God inside of us.
And they covered it with gold.
The Crusades of the Christian world
only cared about gold.
If you can keep up, you'll survive.
Those who can't...
will die.
Like a salamander in the desert.
No one will remember them.
The door always opens
to those who are willing to see it.
If only the man would keep his eyes open.
Here you are.
We were talking about
how gold rules the world
and provides new
opportunities to people, brother.
And to a warrior
as great and as brave as you.
The whole world comes to hear of
the accomplishments of brave warriors
such as yourself.
Everyone knows what you
and Ertuğrul Bey did
to that Mongolian fool.
What was his name?
Noyan.
If you knew how many lives we lost
because of the mistakes Ertuğrul Bey made
before we got rid of that Noyan scumbag,
you wouldn't say that.
Ertuğrul Bey's lack of foresight doesn't
overshadow your bravery, Turgut Alp.
The marks the Templars left on your body
are testament to the fierceness with which
you fought against those degenerates.
How do you know about that?
I know a great deal about the crimes
the Templars committed against our people
under the command of the degenerate Pope.
And how they tortured them.
The Templars murdered our family.
Only Maria and I survived.
They slaughtered our family
because we didn't share their beliefs.
The belief we have in Jesus
wasn't enough to save our family.
My condolences.
Master Simon, you've got a visitor.
If you'll excuse me.
What happened?
The Sultan's spy got away, Master Simon.
How did you let Ertuğrul run away?
Ertuğrul is not the Sultan's spy.
-What did you say?
-I had him. I talked to him.
It wasn't Ertuğrul.
Then his men came and killed ours.
If it wasn't for Tristan, I'd be dead now.
So you saw his face.
Tell me. Who is he?
We didn't find out who they were.
But he knows who you are,
Master Simon.
What did you say?
He asked me about John the Baptist.
He said he was going
to knock his place down.
If Ertuğrul is not the Sultan's spy
we still have to get our revenge for
Master Petruccio and Knight Titus.
Ertuğrul must die tomorrow, Master Simon.
Ertuğrul is coming to see me tomorrow.
I'll do what's necessary.
Take every measure.
Take every measure necessary
inside and outside the inn.
No one acts without my order.
Why don't we finish the business
right away?
Because I'm not sure the man we found
was actually the Sultan's spy.
After that
we let the slave trader and the guy
who looks like a fighting cock run away.
-Where is Doğan?
-He carried out his mission.
Now he's back in hiding
and awaiting your next order.
They surely can't still believe
you're the Sultan's spy.
They must have been so surprised when
they saw it was Doğan and not you.
We can't be so sure, Dündar.
We have to take care of John the Baptist
right away.
Even though he hides among
the Orthodox Greeks,
he's obviously one of the Templars.
A wolf in a sheep's clothing.
They want to kill you.
That's why they've called you in.
-We're still going to go, Dündar.
-What if it's a trap?
They're going to try to kill you.
It's too dangerous.
I'll let him live
until I learn everything about him.
If he wants to kill me,
I won't hesitate to kill him first.
We'll go to that inn tomorrow.
We'll see who lives and who dies.
Sir, Master Hacaturyan
wants to see you.
Show him in, Abdurrahman.
Come in, Master Hacaturyan.
I have... great news for you.
Tell me.
With the help of God...
I think we found the seam of gold.
I don't know how much is there.
But we should certainly mine it.
Good.
Don't let anyone know about this,
Master Hacaturyan.
Don't breathe a word about it.
Return with the men
who first accompanied you there.
Your wish is my command.
Whatever happens...
take care of this matter
with Simon tomorrow.
-Ural.
-Here, Father.
Don't you dare...
cause any problems
or ignore what your brother Aliyar says.
I'll support whatever is good
for our people, Father.
I see that what is good...
is that which passes
between your holy lips.
Çolpan, don't ignore Halime Hatun.
Do not worry, Bey.
If you'll excuse me.
Do you have something to say, daughter?
I've been hearing a lot
about Halime Hatun's mastery in weaving.
She learned a lot
when she traveled through
many countries with her princely father.
This way we'll learn more from
what she knows and has experienced.
Well done, daughter.
If we look at things with our minds
and not with our pride, we will succeed.
Aliyar, do you have anything to say?
Your decision has proved
to be a wise one, Father.
Our women would not have been able
to finish those rugs in such a short time.
With regard to Simon...
We'll get to work with Ertuğrul Bey
and get it done, Father.
Good luck.
The arrow has already left the bow.
And it landed in your heart.
How many times will my father trap me?
How many more betrayals, Çolpan Hatun?
I can't count anymore.
You've put Ertuğrul in his place.
You prevented the Kayis challenging us
by burning their rugs.
In the new world's order,
you've done what's necessary.
Your father is incapable of understanding
the importance of what you've done.
Because he is afraid,
he has let Ertuğrul, his wife,
and his know-all mother become a nuisance.
He offered them this job
on a silver platter,
knowing it would cost us thousands.
But rest assured,
I'm going to take care of this business.
My father, Aliyar and Aslihan
will get what they deserve.
And then?
Let's say you sort this problem.
What happens next?
Who knows how many more traps
and betrayals you'll suffer
at their hands?
Your father obviously favors
your siblings over you.
You come after them.
They get the praise
while you get to run errands.
I told you, they'll get what they deserve.
Don't worry about that.
I never worry when I'm with you.
But as long as Aliyar and Aslihan live,
we can never be too sure.
The path of our people
is a long and holy one, Hatun.
We are noble and strong.
Under the command of the weak,
under the sword of heathens,
we'd melt away
like a snowflake in the sun.
But your man Ural
will never let that happen.
How?
I know a way
of making it impossible
for either of my siblings to remain here.
My father will be alone.
How do we do that?
Through the one they rely on, Ertuğrul.
When I make my move tomorrow
he'll be left humiliated.
And Simon will crush him like an insect.
You smell so nice.
Just for you.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, Halime Sultan.
Are you still nervous, Halime Sultan?
Ural Bey will do whatever he can
to prevent this from going ahead.
Simon is a merchant.
In the end, all he cares about
is the gold he'll get,
not Ural Bey's tears.
You're right.
-What about Aslihan?
-What about her?
I can't decide if she's really naive
or really clever.
What does that mean, Halime?
Aslihan Hatun was the one who told you
about the French getting the rugs.
Why did she do that?
What are you thinking?
I don't know, Bey. But it seems like...
She has as much respect for you
as she has for Aliyar Bey.
I can see that.
On one side is Çolpan and Ural,
on the other Aliyar and Aslihan.
I think...
we have come between
Candar Bey's children.
Our work will not be easy.
As long as you're taking care of things
everything will be fine, Halime Sultan.
That's why I wanted you
and my mother in charge.
I know things wouldn't have
worked out otherwise.
Besides, thanks to you, the Cavdar tribe
will learn how to weave rugs properly.
Let's try to come
to an agreement with Simon.
What was the disagreement between
my brother and Toktamis Bey, Aslihan?
Tell me.
Did it have something
to do with Simon's bazaar?
Yes, that despicable bazaar
ensured the hostility
between them only grew.
What happened? Tell me, sister.
Toktamis Bey found out Ural
was making an unfair profit.
On one hand there's Ural,
on the other, Çolpan.
How will we get through this?
You take care of Çolpan,
and I'll take care of our brother.
If you ever hear something's wrong
you must tell me right away, Aslihan.
Don't worry, brother.
My, my.
Good night.
I've come to give you some advice.
Don't dare follow Ertuğrul
and bring trouble to us.
The fact we can sell our products
and our animals at the bazaar,
we owe to Simon.
If not for this we'd be destitute,
just like Ertuğrul's people.
Ertuğrul is here today, gone tomorrow.
But Simon? He'll always
be in charge of the bazaar.
Brother...
Is it true you teamed up with Simon
to steal our people's money?
Did...
Aslihan tell you that?
Tomorrow, two groups come together
to do serious business, brother.
We all need this.
Don't you dare...
try pulling any tricks on us...
brother.
While the wrongdoers run wild beside me,
I have to wait politically.
It's tough. I feel humiliated.
The skill is not to pull out your weapon
until you can look the enemy
in the eye at the right time.
There is a right time
for an enemy to be defeated.
The enemy is what makes you brave
and like a lion.
When can I unsheathe my sword
and make life unbearable for my enemy?
There are many varieties of cruelty, son.
The sheath stops
the cruelty of the sword,
traps will end tricks' cruelty
and money will end money's cruelty.
A Bey's skill lies in
knowing if the devil is coming
from the right side or the left side.
Being a Bey is a grueling burden.
Yusuf was left in the well
and Ibrahim was thrown into the fire.
Why do you think they
were exposed to such suffering?
If the well didn't exist,
Yusuf wouldn't exist.
And if suffering didn't exist,
humans wouldn't be humans.
Mankind's trials are various.
Some will come out of the well like Yusuf,
some will become the devil
and get kicked out of heaven.
A trial is tough, son, it's tough.
As the Bey, you have to face the cheats
and appreciate justice.
You have to fall into traps,
so you can learn how to get out of them.
You have to experience disloyalty
and betrayal to see loyalty and sincerity.
And then you'll climb out of the well
you fell into
and become the Sultan of your land.
May God help you.
May God give strength to your muscles,
the courage to your heart
and clarity to your mind.
My God.
Eliminate the traps
on our path of holy war.
Grant us wakefulness against the enemy.
My God.
Give our weapons the strength of Zülfikar
and give our hearts the courage of Ali.
Don't let anyone who wants to ruin our
brotherhood, unity and peace succeed.
We ask only for your help
and we kneel down in front of you alone.
Don't let us be without you, my God.
My God.
Today is the day, brother.
When we clean Jerusalem
of the Muslims, that'll be our day.
When we reclaim the Temple of Solomon.
As long as there are knights
such as you... the day is close.
Soon our nemesis Ertuğrul will arrive.
Sometimes our enemies
become our closest friends.
We might have to make deals with them.
Will you accept his offer
of establishing a rug house?
Why shouldn't I if he comes up
with a good offer?
Ural will be enraged.
Good.
Then things will go crazy.
We'll kill two birds with one stone.
Maria won't leave Turgut's side.
I guess she's fallen for the man.
Was it Maria who found Turgut
when he was wounded?
Philip was with her too.
So either of them might
have found the dagger.
Is that what you're saying?
Maria is a naive woman.
She wouldn't understand.
How would she know
about Batuhan's dagger?
Only Philip could be behind something
like this. And if Philip is involved...
-It means Simon is involved too.
-Don't doubt it.
-Did you get the thief I asked you for?
-It was very easy.
I only had to say there would be
gemstones in the pouch he always carries.
Then...
I'll be back.
I'll wait for you, my Ural.
I can't bear being without you.
Bey, they are bent on causing hell.
For Christ's sake, for Muhammad's sake,
give some money to this poor man.
Ever since the birds started perching
on the master's balcony
the crows have gone mad.
May God and all his saints be
on your side, brave man.
May God protect the believers
and those who fight in his name, old man.
Bey, where are we going?
-I'd like to see Turgut.
-I understand, bey.
Shouldn't we take care of our business
first and go see him later?
I miss my brother too but we don't
know what's waiting in there for us.
Welcome, Ertuğrul Bey.
Innkeeper Simon is waiting for you.
Fine, then.
What happened to your foot, Philip?
You're limping.
The work of an arrogant drunk.
I suppose you put him in his place.
A Bey's skill lies in
knowing if the devil is coming from
the right side or the left side.
I am Suleyman Shah's son Ertuğrul!
I want all the world to know...
that any fool who
hankers after what's mine...
will pay the penalty.