Episode 63 will start after 12:28 min.
Brother? Are you all right?
If not for my armor
I would have died, Marina.
I'd have suffered eternally in Heaven
for not fulfilling my duty.
Sultan Alaeddin's spy got away.
We saw that he was not alone
and that we are surrounded by traitors.
Did you see their faces? I didn't.
We saw not their faces,
but what they are capable of.
Even that is an important gain for us.
But the knight got away.
Don't worry. I got him.
He won't make it with that arrow wound.
You are my angel, Maria.
Are you all right, my bey?
I'm fine, Turgut. I'm fine.
The devil Tristan
crushed him hard, my bey.
This is not his doing, Turgut.
He just finished him off.
If they'd got all the information
out of the spy, we might have been saved.
These spies are not easy to swallow.
They stick to your throat.
They did this because he didn't talk.
So, our secret is still a secret.
Agreed, my bey.
Bismillah.
What is that mark, my bey?
It's the name of our enemy.
Who, my bey?
John the Baptist.
God Almighty!
I am your servant, John the Baptist.
Loyal servant of Jesus.
I will be your son, Jesus' slave,
on my holy pilgrimage.
I will take Jerusalem, the holy land
of our Virgin Mary, from the Muslims.
I will rebuild Solomon's Temple.
And Simon swore an oath to Jesus.
My God, I will walk through dungeons
and die with you.
CAVDAR CAMP
Step aside!
Who did this? Who? How could they?
Who did this?
Don't let Toktamış Bey's death be in vain!
What have they done to Toktamış?
-Who?
-They will pay!
His death won't be in vain!
Don't let Toktamış Bey's death be in vain!
Don't!
What a shame!
Shut your mouths!
Valiant warriors of the prairie!
Bronze hearted lions of the Tatars!
Last night...
this infidel,
who treacherously attacked...
our bey, our village...
and its sons, has gotten
what he deserved.
While our Cavdar Bey fights heart and soul
so that our empire may grow,
our empire may prosper
and become more fruitful, this dog...
tried to stab him in the back.
He who attacks our Candar Bey's marquee
will die a horrible death.
This dog that attacked Candar Bey
will hang here to set an example.
Enemies of our people
will see their fate in his eyes.
When jackals ambushed me
in the caves of the prairie...
he gave everything he had.
We swore to be blood brothers
in the shadow of great sycamores.
We warded off Azrael in many a battle.
I went on to wage war...
leaving my wife and kids in his care.
How could he...
betray me like this?
Give me your hands, Father.
They say you were born in sin.
I wish the ground had broken and the sky
had fallen, just so this wouldn't happen.
This betrayal as I am getting ready
to part with this world...
has taken away all my life, my dear.
Toktamış would have done this
for a reason, Father.
We need to figure out what that was.
I would give my life to know what it was,
my valiant daughter.
My life!
I wish you hadn't left that body out,
my bey.
A bey...
should know how to hit
three birds with one stone.
Toktamış's death will make them rise up.
Now...
your father...
will also learn to give in.
He will not trust anyone
but himself and I.
Simon.
If he reveals your secret one day...
Then we will know to introduce him
to Azrael too.
My Çolpan,
why do you worry yourself with this?
I have no worries with you by my side.
But something inside me says
the corpse shouldn't be on display.
Tell that blind devil
that so worries you...
that I will take out his other eye.
Any word on the kilims?
I had the best kilims,
the finest rugs ordered for you.
I will play those Venetian infidels
so that...
they'll place sacks of gold
in my palm without question.
And I will lay the gold out
in front of my father to see.
Then he will forget about Toktamış.
Let us not leave Candar Bey alone,
mourning for Toktamış.
-Come with me to the marketplace.
-I would like that.
I also have things to buy.
Let me tend to your wound.
Father.
I sent for my brother, Aliyar,
without your permission.
I miss him.
You're like your mother, Aslıhan.
You're always up to something.
The people need my brother, Aliyar.
Aliyar is now a Tatar
who has lost his warrior spirit.
They say he who wields a pen
can no longer wield a sword.
-Are the kilims ready?
-They are, my bey.
-Çolpan Hatun prepared them all.
-Aslıhan will go with you.
Çolpan Hatun was going to assist, my bey.
Didn't you hear Candar Bey, Ural?
It's apparent that my father
wishes me to be by his side.
If the Venetians
ask anything about the kilims,
Aslıhan should be with you.
After all, as a woman
she knows more about kilims than you.
KAYI CAMP
No, Artuk Bey, this won't do. We have been
up against difficulties for so long now.
We did as Ertuğrul Bey commanded.
However, he has forgotten Oghuz law.
Artuk Bey is right, my bey.
What is this denial of assembly?
We would die for our bey, Artuk Bey.
But as it is the right of the beys
to ask for an assembly,
it is the duty of the bey of the camp
to accept it.
Ertuğrul Bey has disregarded the law
as he has disregarded us.
Valiant Beys of the Kayi,
foremost of our boys,
what you say is true.
It is. However, hear me out too.
I know you all want
what's good for the camp
and worry about
the future of your children, your tent.
It is true that our camp is going through
rough times.
However, God Almighty says in the Quran,
"There is comfort
after those difficulties."
Not a day has passed
without worry and difficulty
since we left for these lands.
It seems our fate will continue to be so.
However, know that
we are not to blame for this.
The sword
cannot be forged without being beaten.
These sorrows will make us stronger.
But know that the biggest of sorrows
is bestowed upon our Bey.
While we cannot even deal with
our own problems and give up,
he is up against the difficulties
of the whole camp.
His refusal of the assembly request
just shows how big that difficulty is.
In the end, we know that weapons need men.
Men need states, states need rulers.
And rulers need laws.
-True.
That's true, Artuk Bey.
Law is the heart of the state.
Without law, the state is a lifeless body.
Just as a state cannot live without law,
a beylik cannot either.
You know that the mountain
holds up the land.
And the bey holds up the camp.
Our bey knows this best.
Ertuğrul Bey will hold the assembly soon
and do his part, God willing.
-God willing.
What's the situation?
These goods
are not worth the ride to the marketplace.
So it's bad.
How are we to persuade these people at war
if we can't persuade them to trade kilim?
Ertuğrul must return to the camp at once.
Artuk Bey is coming with the people.
I hope it's good news.
It wasn't about the kilims, Hayme Hatun.
They resented our bey
not organizing the assembly.
How sensitive the Kayi camp has gotten.
You can't organize a wedding ceremony
with them, let alone an assembly.
Brother!
Thank god you got back safe.
How was the hunt?
Fruitful, Dundar.
-Power to your elbow, Halime Hatun.
-Thank you.
But we haven't accumulated enough kilims.
Don't worry about it. I know my boys.
They will bring whatever they have left.
My bey, you know
my sons and I always believed in you.
I gave up everything for you.
This is the last kilim
I and my orphaned grandson have.
-You can have this too.
-Thank you, Hatun.
The Kayi will rise
on the shoulders of people like you.
Thank you. May God bless you.
Ertuğrul Bey, this is yours
and our last chance.
If you don't succeed this time either,
know that you won't keep us in this land.
-Samsar!
-Yes, my bey.
-Gather the kilims.
You, come with me. We shall consult.
-Yes.
-Yes, my bey.
HANLI MARKET
Last night the Templars were humiliated.
The enemy that we tried to entrap
ruined our plan.
What do we do now, sir?
First, we find out who our enemy is.
This enemy is like us.
It does not give itself up.
It's the first time we've encountered
a worthy enemy.
The enemy does not give itself up, my bey.
My bey, these are the ones
that came our way before.
They are not as smart as we thought.
They've thrown away a big fish, my bey.
One that doesn't drown in a wild river
but flows in the depths, Turgut.
You are right, Artuk Bey.
We fought Noyan, my bey.
These will be light work.
We knew who the Noyan were, Turgut.
A valiant enemy is something else.
However, these are dishonorable.
How will we identify him?
He came once, he will come again.
He probably wants to know who we are.
We should watch everyone
at the marketplace.
Be aware of every step that is taken.
You will closely follow anyone
who makes a lot of money,
is trading out of nowhere
and has the ability to wage war.
-Leave the Muslims to me.
-And the others to me.
We will use Tristan as bait.
They will definitely come to capture him.
We only have a name. John the Baptist.
First, we must capture that slave dealer.
He will take us to him.
Put Dumrul on this task, Turgut Alp.
Yes, my bey.
However...
they might want to use Tristan as bait
and lure us into a trap.
Well, would you look at Turgut!
As sharp as a needle.
Praise be to my brother! Praise be!
You are right, Turgut Alp.
Dumrul must cover his tracks.
Just gather information.
We will follow everyone.
The merchants,
the customers that come and go...
the people, everyone.
And they will follow us.
Let's see where our paths collide.
Now...
it is time to load the kilims
and be on our way.
The Venetians await us.
-Yes, my bey.
My bey. God forbid, if we can't sell
the kilims, the people will lose hope.
I will find a way to sell them, Artuk Bey.
Otherwise,
I cannot show my face in the camp.
I see, my bey.
My bey, I would also like you to
hear out Hacaturyan.
On what grounds?
He might be God's blessing to us.
Let him come in.
Sit.
I am listening.
Ertuğrul Bey...
like I said before,
I will most certainly repay my debt.
I explained to Artuk Bey.
I have a plan.
A creek.
A pine tree at the beginning of the river.
Inside the river, oski...
Gold! Lots of gold.
Ertuğrul Bey, if you can
get me the required equipment,
-I will dig out that gold.
-What is it that you need?
Long birches, and then hammers,
for we will mine... Sieves...
Okay then.
I will get them from the market.
Pile the kilims on the front.
The Venetians will be able to carry them.
Both you and my brother are so sure
that the Venetians will buy our goods.
I'm sure of everything Ural Bey does.
Are you sure Toktamış is a traitor then?
For me, anyone who draws a sword
on Ural Bey is a traitor, Aslıhan Hatun.
-Is everything ready?
-Yes, my bey. The animals too.
-We can move the goods at your command.
-Good.
We brought all these goods.
What if we can't sell them, brother?
There are no goods at this market
that Ural Bey can't sell.
So, the Venetians await.
I'll come too.
I have a private matter
to discuss with Simon.
Batuhan will bring you in later.
My dear friend Simon.
That's why I like you.
I'm told there was trouble yesterday
in the bazaar...
and you don't even care.
I'm resting my soul.
Toktamış' departure from this world
has made me quite happy.
No one can prevent us filling our pockets
with tons of gold now.
This time it's not 50-50, Sir Simon.
What do you mean?
Thanks to you, getting rid of Toktamış
was easy.
But you must have some patience
until I restore my credibility
with my father.
Take one tenth of the market share
and leave.
As long as you have this cunning
you'll never be able to restore it.
Now that your brother Aliyar
has arrived in the tribe,
your father will give the responsibility
to your decent brother.
Keep your eyes away from my tribe.
Or else you won't get to see
any beauty in the world again.
Calm down, my dear fellow.
It's just friendly advice.
Also...
the beauty is hidden in the details.
That's why you Turks don't understand
women's spirit.
This amulet will make Lady Çolpan
quite happy.
And, my dear partner...
a happy woman means...
a powerful man.
Oh, mankind! You have never given up...
on the cunning of your ancestor, Cain.
Don't bother your conscience, sir.
The punishment was necessary
for the traitor.
Yes, but do you think other traitors
will get the message?
Sir Aliyar is coming, sir.
Aslıhan said you were coming
but I wasn't expecting you so soon.
-Welcome.
-When Aslıhan said to come quick,
I got worried, Father.
I thought something happened to you.
Thank God you're well.
-Thank God.
-Welcome, Sir Aliyar.
Thank you, Aunt. Thank you.
Father...
Isn't that Sir Toktamış?
What happened to him, Father?
Who took his life?
Father. What's going on?
Treason was punished.
What treason?
Yesterday he tried to kill me
and your brother.
But why, Father?
He was your brother, your comrade.
Son, sadly I had to witness
the treason of my blood brother.
Sir Ural did it for all to see.
Father...
The soul is God's gift to the body.
It's the soul which should be punished,
not the body.
Father, let us wash and bury him...
as is appropriate for us.
Even your revenge should be fair.
In a just way.
Very well, son.
Have him buried without a prayer funeral
after being cleaned.
Kutluca, come.
I brought the Venetian tradesmen to you.
We agreed to split the earnings 50-50.
Have some patience, Sir Simon.
You'll get more than you deserve
once I've restored my credibility
in these unclaimed lands.
Ricardo, my dear friend.
Here is the fellow I'd like you to meet,
Ural Bey of Cavdar tribe.
Open up.
I'll pay two gold pieces per rug.
You have to pay at least three.
Why would these rugs
be worth that much?
-Our rugs--
-For once...
they are the best you can find.
With no better options,
you'll have to spend days
searching for alternatives.
Additionally, I know the ship
that is taking you to Constantinople
will not wait much longer.
So, you don't have time,
and I don't have the will
to sell these rugs for less.
You seem to have forgotten
what we discussed, Ural Bey.
I have given my final word, Sir Simon.
I'll be expecting word from you.
Take them away.
You know where to find me
if you change your mind.
Is this the promise you made, Simon?
I trusted you and changed my plans.
Shut up, Ricardo. I'll figure it out.
Brother, why did you say
three gold pieces per rug?
That's not what we discussed with Father.
What will he say if we leave with nothing?
Keep out of this. Your duty
is to create rugs, mine is to sell.
They have to buy these rugs.
I'm not fool enough to let them go
without taking advantage.
They will come to me like a god
and pay me lots of gold.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Abundance of clots in the blood.
Bloodshot eyes.
A tongue the color of indigo.
A shedding skin.
What did they make you drink?
Troubled apostles of Jesus!
Trader sons of Moses.
Brave warriors of Muhammed.
Simon says, "In this bazaar
all the goods are my responsibility.
The vandals
who harassed the bazaar yesterday
will be punished as soon as possible.
If any of you knows them, you should
immediately share the information."
You will catch them. Right.
What if they don't come to you?
What if they don't buy the rugs?
-What would you say to Father?
-Shut up, Aslıhan!
You're cruel enough to obey
those who go behind my back.
-What are you saying?
-Do you think I'm fool enough
not to understand your pact
with that old man Toktamış?
I'll make you pay when the time is right.
Well, well, well!
Brave Bey of Kayi tribe, Ertuğrul.
Arriving at the scene
with his slave again.
It seems your sword has got rusty.
You wander around
like a fish out of water.
It's hard
not to fail in this bazaar, Ertuğrul Bey.
God giveth and God taketh,
veteran of bazaars, Ural Bey.
It's hard not to fail in life, too.
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah,
don't forget my words.
Be careful
not to lose your goods to others.
Excuse my brother, Ertuğrul Bey.
Thank you, Lady Aslıhan.
You have brought the rugs.
We've brought all we have in the tribe.
Hopefully we will be able to sell them.
The Venetians are inside.
They failed to agree with my brother.
You can sell the rugs if the price
is less than three gold pieces per rug.
Appreciate it, Lady Aslıhan.
Turgut.
-Yes, sir.
-Is Dumrul ready?
Yes, sir.
Hacaturyan.
-Yes, sir.
-You know what to do.
Don't you worry, sir. I won't put you
or your tribe in danger.
Hopefully, as you say.
Thank you.
Ural's bid is too high.
We trusted you and came all this way.
Do you Venetians think
you are the only traders?
We know the value of goods
very well, Simon.
What Ural demands
is a whole year's profit.
Ertuğrul Bey.
What gives?
I have 100 rugs sewn by the women
of my tribe.
I'd like to sell them.
You were sent by the son of God.
Look, Simon, look. God is with us.
I'm here with the rugs,
ready to talk with the buyer.
-How much are these?
-Five akces.
Sir, please, sir. We're hungry.
For God's sake, sir.
We are hungry. Please, sir.
For God's sake.
-Please, sir.
-For God's sake.
As-salamu alaykum.
-We are hungry, sir.
-Please, sir.
-Go away, go on.
-Aleykumselam.
What's up, Muslim? Do you have a problem?
Let us help you out if so.
Look, here is my stand.
Let us feed you if you are hungry.
-Rest here if you are tired.
-Much appreciated.
I don't have any problem. Take it easy.
Dundar, show them the rugs.
You are smarter than I thought,
Ertuğrul Bey.
But don't forget...
my bazaar has its rules.
One tenth of every sale is mine.
I am aware.
These rugs are the finest quality, Simon.
I've never seen anything like it.
I can sell them for at least
30 gold pieces a rug in Venice.
Ertuğrul Bey.
How much do you want for the rugs?
Three gold pieces per rug.
300 gold pieces for 100 rugs.
Why would they be worth
300 gold pieces, Turk?
These are meticulously handcrafted
by the women of my tribe.
They were meant to be gifts
for our daughters' weddings,
not intended for sale.
Well, these are the finest rugs
I have ever seen.
And about the price...
That wouldn't let me make a profit.
There's a price for taking all these
precious goods to Constantinople.
You know, bandits are everywhere.
I can handle that, too.
My Alps can take the goods
to anywhere you want in Constantinople.
You can hold me responsible
if any harm comes to it.
We have a deal, Turk.
I will abide by the rules
of the bazaar, Lord Simon.
One tenth is yours.
I wouldn't have it any other way.
How come Ertuğrul knows
the Venetians are here?
Aslıhan told him.
I overheard them talking.
Also they asked me
what happened in the bazaar yesterday.
Send a pigeon to Constantinople
right away.
Let's see what our people know
about Ertuğrul.
-Turgut.
-Yes, sir.
You'll take the rugs to Constantinople
with the alps.
Of course, sir.
Two of my men will go with them.
They are fine musketeers.
They'll be our guests.
Hopefully, they will reach Constantinople
in peace, without any musketeering.
Lord Simon.
What happened?
Have the heathens come to their senses?
While you are sitting here
bragging like a king,
those out on their horses
chasing their bread have learned a lot.
And you are not even aware of it
because of your greed.
What the hell are you saying, Lord Simon?
The Venetians have bought what they want.
From whom?
-Who is the degenerate?
-Ertuğrul.
And he did it for your price.
300 gold for 100 rugs.
Nothing changed for me.
I still made my profit.
How did Ertuğrul know the Venetians
were coming to buy rugs?
Did you tell him?
Not me.
Aslıhan.
-Aslıhan?
-Yes, your sister.
Ertuğrul also said they will take the rugs
to Constantinople with Senior Alp Turgut.
He will be held responsible
if any harm comes to the goods.
Smart man, knew how to win Ricardo over.
Batuhan. Where is Aslıhan?
I saw her going back to camp, sir.
You can buy whatever is needed
with this money.
Yes, sir.
Sir, Ural Bey is coming.
As if he realized his failure.
I'll talk to him.
You deal with your business.
I heard you sold all your rugs,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Showed some trading skills
in addition to your bravery.
I listened to what you said, Ural Bey.
Sold the rugs for a good price.
I like competency.
A competent rival keeps you virile.
Well, thanks to you I'll be more virile
and bold.
Excuse me.
Sir.
Shall we make them pay?
It will be
an exemplary punishment, Batuhan.
Slay all the Alps of Ertuğrul.
Set the rugs ablaze.
Burn their animals alive.
Let the land be filled with their groans.
Should they know it's us?
No...
He won't know who.
The craving for revenge
will eat him alive.
What about Lady Aslıhan, sir?
What will you do to her?
Bring it on, brother. Come on.
Here you go.
Take it easy, fellas.
I see you are in the mood.
Turgut Alp,
I didn't know you were able to laugh.
Who are these people?
These two Venetians will accompany you.
I'm sure you'll keep them safe.
I'd love to host you at our inn
and talk about your voyage.
What does she have to do with you?
I don't get it.
Obviously, Turgut Alp makes her head spin.
Just stop it!
It's inappropriate, Dundar Bey.
What is it?
You've fetched the whole bazaar.
Ertuğrul Bey asked for some materials,
I fetched them.
Well done.
We've got what we need, sir.
We can be on our way.
-Thank you, Dundar.
-We loaded the Venetians' cart
with the rugs. Ready to go.
Safe travels, Turgut Alp.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, brothers.
Sir, I got what you asked for.
Very well, then. Let's be on our way.
Yes, sir.
The wheel of fortune is spinning again.
Let's see who will be crushed this time.
Ural won't let the rugs
reach Constantinople.
With such lust in Ural,
it won't be easy for Turgut Alp.
May the Holy Spirit help him.
What's up, dear sister?
Do you want to lure Turgut Alp
into your net?
You're mistaken, Lord Simon.
My nets only serve our holy cause.
Glad to hear that.
There will be nothing left of Turgut Alp
but dust, soon.
We will enjoy setting the bandits
against each other
while Ural and the rugs burn
in the same flames.
Go for the Castle of Karacahisar
early in the morning.
They owe us a great deal.
I'd like you to negotiate with Philip.
Whoa!
Where is he?
-Where is the corpse of Toktamış?
-Aliyar Bey had it removed.
-Put him back where he was.
-It's too late.
Aliyar Bey had the body buried.
What have you done, Aslıhan?
What's up, brother?
Your eyes are about to pop.
I guess you couldn't take advantage
of the Venetians as you expected.
She is our sister.
Don't break hearts, brother.
Let my arm go, Aliyar.
Or I will break your heart.
If it will ease your anger...
so be it, brother.
Why did you tell him about the Venetians?
You put us in a hard place.
We couldn't sell the rugs because of you.
You lost because of your greed.
The responsibility is yours.
-Aslıhan!
-Brother!
Enough. Come to your senses.
Well, well, well!
Aliyar, this is real life.
It's much different than in those books.
-Know your place.
-What is going on here?
What's wrong with you?
Answer me, Ural.
I was unable to sell the rugs
because of Aslıhan, Father.
Is that true, Aslıhan?
Because of me?
You wanted to sell them
for more than the agreed price.
Why don't you admit you made a mistake?
Are you trying to make me pay
for your own faults, my brother?
Is this true, Ural?
I demanded more in order to bargain.
I thought we were the only option
for the Venetians.
However, Aslıhan happened to tell Ertuğrul
that the Venetians were buying rugs.
So they bought all the rugs of Kayi tribe.
How...
could you do that, Aslıhan?
After all our effort and sweat
trying to improve the rug house,
how could you turn a blind eye to it?
-Father, I just--
-She has stabbed us
in our backs, father.
This is a very bitter surprise, Aslıhan.
Shame on you.
I'm ashamed to have a daughter like you.
Sister Aslıhan made a mistake, Father.
The damage is done.
From now on, I don't want Aslıhan
to be with me in the bazaar dealings.
Either my wife Çolpan supports me
as the head of rug house
or you find someone else
to run the business instead of me.
It cost me 100 rugs. However,
I got rid of Aslıhan and won you.
Don't let Aslıhan get in my way again,
my Çolpan.
Don't you worry, Ural Bey.
I won't let her anywhere
near the rug house now.
Venetians were going to come to us
and buy our rugs.
The rugs of the Kayis will burn in flames.
Ertuğrul will be indebted.
I told that shepherd to go
back to his land, but he didn't listen.
He will pay dearly for it.
Maybe he will take Aslıhan with him
when he leaves, who knows?
-What do you think, my Çolpan?
-It's clear she felt for him.
She wouldn't do such a thing if not.
You...
trust in your man, my Çolpan.
With your loyalty and my power,
the Cavdar tribe
will get what it deserves.
-Welcome back, sir.
-Welcome, sir.
-Welcome, my brave fellow.
-Welcome, Bey.
Welcome back!
Everyone will be delighted, sir.
May God watch over you.
We knew you wouldn't let us go hungry.
Thanks to you, our tribe will be filled
with joy again. God bless you, sir.
-God bless you, too.
-Amen.
You brought food for us, sir!
God bless you.
-Father.
-My Gunduz.
Lend a hand, brothers.
Let's unload the bags.
Or we will starve
because of the long wait of unloading.
So help me God!
-May God protect him.
-Amen.
-Praise be.
-Dear God.
Welcome back, Son. Thank God.
Our tribe will be filled
with peace from now on.
As my mother says,
the steel met with the water.
Our tribe will find its way
just like the water does. God bless you.
We will always find our way
as long as you stand by our side.
Thank God,
our tribe is more prosperous than ever.
We have enough wheat
and flour for everyone.
May God rain prosperity over them.
-Amen.
Amen.
God bless you, sir.
May God watch over you.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
May God protect you.
-Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
-Long live!
Turgut Alp, we are ready to rest, sir.
Very well. Two of you stand guard
while the others are eating.
Then you'll sleep in turns.
No one shuts their eyes tonight.
-The goods we carry are of great value.
-Yes, sir.
Latin Crusaders invaded Constantinople,
persecuting their fellow Christians.
The Empire of Nicaea abhors the Crusaders,
hence the cooperation between
Sultan Kayqubad I and the Roman emperor.
And we stand at the border,
the most dangerous place to be.
But whoever controls these borders,
controls the future.
Then what we must do is
catch John the Baptist
and bring down his evil gang.
Sir, that's a sublime idea.
The only problem is we can't find him.
Bamsi, we'll not only find him...
...we'll bury him alive.
You may come in, Dumrul.
-Tell us about the marketplace.
-Sir, there was a commotion.
I followed Tristan the Trader,
as per your orders,
but I lost sight of him in the chaos.
A man in a thawb followed Tristan closely.
If it wasn't for me,
he would have been long dead.
Surely he'll appear again.
It will be a different man this time.
Who could that be, Master Simon?
Any ideas?
Yes.
Ertuğrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
Who could it be, Bey? Any ideas?
Yes.
The owner of the marketplace, Simon.
He has a hole in his ear
and has had great success over the years.
If he has armed troops as well,
then he either is John the Baptist...
or...
he serves under John the Baptist.
We must get into their den.
We must know for sure, Artuk Bey.
He accomplished great feats
as soon as he arrived.
He damaged the old hand, Ural.
We must take action against him.
Hasan, as a sound Muslim, it's your duty.
Yes, Master Simon.
As you wish.
I've caught everyone's attention now,
especially since I sold the produce
to the Venetians.
Just a little longer, my brave Alps.
Just a little.
But sir, for what?
For the resurrection, Bamsi.
For the rebirth of a nation!
Ya Allah!
-Father, do I have your permission?
-You may sit.
First Ural, now Aslıhan.
It's like I have been slapped
on both cheeks by my children.
I'm not going to beat around the bush.
This is the turning point in our lives.
Either we go down in flames
because of these heathens,
or we learn to stand up against them.
There is no way around it.
Our blessed Tatar tribe
has withstood all kinds of mishaps.
But now, my own kin have
turned against each other in my marquee.
-Father--
-That's not true.
Do not interrupt me!
Listen to me. Pull yourselves together!
Shatter the earth with each step you take!
With a single strike,
lay waste to your enemies!
Unite, or perish as the losers!
-Ural.
-Sir.
From this point onwards,
you will be responsible for trade,
as well as the safety
of our people and Alps.
Your wife shall lead the carpet weavers.
Aslıhan is stripped away from all duties,
except for the cleaning of the marquee.
I don't deserve this.
Now, you would do well to
make the best of what you have left.
Father, I can assure you that
I will carry out my duty properly.
I know Toktamış Bey is irreplaceable.
However, it's our duty do our best to
be an sufficient substitute for him.
On point, son.
That's why I will assign Aliyar that duty.
Together, we will make the decisions
regarding our future.
Of course, I'll not forget to
consult you as well.
However, Aliyar is the absolute
decision-maker from now on.
Dad, don't make me do this, please.
You know I've been meaning to
go to Qahira.
Not only am I not ready to
take on such a duty,
-I'm also not--
-Enough!
The days of us fighting
for our lives are not far away.
Either we all live together
or die together.
Reviving our settlement in Cavdar Plains
and making the most of things
is the only way.
Make no mistake!
To these ends, everything is permissible,
even the spilling of blood.
Lest you forget,
as the stone remains after the storm,
kinship remains after all else is gone.
Head to the market
tomorrow and see what's up.
You must learn the ropes.
Brother...
Don't do anything stupid.
We need you.
Only you can save us
from the greed of Ural
and the blind ambition
of Çolpan Hatun.
If you leave, you won't
be able to come back here,
nor will you ever see us
if you return.
Aykiz...
May God let us stay together forever.
I shall not live to see another day
without your love.
We are being attacked!
Protect the rugs!
-We're being attacked!
Take away the bodies.
We're not leaving them.
Yes, sir.
-Did my son fall asleep?
-Finally, thank God.
He won't stay still, Ertuğrul.
He's become such a rascal.
This is nothing, Halime.
This is just the first.
There will be a second, third...
fourth, fifth...
The prophet wants their ummah
to prosper and grow
so that we can
bring justice to these realms.
I hope so. I really do.
Ertuğrul, what keeps you
so deep in thought?
Turgut Alp.
He's been sulking ever since Aykiz died.
He was captured once.
He almost lost his mind,
but stayed with me, nevertheless.
I want to bring my brother back to life.
Get him to marry and father children.
Sure, but there is no woman here
befitting Turgut.
We can search the nearby settlements.
-Hopefully, we can find him a good woman.
-I hope so.
Once he returns safe and sound
with the rugs,
we'll see what we can do.
Like I said, brother, he was
fighting to the death like a madman.
If my father didn't act quickly...
we could've lost a family member.
Something tells me that Toktamış
was poisoned, Aslıhan.
I wouldn't be surprised.
Whoever profited off of his death...
Aslıhan.
Don't ever judge people on a whim.
Understood?
Everybody is innocent
until proven otherwise.
It doesn't matter if he was
poisoned or not. He still attacked us.
It does matter, but then again...
maybe it doesn't.
We shall see.
But a voice in my head tells me that
we should look into this matter closely.
We must see what's up.
Brother, I hope that voice in your head
also tells you not to leave this place.
If you were to go...
I'd be left all alone.
So, what happened at the marketplace?
Who is this Ertuğrul my brother detests?
The leader of the Kayi tribe.
He's a nimble man.
He has fought and defeated many enemies.
A determined man.
I shall go there tomorrow myself
and see with my own two eyes.
Ertuğrul Bey.
I know every inch of this place.
Gold is heavier than sand,
so there is more gold
to be found in weaker streams.
We should start by combing the Ayi stream
that flows around the Gedik well.
That stream may be weak, but it's deep,
Foreman Haçaturyan.
It's not an easy feat to find the bottom.
You're right, Artuk Bey, but the stream
turns and twists like a snake.
Rocks stand high at those bends.
When the rocks are high,
the stream loses its depth.
Gold hides in the nooks and crannies
of those rocks.
All we must do then is pan the sands.
They say it's easy to extract the gold.
Why, then, has nobody done this until now?
Because gold is skittish, Dündar Bey.
It moves around all the time.
If you don't know where it hides,
all you'll get is a handful of sand.
So, you have to put the sun,
wind and rain into consideration.
Winter is coming, Foreman Haçaturyan.
Once the rain starts to fall,
the streams surge.
We must be quick.
Right on point, sir. It's just as you say.
The best time is the end of summer.
If we find the right spot,
gold should come to us in piles.
Dündar, escort Foreman Haçaturyan
with the other Alps.
See to it that he's provided
with all he needs.
Protect him and keep this a secret.
As you wish, sir.
The rocks you stub your feet against
will soon turn to sand, sir.
We can crush those rocks
at any time, Colpan.
Now is the time for patience.
Sir, can I have a moment?
I carried out your orders.
We burned the rugs
and killed the Venetians and Alps.
-And you weren't seen, right?
-Not a soul saw us.
And we took care of the rest.
What's this smoke?
Follow me.
All dead.
Turgut? Turgut!
He is alive!
Don't worry. You'll live.
Let him die. It's all in accordance
with Master Simon's wishes.
Are you dumb, Philip?
If we take him to my brother,
he'll appreciate it.
He'll be delighted.
Absolutely delighted.
Now give me a hand!
What does it say?
The man who raided Saint Petruchio's
Templar stronghold in Antakya
and killed Titus and our brothers
turns out to be Ertuğrul.
We must take precautions. Ertuğrul might
just be the spy we're looking for.
Then it's time to move.
If Ertuğrul turns out to be the spy,
it'll be two presents in one
from our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ.
Have faith that God will make
the best decision for us.
In the 99 names of He
who gives life and fills us with faith.
In the name of God.
Brave sons of Kayi!
For so long, we've been
on foot, traveling.
We have defeated our enemies...
punished lawless rascals...
and eliminated many traitors.
And now, at last, a bright future
awaits us.
These lands are like no other.
We are not far from our enemies.
The battles here will be
nothing like what we know.
Therefore, we must adapt
to the state of things.
With respect, sir, we have devoted
our lives to your ideals.
You asked us to die for you,
and we are ready to.
However, we ask one thing of you,
and one thing only.
Go on, Karabey.
Don't deny us when we ask for a meeting.
Meetings are our traditional way.
A Bey does not act
without consulting others.
I'm of the same opinion, sir.
A Bey who does not consult others
is not a Bey at all.
Noble men of my tribe.
I see that I have upset the lot of you.
The reason I have not held any meetings
is the secret war that I've been fighting.
You must know that first.
However, from this point onwards,
I shall not turn you away anymore.
Thanks to God Almighty,
there are men that stand up
for their ideals in my tribe.
As long as you stand here
in the name of justice,
no one will bring us to our knees.
May you live long.
Abdurrahman.
-Bring me the chest for the distribution.
-As you wish, sir.
We found Turgut by the roadside, brother.
I thought he might be useful.
Just as you predicted, Ural had
the Venetians and Alps killed.
Well done, Maria. I've raised you well.
Take this man inside immediately.
-Philip.
-Sir.
Head over to the Kayi Tribe
and find Ertuğrul Bey.
Tell him that we found one of his men
heavily wounded.
Anton, take some men with you
and bring the corpses to me in a cart.
Yes, Master Simon.
We must make sure Ertuğrul
knows that we respect him.
I found this knife near Turgut.
The seal of the Cavdar tribe
is on the hilt.
Now we can play with Ural
like a cat plays with a mouse.
Not just with Ural, but with Ertuğrul,
the Sultan's spy, as well.
-Ural, oh, how I missed you!
-Will you go back to Nicaea?
I'm not leaving you again.
Look, I got you something.
Ural...
These are the shoes that I've been
dreaming about since forever!
I would grant you any wish, Amanda.
Any news from the market?
Maria and Philip brought in
a wounded man this morning.
-Who?
-A man named Turgut.
What did you just say?
Where is it? Where is it?!
Where is this accursed knife?! Damn it!
Turgut is alive, you fuckers!
And you told me you killed them all!
But sir, that's impossible!
We killed them all.
We burned their rugs.
I killed Turgut personally.
I know when I cut a man.
What are you talking about?
Then what the hell is Turgut doing at
the inn, you imbecile?!
Simon, you called for me?
Apparently, your rugs were burned.
What?
And two of your men died.
The bodies are being retrieved
as we speak.
Ertuğrul!
He gave his word
that he would cover any damages.
So, he's obliged to.
Sir, I can feel it! This is the place!
It's here! Come on, son.
This is the place.
Come on! Come on!
Come on, son! It's here!
This is the place, Dündar Bey!
We've found it!
The gold is here.
It has to be here.
The gold is here. It's all here.
It's here!
It's not here either.
Here, here it is.
Where is it? It has to be here!
It has to be here!
It was here! Where is it?
Sir, it was here!
It was here, Dündar Bey!
I was wrong, again, Dündar Bey.
But I know.
I know the stream with gold
that I found is around here.
If you could just
give me a bit more time, sir,
I will find the gold before the sunset.
-May I enter, sir?
-Come.
What is it, Aliyar? Speak up.
Father, they raided the caravans
transporting the Kayis' rugs.
They murdered their Alps.
What kind of treacherous
thief could do this?
Theft is not the problem, father.
The rugs were all burned.
Why would they raid the caravan
if not for the rugs?
Ural!
You are right, Father.
I overheard my brother, Ural,
and Batuhan speaking.
If Ertuğrul catches wind of this...
It will not end well
for either of our Muslim tribes.
Especially since
we're surrounded by infidels.
The Cavdar tribe is bigger.
The Kayis have no chance of winning,
but you are right.
And if Ertuğrul Bey hears of this,
there can obviously be no victors.
Listen well, Aliyar.
Go find Ertuğrul Bey
and tell him this:
"Candar Bey would be happy to
invite you over for dinner
in order to get to know your family.
He'd be honored to have a brave man
such as yourself over for dinner."
Got it?
Your sword will protect
not just your chest
but your back as well,
so make sure you keep an eye on your back.
Dad!
You'll be the master of Zulfiqar swords
one day, just like Daddy.
You'll swing your sword in the name
of justice, like your uncles and grandpa.
Ertuğrul Bey, you have a visitor.
Sir, isn't that the guy
who was with Simon?
Let's see what he has to say.
Sir, with your permission,
this man wants to see you.
His name is Philip.
He says he works with the innkeeper Simon.
You may speak, Philip.
Ertuğrul Bey, I bring you
Master Simon's regards.
Received. So, what's wrong?
On the way to Constantinople,
the Alps that were escorting your rugs...
they were attacked.
What, did he say attacked?
No!
Unbelievable.
How is that possible?
We must take revenge.
Silence! Can't you see Bey is talking?
Unfortunately, all your Alps were killed.