Episode 90 will start after 12:30 min.
We keep encountering each other.
And you keep running away, Vasilius.
So, you took your Sultan
for a walk on my land, huh?
To think my fate would allow me
to see both of you together.
You can't see our Sultan,
even in your dreams, Vasilius.
This, again?
It's a trap! Attack!
This is...
how to ambush.
They are everywhere.
Everywhere!
Come on, everybody!
Ertuğrul!
One of us must die today.
May I enter, Halime Sultan?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
-Any news from Ertuğrul Bey?
-Thank God Ibn Arabi
-cured our Sultan.
-Thank God!
And he saved Ertuğrul Bey
as soon as he got up.
Thank God!
Where is he now? At the inn?
He took off with our men
to catch Vasilius.
He wants us to join
with the soldiers from Cavdar Tribe,
and protect our Sultan.
I will send our soldiers to the Sultan
along with Dündar Bey.
Go fast, Dündar Bey.
Don't leave the Sultan alone.
May God help you.
I leave the tribe to you, Artuk Bey.
Go safely, Dündar Bey.
My God!
It's time for you to die, Vasilius.
You may kill me,
but our empire
will live forever, Ertuğrul.
For God!
Sir!
God's blessing.
Men!
Sir!
Retreat!
Protect our bey!
Bamsi! Abdur Rahman!
Sir, are you all right?
Turgut, pull the arrow.
You will lose a lot of blood
if I pull it, sir.
Take it out, Turgut.
Or else, Vasilius will get away.
Go on.
Bear with me, sir.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
For God!
I sent my men to save Vasilius,
Your Highness.
They won't return
before they kill Ertuğrul.
Do you trust those men?
They took this job on my orders.
They won't budge.
Good.
Great.
I don't want any trouble, Cabir.
Tell your men to be alert.
Yes, sir.
May I enter?
Come in.
Sultan wants to see you, Your Highness.
Leave.
I said leave!
Commander Nikolas!
A message from the men
watching over the market.
What is it?
Their Sultan is gone,
but they are still on alert.
Its looks like
they're expecting another attack.
If their Sultan is not there,
what's all this fuss about?
What if the Sultan never actually left?
But how?
Ertuğrul...
He deceived us.
They lured Governor Vasilius
and our men to themselves.
They knew we were going to
attack the inn to kill the Sultan.
They prevented it.
What should we do now,
Commander Nikolas?
We won't wait for the Governor
and attack the inn ourselves.
It won't be long before they find out
that Ertuğrul Bey tricked
Governor Vasilius, Ameer.
Once they find out, they will attack
the marketplace.
I've taken some measures of my own,
Your Highness.
You may rest to recover
from that cursed poison.
I'm okay, Sadettin.
I'm okay.
I'm more worried about
the traitor among us.
With respect, sir, we don't know
who poisoned you, or when.
You visited both tribes.
It's possible that this disaster
happened in either of the tribes.
However, we will find the culprit.
I thought that traitor was
among us, at the inn.
Even so, we will bring him to justice.
I'll find out who
orchestrated this, Sadettin.
Come here, brother.
What do we do? We stop the bleeding.
We need to stop the bleeding.
-Thank you, brother.
-Come on.
Sir!
Sir! Sir!
Who were they, Bamsi?
I have no idea who they might be, sir.
We got two of them, but
the other three got away.
They were trained archers,
they wouldn't let us move, sir.
Vasilius got away once again.
That coward! Let's go after him.
Günküt, Dumrul,
tend to your wounds first.
Take the injured men to the inn.
And tell our Sultan what happened here.
Yes, sir.
Bamsi, Turgut,
we will go after Vasilius.
Take two men each.
Come on.
We have horses this way, sir.
Fool! We won't run away.
They will come after us.
We will end this today.
One of us dies!
This will be the last battle.
And it will be the Sultan's turn next.
This way.
This way!
No soldiers, they are defenseless.
Ready the men
to sneak through the stream bed.
Yes, sir.
On your horses!
Come on!
Commander Nikolas, soldiers from
Kayi and Çavdar are going to the inn.
That damned Turk!
Before we realized his plans
he called for backup from their tribes.
They have more men than us now, sir.
We can't win if we attack.
If they know that we are here,
they will attack first.
Today is not the day for our victory.
Let's pray that Governor Vasilius
gets back to the fortress safely.
What if Ertuğrul ambushed him?
We don't know where they went.
We left the fortress defenseless.
We must go back!
Turgut, Bamsi. Be careful.
Vasilius is not alone.
Whoever those bastards were,
he will want to group up
and ambush us.
Our day has come, sir.
This ambush will be his grave.
Come on! Come on!
What happened after I was poisoned, Aziz?
Tell me everything.
Ameer Sadettin imprisoned
Ertuğrul Bey first.
Ibn Arabi, who you invited here, tried to
heal you after he heard what happened.
However...
What is it?
Ameer Sadettin
didn't let him in
thinking about your safety, Your Highness.
He wanted to protect me
from that holy man?
If Ertuğrul Bey's soldiers
had not insisted,
he was going to throw Ibn Arabi out
along with the soldiers,
Your Highness.
I stepped out of line and
opposed Ameer's orders.
And let Ibn Arabi in, Your Highness.
Why did he imprison Ertuğrul Bey?
Did he tell you anything?
He said he didn't trust him.
When the chief physician
couldn't do anything,
I insisted that Ibn Arabi
treat you, Your Highness.
You did the right thing, Aziz.
Rest at ease.
Your Highness.
Dündar Bey has come.
Let him in.
Dündar Bey, His Highness wants to see you.
On Ertuğrul Bey's orders
we have come to ensure your safety, sir.
Men of Kayi and Cavdar tribes
are ready to die for your safety,
Your Highness.
I see in your eyes the same brilliance
as I do in your brother's, Dündar Bey.
If God permits it,
Ertuğrul Bey's brilliance
will give merry hell
to those arrogant bastards.
I've no doubt that Ertuğrul Bey
will emerge victorious.
I'd hope so, Your Highness.
Because this is the moment of truth.
May your leadership long continue
so that our nation may be everlasting.
Your Highness.
With your permission,
Hayme Hatun and Aslıhan Hatun
would also like to see you.
Let them in.
Stop!
This would make a good ambush spot.
They'll probably
follow our tracks anyway.
But sir, they outnumber us.
The archers dealt with most of them.
We've the same numbers.
We still don't know who
those archers were, sir.
They can't be our men.
Whoever they were, what's important
is that they saved us.
I think that they are
Ameer Sadettin's men.
Only Ameer Sadettin
could have sent help to us.
But, how could he?
He's probably helping us to
stop Ertuğrul in his tracks.
Scatter around!
Scatter! Take your positions.
In your positions!
Would you like to sit?
As I was fighting for my life,
it is said, Sadettin threw
your men out with force.
Despite that, you still came
with the other Turkmen beys
to the Hanlı Bazaar.
We would never
leave you or Ertuğrul Bey alone,
Your Highness.
Thank God Arabi cured you.
What would you have done if Ibn Arabi
couldn't save my life, and Ameer Sadettin
continued to blame Ertuğrul Bey?
What would you do then?
Then,
we'd insist on the path
we think to be true, Your Highness.
Our ardor and faith
in our country
would not allow us to
let you or Ertuğrul Bey fall prey
to Ameer Sadettin's mistake,
Your Highness.
We have seen many a great nation fall
due to the weakness of their
respective ameers.
If Artuk Bey
had not insisted on Arabi treating you,
and if we had not
tried to convince Ameer Sadettin
that he was being mistaken,
then both Ameer Sadettin and
our country would have been weakened.
And you would go against the man
you are going to marry, Aslıhan Hatun?
We would not stop
to think and go against the whole world
if it's for you and Ertuğrul Bey's sakes.
Plus...
I won't be marrying Ameer Sadettin.
Is that so?
I voiced my wishes to lead the tribe
that my brother entrusted me with.
I respectfully told him
that even if our revenge is taken,
and Karacahisar is conquered,
I'm never going to leave my tribe.
I'm the last child of my father,
the very bey of the Cavdars.
It'd be improper to leave, Your Highness.
I'll forever hold that what keeps
my country on its feet is you, the women.
You don't just give birth
to those brave men.
You raise them
and you're also battle ready
on their side at all times.
God bless you women,
who keep our nation alive.
Come now, Ertuğrul.
Come to your death.
It's like that coward hid in a hole.
Where could he disappear
to in the blink of an eye?
It's like he vanished into thin air.
Sir, I saw horses by the stream bed.
It's their horses.
They are still here.
Keep watch on us from afar.
It looks like Vasilius
wants to ambush us.
Yes, sir.
As you wish, sir.
Let's go.
God, help us.
Help us, God.
Commander.
What happened?
Ertuğrul fooled both us
and Governor Vasilius.
What do you mean? Where is Vasilius?
I don’t know.
I don't know, Ekaterina. Got it?
Commander Nikolas.
One of the soldiers that went with
Vasilius has arrived.
Let him in right away.
Yes, sir.
Guards!
Tell me what happened now!
Where is Vasilius?
Sir, Ertuğrul fooled us once again.
The man with him wasn't Sultan Alaeddin.
I knew it! Damn it!
We fought hard.
Governor managed to get away
with the few soldiers left alive.
If the archers had not come just in time
we'd all have died.
What archers?
Who were they?
We don't know.
So that means we are not
fighting damned Ertuğrul alone.
-Do you know where they are?
-Yes, sir.
Send them reinforcements right away!
Guards!
You still can't tell your friends
from your foes.
You still haven't figured out
whose men those archers are.
Just pray that nothing
happens to Vasilius,
because then
Ertuğrul would be able to conquer
this fortress with just his men.
If you are so experienced,
tell me who those archers are.
Long live Nicaea!
You won't live to see it, Vasilius.
Your Highness.
Ertuğrul Bey's injured men have come.
One of them wants to talk to you.
Let him in.
Speak.
What happened?
Your Highness, we beat
Vasilius and his men.
Just as Ertuğrul Bey was
about to kill Vasilius,
some men came to Vasilius' rescue.
They shot Ertuğrul Bey with bows.
May God protect them.
Who were those archers?
We have no idea, Your Highness.
However, our men went after them.
Where is Ertuğrul Bey?
Vasilius got away.
Ertuğrul Bey and his men went after him.
He sent me to let you know, Your Highness.
May God
help them.
Not this time, you bastards!
Ertuğrul got away.
Again.
Cabir, why did your esteemed soldiers
fail to carry it out?
Those soldiers have no fear of death,
Your Highness.
They won't let Ertuğrul escape.
They won't come back
unless they kill him
or die trying.
Everybody dies.
Right, Cabir?
Unless they accomplish their mission,
what use is it if they die?
Who cares?
They would die in vain.
Your Highness.
We know that Ertuğrul Bey
went after Vasilius with few men.
Many of his men returned heavily injured.
My soldiers will carry it out.
It seems you don't know
Ertuğrul yet, Cabir.
They only had one chance.
If they could have done it the first time,
it was over.
Now, it's too late.
Ertuğrul must be prepared now.
Just pray that
he doesn't catch your soldiers alive.
Get out!
Reso, come on!
Long live hell for all tyrants!
Tell me, Ekaterina.
Who went for Vasilius's rescue?
Emir Sadettin.
What did you just say?
-It's impossible.
-It is not, Nikolas.
Your biggest ally against the sultan
and Ertuğrul will be Emir Sadettin.
If we don't put his support
to good use, we'll lose the fortress.
We won't let them take it.
Vasilius will be back.
In all likelihood, Ertuğrul
probably caught him already.
And he will probably have killed him
before your men reach them.
What happens afterwards, Nikolas?
The Turks will make for this place
right away.
They can't breach our walls.
There is not even a crack in the walls.
We doubled the guards.
We will ask for reinforcements.
You still don't get it.
What wins wars is not numbers
but the commander's brains.
And what are you basing
your assumptions on?
You just came here, Nikolas.
But I've lived with them for years.
I know how they think well.
I won't let them take my father's legacy.
But how?
We will kill Ertuğrul
with Emir Sadettin's help.
There's no other way.
Why would Emir Sadettin,
the vizier of the Seljuks,
help us kill Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul's success is driving him crazy.
He'd do anything to put an end to him.
The archers he sent is proves it.
He made a deal with my husband before.
Now, he'll make a deal with me.
We won't give up our fortress.
Vasilius will return.
-And if he doesn't--
-If he doesn't, Nikolas,
I will take command of this fortress.
It's over, sir. He died.
We have avenged...
Brother Doğan...
and brother Aliyar,
along with many others that died.
Rest in peace, Doğan.
May your soul...
rest in peace.
Rest in peace, Aliyar Bey.
We will take Vasilius's body to the inn.
Samsa, make for the fortress.
Tell them that they should
take the governor's corpse.
Yes, sir.
Now that we destroyed these tyrants,
our people will be proud of you.
It's not our victory,
but God's himself, Samsa.
As long as we fight in his name,
nobody can beat us.
However,
if, one day, we think that
it is our victory...
and forget about our cause,
and if we tarnish our cause with...
riches and reputation,
then...
God will make sure we end up the same.
Listen to me well now.
Neither my heart...
nor my men's hearts
can carry more than one love.
We will think and speak what we think.
We will walk the path...
for the same goal.
Allahu akbar!
God bless, look at him.
There is still no news...
from Ertuğrul Bey or the others.
I wonder if something happened to them?
God forbid.
Don't talk like that, Hafsa Hatun.
We will get their good news soon.
Don't you worry.
Whenever...
Bamsi goes to a battle,
I feel like I'm going with him to fight.
It's such a heavy weight.
The wife of an alp
must be strong, Hafsa.
She must keep her head high.
And control her impulses.
Let the wind and waters...
take your worries away,
so that when he is back from fighting,
you can welcome him with a smile.
Is this how it's going to keep on going,
Halime Sultan?
The cycle of separation and reunion
is our fate, Hafsa.
That's why we must always
be patient and strong.
Banu Çiçek!
-Banu Çiçek!
It's coming!
My baby is coming!
Hafsa, quick. Call the midwives.
-Have them come at once.
-Yes, Halime Sultan.
Are you okay? Here, lean back.
Lie down and stretch out your feet.
It's time, Halime.
Your Highness.
Men like me wear a burial robe
as their clothes.
That cloth wraps this poor body of mine,
and I'd lay my life down for you anytime.
This inn belongs to Ertuğrul Bey,
and you were his guest.
Anyone would have done the same.
Did you protect me from a holy man's vice
like Ibn Arabi did, Sadettin?
Or did you protect me from Ertuğrul Bey,
whom I trust more than
most other emirs and commanders,
and who I bestowed with more power?
Answer! Why did you do it?
If Ibn Arabi had not made it in time
and saved my life, do you know
what would have happened?
Turkmen beys were going to take
Ertuğrul Bey from you with force.
Because in their eyes, Ertuğrul Bey is
way more honorable than you.
If I had died, Sadettin, not even
the crusader army
could have hurt my country
more than you would have,
let alone the emperor.
You wronged me, Sadettin.
Your Highness, I--
Your mistake would not have
caused just my death,
but also, the destruction of these lands
and discord between our people.
I always valued your wisdom,
and your skills.
However, you put me and my country...
in danger when I was in such a sad state.
Waiting is killing me, Mother.
Come here.
I used to wait for my father,
who never stopped fighting.
And then Suleyman Shah.
And then I waited for my sons.
And all I could do...
was to seek refuge in God.
We are already going through
such hard times.
And now Emir Sadettin is...
What did he do again?
When I told him that I wouldn't marry him,
he said he'd never give up on me.
His malice started showing up
in the way he talks.
And then he made a full circle
to get at Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul? What does it have
to do with Ertuğrul?
He said my faith in Ertuğrul
lead me to take charge of my tribe.
He thinks I refused his proposition,
because Ertuğrul Bey
protects me and my tribe.
To hell with him! That demon!
-May I enter, Mother?
-Come in, Dündar.
Ertuğrul Bey and the others
are coming back to the inn.
Thank God.
I gather you are not happy
with the measures I took, Your Highness.
I succumbed when I saw you
wriggling in pain.
I understand now.
But I'm ready for my punishment.
I see that you lack the respect
of many Turkmen beys...
in these lands that I entrusted you,
who I had faith in.
Your Highness.
If you have even the slightest
doubt that I won't
be able to carry out my duty,
then relieve me of this duty
until the bastard that attempted
this hideous murder is found.
You may even take my life.
I'd happily lay my life down for you
and surrender myself to the executioner.
Your Highness, a messenger from Konya
brought this letter to you.
They caught the traitor in my palace.
It was my personal aide Kasim.
He confessed everything.
It was he who told the emperor
that I was here.
Then, the one who orchestrated
your murder with poison
must have been that lowly Vasilius.
Only such a lowly man could do
something like this.
He will dread every moment he's alive
and beg for me to kill him.
As for you, Emir Sadettin.
If God permits and
Ertuğrul Bey returns in one piece,
then you will ask for his forgiveness.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Ertuğrul Bey and his men are coming back.
Thank God.
Guards!
Your Highness.
Vasilius, who was cruel...
to both his own people and us,
and who waged wars against our country,
our faith, and our traditions,
got what he deserved.
Brave is the man who sacrifices
his life for his people and country.
And hero is the one
that shines the light of hope
on his people in darkest of times.
Ertuğrul Bey, you became...
a ray of hope in such hard times
to your people with your courage.
God bless you.
Our martyrs have been avenged,
Your Highness.
We got our revenge for the deaths...
of my brothers Aliyar and Doğan,
as well as many others that died.
Their fortress is left leaderless now.
A fortress without a leader needs a flag.
The one who will raise our glorious flag
in the towers of that fortress...
will be none other than you.
God bless your victory, Ertuğrul Bey.
You showed dignity and tenacity
in face of the cruel,
and humility in face of the oppressed.
God heard your wishes and made you
into the leader of the oppressed.
May God grant you many more victories.
Amen.
-Amen.
Your mother loves you so much.
Thank God.
You got rid of yet another problem.
Thank you, Mother.
You kept your promise, Ertuğrul Bey.
You avenged my brother.
God bless you.
May you be brave and victorious forever.
Thank you, Aslıhan Hatun.
God bless your victory, Ertuğrul Bey.
With this victory,
Ertuğrul Bey not only saved
our sultan's life,
but also proved just how great
a margrave he is.
Your Highness.
I sent a messenger to the fortress.
They will take the governor's
body tomorrow.
I'd like to display his body
to make an example of it,
if you would allow it.
The wolf does not hide its prey
like a jackal.
It's not just appropriate.
It's the right thing to do.
Thank God.
You got your baby safe and sound.
We will see you with your baby, too
if God permits, Hafsa Hatun.
I hope so, Banu Çiçek.
Ah, Hafsa Hatun.
If only Doğan was here as well...
If only he could see his baby...
It's true that he can't see his baby,
but we will see that our revenge
is taken, Banu Çiçek.
May God give strength
to Ertuğrul Bey and his men.
Amen.
Come, Halime Sultan.
Bismillah.
God bless you.
You didn't leave me alone.
We all did what we had to do, Banu Çiçek.
I have good news for you.
What is it?
Ertuğrul Bey and his men got back
to the inn, safe and sound.
Thank God.
Vasilius was brought to justice
by the sword of Ertuğrul Bey.
He avenged our brave men.
Vasilius will burn in hell
for all eternity.
Such good news, Halime Sultan.
At last, my father and our men
can rest in peace.
Rest in peace, Doğan.
You have been avenged.
Our son will grow up to be
a gallant alp worthy of you.
The traitor in my palace
told the emperor that I was here.
And he confessed to this.
Vasilius could have found a way
to poison me somehow.
I understand that.
But after what you said to me,
I see that this doesn't end there.
Until we find the archers...
that appeared out of nowhere
when Vasilius fell into my trap,
your life will be in danger,
Your Highness.
Nobody knew that you were going to
ambush Vasilius outside of this inn,
Ertuğrul Bey.
The vermin responsible for that
is somewhere in the inn, Your Highness.
It can't be the other tribes you visited.
All the troubles started with
Sadettin Köpek's arrival at the inn.
If the traitor in my palace
wasn't caught and confessed it all,
I'd suspect him as well.
However,
Emir Sadettin didn't know...
that I was here when he came.
I don't believe that Emir Sadettin
would work with the traitor in my palace.
Nevertheless, it's good that
we both know about it.
Aziz.
Yes, Your Highness.
Call Emir Sadettin.
I thank you...
for letting me in, Aslıhan.
I consider an emir's request an order.
Stop this "emir" bullshit, for God's sake.
I came here as Sadettin.
A miserable man that's in love with you.
A man that came to talk to the woman...
who promised to spend a lifetime with him,
and then turned her back.
I've already moved past that phase,
Your Highness.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Out of respect for my father,
I accepted to be your wife.
-However, with my brother dead...
-Aliyar Bey's revenge is taken.
Am I right?
He has been avenged.
When will you stop being so stubborn?
Will you act as the representative
of the great Cavdar tribe
for the rest of your life?
What's keeping you there?
Just what?
Nobody can take me away from my tribe,
Your Highness.
Not even you.
His Highness is waiting for you, sir.
Still no news.
And all we can do is sit tight and wait.
We sent our men.
We are not just waiting, doing nothing.
We are protecting our fortress.
To the contrary, you look too dumbfounded
to lift a muscle,
Commander Nikolas.
Commander Nikolas, a Turk has come
as the messenger of Ertuğrul Bey.
Let him in at once.
Speak, Turk.
Governor Vasilius is dead.
What did you say?
His body is at the inn.
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to take it.
No harm will be done
to those that come to take the body.
That's all.
Murderers!
I'll kill you all one by one!
Then, you should start with me, Commander.
If you can, that is.
Nikolas! Let him go.
He isn't as valuable as Vasilius's body.
If you kill him,
they'll feed the governor's body
to the crows.
Get the hell out!
Get out!
Open the doors!
Send Artuk Bey to the fortress
as a messenger
when you go back to your tribe.
It will be my last call
for them to surrender.
As you wish, Your Highness.
You sent for me, Your Highness.
Come, Sadettin.
Nikolas either surrenders the fortress
or his life, along with those inside.
My army is on the way for the siege.
Until my army comes
and my marquee is built,
I'll continue staying here as a guest.
That's a great decision, Your Highness.
It's only appropriate for you
to rest here tonight.
However, as you have already said,
it's possible that the traitor
that almost killed you is here.
If that's so, it's your job
to take measure, Sadettin.
Leave it to me, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
With your permission, I have something
I need to tell Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey, I had to make
a weighty decision
when that disaster took place.
That's why I thought it was necessary
to take measure
against you and your men.
I believe you understand my decision.
You may not trust me,
but I expected you to at least
trust Ibn Arabi, Emir Sadettin.
You and Ibn Arabi have my full faith.
I know very well just
how important you are
to our sultan.
However, as I said, I acted out of duty.
Your duty, as my emir,
was to make the best decision.
However, you failed to do it.
I know, Your Highness.
However, the gravity of the situation
compelled me to do what I did.
Nobody would have expected
something like this to happen
at Ertuğrul Bey's inn.
We are at war, Emir Sadettin.
Everywhere is a battlefield
when we are at war.
You know that better than me.
We must be prepared for and expect
all kinds of schemes.
After all, what our enemies like the best
is to set brothers against each other.
And if God had not protected us,
their schemes would have worked out.
And you, Sadettin,
would have been tricked...
and caused a huge disaster.
Your Highness,
what happened here taught me
and the others a great many things.
In the future, we will be mindful
and we won't succumb to such tricks.
There is no future for you, Sadettin.
There is no future for you.
Such a huge mistake
will cost you your life.
My life is yours to take, Your Highness.
Oh, Vasilius.
I should have prevented you
from going after Ertuğrul.
I should have died instead of you.
Nicaea will remember you,
brave commander, forever.
We won't forget what you have done for us.
Commander, stop whining.
What do you think you are doing?
He was my friend.
How could you be so apathetic?
I lost my feelings when I lost my child.
No death can hurt me now.
And you...
As you keep whining,
we will lose everything we have.
-We won't lose anything.
-Gather your commanders.
We must take measure and plan
our next move at once.
We will decide what to do next.
You have no power here.
And this comes from a man
that can't even manage his emotions?
This was my father's fortress.
I'll answer to no one protecting it.
Now, heed my words and work with me.
Do you think commanders
would listen to a woman?
A woman can change everything, Nikolas.
Do as I say.
I don't want any soldiers sleeping.
They will all keep watch on the walls.
It's only a matter of time
until Ertuğrul comes knocking.
Gather your commanders and take measure.
We will make them regret
ever thinking about it.
One more step, Father.
Just one more step...
and I will have your legacy.
-As salaam alaikum.
-Wa alaikum as salaam.
In the name of God, most gracious,
most compassionate.
Glory can't be beat with a mace.
Friends don't take offense with a word.
Crooked are words if they contain lies.
Brave is the one that speaks the truth
and straightens those words.
And the meeting of beys by tradition
is where the truth is spoken.
Blessed be our meeting.
Amen.
Now that our brave Turkmen beys
know the state of things,
they deserve to know what happens next.
What I'm about to tell you
is stating the obvious.
I entrusted these lands to
my margrave Ertuğrul Bey...
and to you.
May your new home be abundant.
-Amen.
-Good luck.
May God spare us any shame.
You are right, Your Highness.
As things stand,
the war with the heathens...
will not end, despite all the dead.
It's time to breach their walls.
Karacahisar, the nest of all evil,
will be sieged...
and will collapse around their heads.
Until the last drop of our blood,
Your Highness.
We are at your service, Your Highness.
The lion's share of this great victory
belongs to Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey's ability
has been proven every time
we have gotten into trouble.
Your Highness speaks the truth.
I succumbed to anger...
due to the most sordid incidents...
that took place earlier.
I offended Ertuğrul Bey...
and all the other beys present here.
I beg all of you for forgiveness.
It will not be repeated.
The basis of justice will not be
tarnished with baseless claims,
and no emir...
or even a sultan,
may pull our country down
with a summary execution.
I'll serve to the best of my abilities
in the position
that our sultan sees fit for me.
We have been studying
Karacahisar Fortress for a while now.
We know well its strengths and weaknesses.
Now, on the orders of our sultan,
and with the help of his armies,
conquest has become possible.
Now, what befalls us
is to raise our glorious flag
on the walls of that fortress.
After the conquest,
I'll grant Ertuğrul Bey the control...
of these lands, and the fortress.
My armies will aid you in the conquest.
So long as you stay united,
we'd know no defeat in both worlds.
As you wish, Your Highness.
We've been looking forward to it.
Thank God we will get to taste victory
under your command.
The meeting is over.
Now, dull your tongues
and sharpen your swords.
Long live the Sultan!
Long live our country!
"To the all powerful
and all glorious emperor.
I carry the baby of great
Commander Vasilius in my womb.
In the defense of our lands
against the Turks,
I'd like to fight to
the last drop of my blood.
I'm ready to lay my life down to avenge
the death of his father.
I seek refuge in your mercy and might.
I wish to take back the rights left by
my late father, that are rightfully mine.
Before I seclude myself to the church
as a nun,
I ask for your permission
to defend this fortress
that my father built himself.
Ekaterina, your most faithful servant
that wants to serve you honorably,
instead of living like a parasite."
Our baby will get back at whoever
did this to us, Ural.
I'll raise our child to be worthy of you.
May you rest in peace.
We have come to take Governor
Vasilius' body, Ertuğrul Bey.
You have a right to
bury your governor properly.
A bey is one who
even the enemy respects.
How lucky you are
that God gifted you with such virtues.
I hope the people of Karacahisar
make the right decision
and prevent any more bloodshed.
That's all I could ever wish for,
Your Highness.
Surely, they will.
And it will be Artuk Bey
that will act as
an important messenger.
I'll wait for your good news,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll come to you as soon as I can,
Your Highness.
If you will excuse me now.
Loyal commanders of Nicaea.
Veteran warriors of our fortress.
We are deeply grieved with the loss
of our governor.
However, we still have a mission.
I gathered you here today to talk about
the measures we need to take
to defend our fortress.
Are we going to do it
in front of a woman, Commander Nikolas?
This woman is the daughter of
the strongest governor of this fortress.
She has a right to speak
just as much as you.
That's disrespectful! Unheard of!
It's against our rules.
Commanders, please listen.
Ekaterina knows the Turks best among us.
I'll vouch for her.
Plus, as things stand,
our rules may change.
We are at war.
Our governor has been killed
and you're still going on about rules.
I'd like to ask you great commanders.
Do you have any idea what
we should do next?
Of course, we will protect our fortress.
And how?
We have walls and soldiers.
Our fortress was breached many times.
Hundreds of our soldiers were killed.
We will ask for reinforcements
from the emperor.
We will get more soldiers,
and take more measures.
That means we will
just lose more soldiers.
And the emperor will hold you responsible
for each soldier that's killed.
Plus, the measures you take
will prove to be utterly useless.
And finally, we will lose our fortress
and get trampled upon by the boots
of those Turks.
What do you suggest, Ekaterina?
We need an ally that can take them down
from inside.
We will hit them where it hurts the most.
They will start killing each other
before they can even reach the fortress.
After all, if they manage to come here,
nothing can stop them, not our soldiers,
and certainly not the walls.
We will start a war between them.
We won't lose a single man.
We brought Governor Vasilius' body,
Commander Nikolas.
Then let us hold a burial ceremony.
Governor Vasilius has sacrificed
his life for our sake.
We shall give him a proper send off.
Get in, Gündüz.
Mother.
Welcome.
Thank you, dear.
Thank God.
-My son.
-Grandma!
Your grandma loves you so much.
God bless your victory, dear.
Halime, my love.
Your prayers helped us win.
God bless you, Halime.
God bless your victory, dear.
Come here.
Big boy.
Once you grow up to be a brave alp,
we will fight wars along
with your brother Savcı.
May God permit.
How is the situation here, Artuk Bey?
Nothing is out of the ordinary,
it's just as you left it, sir.
We were concerned only about you.
Thank God you came back safely
and victorious, to top it off.
All our concerns and worries
have disappeared.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Our Sultan saw you fit to go to
Karacahisar as a messenger.
God bless our Sultan, sir.
I'm honored to take his order.
Once you reach the fortress,
tell the commander that
they should surrender before our
Mighty Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad arrives.
Otherwise, I shall leave no one alive,
and destroy that fortress.
Leave it to me, sir.
I'll get going right away.
Bey.
I have good news for you.
What is it, Halime?
You have a healthy nephew.
Banu Çiçek...
Thank God.
How is she, dear?
She is great, Mother.
She gave birth to a healthy son
without a sweat.
God bless.
God bless, I'm happy for her.
Amen.
Banu Çiçek.
My forlorn girl.
May God help us protect
this peace forever, Dündar.
Amen, brother.
God bless both Artuk Bey and Ishak.
Thank God they treated your wounds.
That's right.
I lost count of how many wounds
Artuk Bey and Ishak treated.
I'd always put ointment
on my wounds by myself.
Or it was my brothers.
And now, it is you.
With the touch of your hands,
I'm sure my wounds will close up sooner
and I'll feel no pain anymore.
Rather than being the cure of your wounds,
I'm more worried about seeing
you wounded like this again, Bamsi.
It's over now.
The head of the snake is crushed.
-No need to worry.
-Thank God.
Now, my father can rest in peace as well.
It's one bit of good news after another.
Oh, I hope it's good.
Tell me what is it, love.
-Bamsi.
-Yes?
Congratulations.
Hafsa Hatun, don't say that
I'll be a father.
Not a father, but an uncle, Bamsi.
Meaning?
Oh, my God! Did Çiçek Hatun give birth?
Oh, my God! I'm an uncle!
I'm an uncle!
How is he, Hafsa?
What does it look like?
How much does it weigh?
Hafsa Hatun, is it a he or she?
It's a he, Bamsi.
Oh, my God! One more alp for us!
God bless!
Hafsa Hatun, let me pass this
on to my brothers.
Let me tell them about it.
I can't wait.
I can't wait, I'm going.
Here I go.
Bamsi! Change your clothes before you go!
-May I enter?
-Come in, Ertuğrul Bey.
Sit.
It's so nice to see you in such bliss.
-May God make it everlasting.
-Amen.
Thanks to your prayers and favor,
we defeated that troublesome Vasilius.
Now, all I hope for
is to raise our flag
on Karacahisar Fortress.
Strive for it, and God shall help,
Ertuğrul Bey.
May God help you work harder.
If you make every effort for it,
God will fill in if you need anything.
Thank you.
You fight against the cruel
to spread God's words
and for the victory of Islam.
As our holy religion dictates,
we shall strive to save the oppressed
from the hands of the cruel.
You aim to establish justice
in the whole world.
Our prophet Muhammad
says this in one of his sayings.
If winning prizes,
gaining fame and glory
and gaining authority
are the reasons for this war,
then it's no war. The real war
strives to bring glory to God's name.
How lucky you are to be
fighting for this holy cause.
Our prophet and other Muslims
fought in the Badr, against the cruel
who severely outnumbered them.
And he emerged victorious.
After Badr came the Battle of Uhud.
And the Battle of the Trench ensued.
There was no end to the many wars
and the amount of dead.
We must be prepared for Uhud-like wars.
We must be prepared for more Trenches.
That's why we must not
let ourselves relax just yet.
Once the prophet got back from a battle,
he said this to his followers:
"This turned into a great jihad,
which was only a small one."
His believers were dumbfounded.
They asked the prophet
if there were greater wars.
He said this unto them:
"The real great war is against greed."
Ertuğrul Bey, you are only victorious
if you can grasp the hearts.
You must be free from arrogance,
disdain, and ambition.
We need you.
Your existence gives us strength.
May God bless you.
There are two kinds of soldiers,
Ertuğrul Bey.
One strives for victory,
while the other for prayers.
One fights with his swords,
while the other embraces
a shield of prayer.
Victory comes to those armies
who have equal amounts of those.
We will always be with you
with our armies of prayer.
Thank you.
Brother, put this ointment on
in the mornings, not now.
You also lost a lot of blood.
Drink pekmez often.
Thank you. God bless you, Ishak.
Thank you, brother.
Don't worry, Ishak.
Neither Bamsi, nor Abdur Rahman
would ever run out of blood.
And why is that?
Because both dropped in pekmez cauldrons
when they were young.
Brothers!
Oh, my God! Congratulations!
What's all this about, Bamsi?
Brother, we became uncles.
Turgut, we became uncles!
What do you mean, brother?
What do you mean uncle?
Do you mean, Banu Çiçek...
Exactly, brother. Banu Çiçek
gave birth to a healthy young man.
Our brother Doğan has a son.
God bless!
Thank God, brothers,
for showing us such a day.
You are right, brother.
First, we took the head of
the dog Vasilius, and now this.
Thank God.
How is he, Bamsi?
He's well. He is quite something.
I didn't see him myself
but that's what Hafsa Hatun said.
God bless, what is she going to name him?
That's our decision to make.
Ertuğrul Bey shall name him.
Thank God that he was born healthy.
Thank God.
Now, Bamsi.
It's your turn next, brother.
Amen, brother.
However, you should think about it, too.
It's your turn next as well.
Bamsi, never mind that.
What's this get up, brother?
I don't know,
I just ran out of the tent, brother.
I ran off to tell you.
Brother, if there was an ambush now,
and the drums were beat,
is this how you would face the enemy?
There is no enemy
better than you, brother. Come now!
Come here!
You are the worst enemy!
Men! Commander Vasilius
has left us an important legacy.
Karacahisar Fortress.
We won't surrender our forefathers' legacy
until the last of our men dies.
This is our home.
They will want to take it from us.
But we will protect this fortress as if
it was the last fortress of our empire.
We won't let them go unpunished
for taking your friends.
We are ready to die in the blink
of an eye like Commander Vasilius.
Let us honor his legacy!
Long live Nicaea!
Everyone that I want dead
will die like this, one by one.
And Ertuğrul, your turn
will definitely come as well.
Brother.
My brave brother.
The bravest of them all, Aliyar.
My martyr brother.
May you rest in peace.
May you go to heaven.
Rest assured now.
You have been avenged.
We took your revenge.
I will walk on your path.
And die for your cause.
Your tribe is safe with me.
Your sister will carry on
with your cause from now on.
What happened, Bamsi?
It's been a while since
you were like this.
Sir, if you encourage him like this,
he will lose his self-control.
I still remember
the very first day we came here, sir.
Look at where we are now.
That's why my mind is racing, sir.
I can't stand still.
Remember the plane tree, sir?
I remember the day we planted it,
crystal clear.
Come on, brothers.
God, let the branches of this plane tree
embrace the whole world.
May it take root here.
So that our people may spread
your justice and compassion
to the entire world.
This shall be our mission, too,
as it is for this plane tree.
Amen.
The sun will be our flag,
and the skies our tent.
We will ride our horses
to the endless meadows.
Our swords will be our lovers,
and we will make our armies strong.
Our seal shall ripple for all eternity
as the signal of justice.
We will carry God's holy word
beyond the mountains and seas.
-Allahu akbar!
-Allah!
Allahu akbar!
Our tree has spread its root
to the earth, brother.
Yes, indeed, brother.
So much so, that nobody can tear it down.
Vasilius got what he deserved.
Sir, celebrate this day.
Let's make it a double celebration.
Now that I've become an uncle,
nobody can stop me.
I'll eat honey for 40 days straight.
I will eat tons of pastrami
and fried meat, sir.
Dad!
My big boy. God bless. Come here.
Another alp has been born.
Now, I have not one, but two alps.
Wonderful, great commander Gündüz.
Gündüz, come now.
Let's watch over your men.
Come.
Ertuğrul Bey, Banu Çiçek brought
her baby for you to name him.
Congratulations, sister.
Thank you, sir.
Shed no more tears, sister.
We took Doğan's revenge.
He's been avenged.
God bless you, sir.
-Amen.
-Thank you.
May he rest in peace.
May Aliyar rest in peace, too.
Our enemies at Karacahisar Fortress
will live in unrest now.
We will conquer it soon, sister.
Sir, if you'd be so kind as to accept,
I'd like you to name Doğan's legacy.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Allahu akbar!
Ashadu an la ilaha illa'llah.
Wa Ashad anna Muhammadan Rasululu'llah
Hayya alas Salah
Hayya alal Falah
Allahu akbar.
La ilaha illallah
Your name is...
Doğan.
Your name is Doğan.
You took your name
from your martyr father.
May God give you a long life.
-Amen.
A son of a Turk is born a wolf,
and his home is wherever he sets foot.
Let the heavens and the earth know that
his name is Doğan.
May he be blessed.
Ertuğrul Bey, you gave him
the name we all wished for.
God bless you.
Thank you.
Grow up to be a brave and merciful alp,
like your father, your namesake.
May he never stray from
Ertuğrul Bey's cause.
Dündar Bey.
Hold your nephew.
Thanks to many martyrs,
such as Doğan
and Aliyar Bey,
our children are born free,
and shall live free.