Episode 89 will start after 12:40 min.
Were you expecting Emir Sadettin,
my Sultan?
No.
But it's good he's here.
He should know of my decision
concerning your new duty.
When I return, I'll leave
Sadettin here to support you.
My Sultan.
What brings you here, Sadettin?
My marriage to Aslihan Hatun, my Sultan.
But her father's death,
and now Aliyar Bey...
It's good that you're here.
That you came in time
for Aliyar Bey's funeral.
Also, after talking over some
matters with Ertugrul Bey,
I've come to a decision.
A decision you should be told about.
I hope it's good news, my Sultan.
Ertugrul Bey is now
the chief Bey of my state.
He will govern these lands.
It's an honor for me to serve
my state and nation, my Sultan.
I have no doubt my Sultan
has made the right decision.
Ever since Ertugrul Bey
first came to these lands
he has been my eyes and ears.
I know everything that happens here
thanks to the information he provides.
I trust and respect him.
Ertugrul Bey has fulfilled his duty well.
I now intend to fulfil the great mission
our Sultan has entrusted me with, Emir.
As you command, my Sultan.
I have no doubt Ertugrul Bey
can carry out this task
given his loyalty to the state.
I will do my best to always support him.
God willing.
I would like to go to Hanli bazaar now
to discuss my plans with both of you.
Afterwards he will organize a council
meeting of the Turk tribes.
When the Beys arrive, I will see them.
I will inform them
of my decision, personally.
Still no news.
Patience, Nikolas. Patience.
I have learned that only patience
brings victory against the Turks.
And if she doesn't succeed?
Everyone knows she's Ural's wife.
If she doesn't...
then we'll have lost one more
on our way to victory.
And we'll never know
who that merchant actually is.
Emir Sadettin wouldn't have
come here for no reason.
Emir Sadettin is like a fly
chasing the light.
If the Emir is here...
if the news given by the Emperor is true,
then we'll extinguish
their light forever, Nikolas.
Then let's hope Ekaterina brings us
the information we want.
Men!
Keep your assigned positions.
Be alert!
Don't let anyone come close.
Understood?
Yes, Commander Turgut!
Now, I want archers to hold the rooftops.
Take your positions, everyone!
-Yes, sir!
-Come on.
Faster!
Turgut, brother!
Brother.
Brother, we filled the stream bed
with our men.
All right, brother.
Not even Genghis Khan could pierce
our defenses.
I hope that Emir Sadettin or whoever
sleeps without worry now.
All this fuss is not for Emir Sadettin.
It's unlikely that Ertuğrul Bey
would lift a finger for him.
Then, what's all this measure for?
For who?
Abu Mansur.
Good.
If it's for that brave merchant
that we know nothing about...
Anyway, brother. I don't mind helping him.
He swung his sword to save
all of us once.
Do you still believe that
he's a mere merchant?
He isn't?
Then what on earth is he? An angel?
May I enter?
Sadaq Allah Al-Azeem.
Come in.
As salaam wa alaikum.
Wa alaikum as salaam.
Welcome, Your Highness.
Thank you.
As it stands, I must be in disguise.
I wish I could have met you before
to take your blessings.
Even in the thick of it,
I know that you do what you must do,
Your Highness.
I figured it out when I saw you
at the cemetery.
Come in.
Our prophet says thus:
"When two Muslims get together,
God ensures that,
as a reward,
both are beneficial to each other."
Thank God for getting us together.
Amen.
We are surrounded by the enemy.
I came here to take your blessings,
destroy the devil's nest Karacahisar,
and pave the way for conquest.
May God help you in your quest.
Thank God for letting such a bey...
meet such a sultan,
and for allowing our sultan
to work for his cause.
May your unity be everlasting.
-Amen.
Death in one ring...
and life in another.
So, what am I afraid of?
Come on, Sadettin.
Finish this.
We are ready to leave, sir.
All right, Cabir.
Let Ertuğrul Bey know
that we are going to the bazaar.
Guards!
Were you here, too?
Many a great army has saluted me.
And I brought many more to their knees.
I was never trampled over
as you trample over me.
-Your Highness, I--
-Silence!
If love is the fluttering of a bird
that's fallen from its nest,
then I, too, shall flutter to get to you
until I die.
I will never,
ever,
let anybody take you away from me.
I harbor no love in my heart,
Your Highness.
Whatever I did, I did for my tribe.
Just as how you do everything
for the sake of your country.
Don't you know that...
I see through your lie
as I look into your eyes?
Do you think I don't know who...
gives you the courage to lead your tribe?
Ertuğrul Bey became the hope
of my tribe, and as he became mine.
God bless him.
This is the truth.
We both know very well
what the truth is, right?
Let me go!
You are hurting me.
The truth is that...
you still haven't let Ertuğrul,
who you once loved, go.
Is it not true?
Is it not the truth?
Tell me.
Is it not?
It's not true!
I'll never give up on you, Aslıhan.
Never.
Nobody will be able to take you
away from me.
Not even him.
There is grief in separation,
and hope in unity.
Now, you, as a fine ruler,
and you, as a fine supporter,
strive to establish our unity.
God loves those who
get along well together.
I believe that this unity will bear fruit
and lead to conquest.
I hope so.
I hope so, too.
Tomorrow, we will hold a meeting
that our sultan will attend, as well.
We'd like to see you among us.
It's our tradition to accept invitations.
If my fate allows it,
I'll attend for sure.
May God bless you with a long life,
and allow us to benefit
from your wisdom and understanding.
May I enter, sir?
Come in, Abdur Rahman.
Emir Sadettin says he's ready, sir.
He's waiting for you to leave
for the bazaar.
Be prepared for everything, Cabir.
A huge storm is closing in.
Don't you breathe a word.
-Understood?
-As you wish, sir.
My life belongs to you alone.
Good.
We sent for other beys, Aslıhan Hatun.
We'll have a meeting tomorrow at the inn.
I'll be sure to be there, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll represent my brother with honor.
Till the day I die.
Or a new bey is chosen.
Emir Sadettin,
I may not be a bey,
but I'm a servant of my tribe.
There is no doubt that...
you will do justice by the duty
you have been entrusted with.
My duty will not be completed
until I avenge my brother,
Emir Sadettin.
I carry my tribe and my country
on my shoulders.
It's my duty to carry this esteemed
burden forever.
If your brother and your sultan saw you,
I'm sure they'd be proud of you,
Aslıhan Hatun.
The Seljuks will rise on the shoulders
of such brave Turk women as yourself.
Thank you, Abu Mansur.
We hope to pay our due respect
for Aliyar Bey with this meeting.
May God grant our wishes.
Amen.
Bismillah.
Blessed be the one that gave you to us.
-Mother.
-Yes?
I wonder why the sultan came
all the way over here.
Dear, don't you know
what kind of place this is?
He surely must have come
to alleviate a problem.
Then why does he keep it a secret
from everyone?
Why did he come in disguise?
Who knows? He must have his reasons.
I'm scared of something happening
to Ertuğrul.
My dear.
The sultan believes in Ertuğrul.
That's why he's here.
Don't let such trivial things get to you.
With God's permission,
these challenging days shall pass soon.
I hope it does, Mother.
May God protect them from evil.
Amen.
Your grandmother loves you so much.
Ural is dead.
Aliyar is dead.
The Cavdar tribe is left without a leader.
Ertuğrul will try to take them
under his dominion.
He will try.
Let him.
The fate of the Cavdars lies in my hands.
What do you mean, Vasilius?
Ekaterina carries the heir
to the Cavdar tribe in her womb.
How is that even possible?
The last favor Ural did for us
before he died.
Always one step ahead, Vasilius.
It's much too soon to celebrate, Nikolas.
First, I must ensure that Ekaterina
is loyal to me.
What are you suspicious of?
What did we say?
Clever women are dangerous.
But you are the cleverest commander
I have ever known.
You deserve to be an emperor.
Unless the king falls,
the game doesn't end, Nikolas.
And unless we get rid of all the pawns,
we can't reach the king.
There is an order to it.
Come on, men!
This marketplace you took
from the Templars
brought life to these lands, Ertuğrul Bey.
Once we take the fortress,
these lands will be
even more abundant, Abu Mansur.
We took measure as per your orders, sir.
Thank you, Turgut.
Tell everyone in the market that
nobody is to open their shop.
We'll have a meeting with the beys.
-Yes, sir.
-Cabir.
Sultan Alaeddin.
Turgut, brother.
Is my understanding correct?
Did he literally close the market?
All this for Abu Mansur?
All Turkmen beys will have
a meeting tomorrow, Bamsi.
He might have done all this
for the meeting.
Let's hope for the best.
Let's do that.
I do hope so.
Welcome, Your Highness.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey, we cleared
the inn as per your orders.
The travelers are placed in tents.
Only Abu Mansur and His Highness
will stay at the inn.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Excuse me, sir.
Let's meet at dinner to discuss
Karacahisar Fortress.
I'll read the letters from Konya now.
Ertuğrul Bey, we need to talk.
I have time and again witnessed
how our sultan
always makes the right decision,
Ertuğrul Bey.
His wisdom and faith
protected our country.
May God bestow him with a long life.
Amen.
However, I'm worried that
the Karacahisar issue is left
upon your shoulders.
Rest assured, Emir Sadettin,
there will be a lot of Turkmen beys
along with their soldiers by my side.
And you as well, as the sultan said.
Right.
Knowing you are with me gives me strength.
Thank you, Ertuğrul Bey.
I've known you
since the Battle of Kapetron.
You have always been
this unfaltering and persistent.
And look where you are now,
on our sultan's orders.
You got that position by clawing
your way up.
You may very well have deserved it,
but my worries still stand.
You may voice your worries to our sultan
at dinner, Your Highness.
Is it realistically possible to take
Karacahisar Fortress with a bunch of men?
Assuming you take it,
will the emperor stand still?
What about the Latins?
Will they stand still?
You might have convinced
our sultan with your ambition today.
What about tomorrow?
When all that I predict
starts coming true,
will you stop to think how it will affect
our country?
I've been thinking about it since the day
I came to Karacahisar.
I've taken precautions all for this day.
So, you are saying you won't back down?
If the sultan decides so,
then our duty is to fight for it.
Don't you worry.
I'll pray for your safety
with all my heart.
But I'll be watching you.
That's fine by me.
In the name of God,
who wills things to existence
and fills our hearts with faith.
Brave beys of the Cavdar tribe,
Aliyar Bey served as bey honorably,
as it was his right.
The passing of Aliyar Bey
deeply saddened us all.
And many of our beys and
brave soldiers passed away, too.
We are in a dire situation.
How lucky they are to have been
worthy to be martyrs.
We will not stop till God grants us
martyrdom as well.
We will not deprive ourselves
with sadness and hopelessness.
And there is no place in my tribe
for those among you who are deprived.
You better know that.
For a thousand years,
we've always had a leader.
And I'll not let this change
as long as I'm alive.
Make no mistake.
I'll carry out justice by the authority
my brother granted me.
And those with reservations about it,
speak now.
We have full confidence in you,
Aslıhan Hatun.
Until we avenge my brother,
I'll make the best of my authority.
When we achieve our goal,
we will choose a bey for our tribe.
And I'll be a soldier working
for my tribe till my last breath.
What about your marriage
with Emir Sadettin, Aslıhan Hatun?
My home is my marquee.
Anything else is haram to me.
You should know that.
That's very becoming of you,
Aslıhan Hatun.
May God grant us victory
over our enemies.
Amen.
We will hold a meeting tomorrow
at the inn.
I, too, shall attend as the representative
of the Cavdars.
Your attendance will give strength
to our tribe and honor our name.
You have our full faith, Aslıhan Hatun.
May this meeting benefit
our home and country.
You walk the same path
as our late Aliyar Bey.
We know that well.
God bless you.
Amen.
May God help me carry
this authority with honor,
and protect me from taking
rightful due of another.
Amen.
Today is a festival for all
of us, Vasilius.
Did you see Abu Mansur?
I did.
They came to the inn after Aliyar's
funeral along with Ertuğrul and Sadettin.
I saw that nobody could get close
to the inn without Ertuğrul's orders.
Rooftops, the periphery
of the marketplace.
Ertuğrul was meticulous
in taking all kinds of measures.
Get to the point already.
Who is all this measure for?
Of course, it's for Sultan Alaeddin.
Are you sure?
As I'm sure of this hatred inside me.
As I'm sure of the hatred inside you.
Now you have given me
the whole wide world, Ekaterina.
I dedicated myself to serving you,
Vasilius.
To serve me?
You will be repaid
for your services in kind.
Power.
If it's not to take life,
but to give life,
then I am power.
I am power.
Ertuğrul.
How did I put up with you for years?
How could you get away
from the traps I laid for you?
But it ends here.
Now, nobody can save you.
You will be crushed...
under my power, which I used first
to give life and now to take it.
You will not take this land that is...
rightfully mine,
nor the sultan's trust in me,
nor Aslıhan.
The poison in my ring will slip away
to the sultan's food like a snake.
Then, all your tantrums shall cease.
And once I give the cure
in my other ring...
to the sultan,
he will be reborn.
Once he regains his health,
he will figure out the treason
that happened in your presence.
However, you will...
have been long dead, God willing.
God willing.
Greetings.
Bless you.
Brother, these men of Abu Mansur's
are like the statues of the heathens.
Did you see their wrists?
They're like steel swords.
Are you still calling him
a merchant, Bamsi?
Thank God they are not the soldiers
of the heathens,
or else they would give us
one hell of a time.
Brother, what do you think Ertuğrul Bey
will talk about with the Emir
and this Abu Mansur guy over dinner?
Probably about the rugs.
This new deal will give us relief,
hopefully.
Easy now, Dündar Bey.
There's something amiss here.
I hope it's for the good, though.
Speak of the devil, brother.
Send for Ertuğrul Bey and Abu Mansur.
I want them before me.
They're talking...
in the hall,
Emir Sadettin.
Brother, you know that I don't know
much about politics and all that.
But do you think this so-called Emir
envies Ertuğrul Bey over Abu Mansur?
It's not just envy, Bamsi.
He looks like trouble, but...
let's hope for the best.
There are 11 big water wells
inside the fortress, Your Highness.
Obviously, they won't need water
in case of a siege.
Even if they have water,
the supplies for their soldiers
will be insufficient, Your Highness.
They can't find anything to eat.
Since Vasilius ceased all trade
with the bazaar,
he gets his supplies with the huge tax
he takes from the villagers.
That's right, Your Highness.
Come in, Sadettin.
Listen to Ertuğrul Bey.
He's giving us the intel on Karacahisar
that he has collected so far.
It is extremely important.
Many of his men died for this cause.
That's Ertuğrul Bey's greatest strength.
Once he sets his eyes on something,
he never lets go.
If we can manage to corner Vasilius
in the fortress with a siege,
we may be able to defeat them
with hunger, Your Highness.
What happens if the emperor
sends reinforcements to the fortress?
There are two roads leading
to Karacahisar from Nicaea, Your Highness.
If we hold both roads,
we can stop the soldiers coming from
Nicaea from reaching the fortress.
The beys of Turkmen tribes and their men
will control both roads.
Since my spy at Nicaea died,
there's no other way.
We will bury Vasilius and his men alive
in Karacahisar Fortress, Your Highness.
We will fight to the last of our breath
for Aliyar Bey and all the other martyrs.
I have no doubt about it, Ertuğrul Bey.
However, if the siege lasts longer
than expected,
and the reinforcements the emperor sends
turn out to be strong,
it will cause huge losses.
In fact,
it could be a disaster for Turkmen tribes.
Let us eat.
Sit.
Bismillahirahmanirahim.
We will not siege the fortress,
Your Highness.
Vasilius will choose to attack.
I can say this because of the unit
that was coming from Nicaea.
If your army doesn't come here,
they will attack us.
And once he attacks us,
he will have nowhere to run.
So, once Vassileios gets out
of the fortress,
you mean to fight him.
We are waiting for the day
that we'll deliver his head
to our sultan, Emir Sadettin.
Thank God.
Nikolas.
Do you know how a raven...
gets close to a carcass that he knows
is surrounded
by stronger animals than him?
How?
By causing an uproar.
By distracting the animals around it.
It's a jealous bird.
It doesn't want to share his prey.
And if his prey were to get away,
that small, pitch-black raven...
with a rugged caw turns into a monster.
You don't mean Ertuğrul.
It's Emir Sadettin.
He couldn't deal with Ertuğrul.
And now, the sultan is his guest.
Look at that.
I'm sure that the sultan
will give Ertuğrul something that will
make Emir Sadettin jealous.
Emir Sadettin will not like that at all.
So, out of jealousy, he will
cause an uproar, huh?
Just like a raven.
And we will take advantage of that.
If Emir Sadettin is as clever
as you make him out to be,
then he will make it easier for us.
But what?
What could he do?
I don't care. He can do whatever he wants.
Victory shall be ours.
What do you think about it, Sadettin?
I know Vasilius well, Your Highness.
Ertuğrul Bey is quite right.
He is blinded by his desire
to spill Turk blood.
Out of his hatred for the Turks,
he will prowl out of his fortress...
like the dog he is,
and find something to bite.
Along with his treachery.
Are you all right, Your Highness?
Do you need water?
Your Highness...
He's been poisoned.
Our sultan has been poisoned.
Quick! Call the doctors!
Quick!
What's the meaning of this,
Emir Sadettin?
It's on you
to answer that question, not me.
What's happening here?
What's the meaning of this?
I know you are panicked
but watch your mouth, Emir Sadettin.
Guards! Take Ertuğrul Bey's
sword from him.
Come on!
Arrest him.
Give your sword to the guard, Ertuğrul.
What do you think you are doing,
Emir Sadettin?
-Make way.
-Is he all right?
What are you doing?
What's going on, Your Highness?
Abu Mansur has been poisoned.
Take him to his room.
Come on!
Throw Ertuğrul Bey in jail.
What did you say, Your Highness?
Why would he poison the man
that saved his life?
Have the Kayi alps leave this place.
They shall go back to their tribe.
Your Highness, let me put my skills
as a doctor into good use.
Abu Mansur has his own doctor.
He'll take care of him.
Now, leave this place at once.
Go!
Be quick.
We must make him vomit.
Your Highness! Your Highness!
How could you be so stupid,
Emir Sadettin?
How could you be fooled like this?
We won't let you take my brother!
Ertuğrul Bey, calm yourself
and have your men put away their weapons.
I don't want any bloodshed between us.
Surrender!
Dündar Bey, Artuk Bey.
Take the men and go back to the camp.
Let everybody at the camp
know what happened here.
Sir. Sir!
Let us stay with you.
How could we just leave you here?
What's happening here, sir?
Who are these men?
Who is this Abu Mansur?
Leave now if you don't want bloodshed.
Turgut.
Let's go!
Surrender your weapon.
Take him.
What kind of treachery is this?
You are being played off against me.
Pray that this doesn't turn out
to be on you.
Because if it is,
you shall die a terrible death.
Take him!
Bamsi.
Calm down. Bamsi.
Let's calm down
and think of our next move.
We know what we must do, Artuk Bey.
We must save Ertuğrul Bey.
Samsa, inform the Cavdar Tribe fast.
Tell Aslıhan Hatun to come
to the Kayi Tribe.
All right, Artuk Bey.
Men! Come with me.
Come on.
We will call the beys going
to the meeting to Kayi Tribe,
else we won't be able to
fend off this trouble.
Why would Ertuğrul Bey
want to kill a merchant?
Nobody would be fooled by that lie.
All the beys will support us.
Yes, I know that everybody knows,
but Emir Sadettin would not get it.
Our bey has been an ally
to Emir Sadettin for so long.
What issue could he have with our bey?
Good faith may cause
ill-fate sometimes, Bamsi.
Emir Sadettin is after something.
Artuk Bey, something I don't understand
is going on.
Who on earth is this guy
called Abu Mansur?
Plus, why is Emir Sadettin
head over heels for this guy?
We will find out everything, Bamsi.
Yes, we will.
We will.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Throw it all up, Your Highness.
O, the one who cures!
It's...
It's poison.
God.
On the honor of your name, help us,
o, one who cures.
This is not good.
God sent us this trouble,
but he sent us our remedy, as well.
God bless.
Thank God. God bless.
Bismillah.
Healer.
How is our sultan?
He's not okay, Your Highness.
I'm trying to empty his stomach.
Water.
Let me do it.
Take this out of here.
Your Highness.
What are you standing around for?
I don't know what's happening.
I have no idea what he was poisoned with.
He's in a critical condition.
We're losing him.
-As salaam wa alaikum.
-Wa alaikum as salaam.
What's all the fuss?
You were sent by God, sir.
We are in huge trouble, Ibn Arabi.
The merchant Abu Mansur was poisoned.
The emir holds our bey responsible.
You saved Ertuğrul Bey from poison once.
We have faith that you will save us
from this false accusation, as well.
Artuk Bey, fate protects
the man from death.
Our duty is...
to intervene to protect the man
from the grasp of his fate.
Let me see Abu Mansur immediately.
Where do you think you are going?
The emir's orders are absolute.
All right, we won't pass.
It's just Ibn Arabi.
I said nobody goes in! Are you daft?
Go back to your tribe.
Do you think we would let
our bey die in your hands?
We've done as you said up until now.
However,
you will let Ibn Arabi in...
if you want Abu Mansur to live.
Either he enters in one piece,
or nobody leaves here in one piece!
What's all this fuss?
Don't you see that they are
disobeying the orders of the emir?
All we want is for Ibn Arabi
to cure Abu Mansur.
Let him in.
Follow me, Ibn Arabi, sir.
Are you going against his orders, too?
I only follow Abu Mansur's orders.
Make way!
Go ahead, Ibn Arabi, sir.
Stand down!
Bamsi.
Bamsi, gather the men
who were guarding the inn.
Hide somewhere close.
Wait for my orders.
There will be chaos.
-We can't leave our bey alone.
-Right on, brother.
We will do anything for our bey.
And if we must die for his sake,
then die we shall.
Don't worry, Your Highness.
Our country will be safe.
Emir Sadettin will fill the gap
left behind by you.
Did I not order you to not let anybody in?
Emir Sadettin.
Ibn Arabi has come to cure our sultan.
He has his own healer.
But his hands are tied.
Arabi is Ertuğrul's man.
Why would I trust him?
Take him away.
Your Highness.
If the high state officials find out
that you turned him away
at such a crucial time,
they will put all of us
in a grave, along with our sultan.
And you'll go down first.
You...
dare threaten me?
I dedicated my life to the sultan.
I do as my duty calls.
If need be,
I'd gladly surrender my life for him.
Emir Sadettin.
If it's in his fate,
let alone such a miserable man as me,
nobody would be able to save
our sultan from his fate.
However,
you will nonetheless
be remembered as the man
who obstructed me.
If His Highness dies,
I'll kill you with my own hands.
Go ahead.
How is his condition?
It's still bad, Your Highness.
Let Ibn Arabi handle this.
What have you tried?
I tried to empty his stomach,
but it was to no avail.
I don't understand what’s happening.
Don't take your eyes off him.
As you wish, Your Highness.
Give me a cup. Let's check his blood.
Right away.
Get me the herbs I'm about to list,
chief physician.
Bismillah.
My sweet son.
May I enter, Mother?
Come in, son.
Mother, I have bad news.
What bad news? This is going to kill me.
Abu Mansur was poisoned at the inn.
He was alive when we left,
but his condition is still critical.
Emir Sadettin
holds Ertuğrul Bey responsible.
He took him captive.
Oh, no!
Mother!
What do we do?
Emir Sadettin had all of us
leave the inn.
We informed the beys that were
invited to the meeting.
We will meet at our marquee tomorrow.
Aslıhan Hatun is on her way as well.
It'll mean Ertuğrul Bey's death
if something happens to the sultan.
Did you say "sultan"?
Abu Mansur is the sultan?
How is that even possible?
Abu Mansur
is Sultan Alaeddin Kayqubad.
He came in disguise.
But keep this a secret.
Don't let anybody else know.
This explains all the fuss.
Pity that I had to meet
with our sultan in such dire times.
God bless him.
Ertuğrul Bey won't be able to
get out of this alone.
What do you mean "alone"?
We are with him, son.
All the other beys will stand by his side.
Right.
Mother, the sultan must live,
or else Ertuğrul Bey will...
This misunderstanding will right itself.
My son would never do something like that.
What is worse is
if something were to happen to the sultan,
then our country would be in danger.
Artuk Bey.
Tomorrow,
we will gather the Turkmen beys
and explain the situation.
We will make for the inn together.
And whoever did this,
or put this on my son,
we will call them to account for it.
Artuk Bey, you and Dündar
will stay with the tribe.
If something happens to Ertuğrul or us,
you will lead our tribe.
-Mother.
-Dündar!
You are a bey.
You are the leader
when Ertuğrul is not here.
Don't you worry, Hayme Hatun.
Leave it to us.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Can you excuse us?
I presume you are wise enough to know
what will happen
if you let our sultan die.
Your Highness, we must do
as Ibn Arabi says.
Gather them, Your Highness.
Gather all seven of the fruits.
Gather them in the name of God,
who gives life.
Gather them in the name of him
who cures the sick.
For God is close,
and answers our prayers.
It hurts so much.
I can't bear it any longer.
God's decision will reveal itself soon.
Endure.
Al-Hayy, Al-Qayyoom.
More trouble has landed on Ertuğrul
before he could even see his child.
Greater mists fall on great mountains,
my dear.
Ertuğrul has many enemies,
but he has just as many friends.
Don't you worry.
Mother.
-My dear.
-Halime Sultan.
Aslıhan Hatun.
Mother, what happened?
This is just a test, dear.
Why would Ertuğrul Bey
poison the merchant that he works with?
He is no merchant, Aslıhan Hatun.
He is Sultan Alaeddin.
What...
What did you say, Halime?
Mother.
No! It's worse than I thought.
The welfare of our country and
Ertuğrul Bey's life are both in danger.
How could you not recognize him, Halime?
I saw him once when I was
imprisoned many years ago.
We had to run away with my father.
I felt I recognized him at first,
but it took time to remember.
Whoever is behind this,
he is wise enough
to get a thousand birds with one stone.
Little by little you took away my dreams.
Little by little you took away
those I loved,
and left me begging to the traitors.
Left me as a slave to the enemy.
Look at you, Colpan.
You were Nicaea's princess once.
You became the sultan of the Cavdars.
And now, you are trapped
in the fortress of these bastards
with a baby in your womb.
Ekaterina.
Come in, Vasilius.
I have good news for you.
You
have given me the chance
I've been looking for all this time.
The chance to destroy all my enemies.
Tomorrow...
they will all die.
So, you will avenge my baby's father
before he is even born?
We will avenge you.
When your child grows up,
he will see what you have accomplished
and be proud of you, Ekaterina.
They'll both be proud of you.
The sultan was poisoned at your inn.
Even that shame is enough for you.
Is there any use in me killing you?
Pray that Arabi saves our sultan
as he saved you.
He will, should God allow it.
I can see in your eyes the hatred
you feel toward me, Emir Sadettin.
You very well know that
I did not poison him.
The hatred in you...
became clear when our sultan
appointed me as the margrave.
What would an Emir of the Seljuks,
such as I, ever hope to gain
from a margrave, such as yourself?
What could I want from you?
You poison everybody around you, right?
And not just our sultan.
Who do you mean, Emir Sadettin?
You poisoned Aslıhan with your ambitions.
Are you aware of what you are saying?
Aslıhan refused to be my wife.
Why?
Just why?
Because of you.
Yes, all because of you.
She said something about
leading her tribe
and carrying out the responsibilities
left by Aliyar Bey.
And that she'd dedicate her life
to her tribe.
And why is that?
Because of you.
She said you'd always be with her,
and that you'd protect her and her tribe.
What about me?
You took the woman I fell in love with
away from me.
I curse the day you came
to these lands, Ertuğrul.
Emir Sadettin.
Even if she loved you,
she wouldn't leave her tribe.
That gallant woman...
wouldn't hesitate to sacrifice
her life for her tribe.
If you really loved her,
you'd be proud of her.
You'd support her decision.
Yours is nothing but obstinacy.
The fact that she refused you...
hurts your pride.
This is the truth.
Do you think I don't know that...
she once loved you?
Open!
Governor Vasilius!
Power...
courage...
and faith.
These virtues are inherent
only to the most honorable soldiers
of noble descent.
You are all such soldiers.
Fear...
weakness...
and vulnerability.
These, on the other hand...
are inherent flaws of those
stupid enough to face you brave soldiers.
You will face such men.
My men!
This is the day we have always dreamed of.
This is the day we bring honor
to our glorious history.
This is the day they will sing our songs,
and we will be the talk
of the whole wide world.
Now,
either we become a part of this victory
and live an honorable life,
or we fight and die
with our honor intact,
and embrace the promise of heaven.
This is our last war.
We will protect the last fortress
of our civilization until our last breath.
Long live Nicaea!
Attention!
Ertuğrul Bey, son of Suleyman Shah,
has always followed his faith,
his country and his traditions.
He protected all of you, risking his life.
Now it's your turn.
Ertuğrul Bey was put
in a difficult position
due to a disastrous incident.
Hayme Hatun, tell us what the problem is.
We'd gladly lay down
our lives for Ertuğrul Bey.
I know you would.
That's why I'm holding this meeting.
The Sultan
Alaeddin Kayqubad
has been staying in our tribe
as Ertuğrul Bey's guest
for a while now.
God bless.
-What an honor!
-God bless. Such a pleasing thing.
Mother Hayme, what an honor
it is for our Sultan to visit you.
I wish we could have seen him.
-What an honor!
-Listen now.
His Highness Alaeddin Kayqubad
was poisoned by someone
at the Hanlı Bazaar yesterday.
-Who could have done this?
-Who dared to poison him?
How could they do it?
How is that possible?
Who would attempt something like that?
This was pinned on Ertuğrul Bey
on a baseless claim.
It's a smear attempt.
He's charged with poisoning
his very own Sultan.
That can't be!
Ertuğrul Bey would never do that.
This is not a simple coincidence.
It was thought out well.
We must put an end
to this baseless lie before it's too late.
That's why, if we don't stand
by Ertuğrul Bey now,
he will be in grave danger.
Let's go and rescue him.
Let's do whatever we can, Hayme Hatun.
We shall go.
Emir Sadettin
took Ertuğrul Bey captive, and he is...
after a summary execution.
We will never let that happen.
Never!
Either we save both my son
and our Sultan
from this pit of hell...
or we will all be consumed
by this disaster.
What are we waiting for, Mother Hayme?
We will stand by Ertuğrul Bey forever.
Yes, Mother Hayme!
God bless you all.
It's time
to save our future.
O, God, you come to the rescue
of those who are in trouble.
You protect all that exists
just the way they are.
You are the most merciful.
Everything we have
is dependent on you alone.
Not even a leaf falls without your wish.
You are all knowing and all powerful.
Who could cure the sick
if you don't help them?
Whose house could they take shelter in
You help your followers
when they are in trouble.
We beg only you.
We take refuge in you
as helpless as we are and beg you.
Honor thy name as the one who cures,
and cure this servant of yours
who struggles to serve you.
Hear our prayers for the love
of your holy prophet.
Hear our prayers.
Why did you want to see me?
What do you want?
How is the Sultan's condition?
He's in agony. What do you want?
If the traitor is not one of us,
then it means that Vasilius
knows our Sultan is at the inn.
He couldn't possibly know
that the Sultan is here.
We know that there is a traitor
in the Sultan's palace.
Where did that come from?
The Sultan's eyes in Nicaea
was coming to tell me who the traitor was.
But Vasilius killed him.
The Sultan knows about it.
Who is that traitor, then?
He got away from Nicaea
before he could find out.
If the traitor told the emperor
that the Sultan was coming here,
then it means that Vasilius knows as well.
The Sultan only tells his closest circle
where he's going
when he walks in disguise.
If something were to happen to him,
it would be them who lost their heads,
so it's impossible for that traitor
to find out about it.
If Vasilius attacks the inn,
that means we are doomed, Emir Sadettin.
That's impossible.
It was equally impossible
to poison our Sultan.
Why didn't he tell me that
there was a traitor at the palace?
Why?
So, he trusts you and not me, huh?
This is not the time and place
to be crying about it.
Even if our Sultan is cured
from that poison,
he won't make it if Vasilius attacks
this place without my men protecting it.
Take the necessary precautions.
This is my last warning.
Open!
Victory awaits us beyond the horizon,
Nikolas.
A glorious victory.
And your name written all over
that victory.
No.
Our name.
The shadow of our dominance
will stretch all the way out here.
I can feel the Lord's soul with us.
God bless our army.
Sir, Turkmen beys are heading to the inn.
It's time, Nikolas.
It's time to embrace the victory
awaiting us
beyond the horizon.
Is this how you greet the loyal beys
of our Sultan, soldier?
What's this?
What do you want?
Every one of the Turkmen beys
that the Sultan placed on these lands
wants to see Emir Sadettin.
Let him know.
On the orders of Emir Sadettin,
we can't let anybody in.
Tell Emir Sadettin that
Aslıhan Hatun has come
as the representative of the Cavdars.
He's aware of everything,
as our Turkmen beys are.
Do as we say, or else...
You can only take our dead bodies
away from here.
Wait here.
Tighten the security
around Hanlı Bazaar.
The bastard Vasilius could attack
at any moment.
Your Highness,
if that's really possible,
then we must get our Sultan
out of here fast.
Don't you know that he's in pain?
How could we move him the way he is?
What if we are attacked on the road?
Do as I say. The Sultan stays here.
Tighten the measures around the inn.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Turkmen beys have come.
Damn. That's the last thing we need now.
Tell them to leave.
Aslıhan Hatun and Hayme Hatun
are both among them.
They said they will not leave the inn
under any circumstances
I can't believe it.
They say they know everything.
They know that our Sultan is here.
Jeez. All right, let them in.
Gosh!
Ertuğrul Bey!
We have come with the Turkmen beys.
Know that we are on your side.
Mother.
Whenever you are nearby,
trouble befalls us.
You didn't surprise me this time.
We all know that Ebu Mansur is the Sultan.
Just like we know that
Ertuğrul Bey is innocent.
All the other beys before you have
the same opinion, Emir Sadettin.
Yes, Ertuğrul Bey is innocent!
Let him go right now, Your Highness.
You can right this wrong.
How dare you?
How dare you dictate
the Ameer of our country
on what to do.
Men! Guards!
Throw them all out.
If they resist, show no mercy.
Hayme Hatun.
Aslıhan!
What do you think you are doing?
We are well aware of
what we are doing, Emir Sadettin.
The question is, are you?
If need be, we won't hesitate
to put you in your place.
If we must die, we shall die
for the sake of Ertuğrul Bey.
Let him go!
Emir Sadettin!
-Impossible! Sultan Alaeddin!
-God bless, our Sultan is saved.
Your Highness...
Thank God, you are okay.
Thank God.
How could you think that
Ertuğrul Bey would poison me?
How dare you
treat my margrave, to whom I would
entrust this land in a heartbeat,
like this?
Let him go right this moment.
Right now!
I want to see him now.
Soldier.
Get Ertuğrul Bey out.
Have him come here fast.
Beys!
Brave women of Turks!
Sit.
Sultan wants to see you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Is he all right?
Turkmen beys have arrived.
He's with them now.
Thank God.
Once again, I witness just how much
Ertuğrul Bey is liked and respected
thanks to you all.
Emir Sadettin lost his composure
and stepped out of line
because of what happened to me.
I know that Ertuğrul Bey is innocent.
Your Highness.
Come, Ertuğrul Bey. Sit.
Thank god you are okay, Your Highness.
If I can still breathe
and sit alongside my brave beys,
it's thanks to Ibn Al Arabi and you,
Ertuğrul Bey.
I'd like you to forgive Emir Sadettin
for the way he treated you.
Whose doing is this then, Your Highness?
I don't know where I was poisoned.
It could be before I came here.
We will never find out
when the poison entered
our Sultan's body.
However, he made it out alive
thanks to everyone's prayers
and his strong body.
Right.
Thank god we pulled through this,
Your Highness.
But I want you to know that
there is yet another threat.
What are you worried about, Ertuğrul Bey?
Vasilius.
He definitely knows that
you are at the Hanlı Bazaar.
I took the necessary measures.
If there is an attack,
we won't be able to protect ourselves
against it
with the few guards and soldiers
we have at the inn.
Your Highness.
You've received some important intel
from one of our men watching Karacahisar.
What did they see? Tell me.
Vasilius left the fortress
with his men, Your Highness.
He's garrisoned on a hill
near the Hanlı Bazaar.
You were right once again, Ertuğrul Bey.
We will retaliate if there is an attack.
Sir, Bamsı is waiting for your orders
outside the inn with his men.
Thank you, Turgut.
Your Highness, allow me
to tell you one more thing.
When we were fighting,
Vasilius saw who Ebu Mansur
and his men were.
If he sees them leaving the inn now,
he will definitely go after them.
We should have your guards
protect the inn, if they may.
And we should send for help
from Cavdar and Kayi tribes.
You will be safe here.
Me and my men
will disguise in your clothes
and leave the inn.
Vasilius will think you got away
and follow me instead.
This will grant us with enough time
for my men to come here
and ensure your safety.
Once Vasilius goes after you,
you won't make it out alive, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'd lay my life down for my country
and for you anytime, Your Highness.
I'll instruct my men around the inn
to wait for me at Raven Valley.
I'll lure Vasilius to Raven Valley
once I'm out of here.
At last, the day has come.
I'll take Vasilius down.
Keep the formation!
You will surround the inn
and wait for our orders.
Archers will be right behind you.
There is nowhere they can run.
They are fewer in numbers.
But we will have a unit here
against all odds.
The archers will protect us from here.
We won't start before we surround the inn.
We will be as silent and strong
as the wind.
They might take the Sultan
and run for it with the first attack.
Leave it to me.
I want to catch the Sultan alive.
What about Ertuğrul?
Ertuğrul...
I would have liked to make him watch
the torture his Sultan will go through.
But I can't stand him after all.
He dies.
As you wish, sir.
Our men are in position.
They are waiting for your orders, sir.
Good.
Great.
Sultan Alaeddin is nothing
like the emperor.
Such a courageous man.
It is unbelievable
that he came here in person.
The Sultan is only a sultan
if he's one with his people, Hafsa.
He is one of us.
However, the dangers are imminent.
We're already in danger.
Everybody knows
that Ertuğrul Bey is innocent.
I'm sure the Sultan will think the same
once he opens his eyes.
What if he doesn't?
Don't talk like that, Hafsa.
He's a resilient man.
He will pull through this.
If he can't make it,
that's when we will all be doomed.
Come to your senses, both of you.
There is no use worrying.
Our men have pulled through
the gravest of dangers.
They will surely find a way
to pull through again.
Since the day I came here, I've been
living with my heart in my boots.
I understand now what it means
to be the wife of a Turk.
What makes Turkish women strong and proud
is pain, Hafsa. It's their loyalty
and faith in their husbands.
Never lose your faith.
Sir.
Bamsı and his men are on the way.
They will lie in wait at the Raven Valley
and set up a trap.
Thank you, Turgut.
We are ready, sir.
May God protect you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Blessed be your war.
May your swords be sharp
and your horses fast.
May God help us all.
Amen.
Give me your blessings.
God bless you, Ertuğrul Bey.
Give me your blessings, too.
-God bless you.
Your wife and your children
are waiting for you at the marquee.
Go, and come back unharmed
and victorious, son.
I hope I can, Mother.
May God help you, Ertuğrul Bey.
I'll pray for your return with victory.
May God grant you with victory.
Amen.
Let's go!
This is the last day Vasilius will see.
This is the day that evil is defeated
and we bask in our peace.
Off we go!
O God!
It's time, my soldiers.
It's time to die for our empire
if need be.
Long live Nicaea!
We will show no mercy.
Show no mercy! And remember.
Either Nicaea lives, or we die.
Long live Nicaea!
-Sir.
-What is it?
Sir, the Sultan left the Hanlı Bazaar
with his guards on horseback.
What? Is that true?
I saw it with myself, sir.
Ertuğrul was with him.
They know we are here, sir.
They plan to take the Sultan away.
Or Ertuğrul is just up to his tricks.
-What could it be?
-He would do anything.
Considering that they finished
the meeting already and left,
they must be in a hurry.
They will get away if we wait any longer.
What are your orders?
We will leave some men here.
You will lead them.
And cover us in case
something happens.
I'll go after them.
Yes, sir.
The vanguards, come with me!
-Turgut.
-Yes, sir?
-Position our men.
-Yes, sir.
You all know what you must do.
May God bless our war!
Amen.
Come on, everyone!
Scatter. Keep quiet.
I can hear your heartbeat, Ertuğrul.
It's fluttering like a bird out of fear.
Tell me, where did you disappear to?
This way, sir.
-They took a break.
-A break?
So they don't know that I'm here.
I overestimated you, Ertuğrul.
What a pitiful outcome for the Turks.
They'll rot away on a stream bed.
-Commander.
-Yes, sir.
Order our men to surround them.
But make sure they keep quiet.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
I want the Sultan alive.
Surround them.
Sir, even if he doesn't come,
Vasilius' archers could kill us all.
Vasilius likes to show off, Dumrul.
He won't make his move without boasting.
Vasilius learned his lesson, sir.
I don't think he wants to talk to you.
Maybe not with me,
but he will want to talk to you.
Right, sir.
Look at that, Ertuğrul!
We keep encountering each other.
And you keep running, Vasilius.
So, you took your Sultan for a walk
on my land, huh?
To think my fate would allow me
to see both of you.
You can't see our Sultan,
even in your dreams.
This, again?