Episode 25 will start after 12:12 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Long live Suleyman Shah!
May God bless you in both His realms!
Amen!
You blessed me with a holy conquest
at this age.
May God preserve you for us, Bey!
Amen!
Let us collect our dead at once,
and tear the castle apart.
What happened to Titus the heathen?
He escaped towards the castle, brother.
My Bey, I desire to send Yigit Alp
back to our tribe, if you permit.
His sister would be in deep concern.
-Send him right away.
So that the glad news
shall reach our tribe.
Great God!
Stop!
Bey, our Alps cornered
the head of Templars
while they were trying to escape.
They locked themselves in. We are
trying to break the door and enter.
-How many are there?
-Nine or ten, Bey.
They did not surrender
even if we had insisted.
Bey.
Please let me, brother.
Come, Turgut brother.
Come on, brother.
-Come on.
Come on.
Come on, brother.
-Give me a hand, brother.
-We will open it, brother.
With God's help we will open it.
-Come on, brother.
-Come on.
Come on.
With the name of God!
Hamza!
Mercy! Mercy!
I do not know why,
but he reminds me of Kurtoglu.
These people do
every kind of wretchedness.
And ask for mercy when they understand
that they will not get off.
Take these rascals.
I will punish them at the yard.
All of this wickedness comes from your
small minds, eh?
This is where it ends, you devil.
I will give you hell in your own temple.
Take him to the dungeon.
I will handle him myself.
Cowards! Kill me if you will!
It will not be as easy like that Turkmen.
You will beg for it.
My God, bless you.
You allowed me to see this blessed day.
Although as Suleyman Shah said,
I was not able to become a martyr.
But I saw Ertugrul Bey planting our flag
to these bastions.
His sword in one hand,
our flag in the other.
Screaming the name of our God.
My God
you allowed me to go to battle with
my Suleyman Shah and his two brave sons.
Blessed be God.
Sit down Wild Veteran, sit down.
You are wounded.
Bey, my wounds are my medal of honor.
They made me a veteran in the eyes of God
and proud, in the presence of your
brave sons.
As long as we have Alps like
Wild Veteran and the likes of you
who considered being a martyr
is the ultimate way to earn
God's blessing,
the enemies of Islam will never
stand a chance against us.
God willing, Bey.
On this day, you have honored me.
And not just me.
You who carry the noble
blood of Oghuz Khan,
did not let the sacred
flag of Kayi to fall.
Our flag flies in the sky!
May God bless you all.
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
Tatos Harput, animal trader, is it?
He is nothing but a trader of evil.
This rascal is responsible for every
calamity from Antioch to Aleppo and
Damascus to Konya.
The great devil!
No fire can can harm the sons of Ibrahim.
No well can devour Josephs.
And the pharaohs cannot rule over Moses.
Do you know who poisoned you?
Black Priest, Thomas.
Are you surprised?
He was the one who gave Isadora
the poisoned dagger.
And we have the Black Priest right now.
You will be gathered
on the Day of Resurrection,
as blind, dumb and deaf men.
Your faces will be buried in the ground.
Your path will lead you to hell.
It's fire will be rekindled,
whenever it starts to fade away.
You will not escape the torments of hell.
Move!
I will not die
until I take a life from you.
Do I have your permission, Bey?
This is your day, Turgut.
Revenge is halal to you
like your mother's milk.
Bey!
We captured the castle completely.
Good, prepare the bodies of our martyrs.
We will bury them at the nomad group.
Gather the corpses of heathens
in the dungeon.
As you command.
We will raze the castle on them
as their gravestones.
Ertugrul, handle them as well.
As you command, Bey.
Hamza, handle them.
What about Titus?
It's Like the ground has
swallowed that wretch.
Titus!
He couldn' have escaped.
He must be hiding somewhere in the castle.
We will search every hole.
As you command, Bey.
Mix this.
Sit down, I will handle this.
Are there any news?
No, Gokce Hatun.
If God permits,
we will hear the good news soon.
I can almost see my Turgut
returning to me with his horse.
Now I understand what it means
to be the wife of an Alp who goes to war.
You always said how hard it was
to be the a wife of an Alp.
Our brave husbands carry our hearts
with their swords.
You are right.
As long as our brave warriors are alive,
they will not let tyrants rule the world.
Messengers are here.
God willing.
God, let it be good news!
Yigit, Yigit!
Yigit. Thank God.
Welcome.
Gundogdu Bey saved me.
It was a huge battle.
We won in the end.
The castle of Templars
was burned to the ground.
Oh, thank God!
Mother Hayme, I bring the prayers
and good will of Suleyman Shah.
The castle of infidels has been captured.
Those who brought trouble to our
nomad group have perished one by one.
Thank God, bless you.
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
Let us make sacrifices,
and prepare for our brave ones, sisters.
Okay, mother.
However, we have many wounded and martyrs.
Bey wanted you to make preperations
for the wounded they are bringing
with them.
Suleyman Shah need not worry.
We will prepare everything.
Both my husband and my father are
there, Alp. Are they okay?
They are both fine, Aykiz.
You should have see your father.
He was the first to charge
and open the gates.
Ertugrul Bey climbed to the walls
and planted our flag.
Do not worry.
My lion!
What about my Alp?
Are there any news of Konur Alp,
my brave?
Are there any news of Guney Alp,
Mothers, sisters!
Both ghazis and martyrs are ours.
The martyrs who fell in the battle are
all of our brothers.
Do not cry.
Do not hurt the souls of our martyrs.
They were blessed with the
highest of blessings.
Kayi women stands strong.
Let us start our preparations together.
Come on.
Where is this son of a swine?
He is somewhere around here, brother.
I know he wants to save his skin.
Bey, they are not talking, either.
Speak or I will beat you to a pulp,
you pig shit!
Okay, Bamsi Beyrek.
Apparently he is hiding somewhere
that nobody knows.
He will leave his hole sooner or later.
I am going to look for him, brother.
It is forbidden for me to live
as long as he breathes.
You are right.
I will not die until
I kill the last one of you, Turk!
According to these documents,
they made everything to convince Pope
and Emperor Frederic to start
a new crusade.
They assassinated many to provoke
Muslims to fight among themselves.
They bought hundreds of people
in the army and state.
But it doesn't end there.
They did every kind of cruelty to
the Orthodox Christians, whom they hate.
I heard crusaders shed the blood of
innocents
when they conquered Constantinople.
They pillaged many cities,
including Constantinople.
They still continue their vile acts.
They do not hesitate to massacre
even their Christian brethren.
They kill their own brothers just because
they are from a different church.
You have to take these letters
to Sultan Aleaddin, Afsin Bey.
I will take them, but
some of the names I have seen in these
lists have shocked me.
With your permission,
I want to keep reading.
You will inform us later on, Afsin.
Oh, wow!
Wretches!
Who knows, whose claims are these.
They tried to buy our nomad group and
the traitors to Islam with this gold.
What about these gold, brother?
Whatever Bey says.
He will make the right decision.
Haven't you found him already?
Search everywhere.
Gundogdu
distribute some of our spoils
to the families of our martyrs.
And some to the Christian villages at
the neighborhood. Compensate their losses.
They have been under heavy taxes for
years. Let them breathe a little.
And you shall distribute the rest of it
equally among our tribe.
As you command, Bey.
Any news from Titus?
No, Bey.
Keep searching.
We have to find him.
As you command, Bey.
It is my turn to die, huh?
On the contrary, you will not die.
You will live.
So that, the Papacy will know
about the deeds of a bunch of Turks.
Although, I highly doubt that
you will have the courage
to go to Constantinople or Rome
after the letter of Afsin Bey.
I think he has the courage, brother.
Papacy must waiting the victories of Turks
impatiently.
Stop idling and go.
Your horse is ready outside.
Keep your eyes open on the road.
If the villagers see you, they will
tear you up before you reach Antioch.
Ertugrul
can you tell me what is in the chest of
Ibnul Arabi?
A gift that will honor it's owner,
he says. That is all.
For some reason,
I am not curious about it's owner.
This is just the beginning.
This conflict will not end,
even after a thousand years.
It's true.
Our blood will never stop chasing you
even after a thousand years.
You will not sleep at peace.
You will most certainly pay for
what you have done.
Since when do you feel nauseous?
It just started.
But I could not say a word to anybody
after all this trouble.
Selcan Hatun
I swear you are pregnant.
Finally, you will have a child.
My fear are true.
What am I going to do now?
Will they believe me now?
Your father is dead, brother.
May he rest in peace.
Thank you, brother Dundar.
I hope that you will take your
revenge with your own hands one day.
I vow to take my revenge one day.
You spoiled the plans of the Templars
and saved the nomad group.
Praise to God. We stopped the heathens.
Let's take a stroll of the nomad group.
Mother, we are going out with Yigit.
Okay.
You can tell what kind of a man
these two will become. Just look at them.
Their blood is wild.
They want to conquer the world.
They do mother.
Yigit gets restless with each day.
Ertugrul became a man at their age.
He never got off of his mare.
He brought many opponents
to their knees in wrestling.
He was bouncing off the walls.
But God knows, he never hurt us.
He never broke our hearts.
We knew he was different when he was born.
God Bless, mother.
You raised up a very beautiful son.
Look, daughter.
A man is like a wild stallion.
It is his wildness,
that keeps his marquee alive.
If you want to have peace in your marquee,
you shall not try possess him.
Because he does not like to be possessed.
Of course you will feed and tame him
like a hostler.
You will serve him willingly.
Then, that stallion will be loyal to you.
If you do not do what I say,
he will be the first one to kick you.
A valuable lesson for me, mother.
Suleyman Shah may want to marry you to
Ertugrul right after they are back.
So let us start to set up your own tent
right after tomorrow. Okay?
Okay mother.
Whatever you deem appropriate.
Farewell, Kayis.
I will see you one more time.
These heathens
have made plans for the downfall of the
Islamic world on this table.
If we succeed, all of the borders of this
realm will change.
It is not going to be hard for us when
Muslims are fighting each other, Titus.
We will reach our goal the day we incite
Turks against the descendants of
Saladin Eyyubi.
Jerusalem will be ours.
With God's will, we spoiled their plans
and razed their castle.
Praise to God.
Now it our turn to make plans.
Oh, the great Otugen!
I missed you a lot
with your grand mountains
cool tablelands and wild rivers.
If God permits, we will return to the
land of our ancestors one day, father.
Son
it was our duty to ride through west
as the descendants of Oghuz.
Our target will always be the lands
where the sun sets.
After the Dandanakan victory,
Tugrul Bey has gathered a big council
and decided the fate of Oghuz tribe.
Our destiny lies in the lands
where the sun sets.
Bey.
Heathen Titus has eluded our Alps
and escaped.
He has escaped.
Catching him after this will be very hard.
Until he confronts us.
The sheep dog has escaped, huh?
He martyred two of our Alps on his escape.
We have seen that it is possible to
defeat these jackals.
The power of our faith and
sword is enough for us.
However
their attacks will never end.
They need to be confronted by a state
for that to happen, father.
You are right, son.
First, we have to become a state.
Ayyubis are torn apart.
Seljukian shahzadas are fighting
among themselves.
World of Islam is leaderless.
First, we have to establish
a powerful Seigniory.
Brother, father.
Do you hear yourselves?
We hear very well, son.
Ertugrul is right.
Establishing a Seigniory should be
our nomad group's priority.
Elaziz is our friend.
However, no emperor, no Bey would
let another Seigniory to be established
in his realm.
If founding a Seigniory is our destiny,
the land will find us, son.
My time has passed.
You will be the ones to strive for
this opportunity.
The future of our nomad group is
in your hands.
My sons...
...If anything happens to me,
never abandon each other.
Stay together all the time.
If you stick together,
our people will grow
and find a land of their own.
Thank you father.
Father!
I will rest for a while.
You should rest, too.
We will take the road after
I perform my two rakat prayer tomorrow.
God willing.
How bad is his pustule?
Very bad, brother. Very bad.
It covers all of his back.
We should talk to Arabi,
when we get back to our nomad tent.
He will take care of it.
What kind of an illness is this?
It hasn't healed.
The Beys of Oghuz Tribes will gather.
Do white beards know about this?
Nothing happens without their
knowledge, Ertugrul Bey.
They must invited all the Beys from
Seljuk Empire and Oghuz Tribes.
Why does Oghuz Tribes gather?
White beards are going to form a group
in case Mongols come to Anatolia.
I hope we will succeed, Afsin Bey.
Otherwise we will encounter a much
bigger danger than the crusaders.
Mongols have sent their spies
to the corners of Anatolia.
They are everywhere.
We must be vigilant, Ertugrul Bey.
If God permits, Afsin Bey.
First we should go back
to the nomad group.
We have not tasted victory for a
long time. It will reassure everyone.
Thanks to you, Bey.
Thanks to you.
Thank you, Afsin Bey.
Campaign is ours,
but the victory belongs to God.
We don't want to be late for the
praise prayer.
I intend to perform two rakat of praise
prayer in the name of God.
God is great!
God hears all of his creatures.
God's mercy and grace be upon you.
My supreme God, who is the maker
of the sky and land.
We belong to you and
we will surely return you.
Do not abandoned us.
Amen!
Bless our battle.
Never let us deviate from your path.
Amen!
Take our martyrs beside you.
Let the world of Islam be reborn.
Amen!
Al Fatihah.
My brave sons who conquer castles.
Everything has an end.
My life is about to come to an end.
Maybe this was my last battle with you.
My legacy to you is that you
should never avoid battle.
Do not betray your Bey, your traditions
your people and your religion
like Kurtoglu.
A handful of men conquered this castle
with their faith and courage.
Do not ruin your unity and peace.
May God always be with you!
Amen!
The best way to deal with the desert sun
and sandstorm is our tents.
Yes.
Girls! Stretch them more.
Stretch it.
Stretch it so that the tent breathes
in the summer and...
...never lets rain and cold
inside in winter.
Okay, Mother Hayme.
Mother Hayme, do not worry.
Ertugrul Bey will not get cold.
Although he went to so many battles
and he challenges the whole world...
...he is always going to be
your little son.
Yes.
He has never slept outside
even when the marquee was full.
This is not about boy or girl.
Another bird is going to fly away
from the nest.
Even though
you will be under my nose every day...
I do not know.
I cannot replace you, Mother.
But, we will take care of each other
very well. I promise.
I know, my beautiful daughter. I know.
Tie them tightly.
Let the place level with the ground.
Let them not resort to get inside
of this snake nest again.
Do not worry, Bey.
We will lay this place to waste.
May God speed you.
Hamza!
You will bring our martyrs after us.
As you command, Bey.
Finally, I finished this.
Halime!
What is wrong?
Why are you sad now?
I remember my father.
All those sufferings
he had through for years.
His struggle to save the honor of
Seljukian Dynasty.
Then his surrender.
Sometimes I think...
...that my father
overlooked certain things.
Otherwise there is no explanation of
his aspiration of the throne.
He resisted and struggled all his life.
And then...
I wish he were here and saw my happy day.
Rest in peace.
He was a very good man.
I am sure he would have been
very happy for you if he were alive.
He liked Ertugrul very much.
Very much.
Thank you, Aykiz.
I will not stop until I die, Ertugrul.
Soon you will pay for what you have done.
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
We did not do anything
other than God's orders.
We were not cruels.
We took every step with gratitude.
We enlivened every land we stepped on...
...with the light of Islam.
We are Alps.
Our occupation is to follow God's way.
Our aim is to spread God's religion.
We brought the Templars' castle
down on them.
We routed the home of instigation.
The war booties are going to be...
...distributed to everyone equally
including me.
I wish mercy for our...
...martyrs who did not leave the battle
and made us victors.
Amen!
May God bless all of them!
Allahu Akbar!
Welcome to your marquee, Bey.
Thank you, Hayme.
Thank God we came back
from another battle safely.
Thankfully.
Suleyman, are you alright?
I am fine, Hayme.
Do not worry.
How can I not worry?
You went to battle
with this wound on your back.
You came back with victories.
Thank you. Live long, Bey.
You live long, as well, Hayme.
We got news.
All Oghuz tribes will get together.
Will you go there like this?
I have to go, Hayme.
I have served to Kayis
and the Oghuz tribe for all my life.
I know. You have gone to battle
and hunting with all of them.
You guided them so many times.
But, I wish we cleaned that wound first.
This is why
I have to go to that congress, Hayme.
There is a chance that
I will not return from this mission.
Why are you talking like that, Suleyman?
Please do not say that.
I have lived enough.
I served to my religion and my family
as much as I could.
I would like to see
Ertugrul's wedding before I die.
What are you saying, Bey?
-You will see your grandchildren.
-If God permits, Hayme.
Let us deal with this
before I go to Ahlat.
Do not worry, Bey.
I started the preparations right away.
There is so much pain going on.
The wedding shall not be festive, Hayme.
I know.
Do not worry, Bey.
I just wanted
to congratulate your victory.
Thank you.
I have something to say.
Tell me.
I wonder what lies you will tell
this time.
I am...
I am pregnant.
Do you think I am stupid, woman?
Selcan...
...do you have any pride,
honor or modesty?
I do not believe these lies anymore.
Go before I say something bad.
Get out!
As you wish, Gundogdu.
However, you should know that
my words were true.
To hell with you and your words.
Even though I sent you to war
as if sending you to a wedding...
...it cuts me to the quick, Turgut.
I felt like your battle lasted for years.
I waited for years
to come together with my Aykiz.
As long as I have your love,
neither the infidels' arrows...
...nor their swords will hurt me.
You think I don't know my sorrowful violet
is longing for me in our tent?
Do you think I do not?
How could I not run to you
knowing that, Aykiz?
Then, my faith shall be your weapon...
...and my patience
shall be your shield, my brave man.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in.
Come in, sister Gokce.
I wanted to ask you
if you need anything, Bey.
Thank you.
I do not.
I know, Bey.
What my sister did, aches your heart.
It devastated me as well.
She is the one who dragged
our nomad tent to trouble.
Your sister killed the human inside me,
Gokce Hatun.
I have thought of her...
...as my woman
since the day I came to my senses.
However, your sister thought me
as a ride for her marquee.
Now she says that she is pregnant.
Just for me not to divorce her.
So she is still into playing games.
Old habits die hard.
What about you, Bey?
Why do you not divorce my sister?
It is on the tip of my tongue.
But...
...my heart does not let me.
You brought me my brother, Ertugrul Bey.
You made me happy.
I gave you a promise, Halime Sultan.
I would either bring him back or die.
You collapsed that cruels castle, as well.
Now the instigation will end.
They say the Mongol bandits are all over.
Do the enemies of the justice army
ever end, Halime Sultan?
May our enemy never end,
so that our battles increase.
Forget that now.
Is everything ready for the wedding?
We prepared our tent with Mother Hayme.
However, you will not see it
before the wedding.
Promise?
Promise.
My Gokce.
How long will this continue, sister?
How long will you keep on
playing this game?
What game are you talking about?
What are you saying?
After all those lies and slanders,
what made you became a religious women?
Don't talk like that, Gokce.
Sister, enough!
You were the one
behind every instigation with Kurtoglu.
How did you become as pure as the
driven snow? Tell me, how?
I am speechless for your words.
My lips crack. My heart aches.
Words fail me, my dear.
However...
...if the devil inside me
was still alive...
...would I have confessed all my sins?
You are such a devilish woman, sister...
If you do something, there are
definitely many instigations behind it.
How could you expect me to
believe you after all...
...you have done?
How could I believe you anymore?
When Alp Argu came to the tent
to kill Ertugrul...
...did you show the way to Kurtoglu?
What is your role in
Alp Argu stabbing me on my groin...
...so that I will not have a baby anymore?
Tell me, what is your role?
I hate you.
I hate you sister.
Stop!
If I sat in my tent silently
all this time...
...it is because I waited for good news
from Gundogdu.
Thankfully, I heard good news.
My brave man is fine.
So, from now on...
...there is no need for me
in this nomad group.
I am done here.
This is what I say.
As for your question...
...yes, I had a role
in every instigation.
If you will not have a baby,
I am responsible for this.
No matter what you do...
...you will never be able to erase
the disgrace of your heart, sister.
May God speed you, my dear sister.
I hope you find the happiness...
...you are searching for
with your pure heart very soon.
We have seen so many boils
and so many heads of boils.
I will not be afraid of a boil on my back.
Of course, God gives and takes lives,
Suleyman Shah.
Brave Beys like you are...
...not afraid of that boil.
However...
...if the will is from God,
the duty of precaution is on the servant.
You should know this, as well.
What should I do my Sheikh?
I will prepare you a cure from herbs out
of respect for the name, Al Shafi.
It will relieve your pain.
However, you shall not hide your pain
either from your wife or me.
It is obvious.
You shall not think of this trouble
as unimportant.
I say that you should not travel.
Your sons became famous from the
Seljukian Palace to the Ayyubis Palace...
...from the Pope's Palace
to the Emperor's Palace.
They will represent you in the best way.
I do not doubt of that, my Sheikh.
However there are definitely people like
Kurtoglu in the other nomad groups.
I consent to die on the way
if I will have...
...even a little bit contribution
to this big Islamic alliance.
May God help you, then.
Thank you.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in, Abdurrahman.
Our martyrs are here, Bey.
For the souls of our martyrs...
Al Fatihah.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Ertugrul, Halime.
I would like to perform your wedding
ceremony tomorrow night before I go...
...to meet the Oghuz Tribes.
You could not have given us
a more beautiful gift than this, father.
You did what would make us the happiest.
It comes to my mind that you raised...
...your eyebrows and held the weapons
when you saw the Mongol idolator, woman.
It comes to my mind that...
...you said we should
fight for our daughter, Aykiz.
That you said the survivor of us
shall be both the father...
...and the mother of Aykiz.
You died at the battle like an Alp.
Being both mother and father
was left to me.
I wish I died...
...and you became
the father and mother for our daughter.
I wish you were alive.
Then you would have done...
...what I could not, somehow.
Anyways.
I got our daughter married.
Aykiz was with me since you were gone.
Now, she is at another one's tent.
I do not know how to cope with loneliness.
I pray to God to end this every night.
I miss you very much my wild flower.
Very much.
Do I have permission, father?
Come in, my children.
Eyrek Alp caught this partridge
in the hunt.
He gave it to us.
He wanted me to cook it for you.
He said, "Let him eat this
and his wound will heal soon."
Turgut?
Yes, father?
Aykiz...
...I want a grandchild from you
right away.
I want to hold him in my arms.
Ameer El Aziz from Aleppo wants to
meet your Bey, Suleyman Shah.
Bey, El Aziz is here.
He wants to meet you.
I say we should not make El Aziz
wait too long, father.
Let him in.
You can go in.
Welcome, El Aziz.
Thank you.
I was headed to Egypt.
There might be no coming back either.
I wanted to see you for the last time,
while I am still alive, Suleyman Shah.
Although you humiliated me
the last time I saw you.
What will you do if I gather my armies...
...and advance on you?
How do you talk me like that?
Who do you trust?
We trust whoever we trusted and...
...said with God's help when you threw us
in front of the Crusaders.
Do not forget Ameer ...
...we Kayis believe in God,
trust in God and take refugee of God.
If your army is bigger than that,
bring it on!
There is nothing better to show the way
to a man who has gone off track...
...like the telling off of a
brave and honest man like you.
Welcome, El Aziz.
Thank you, brother.
Please.
Melike Adile and Sultan Alaeddin
got married.
This is a propitious marriage
for the world of Islam.
I told about the contributions of you
and Gundogdu Bey...
...for this marriage to happen in
the letter I wrote to Sultan Alaeddin.
It is praiseworthy that you brought
the Templars' castle down on them.
May God bless you and your martyrs.
Amen!
The reason why I came here is that
I would like our friendship last forever.
I believe that you will support
the Seljukian and Ayyubians alliance.
We hold all the efforts for peace
in high esteem...
...El Aziz.
I told you a word back then,
do you remember El Aziz?
Remind me.
We fight so much that
our swords do not get into their sheaths.
Our horses never fear of the battle.
As long as we have an alliance to carry...
A bowl of water to the fire at home.
My brave brother who always stands
behind his words...
Suleyman Shah...
...there is enough coin to buy
all of your herd.
In this chest...
...there are gifts for brother Ertugrul
and Halime Sultan's wedding...
...from not only me but also
Ayyubi Dynasty.
If you accept, you would honor
the descendants of Salahuddin Ayyubi.
If holy God allows you to be
born healthy...
...I will take you to your dad.
How can a sinful woman like me dare...
...to bring up the child of such a brave
courageous father, my little one?
However, you must know that...
...your mother will always love you
so much.
While dying and citing God's name...
...you will always be on my lips.
Forgive your poor mother
my little one...
...forgive your sinful mother.
Forgive.
May I have your permission, Bey?
Come in, son.
You ordered me to come.
Be seated.
We want to talk about Selcan with you.
You told everything was over
when Selcan confessed every sin...
...she committed.
Even that you would divorce her.
Then, you told us did not know
what to do and asked for some time.
However, enough time has passed.
Do you know what to do now, son?
Father, Mother.
I told Selcan "I divorce you!"
twice in the tent.
When I was about to say it
the third time...
...she put my dagger to my hands
and begged me to kill her.
That moment haunted me.
I did not know what to do.
But you must make a decision.
What do you think?
Selcan is on her way to repent
and determined her will.
I say, open your tent to her
one last time.
Bey.
A small present, the least I can do.
Fox fur. It is beneath you.
I will carry these furs for my three brave
Alps, until I die.
I grew up with you.
I met the sword with you...
...learned how to use it with you.
You taught that the Alps are the ones
make a hunt worthy...
...and a man into a Bey.
Whatever I learned,
you were always beside me.
If I became the head of the Alps...
...if I am one of those trusted with
a duty...
...your contribution in this is great.
If I deserve to be your Bey...
...how happy I am!
Bey!
May God keep you beside us!
May you be happy all your life,
if God permits.
Thank you Turgut, thank you.
May you be happy with Halime Sultan
throughout your life, Bey.
Thank you Dogan.
What is wrong big man?
He is miserable because you got married,
Bey.
I do not know Bey...
...I thought that you would marry
your armor, love your horse as a child...
...like I do, I was keep telling myself.
Bey, this if for my sister, Halime Sultan.
Your precious?
-My precious, Bey.
-Kudret.
May God give you happiness, Bey.
Make you fortunate.
What can I say?
May God give you many children, Bey.
Three, five, eight...
Take how many God may give you, Bey.
If God permits. If God permits!
Do not worry Bamsi.
We can find a wife for you,
from Banu Cicek's nomad tent as well.
Stop there Dogan! Stop! Stop it!
Sensitive bear!
I applied henna on you. For what?
To be sacrificed to the tent of my brave
man who I am getting married to.
What else for?
To know how to apply it to the back of
sacrificial  lamb at feast of sacrifice...
...on palms of my Alp when
he is going to war.
What else? What else for?
To listen to holy azan of Mohammad...
...may our customs, the souvenir
of our ancestors be everlasting.
May your happiness be everlasting,
Halime Sultan.
The day you have been waiting for
has arrives, is it not Ertugrul?
Thanks to you.
You have become my compass.
You lead me in my darkest hours.
When I thought I was left in the dark,
you became my light.
And thanks to you I am getting married
to the woman I love.
How happy for you! Let your nomad people,
nomad tent, tribe, kin and your nation...
...last forever with your happiness.
May the fruits of your marriage
take hold of the world.
Thank you.
After we solemnize you, right after the
morning prayer, I will hit the roads, son.
I hope to see you again, if God permits.
If God permit we will see each other.
If you will go, let me bring you
the deposit.
It is not a deposit anymore Ertugrul.
It has found its owner, thank God.
You were not only a sister but also
a mother to me while there were...
...lots of enemies, wanting to kill us,
to use us putting in prison.
I will never be able to make up for what
you did for me, sister.
If I was able to find my brave man who
I have been looking for my whole life...
...and marry him and make a home
with him you contributed greatly.
Especially me, I will never pay you back.
My dear brother.
Permission?
Come in Ertugrul Bey.
I entrusted you not only my sister,
but my dear, my beloved.
Take good care of my precious,
Ertugrul Bey.
Show your fist's power to the enemy
and your heart's mercy to my sister.
May God make you happy and felicitous.
A gazelle brought her to me.
While I am thanking my God who sent
that gazelle to me, every single day...
...how can I break her heart, hurt her?
I rather that God would take my life...
...a thousand times instead of letting me
live through that.
So Selcan Hatun, you reap what you sow.
It is time to leave.
Let us see what lies in your destiny.
Everybody keep your hands open,
do not tie them.
And say it with me.
For our sins...
...we swear not to repeat them.
We swear not to repeat them.
-We swear.
For He is the Greatest.
For there is no deity but Him.
He is the owner of everything.
We ask His forgiveness.
We believe in God and in His angels...
...and in His books and in His Prophets...
...and in the day of reckoning
and in destiny.
We believe that goodness and malice
are all His creations.
There is no deity but God and Muhammad
is his Prophet and subject.
The daughter of Numan, Halime,
with the son of Suleyman, Ertugrul...
...on the condition that he gives you
10 dirham gold and 20 sheep...
...as prenuptial support,
do you accept him as your spouse?
I do.
Do you?
The son of Suleiman, Ertugrul.
On condition of the prenuptial support,
have you accepted her as your spouse?
I do.
-Do you?
-I do.
Do you?
I do.
Witnesses. Have you witnessed?
Yes, we have.
May God bless your marriage.
Amen.
Holy God.
We have witnessed these two beloved
youngster's marriage.
You witness it, too.
Amen.
May you bless their marriage promise.
May you let this couple get on well,
love each other and persevere.
-Amen.
-Never let them be in hatred...
...conflict or divorce.
-Amen.
God...
...may you bless them with a good
relation, good terms and affection...
...between our holy Father Adam and
our holy Mother Eve...
...and Prophet Muhammad, and our holy
Mother Hatice and holy Prophet Ali...
-...and our holy Mother Fatima.
-Amen.
God.
May you give this couple good kids,
long life and abundant livelihood.
Amen.
May you let these kids which will come
from them to rule the world.
Amen.
Al Fatihah.
Be prosperous my dear children.
For the day of our nomad group's time
to be a Seigniory...
...give birth to many sons many daughters.
May God let gives you happiness
and velocity.
Amen father.
I wish you and your kin may last long.
I hope you make an impact all around
the world, if God permits.
Live a long life with your children.
Amen Mother.
May God let you live long and happily
ever after.
Amen.
My brother.
God Bless.
Live happily ever after.
Amen brother.
Do I have permission, Selcan Hatun?
Selcan.
What have you done Selcan?
What did Ertugrul Bey do?
He put up a tent in the sky.
What did he do to make the woman
he loved happy?
He made a horse to a stallion,
a cow to a camel, a sheep to a ram.
Did he break any hearts?
Did he say anything bad?
He neither broke any hearts
nor said anything bad.
He has entered the nuptial chamber
and attained his desire.
Then may they live happily ever after.
Amen!
Have a long lasting marriage and
be happy ever after.
What did Ertugrul Bey do?
He put up a tent in the sky.
Come on!
Selcan?
Have you seen Selcan Hatun?
She has just left Bey.
She forgot the laundry by the river,
she said she would go and retrieve them.
Selcan!
The remedy of love is reunion Ertugrul.
Thank God for sending me the gazelle
that showed you to me.
Thank God for granting me to be
the wife of an Alp like you.
May God let this reunion be forever.
Never make us suffer a break up
Halime Sultan.
Amen.
May God give us a long life
with our children.
Amen.
Kayis and Kinik...
...become embodied in this tent.
We have united to tribes into one,
Ertugrul Bey.
May the tribes become one
our kin be blessed Halime Sultan.
Selcan!
I told you I would make life unbearable
to you.
Titus never gives up.
No!
Selcan?
Selcan!
Gundogdu.
Forgive, forgive me.
Selcan!