Episode 21 will start after 12:12 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
God is Hakk!
Catch them!
Kayi Tent
Why do you think Kurdoglu put us here?
I do not like the way Turgut looks at us.
Ertugrul said he recovered, but...
That is exactly why he put us here.
To scare and suppress us.
His hands and feet are tied up.
For now.
You never know who unties him.
What is going to happen now, Suleyman?
He will do as much as he can
to make them give the decision he wants.
I knew he would do all kinds of violence,
vileness and betrayal.
But I was not expecting this early.
You took all kinds of precautions.
You could not have known the beys
in the tent would be such corrupt.
I did not take all kinds of precautions.
I showed mercy.
This is how it ends if you show mercy
to the head of the instigations.
You and your children,
give your blessings to me.
I put you in trouble.
Do not worry about us.
We will be proud even to die
if it is for you.
Besides, Ertugrul is still away.
He must have heard of what happened.
What can he do by himself?
Let us pray that he does not come here.
Or he will end up like us.
Dogan!
Bamsi!
Bey, why did we not attack them
instead of running away?
We are not running away, Bamsi.
We are luring them to the places
where we can fight in equal conditions.
We will kill them all
until we reach our horses.
You four, this way.
The rest will come with me.
Dogan!
Let go of me!
Let go of me! Do not touch my arm!
Do not touch me!
Go to hell!
Burn in flames!
How could you be the
servants of that bastard Kurdoglu?
-Selcan Hatun, be good or...
-Or what?
Or I will decapitate you!
She killed my baby!
Selcan Hatun...
Come here, have a seat.
They did not touch you, did they?
Any news from
Suleyman Shah and Mother Hayme?
No news from my father, either.
-What if they kill them?
-Sisters!
Pull yourselves together.
That bastard will not be
able to bring us to our knees.
Both Mother Hayme
and Suleyman Shah would not give up.
That coward Kurdoglu
cannot do anything to them.
Wild Demir is such an experienced warrior.
God knows he will not give up, either.
What is going to happen now?
Kurdoglu broke the order of the tent.
He went against the tradition.
Look what you did
to the Kayi Tent, Kurdoglu.
How could they do this
to Suleyman Shah and our Mother Hayme?
How?
He tried to come to the throne
with tricks after he lost the election.
So, he was the traitor in the tent.
He disguised himself very well.
Untie him!
Do not touch me.
This my armor of pride, Kurdoglu.
I will never take these off
before I put them around your neck.
If I do not succeed,
then I will be buried with them.
Wild Demir...
...you forged so much iron
with your hammer for such a long time...
...but you could not
forge your mind and heart.
You are still wild.
Kurdoglu...
Our ancestors named you "Kurdoglu".
Why?
Obviously, they saw talent in you
while you were a child.
But you could not protect your heart.
You sold your heart
to the Devil, Kurdoglu.
I have been working so hard for such a
long time for the future of my tent.
However, Suleyman Shah and his children
dragged us from one danger to another.
I warned them a lot of times...
...but they did not listen to me.
-And then, they lost their crown.
-Kurdoglu!
Cut it short!
Say what you are going to say.
I would like to grant you
a final opportunity.
Obey me as the new bey.
Let us turn our tent
into how it was before.
You and your daughter will be at ease.
Kurdoglu...
I will never obey you.
If I do, persecution
will be legalized forever.
And to write a history will be
impossible for the children of Kayi.
After all this has passed, the children of
Kayi will remember us, not you.
They will say that we never surrendered
to persecution and the persecutor.
I will not obey you
if you chopped me to pieces...
...let alone kill me, Kurdoglu.
Take this rebel
to where Suleyman Shah is!
He will see what persecution is like.
Take him!
Where is my daughter?
Getting ready to go to hell.
I said take him!
If you hurt my daughter, Kurdoglu...
...I will make life unbearable for you.
Make no mistake about it.
Take him!
Wild Demir, tell our Bey
that we are very sorry.
Stop, stop!
Blasphemy goes on,
but persecution does not!
The traitor we have been looking for
is in the marquee! Beware!
Beware!
This way.
Master Demir!
-Mother Hayme.
-Wild Demir?
Bey...
Are you alright?
I am, Mother Hayme.
We had a little commotion.
Thankfully, I am alright.
But the silence in the tent
breaks my heart.
Blood has spilled, Wild Demir.
There were casualties.
Our people still did not understand
what is going on.
Mother Hayme...
-You will come with us.
-Where are you taking your Mother Hayme?
To where the other women are.
What about my children?
Dundar and Gundogdu
are in Akcakoca's tent.
The midwives are taking care of them.
Gundogdu Bey is alright.
Tell them I am alright.
Do not forget what I told you.
I will not, Bey.
May God protect you.
You, too.
My biggest pain is that...
...I could not use my sword.
What do we do now?
I hope we can survive,
so that you can fight like a sword...
...after staying
in your sheath for so long.
This bastard will not be
getting away with what he did, for sure.
I came here from the marquee.
He tried to win me over.
I wish you accepted.
How can I do that, Bey?
He is the traitor.
Did he not
sell us all out to the Crusaders?
What about Aykiz?
Everything happens
according to God's will.
Mother Hayme!
I was so worried that you would be hurt.
I do not have anybody other than you.
My beautiful girl.
Being afraid would be unseemly of us.
The persecutors will be happy
if we get devastated like this.
Wipe those tears now.
Smile with that beautiful face.
Come on, sit by my side.
How is Suleyman Shah, Mother Hayme?
He is very well, my daughter.
He told you not to be sorry for him,
and not to be sad.
He said that we will fend off
this plague by God's will.
He told you not to be worried
and to be at ease.
Any news from my Gundogdu?
Gundogdu is also alright.
He is in Akcakoca's tent.
My Dundar is with him.
Thank God.
Any news from my father?
My beautiful girl.
You know how your father is.
He is happy at all times.
His madness is the biggest gift
that was granted to him.
He is trying to find a way to fend off
this plague with Suleyman Shah.
Can we overcome this plague, mother?
My beautiful girl...
God who saved
Hazrat Noah from the flood...
...Hazrat Ibrahim from the fire...
...Hazrat Yousuf from the well...
...will hopefully
save us from this plague.
-Amen.
The only thing we can do...
...is to surrender to God Almighty
as our prophets had told us...
...without losing our hope.
Idiots!
Incompetents!
Find those goat shepherds now!
Sir, this is very dangerous.
Move!
Everything in the tent is secured now.
We beheaded the ones who resisted.
We have to tell the people of the tent
very well why we overthrew Suleyman Shah.
He will always be a threat to us
as long as he lives in this tent.
Kurdoglu, why do we not kill
Suleyman Shah?
It will be persecution unless
we kill him without trying him first.
But if we handle it
in the headquarters meeting...
...it will legalize
everything we do, Karabudak.
This will cause
the blood we spill not touch us.
I admire your wit, Bey.
Thank you, Kutlu Bey.
We have to make the people happy
after the meeting.
But first, we need to make
Suleyman Shah's kins obey us...
...so that our power in the tent
will be shown legit.
Bey, this way.
Catch them!
I first saw Suleyman Shah
in my father's tent.
Our marquee
was near Ahlat back then.
Ahlat is a great city.
So many saints and Alps
are buried there.
It is the gate for the Turks
that opens to Anatolia.
I gave birth to my Ertugrul
in that beautiful city.
Anyway.
Suleyman Shah was a brave young man.
His fame had spread
all over the Oghuz tents.
I thought my heart would stop
the moment I saw him.
My father liked him very much, as well.
They went to so many raids together.
They conquered so many lands.
Suleyman Shah
liked me very much when he first saw me.
Then, one day...
Kurdoglu Bey wants to see Selcan Hatun.
Why is that?
We do not know. Come on, Selcan Hatun.
Selcan, go and find out
what that devil wants.
Turgut, son...
Never forget who you are
whoever whispers things to your ear.
You are an honorable Alp.
Do not forget that you have a loved one
who waits for you.
Stand up, Turgut Alp! Come on!
Bey, what is this rascal up to?
All his evil acts
will come against us, Wild Demir.
You are right, Bey.
You are right.
Welcome, Selcan Hatun.
What do you want from me?
You were the only woman in this tent
who understood me.
We struggled so much together
for the unity of this tent.
If we succeeded, this marquee
and crown would be you and your man's.
But that coward man of yours
messed up everything...
...and caused the tent become like this.
Kurdoglu, we struggled
for Gundogdu to be the bey.
He did not want it.
He allied with his father.
Then I understood that
it was our duty to shut up.
But you revealed your true intention.
You would have overthrown even Gundogdu
if he came to that crown!
Oh, Selcan...
Even the Devil says
"What am I good for?" when he sees you.
We would have brought the world
to its knees if you were a man.
Kurdoglu, what do you want from me?
If you want to take
one more breath in this world...
...if you want your sister live...
...you will never talk about
the alliances we have made together.
Otherwise, I will kill you both!
I would like to give
you and Gundogdu a last chance.
If Gundogdu obeys me
before the meeting...
...I will save your lives.
Now, go and tell this to your husband.
You do not want to be called
a traitor after being the bey.
I see you are in the euphoria of victory.
However, you will lose!
How nice.
Obey me, and we will lose together, then.
Alps!
Get out.
I said get out!
If only we had our share
from those infidels' wit.
Look how they turned a sturdy Alp into.
Am I right, Judas?
Judas...
Yes, Judas.
You will be my Alp from now on.
I will need brave warriors like you.
And you will finish the business
you left unfinished.
I am talking about Ertugrul.
Did you get it?
Good.
But first, I will give you duties
as important as killing that ominous boy.
My right arm.
My precious Alp.
Gundogdu...
Thank God you are alright.
I am alright, woman. I am alright.
Dundar...
He is the same.
Do not worry,
the midwives are taking care of him.
How about them?
My father and Wild Demir
are in the cage.
They took us to another tent.
Mercy leads to disaster, woman.
We should not have shown him mercy.
How could he do this?
How could he escape
from my tricks so successfully?
Either he is very clever,
or I am very stupid.
I was with him just now.
What does he want?
He wants you to obey him.
I would rather die honorably
instead of obeying him.
You will not courage him no matter what.
I would rather go to hell with you
instead of obeying that ominous bastard.
Do not worry.
Forgive me for the words I said to you.
I would die if you wanted me to.
When the time comes, you will not
let anybody from his family live.
Do you understand?
I said do you understand?
Good.
I will let you know.
Yes, sir.
Now, go and take a bath.
You smell like a pig.
Clean up.
Put on some clothes.
Look like an Alp.
Here.
Alps!
This is my new Alp, Turgut.
Take care of him. Please him.
I decided that he has recovered.
Come on.
What did Kurdoglu say?
He wants Gundogdu to obey him.
He sent me to Gundogdu.
And?
Gundogdu said he would not obey him
even they buried him alive.
He will try anything
to show himself legit.
Kurdoglu!
Let us see
what other games he has in store.
Could they not catch them yet?
No, sir.
Bu we have their horses.
They cannot escape.
God damn Turk!
How did you come here, Titus?
I turned back to the castle
from Aleppo.
I found out that
you set a trap here for Ertugrul.
You were right on time.
I needed you.
What did you do in Aleppo?
We successfully did our duty, sir.
We have the queen.
The Ayyubid army
is looking for her everywhere.
I deemed necessary to wait a while
instead of taking her to the castle.
I hid Eftelya and the queen in a cave.
Good thinking.
Is Eftelya alone?
No, my knights that I trust the most
are with her.
Good.
You stopped Alaeddin Kayqubad's move...
...that was going to unite the
Islamic world against the Crusaders.
Congratulations, son.
If this marriage happened...
...it would be very hard for us...
...to convince the Pope
for a new Crusade.
Thank you, sir.
And now, Ertugrul.
They will not
get out of this forest alive.
We will fend off this plague.
I need Ertugrul alive, Titus.
Sir?
Why?
You know, this man always
managed to escape from us.
Do what I say, Titus.
This is our last opportunity to kill him.
Alright.
But why?
Because only he knows
where the arc that Arabi carries is.
You have to bring him to me alive.
This may be our last chance to kill him.
Do what I say, Titus!
That arc is much more valuable for me
than that ominous Turk.
What is going to happen now?
This is against our tradition.
What will happen
to Suleyman Shah's family?
From now on,
we want to have peace in this nomad tent.
The ones who go against this,
will definitely end up like Suleyman.
I will be against the ones
who do not want peace and wealth!
Kurdoglu, what did you do?
Raiding the marquee in the night...
...and be the bey by stabbing the bey
from his back is unheard of.
-This will not bring peace to the tent.
-He is right!
-You cannot be a bey like this.
It is against our tradition.
He is right.
-You cannot be a bey like this.
-It is against our tradition.
It is a shame for our tradition, our
people, the Kayi's, the Oghuz generation.
What you are doing
is definitely persecution.
Shame on you. Both as a man, and as a bey.
So, were you the traitor?
Were you the traitor
who made the tent suffer so much?
Was it you, Kurdoglu?
There are three traitors...
...in this tent
who allied with the Crusaders.
Baybora, Alpargu and Sarikayin.
All of them paid for it.
And he was the fourth.
There are not any traitors left
in our nomad tent.
And I will not allow betrayal anymore.
This traitor matter is closed now.
Now...
...I'll start the meeting regarding the
decision on Suleyman and his family.
Alps...
Bring Suleyman here.
Shah Suleyman,
they want you to come to the meeting.
Let us see what they've decided on us.
They cannot make a negative decision, Bey.
It would be a shame.
The beys would not let that happen.
You are our bey!
Forgive us, Shah!
Kurdoglu will pay for it!
Justice will be done!
Traitor Kurdoglu!
Shah Suleyman, you are our bey!
Let go of our bey!
You are our bey!
Forgive us, Shah!
Shah Suleyman, you are our bey!
Forgive us, Bey! Forgive us!
-Bey! Shah Suleyman!
-God will punish him, Bey!
He will surely punish him
by way of somebody among us!
The honorable beys of Kayi...
Our nomad tent will not have peace...
...as long as Suleyman and his sons live.
My wish is that Suleyman and his sons
be hung immediately.
And the women of the family go into exile.
I would like to have your
valuable opinions on this matter.
Your silence shows that
everybody agrees with me.
Bey Akdemir wants to say something.
I suppose he will support me.
Shah Suleyman has been our bey
for many years.
He worked so hard for the unity
and wealth of our nomad tent.
He is right.
He lost his children
and his first wife for this cause.
He did not have peace even for a day.
He laid eyes neither on our food
nor other women.
Of course!
We never saw such a thing. You are right.
Akdemir is right.
-He is right.
-Yes, he is right.
You are right, Akdemir.
So did Bey Gundogdu and Bey Ertugrul.
What I am saying is that...
...let them go into exile
instead of being hung.
You are right, Akdemir.
However, let them know that
they will be killed without mercy...
...if they come near the nomad tent.
Akdemir is right.
-Yes, let us exile them.
-Let us exile them.
Mercy leads to disaster.
However, it is my duty as your bey
to confront this disaster...
...that will result from showing mercy.
My heart also aches.
Suleyman is my blood brother.
He is my life. My brother.
I brought Gundogdu and Ertugrul up.
I would like you to know how hard it is
for me to take this decision.
However, as this is your opinion,
I can only accept this.
-Thank you.
Bring Shah Suleyman in.
Bey Kurdoglu is waiting for you.
Do not let our bey in!
Take him out!
So they killed you too, Yagiz?
Suleyman, the decision about
you and your family has been taken.
It is my duty to inform you
of this decision to your face.
You and your family will go into exile
from the nomad tent tomorrow.
However, you will be killed
without mercy...
...if you come near our nomad tent.
Do you have anything to say?
I only say a word to the one
who knows his traditions.
However, you should know that...
...this world has seen so many pharaohs.
And Nimrods.
And Abu Jahls.
But Hazrat Ibrahim's cause prevailed.
You should know that
I become a martyr if you kill me.
I become an exile if you exile me.
I become a monk if you imprison me.
I would thank God and forget it.
Suleyman...
...tomorrow, you will be sent to
Bey Korkut's nomad tent.
God help the Kayis.
Amen!
Take him!
Did they make a decision, Bey?
It was as you mentioned.
He could not convince the beys
to kill me and my sons.
Thank God.
They will exile us.
And you will share this fate with us.
Thank God, Bey. May our fate be your fate.
Where are we going to go?
To Hayme's brother Korkut's nomad tent.
Kurdoglu must not be happy
about this decision.
He is scared that you and Korkut
will take hold of the seigniory together.
They will not send us
to Korkut's nomad tent, anyway.
You are right, Bey.
They will think about a plan for us
on the way there.
Son! Gundogdu!
Are you alright?
I am, father.
I heard about the decision.
They have decided to kill us on the way.
We must escape immediately.
Or they will kill not only us,
but also the women on the way.
Hayme Hatun, it was decided
that you will go into exile.
You will set off as soon as possible.
So he is kicking us out of the nomad tent
we have been living in for so many years.
What a cruel man you are, Kurdoglu.
A shameless man
who does not care about God.
How can a brother persecute another,
just for the sake of the crown?
He does not care about exiling us.
He cannot kill us in front of the people.
His intention is to kill us
under the pretext of exiling us.
He can go to hell.
It is our duty
to go against persecution...
...even though we know
we are going to be killed.
This will be our Karbala.
We will neither be sad nor whine.
Finally, we have overcome
the Shah Suleyman plague.
Not yet.
Every breath he takes
is a big threat for us.
What is your plan, Bey?
The Angel of Death must cross his path
with Suleyman and his family on the way.
Bey, there is no need
to cover our weapons with blood.
If this is heard in the nomad tent,
we won't be able to keep it together.
Are you scared?
Listen, gentlemen...
If you cannot guess two steps further...
...you cannot continue being the bey.
Shah Suleyman could not,
and lost his crown.
If he had not shown mercy to me...
...the crown would be his,
and the tomb would be mine.
However, I will not show mercy to him.
What about Ertugrul?
I have games for him, too.
He will taste death when the time comes.
Bey, is this bastard
the head of the Templars?
Yes, he is.
I cannot believe
Isadora has such a low-down uncle.
-Let me go and cut his head off!
-Wait, you big bear.
Bey, we can kill half of them
until we die.
And the other half will kill us.
Dogan is right, Bamsi.
It is not about dying or not.
If we die before we solve our nomad tent's
problem, it will be for nothing.
Bey, I do not understand
how they made us fall into their trap.
Do you think Isadora...
No. I think they found out
that Isadora was with us.
They must have made us
fall into the trap by using her.
Then, Isadora...
Then, her father Omer
who was Ibn al-Arabi's disciple...
Yes, him too.
My poor sister! Poor man!
Bastards!
Ertugrul!
Now, listen to me carefully!
I will not repeat this.
While you set off
towards my trap for you...
...Kurdoglu overthrew your father
and became the new bey.
From now on, he is
the new owner of the Kayi's marquee.
Your father, your mother, Gundogdu...
...and everybody from your family
is in Kurdoglu's hands now.
And of course,
your loved one, Sultan Halime!
Kurdoglu you traitor!
The real traitor is you, Ertugrul!
Your father lost his crown because of you!
I will bring your order down!
Neither your power nor your lifetime
will suffice for that.
I will fight your order
with all the power I have!
As for my lifetime...
...those of my generation
will root out the crusaders.
Ertugrul, if you surrender...
...I will let your family
and Sultan Halime live.
What do you want?
Arabi's ark.
Bey, what is this bastard saying?
It was a secret that nobody knew
except Halime and me.
How can he know?
Is what he's saying true, Bey?
It is.
I would not have told you
even if I knew where it was.
I know you do.
-How?
-I know everything.
I will never tell you!
I told you he would never give up, sir.
We need to get out of here, Bey!
-If Kurdoglu took hold of the tent...
-He will kill everybody.
The beys would not allow that.
What do we do now, Bey?
We have to go to the tent immediately.
Give me your blessings.
You have our blessings, Bey.
These are all traitors.
-Traitors!
-Let go of me!
Let go of our bey!
Let go of him!
Let me go!
The people of Kayi!
What is this outburst?
What kind of rebellion is this?
What kind of tactlessness is this?
I saved you from the traitor beys.
You did not say anything to the bey
who has been harming you for so long.
But you get hostile against the bey
who tries to bring you peace.
We will take our goods to Aleppo
and earn money.
We will take our flocks
to more abundant lands.
I've worked for everybody to be happy.
I've struggled for this to the death.
People of Kayi!
I forgive this traitor.
Now...
...as my last words...
...whoever creates a commotion
or tries to start a rebellion...
...I will hang him
in front of the nomad tent!
Go back to your work now!
You will pay for this one day!
I want Ertugrul alive!
I want him alive!
Master, thank God
I became a Muslim because of you.
Ertugrul!
Drop your sword!
Or your Alps will die.
Bey...
...we must escape today.
They will chain us all on the way.
They will kill us all like birds.
We can neither fight nor escape.
Shall we escape tonight?
I am positive, father.
But, how?
It is difficult to get out of here.
Say we escaped.
How are we going to save our women?
If we manage to escape...
...the ones who do not want
Kurdoglu will revolt.
If we can go to Uncle Korkut...
...we can overthrow Kurdoglu
with his Alps. The Alps are upset.
They want you, not Kurdoglu.
They do not say anything
because they do not want a civil var.
As for the women...
He cannot do anything to them.
He has to let them live
to use them against us.
What if they catch us?
If they catch us,
we will think about it then.
Where is Arabi's ark?
It is a secret between us.
It cannot be told.
Are you going to
save your family like this?
Is it more valuable than your family?
Talk.
One who cannot save a secret,
cannot save anybody.
That is enough, Titus.
Good.
Kurdoglu fulfilled his duty, Ertugrul.
Your family will be exiled in the morning.
Your Alp Turgut will escort them
all the way, of course.
You understand I mean the way to hell.
You are lying!
Your father thinks he will be going to
your uncle Korkut's tent with this family.
You are surprised that I know
where he will be going, are you not?
I do not need to lie to you.
The only thing I want is for you...
...to give me what I want in order
for your family to get there safely.
Do you understand?
I will never tell you where that ark is.
God damned Turk!
I will take you to the castle.
I will do to you and your Alps
what I did to Turgut.
I will throw your loved ones' corpses
into your dungeon!
You will live together
with their rotten flesh.
Until the time you become my knight.
And then, you will take me to Arabi's ark.
Sir...
Are you really going to
take them to the castle?
Set off now and bring the queen.
Let the game begin.
Kurdoglu will not leave the throne
in the nomad tent, mother.
Shah Suleyman
must be thinking of a solution.
I wish Bey Ertugrul came
as soon as possible.
He would save us all.
We must find a solution
until my Ertugrul comes.
Kurdoglu will want to kill us
with his men on the way to the tent.
It may be Alp Turgut.
Turgut will not kill us.
He cannot.
I saw him entering Kurdoglu's tent.
He is at his service.
Selcan...
Heaven forbid.
Ertugrul will surely come on time.
You will see that tomorrow is another day.
Hopefully.
If my Turgut attempts to do this...
...you know that
it is my duty to take his life.
Get out of our way!
Move, man!
We will pass!
Come and move me, then.
God will give you an important duty.
Of course, master.
One of your brothers is in trouble.
You will help him.
You will save him
from the hands of persecutors.
He will be your brother of faith
in both worlds.
You will serve Islam together with him.
Of course, master.
I will do whatever I can with God's help.
I brought you greetings from Ibn al-Arabi.
Just like the old days, Bey.
I had three Alps back in the day.
I also have three Alps now.
One of them is hunting. Ertugrul.
One of them is by my side. Gundogdu.
And one of them is me.
I have three Alps
who can take all kinds of risks for you.
It is no less.
You saved the nomad tent
from falling apart...
...and kept it in unity for years.
Who knows what you will do
with your three Alps, Bey.
I did so many bad things to you.
But you should know that
I am not the same person anymore.
Forgive me
for the bad things I did to you.
Nobody broke my heart
as much as Turgut did.
My only worry is Turgut for the moment.
As for the things you did...
...may God punish you.
I am already being punished.
I paid for all the things I did.
I just want to have your blessing.
Give me your blessing before I die.
You have it.
You have my blessing.
I hope my hands
that whipped you get broken.
I hope my hands get broken.
Halime...
Please forgive me.
Welcome to our nomad tent.
You are this nomad tent's daughter now.
We are sister-in-laws now.
Thank you, Selcan Hatun.
Thank you.
I did so many bad things to you, as well.
I broke your heart so much.
Give me your blessing.
I forgot all the disappointments
in my heart.
You did it because you did not want
the order of the tent be broken.
Be at ease.
You have my blessing.
Thank you.
My Christian name was Claudius.
My master Arabi
named me Omer after I became Muslim.
My master said
"You will be an Alp to Ertugrul...
...if you want to serve Islam
and be forgiven for your past sins."
Why did you become a Muslim?
I was given the duty of
killing Ibn al-Arabi and take the ark.
When I went there to kill him,
I almost died myself.
But Hazrat Ibn al-Arabi
helped me even though he knows it.
And I found health.
His mercy impressed me a lot.
God forgive my sins.
But the Templars...
...made your Alp Turgut suffer so much.
I just saw the difference.
Bey, are we going to believe
what he said?
What can we do other than believing a man
who brought Arabi's greetings and prayers?
What if he is lying, Bey?
He killed so many Alps of ours.
He said himself
that he had set a trap for Arabi.
Is it possible for an evil man like this
find the right path just like that?
We cannot now which dark souls
God's light will enlighten.
Think about Kurdoglu.
We would pray
with him together in the nomad tent.
You are right, Bey.
Alps!
Anybody there?
What is it?
My father.
Check him out for God's sake.
Call the midwives.
Bey...
I will keep an eye on him anyway.
Bamsi is right
after all the things Turgut did.
Bey, do you think we should have killed
Turgut in the first place?
What if he does anything to them
like this bastard said?
Do not think bad things like that!
Let us set off after the meal.
We must arrive the nomad tent
before sunrise.
-Yes, Bey.
As for Omer...
...keep an eye on him
until we hear his story from Arabi.
Be cautious about him.
What if he is up to something else?
What do you mean?
That ark matter.
What if it is a trick again?
So, where is the ark, Ertugrul Bey?
So, you know about the ark like that
jackal whom they call Grandmaster.
Not only him. Cardinal Thomas
is also after that ark.
They hate each other.
But they would do anything for that ark.
Are they not on the same path?
The Pope is scared of the Templars' power.
And the Templars are trying to convince
Emperor Frederick to Crusades...
...by using the Pope.
Blood politics, as in everywhere.
I tempted so many innocent Christians
in this ugly game.
As many as the
number of Muslims I killed.
My sheikh show me God's way
to clean myself off the blood in my hands.
May God protect me from depraving.
Turgut.
I should have smashed your head and fed
the birds with it when I first caught you.
You must be thankful
to my brother Ertugrul.
Drop the swords.
Drop the sword.
It will be a long way tomorrow.
Are you going to come with us tomorrow?
Yes.
We will have a long way.
Gundogdu!
Enough!
It is over.
So, this is it, Bey.
We will go for our exile like lambs
who are about to be slaughtered.
Nothing is over yet, Wild Demir.
I will not be scared of anything
as long as Ertugrul is out there.
Put them in the cage.
My mother. My life.
My mother
who sacrificed her life for us.
I was arrogant. I broke hearts.
I mostly went against you.
Forgive me.
My beautiful eyed girl.
I never had a daughter.
I always loved you like my daughters.
I cherished you.
You have my blessing.
Do not ever worry.
Now, be at ease.
Tomorrow is another day.
Every dark night has a dawn.
Hopefully.
Ertugrul...
Ertugrul!
What if they got out, Bey?
Let us wait for a while, Dogan.
I will go down the nomad tent
to check it out if nobody comes out.
I am scared to go to his marquee.
Do his eyes scare you too, Karabudak?
His eyes, his words, even his breath.
What did we do, Kutlu?
Kurdoglu...
...you will die in such a way that...
...the world will be talking about
your carcass, not your throne.
Take them!
Get out.
Kurdoglu is trying to get us out silently
because he is scared of the reactions.
You rely on the cage.
Not the cage. I rely on myself.
You are so brave
while my hands and feet are tied up.
What was your courage
and mercy good for?
You lost your throne.
You will surely pay for this betrayal.
However, what I wonder is that...
...while our lifetimes
are coming to an end...
...why betrayal?
Why?
Oh, Suleyman.
I was braver than you.
I was more clever than you.
I worked so hard
for my nomad tent for years.
I fought a lot
just for you to gain victories.
Then I thought to myself...
..."Why is he the Bey, and not me?"
"Why is he the bey of Kayis,
and not me?"
But it was me
who did everything, Suleyman.
It was me.
Me!
Kurdoglu, words and weapons
would be no good for you.
You have the illness of
Adam's son Qabil...
...who killed his brother.
Qabil also killed his brother
thinking "Why him, but not me?".
Do not forget that elder brothers die,
but Qabils die a thousand times.
Your reign is over, Suleyman.
You cannot deceive me with these words.
Alps!
Take him!
You know what you have to do, Judas.
I do, Bey.
Kill Suleyman the last.
I want him to witness his family's death.
Yes, Bey.
Father!
We will be strong
and give them strength, Bey.
Hang on, girls.
You were strong until now.
Let us leave here
in the way that makes Suleyman Shah proud.
Ertugrul will come and save us.
He will never leave us like this,
no matter what.
Let us stand by our family.
We have our orders, Bey.
You will not come together on the way.
My father is coming.
Is everybody alright?
We are, Bey. Do not worry.
We will be better
as long as we have you as our leader.
Dundar...
Dundar, son...
Dundar!
Let me go! My son...
Dundar...
Son... Do not touch me!
-Is everything ready?
-Everything is ready, Bey.
Do not show mercy
if anybody causes trouble.
Yes, Bey.
Single out Halime Sultan.
She will stay in the nomad tent.
-No!
-What?
-Halime!
Kurdoglu, what are you doing?
She is my daughter-in-law.
The decision was about
you and your family.
Halime is not family yet.
Kurdoglu, that is enough already.
You got what you wanted.
Halime is coming with us.
Do you not have any amount of
shame, honor and pride, Kurdoglu?
He will use Sister Halime
to capture Ertugrul.
You should have used that wit of yours
before setting me traps with your father.
Kurdoglu, I swear
I will nail your head to my spear...
...and show it
to everybody in the nomad tent.
This is a word from Suleyman Shah!
Pass my greetings to Korkut Bey.
If he attempts to come at me
with his 300 or 400 Alps...
...I will deem his nomad tent
a place for booty.
Take Halime Sultan back.
Mother!
Sisters, give me your blessings!
My girl...
I will kill you with my own hands.
I will put your carcass
in the nomad tent square!
I will kill you, Kurdoglu!
Alps, may God speed you.
Move!