Episode 17 will start after 12:15 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Do you want to kill me?
Do it.
Do it. Otherwise
accept that I am your brother.
Brother?
Brother.
Kill him!
Drink this. You will feel better.
Kneel if you want your magic water.
Turgut!
Bey! Turgut!
Pigs!
Bastards!
How could you do this
to my brothers?
He is alive.
Thankfully, brother Turgut is alive!
We must take them to the tent.
Ertugrul is seriously wounded.
The Crusaders' sword cannot cut him.
There must be a reason.
Brother, there is blood
on all over Turgut's body!
But he does not have a wound!
-Take a look!
-Move aside!
Bey, how could they do this to you?
Bey! I will take your revenge!
I will pull their lungs out
and feed vultures with them.
He lost blood. Take this off!
Take it off.
Where did these bastards hit?
I cannot find your wound!
Brother! God, keep me sane.
Where are these villains?
Brother Turgut...
Are you alright, brother?
Did you do this to Ertugrul Bey?
Brother Turgut!
I was not devastated this much even when
the Mongols killed my family.
Say that you did not do it!
Brother Turgut!
Turgut!
I will hurt you so much that
nobody will scream like that!
Turgut!
God, do not take my live
before I take these bastards' lives!
Turgut!
Kill all of them!
Attack!
Judas!
Turgut!
Ertugrul.
My brother.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
We are the messengers of
Alaeddin Keykubat...
...the ruler of the Great Seljuk State.
We want to see your Bey
Suleyman Shah.
Welcome. Welcome to our lands.
We will let Suleyman Shah know.
Thank you.
You should keep the loops tighter,
or it will break up.
And keep your dye solid
if you want a neat pattern.
Go on with your smiling face.
They will get spoiled in no time.
Sisters...
You listen to Sister Gokce,
right, Selcan?
Go away, Kurdoglu!
Where is Gundogdu?
They went to find customers
for the flock.
Are you sure?
They made a deal with Tatos Harput.
I hope he is not up to something
behind our backs.
What on earth is this?
Who are these man?
The Seljuk commander Ersogun Bey.
The storm is near if he came here.
His father died, but his sister
is still troubling us.
Let us see how this ends.
If we have one more trouble
because of her...
You will do what you did to Liva?
Halime must not die
as easily as that women did.
Bey, Sultan Alaeddin Keykubat's messenger
would like to see you.
Bring him in.
Suleyman Shah is waiting for you.
-Your weapon.
-No need for that.
Welcome, brother.
Welcome to our land.
Thank you, Suleyman Shah.
Thankfully, we are
seeing each other again.
Thankfully.
Come here, brother. Please.
I see that both the tent
and you are very well, Suleyman Shah.
Thankfully.
We overcame a lot of troubles.
I know all of them.
One of these troubles
was from the shahzades.
We know very well
the problem with Kara Toygar.
Kara Toygar caused so much trouble,
Ersegun Bey.
I hope Sultan Allaaddin will not
send another Kara Toygar...
...for the young shahzade.
Well, well, well.
Kurdoglu, the brave warrior
of the battlefields.
Your mouth is as sharp as your sword.
This matter is finished for our Sultan.
Especially after he found out about
what Ertugrul Bey did in Aleppo.
Ertugrul Bey protected the Islamic world
from a big war.
Everybody in Konya talks about
how a big hero Ertugrul Bey is.
Sultan Alaeddin would not
send you here for no reason.
I hope nothing is wrong.
It is a state secret, Kurdoglu.
I cannot say anyone
other than Suleyman Shah.
Unless he sees fit.
Let us talk alone, Kurdoglu.
Nobody can even milk a cow in this tent
without Kurdoglu's permission, Suleyman.
I will make you realize this, too.
What is the matter that is so important?
Suleyman Shah, the Islamic world
has hard times ahead.
The fierce breath of the Mongol thugs
started to cause pain in Anatolia.
We must stop this monster.
Otherwise, they will destroy
everywhere they pass through.
Nobody knows their banditry
more than we do.
The Mongols caused great distress to us...
...when our unity and welfare
broke down with factions .
Sultan Alaeddin
seeks for alliance because of that.
How so?
An alliance with the Ayyubids,
Suleyman Shah.
Thank God for all this.
That was what we needed,
Ersagun Bey.
Unity and solidarity.
Your young son Ertugrul paved the way
for Sultan Alaeddin for this.
He sent both you and your son
his regards.
And some presents, if you accept.
Let them bring them in.
Soldiers! Bring them in!
Tell him I say thank you.
The seal for this alliance
will be a marriage.
Sultan Alaeddin wants to marry
the Damascene Queen Adilliye.
This is very accurate politics.
He gave the duty
to ask for the girl's hand to me.
The train that is brought for the wedding
waits in Aleppo.
What does he want from us?
Sultan wants help from Ertugrul Bey
and his Alps for the train to be set up.
And then, to come together with you and
your son to have a meal and talk.
I am honored by the Sultan's
request and invitation.
Ertugrul is on the way. I will send him
with you when he comes back.
Thank you, Suleyman Shah.
There is one more matter.
What is it?
Halime Sultan and Shahzade Yigit.
We were informed that
they stay in your tent.
The tent foamed up
like Euphrates's water again.
You have to find out what is going on.
If the Seljuk Sultan
sent a messenger to the tent...
...and shared a state secret,
it is clearly not good news.
Of course it is not.
Ertugrul is a hero now
for both the Seljuk and Aleppo.
The train in front of the door
is for presents.
Those generous presents
are for Ertugrul and his father.
While I prepare the tent's beys
for the seigniory of Gundogdu...
...you watch your girl.
Do not let her ally with his father
and go against me.
Do not worry. I will spoil every game
Suleyman Shah makes with Ertugrul.
Good.
They will come after me
like they did for my father.
Either to kill or to use.
Our father does not even have a tomb.
We cannot even go this tomb
and pray for him.
Do you think it will end
different for me, sister?
Ertugrul Bey
will protect you from everything.
Do not worry like this.
He does not even care if I die or not.
I will not let you suffer for me anymore.
It is enough.
You always suffered
since the day I was born.
You have been my sister,
my mother, my shoulder to cry on.
There should not be any more suffering.
You should be happy, too.
Let me go. I cannot live
between Ertugrul and you like an ulcer.
Yigit, what are you saying?
I will not let you two suffer.
Yigit...
Welcome, Halime Sultan.
Thank you, Sister Gokce.
I am sorry for your father.
God forgive his sins.
However, your brother...
He is also a shahzade.
We are worried about new troubles
that might come.
The Seljuk messenger...
I hope he is not the foreshadow
of new troubles.
Suleyman Shah waits for you
in the pavilion.
Speak of the devil...
The Seljuks are after me.
I will not stay here anymore.
They will leave my sister
and Ertugrul alone.
You can go to hell.
Ersagun, Sultan Alaeddin's messenger.
I brought you Sultan Alaeddin's regards.
Sultan is worried about
you and your brother's health.
Whenever he worries about our health,
it means trouble for us.
Sultan loves and respects you
because you are a noble Seljuk princess.
He made a mansion prepared
for your brother in Kayseri.
You will have servants.
They will do what is necessary
for our shahzade's education.
He wishes you to marry an emeer
and be happy.
If you see fit, of course.
I will think about the Sultan's offer
about my brother.
As to me...
...I plotted a different route
for me and my heart.
I want to spend the rest of my life
as this tent's daughter if they see fit.
Pass my regards
to my uncle Sultan Alaeddin.
Excuse me.
It is strange
that she wants to stay in your tent.
She has to be aware of the values
that have been granted to her.
You are a very brace child,
as your name suggests.
You will be Alps with Dundar
when he gets up.
When that time comes,
I will make your swords with my hands.
So, do not upset your sister, alright?
Also, just like he is the tent's girl,
you are the tent's brave man.
Sister?
Yigit...
What does the Sultan want from us?
Do not worry, Yigit.
He is not our enemy anymore.
See, Yigit?
That trouble has been overcome now.
After my father payed for it?
Ertugrul!
Akcakoca!
Hamza!
Ertugrul!
-Where is Akcakoca?
-Went up the mountain, Bey.
Let us carry him.
I will put firebrand on it.
Come on, come on!
Faster! Come on!
Yes, Bismillah!
Turgut?
Where is my Turgut?
-Bey may I come in?
-Come in.
What is going on?
They arrived, Bey.
Are my children alright?
Dogan, Bamsi and Afsin Bey
are wounded, Halime Ana.
And Ertugrul Bey...
-...is seriously wounded.
-What?
Halime!
Ertugrul!
Ertugrul.
How is he, Gundogdu Bey?
Not good at all, Sister Halime.
Not good at all.
Wild Demir, should we find Arabi?
I will let him know, Bey.
What happened, Dogan?
Bamsi? What happened?
Where is Turgut?
If anybody says that traitor's name
in this tent anymore...
...I will cut their tongue off!
Bamsi, what are you saying?
Do you hear what you say?
It was not the Crusaders
who put us in this situation.
It was your bastard husband.
He betrayed us.
You are lying! Turgut would never do that!
Lie!
Women out.
Help us, Shafi!
Gundogdu got me disappointed
whenever I got high hopes for him.
He brought his brother behind my back.
I should have known when Abdurrahman
brought news from Ertugrul.
He came as a trouble
when he was supposed to come dead.
Do not worry, Bey.
He will pay when the time comes.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My Turgut would give is life
for Ertugrul Bey.
How can this be, Halime Sultan?
You knew them.
They were so close.
How can this be?
Please tell me there is a catch to it.
I do not now, Aykiz.
But that castle is like hell.
You pray every day to die.
God, give my Ertugrul back to me.
Do not leave me without him.
Turgut would never do this to Ertugrul
even if they cut him into pieces.
What am I going to do now?
Aykiz, it is okay.
God...
Cry, my dear sister.
This is our fate.
I have been missing him for years
even when I was with him.
My beautiful sister.
Somebody showed up
the moment I thought I had him.
And now the Angel of Death
wants to take him.
Where there is life, there is hope.
Do not torture yourself.
If fate takes him from me...
...I will be in deep sorrow.
I will be devastated.
If I lose him, too after my father...
...every breath will mean death to me.
Do not do this, Gokce.
His brother Gundogdu saved him.
Now Arabi seeks cure for him.
There is nothing to do for us
other than praying.
Sister...
I cannot breathe without him.
Ertugrul!
Ibn al-Arabi is by his side.
Do not worry, he is in safe hands.
If anything happens to him...
...how can I live, Bey?
Be strong.
You the mother of not only
your children, but also the tent.
If you be devastated...
...how can I order
my young Alps to die?
I have a heart the size of a fist.
Strength, but how much longer, Bey?
I am going to his tent.
I will wait there.
Father, how are we going to
show our face to our people?
What if Turgut chose the wrong way
as they say?
How can we stay in this tent?
If they are telling the truth...
...it is my duty to hang Turgut's head
in the middle of the tent.
I loved him like he was my own son.
These are not the things
he would do, though.
We will stand upright and be patient.
Do you understand?
Let me give you good news, woman
May your brave man not fall down
May your shadowy big tree
Not be cut down
May your glorious water
That runs like blood
Not dry up
May the tips of your wings
Not break
May Al-Qadr not let you lean on
The despicable
Did Turgut do this?
I remembered the day Ertugrul found you
in the woods and brought here.
You were so hungry that...
...you ate the partridge he hunted raw.
I cherished you like my own sons.
Why?
You did not let us be in sorrow
for not having a mother.
But he...
I will make him pay in both worlds.
He will be punished.
The bishop to E-4.
One of my Cardinal friends
has told me once:
"Baphomet is the god that
the Templars worship to.
They deceive people.
Black magic and
all kinds of mischief come from them.
The satirical goats of
Sabbath witches guide them.
The ones who cannot defeat us
with their own strength...
...cannot bring us down
with various defamations, Thomas.
I only knew one person
who defeated you with his own strength.
And it is Ertugrul.
Your temple will not have
any value to me...
...as long as Ertugrul lives,
my dear friend Petruchio.
Cardinal, his majesty...
...are you alright?
I have had better days, Eftelya.
You must read this demon's letter
to the Pope at all costs.
What will we do
if he wrote something bad about us?
It would be good to kill him before
the Council of the Templars gather up.
Yes, sir.
How did those damned Templars
tempt Turgut Alp?
They are the sneakiest enemy
we ever had.
They will not come to the battlefield.
They either lay an ambush
or sneak in disguise.
We are talking,
but what is the remedy, Bey?
How many more soldiers we will loose
and cry after them?
We have to stop this mischief
spreading from this castle.
Their mischief reach our tent...
...even when they are
beyond the Ayyubid border.
It has to be stopped, but how?
We must bring their castle
down on them.
Is this remedy, Bey?
Are we going to spend all our lives
with our swords put on?
They are sneaky, we are brave.
They are the winners, we are the losers.
Is that so?
There must be another way.
Yes, there must be another way.
Our people does not want war, Bey.
We are the Alps of the battlefields, Bey.
We cannot bring a castle down.
We have neither appropriate equipment
nor training for this.
Getting angry and making mistakes
would be unacceptable.
Karabudak is right.
We cannot bring that castle down.
However, we can hit them
with their own tricks.
How is it going to be, Gundogdu?
How are we going to manage to be
as vile and sneaky as them?
His body is as strong as his heart.
He did not give up.
Halime...
I am here, Ertugrul.
Let us not tire him much.
Alright, girls.
I will stay by Ertugrul's side.
You go back to work.
Come on, do not stay here.
Come on.
Ertugrul Bey is awake, Bey.
He is alright.
Thank God.
We do not have to be
sneaky and vile, Kurdoglu.
A little courage and a little intelligence
would be enough.
And of course, faith.
If one of them is lacking...
...it means that
this is not a tent anymore.
Thankfully, we have faith, Bey.
Our bodies and hearts are strong.
We respect Gundogdu's intelligence
who has a Bey's qualities.
Let us listen to him.
Listen, so that
we would broaden our horizons.
Thank you, uncle.
Thank you.
I say let us make these Templars come down
to the plains from the mountains.
Otherwise, we cannot even
budge the door of their castle.
The Templars are everywhere.
Like mosquitos.
If we do not bring their castle
down on them...
...if we do not drain that swamp...
...it will not matter
if we kill all the mosquitos.
I say, we must make
the Seljuks and the Ayyubids ally.
If we do this, we can bring that castle
down on them with their help.
And when we do this,
our attack becomes a victory.
Gundogdu Bey is right, Bey.
Two heads are better than one, Bey.
This brave man is telling the truth.
Kurdoglu turned out to be right
as usual.
Gundogdu, who talked about
Aleppo once...
...found our cure again.
He guided us
with his intelligence and valor.
Thank you, Karabudak.
Gundogdu...
...attacked us with his Alps.
And Ertugrul?
He was breathing.
We will not have peace
as long as that Turk breathes.
I will find out what is going on
from Kurdoglu.
We will talk in the morning.
I was worried about you.
Here I came.
Welcome, Turgut.
I am sorry, I said it by mistake.
"Judas".
Did you succeed?
He was lying there in a pool of blood.
He and his friends.
But he was still breathing.
My duty will not finish
as long as Ertugrul lives.
If you take this medicine this much...
...you will have nightmares
while awake.
And then die in the worst way.
Isadora...
My beautiful princess.
You are too inquisitive.
This is not a good thing
for such a lady like you at all.
Bey...
I would like to escort
Alaeddin's dowry train if you see fit.
Father, I intend to enjoy
the best of both worlds.
How?
We will certainly gain
Sultan Alaeddins's respect.
But the most important thing
is the Templars.
It is clear that the Templars
will want to prevent this marriage.
-They will probably ambush the train.
-Meaning?
Meaning, the hunter becomes the hunted.
It is a very good opportunity
to both put them in their place...
...and increase our tribe's reputation.
So, I would like to escort the train
if you see fit.
Alright.
God help you.
Amen.
Thank you, Bey.
Mother Hayme.
Come in, my girl.
Mother Hayme...
You are very tired. Have some rest.
I can sit by Ertugrul's side.
Do not leave Dundar alone.
It is so hard to be a mother, Halime.
You will understand
when you have children one day.
Whenever a thorn pricks their foot...
...your heart turns into a fire ground.
I am leaving Ertugrul in your hands.
Do not worry, Mother Hayme.
You said you would not give me to them
even the whole world came together.
And you did not.
Do not go and leave me alone, Ertugrul.
The day when I accepted death
instead of being another man's woman...
...these words made me cling to life.
I did not give up.
And you do not give up, either.
Come back to me, Ertugrul.
I will not give up on you
as long as your breath.
So, they hid the marriage of Sultan
Alaeddin and the Damascene Queen from me.
We knew about it
before the dowry train set off from Konya.
This marriage would not fit
into our best interests, Kurdoglu.
And yours, either.
That train will not arrive for the Queen.
I will not let this happen.
We know the train's every move.
That the Sultan
wanted help from the Kayis.
Everything.
But there is one man who troubles me.
Ertugrul. He cannot take the train there.
He is seriously wounded.
It is a miracle that he even lives
with that wound.
Turgut Alp opened the strongest hole
I have ever seen in his body.
However, sometimes
God does not allow someone to die.
Whoever goes, will die with the messenger.
The train is our business.
You strengthen your power in the tent.
We will take care of the rest.
There will not be a better opportunity
to overturn Suleyman Shah...
...while Ertugrul is in this situation.
I cannot bear anymore, either.
Each passing day is to my detriment.
Sooner or later, they will find out
I am cooperating with you.
You are right.
I am relieved to see that we think alike.
But first, you will
turn two people over to me.
Ibn al-Arabi and the young Shahzade.
Ibn al-Arabi will set off tomorrow.
There will be nobody else
except his dervish with him.
-Good.
-As for the young Shahzade...
...do not worry.
Yigit will come to you himself.
Do not say it. I know that
you trust me most in this tent.
But do not say the duty
your father gave to you even to me.
Selcan, what are you saying?
There is nobody except us here.
Walls have ears.
May God protect you.
You cannot say no
to Sultan Alaeedin...
...when he sends a messenger
to the tent and requests from your father.
However, what is important is that
your father gave you this duty.
You see how everything has changed,
do you not?
You fought with knights
and defeated them.
You saved your brother and the Alps
and brought them to the tent.
You found a good customer
for the flock.
You brought trust and gold
to our tent.
You know what this means,
do you not?
It is for you, woman.
For our future baby if God permits.
But as I said, do not let
even the Alps know where you are going.
And what are you going to do.
God forbid.
I am scared that something happens to you
if that ominous infidel hears of  it.
What about my uncle?
You must watch out
especially for Kurdoglu.
It would be good if you found out
if he is a traitor with a little trick.
He will be your closest ally
on this way to be the Bey.
One who goes on the wrong way
does not find the right way ever.
What is in your mind?
I will tell my uncle
about the duty that was given to me.
But I will mistake him.
You will lure him to make a mistake.
If my uncle is a traitor...
...he will tell the news to the Templars
and make them ambush me.
If that happens, I will shed him blood.
Otherwise, he will be my
biggest ally on the way to be the Bey.
My daughter!
-Father!
-You must not come here.
It is very dangerous.
I found a way to get you out of here.
May God heal you
with the quality of his name "ash-Shaafi".
Amen.
He is healed with the permission of God.
Keep an eye on him at all times.
We have to go now.
I wish you would not leave us alone.
Do not worry. This brave man
has so many protectors by his side.
I will give you something before we leave.
You will give it to Ertugrul
if he heals before I come back.
Do not you ever look inside it.
I will protect it at the cost of my life.
Good thinking.
Only the Kayis can do this.
And you can freed this young man
from the effects of the drugs.
I will come back with the Kayis
and get you out of here.
If my sheikh Ibn al-Arabi
is in the tent as they say...
...tell him that I did my duty.
I remembered him every night
in my prayers.
God help you, my daughter.
Goodbye, father.
This is not a farewell.
Because I will be back.
What are we going to do
with Aykiz?
She clearly sees us as enemy.
What if she is on the same side
with her traitor husband?
What if they were
spreading news about the tent?
-Woah!
-Why are  you surprised?
Would you believe that
Turgut would stab Ertugrul Bey?
I would shove down your throat.
Yes! See?
By the way,
how can we know if Aykiz is a traitor?
We will go and hold Turgut first.
We will hang him with hooks
smaller than my nails...
...which stretch his from head to toe.
We will chop his white flesh
and cook black roast from it.
And we will put it in front of Aykiz.
What if she eats it?
Then, she will wish Sister Selcan
whipped her again.
She will think that pain is much lighter
compared to what I will do.
You must help me if you want God
to forgive your sins.
I will do what is necessary, milady.
-You must get me out of this castle.
-But... you cannot come back again.
I will not be alone when I do.
Where are you going?
To the Kayi Tent.
To find Ertugrul Bey.
And Aykiz.
Turgut's wife.
Alps, may I come in?
Come in, sister.
I have been loving him
since I was born into this black world.
He was my brave man whom I loved
since the moment I opened my eyes.
I said "Those black mountains
are no good to me after  you are gone."
I said, "May those highlands be my tomb."
I said, "May those cold waters
be my blood."
I said "May your horse be my shroud
if I ever ride it."
I said "May the colorful snake bite me
if I love another man after you."
I said "May my life
be a sacrifice for you."
However, if he did what you are saying...
...you should know that
it is my duty to take Turgut's life.
If you go after that bastard
and not take me with you...
...you should know that
I will not give you my blessing ever.
Turgut Alp.
They were giving him something like
potion in the Templars' castle.
A blue liquid.
They were torturing him heavily.
There is a catch...
...but what?
We need to go, Suleyman Shah.
We could not welcome you well,
sorry for that.
No problem.
When will we see you again?
I will be back... if God permits.
We will be waiting.
May God protect you.
Always pray for us, please.
My prayers are always with you.
Thank you.
Soldier, good luck.
Good luck.
Soldier... good luck.
Good luck, soldier.
Hamza, let the Alps I chose say goodbye to
their families and ask for their blessing.
Let them smell their children
if they have and be ready.
Understood, Bey.
What is it, Gundogdu?
You look like you are going hunting.
Do you ever miss anything, uncle?
They did not name me "Kurdoglu"
without a reason.
What is this preparation for?
Or are you going to hide this
from me, as well...
...like you hid you were
going to take Ertugrul?
I trust you completely, uncle.
First my father, then to you.
What is going on, then?
What are you going to do
with your Alps?
Alaeddin's messengers are going to come.
I will meet them at Busra Hill
near Aleppo and take them to Damascus.
Alaeddin wants to marry
the Damascene emeer's niece.
They will ask for blessing.
Well, well, well.
The big alliance.
So they threw you
onto the line of fire again.
If the Templars heard of this,
it will be very difficult for you.
You did the right thing
to hide this even from your Alps.
We have to hide everything until we
find out who the traitor among us is.
Do you have anything else to tell me?
I only want your prayers, uncle.
Nothing else.
My prayers are
always with you, Gundogdu.
Amen.
Go to Busra Hill and lay an ambush.
I will go to Damascus on another way.
If anybody from the Templars'
or Kurdoglu's men come, behead them.
Understood, Bey.
Let us see
if my uncle is a traitor or not.
I heard that you sent a troop
to have Ibn al-Arabi taken, sir.
You have a more important duty, Titus.
I did not want to send you
for just an old man and a dervish.
What is it, sir?
Sultan Alaeddin.
He is sending a messenger
to have the blessings to marry...
...the Damascene emeer's niece
with the support of the Kayis.
Neither the messenger, nor the train
or Gundogdu who escorts them...
...should come back.
Understood, sir.
As to you, Eftelya.
Tonight, you will take the report
that the Cardinal wrote.
After you make sure
he falls into sleep with this drug...
...we will read that report line by line.
If he wrote lies about us,
he will never wake up.
Then, you will go to Damascus.
If things go wrong...
...you will do what is necessary...
...to prevent a bride to go
from the palace to Konya.
Peace be upon you, brothers.
The chest you are carrying.
The one with the relic in it
which no mortal has seen before.
Will you give it yourself,
or shall we take it by force?
Do not extend your hand
to take things from people.
You can only take it if you know that
it is God Almighty who gives in reality.
In that case, only take the amount
that your knowledge sees appropriate.
Drop that carpetbag!
Where is the relic?
Here.
If you want to learn,
I can tell you with my mouth.
If you want to pull it out from me...
...my heart is as close as your sword
to you, son.
Leave the old man alone.
Go on your way.
Silence that man!
I must have fallen asleep.
You were awake the whole night.
Go and get some rest.
I will stay by his side.
I was with Ertugrul.
Thankfully, he is good, as well.
Thank God.
Go and get some sleep.
Any news from Kurdoglu?
No.
Gundogdu's trick
will reveal everything before the sunset.
I am praying. I hope all the things
we have thought of Kurdoglu...
...were nothing but delusions.
Hopefully, Bey.
Hopefully.
If the traitor among us is him...
...I will make him pay
in the most severe way possible.
But if he is not...
...I will ask my blood brother
to forgive me for all my delusions.
I wronged you.
Forgive me.
Allow me to be your dervish.
Give my life for you and your way.
Sister, go and help them with the rugs.
Did Gundogdu try to lure you?
He did.
He thinks I will denounce it
to the Templars.
He will see that he is mistaken.
And then, he will bring peace
to the tent with his uncle.
There is a lot of doubt about us.
Mother Hayme?
Do not worry.
Those doubts will also go away.
How?
Spring came to the tent,
are you not aware?
Just smile a little.
Stop the nonsense. I said how?
Today, the traitor in the tent
will be revealed.
Watch what happens after that.
Where will he be revealed?
By the side of Ertugrul's corpse.
Do not worry.
Have a seat.
Is everything ready?
Yes, Bey.
Do not worry.
Everything will be very easy.
Good.
Open it.
You will have the rest
when Ertugrul dies.
What are you going to do
with all this gold?
The biggest flock of the tent
will be mine, Bey.
Stupid.
You are the biggest ox in that flock,
but you are not aware of it.
Well, well, well.
The daughter of the tent is taking a walk.
Sultan Hatun would probably
not bother to talk to us.
She does not see this fit...
...but she confuses people saying "I am
the daughter of this tent from now on."
Selcan Hatun.
I would not even think of
one of the things you said.
However, you had hard times.
I refrain from breaking your heart.
One would think you were an angel.
If you are so much concerned about
other people's hearts...
...think about what you have done
to my sister.
What could I have possibly
done to your sister?
I have neither said a bad word
nor threw an evil glance to her.
We know loose girls like you that have
been brought up in the palace.
We have seen a lot of countries.
There are so many girls like you.
It is obvious that you spend your time
in palaces, Selcan Hatun.
I told this to you
the first day you came here.
"This tent is not for you.
Go to your own homeland."
I turned out to be right.
We suffered so much because of you.
Now you came back.
You constantly hurt my sister.
I am with the man I love
who loves me back, Selcan Hatun.
I have not done anything to your sister,
and I would never do.
What about his father?
What about Suleyman Shah?
He told Ertugrul to marry Gokce
as part of his will.
Ertugrul Bey would never do anything
other than what his father says.
If you have not still learned that...
...you are either blind or ill-minded.
Or really a stupid girl in love.
I am the girl Ertugrul Bey loves,
Selcan Hatun.
I left behind everything I have
and came to him.
And I am this tent's girl
until he tells me to go.
I came because he told me to.
I can go if he tells me to.
But this will only happen by his word.
Not by your or Suleyman Shah's word.
Make no mistake about it, Selcan Hatun.
It is obvious that
we will not get rid of you...
...until he sends you away,
or until Ertugrul comes to grief.
And he will come to grief soon, anyway.
Good luck, son.
Thank you, father.
Good luck, niece.
Thank you, uncle.
Alright. Bismillah.
This is an important duty, Bey.
If he succeeds, the way to be a bey
will open for Gundogdu.
He showed everybody that
he is a son fitting a father like you.
What do you want
from my son, Kurdoglu?
I see the future of the tent
in his hands.
If I see you are mistaken,
I support my niece.
I open his eyes
to see what is right or wrong.
What are you saying?
You know me, Bey. I do not lie.
I am a frank man.
You harnessed the wrong horse.
Do you know when?
The day when you sent Ertugrul
to Aleppo as your messenger.
This is the day, now.
I am not dead yet, Kurdoglu!
The future of the tent
does not rely on your lifetime.
I do not want anything for myself.
We are all meant to die someday.
I have common sense and it does not
let me leave this tent...
...for the sake of which I have lost
my woman and children...
...to a rascal's hands
who runs after women.
And this is the point.
Are your knights ready?
Yes, sir.
They are waiting for me in Hara.
Good. I want you to go after Ertugrul
with Judas, after that.
Finish him in his weakest moment.
I want this handled before the
Council of the Templars come together.
Yes, sir.
Thank you for the ride, uncle.
Isadora. I got Windmill prepared for you.
It is a meek and clever horse.
Thank you, uncle.
Enjoy the ride, Isadora.
We will not be defeated as long as
we have men like you...
...who think about
the future of the tent.
Thank you.
Karabudak?
What do you think?
You are right, Bey.
You are a very experienced warrior
and server to the tent.
We trust every word
that comes out of your mouth.
However...
However?
He cannot say it out of his respect.
Let me say it myself.
It is clear that
you have talked about this.
When it comes to Suleyman Shah,
we have to think twice.
You know it best, Kurdoglu.
You have talked all night like crickets.
So, what is the result?
Why do you want Gundogdu
to be the bey, but not you?
I do not have my eyes
on any seat or gold.
If I did, I would have done it
when we were having the hardest times.
But, why Gundogdu?
What is your in for it?
You will understand
when your pockets will be full of gold...
...after the selling of the flocks.
Our people who have lost
their children, husbands and flocks...
...because of Ertugrul and his father
will also understand.
Only people who suffer
know what pain means.
Our tent is full of widows
mothers without children.
Do you want a bey...
...who confuses people
with dreams of war...
...or a bey who knows what to do
and revives his tent.
Is it about the sword
being strong in its sheath...
...or coming out of its sheath
and suffer pain after pain?
Bey, are you alright?
I am.
I am, but...
...nothing will be the same
anymore, Hayme.
Kurdoglu opened my eyes.
He woke me up.
What are you saying, Bey?
Even if it is your son...
...when it is time to be the bey...
...arrogance shows itself.
Things that we have heard
from the Oghuz sagas...
...have been going on around us,
but we were not aware of them.
But now, I see everything more clearly.
What do you see?
When the bey gets older...
...and arrogance shows itself...
...storms in the tent will not calm ever.
Maybe it is best to abdicate
when everything is settled down.
The marriage between the Damascene Queen
and Sultan Alaeddin is very important.
Sultan Alaeedin declared that for the
sake of strengthening the alliance...
...between the Ayyubids and Seljuk...
...he will declare the child of this
marriage his heir to the throne.
I saw Sultan Alaeddin's
presents of nine.
The nine horses and the nine slaves.
Who knows what else are inside them.
It is worthy of Seljuk.
It is a hard but accurate decision.
I understand now why you wanted to keep
the train going to Damascus a secret.
But if those infidels find out about it...
...they will do everything
to prevent this.
Thank you, brother.
What about Kurdoglu?
I trust my uncle completely.
But my father and Ertugrul
feel suspicious.
I understood there was a problem...
...when Suleyman Shah
wanted to speak with me alone.
You should know that
I have fought Kurdoglu before.
He is one of the best warriors
I have seen. He is brave.
And he has been serving your father
for such a long time.
Your uncle will overcome
your trick blamelessly.
Thank you, Ersagun Bey.
We will set off whenever you want.
We are ready, but first
let us have some meal.
We have a long way ahead of us.
Thank you. Altogether. Please.
Isadora...
Uncle...
Greetings.
Yes, my girl.
I am looking for Aykiz.
Aykiz?
I am her father. Who are you?
I am coming from the Templars' castle.
My name is Isadora Manzini.
I am
Grandmaster Petruchio Manzini's niece.
I brought news from Turgut Alp.
What do you mean she ran away?
Where could my niece go?
Why should he go?
She untied her horse
and ran away before letting us know, sir.
Damn it!
PLACE NEAR ALEPPO
BUSRA HILL
Bey, there is nobody coming.
We should go before the sunset.
We have a long way ahead of us.
You are right.
Let us go back.
Tell the Alps to get prepared.
We should not make Gundogdu Bey wait.
So, Kurdoglu is not a traitor.
Oh my...
We accused him wrongly.
What did you say?
Never mind.
Get prepared. Let us set off.
Where is she?
My daughter
knows everything about you.
What kind of murderer and evil you are...
She knows everything about you.
How?
How did she find out you were alive?
You will never know.
I found out about Ibn al-Arabi's secret.
I do not need you anymore.
You need to be a human first
in order to know that secret.
I need neither you nor your daughter.
My daughter will prevent you
from gaining a victory.
I bear witness that there is no god...
...there is only God.
Intended for Turgut, realized by me.
Damn it.
Gokce...
We will spend the night here.
Riza, tell our men
that they can have a rest...
...after they take the necessary measures.
Yes, Bey.
Take the horses to the creek down there.
Keep the horses that are the Sultan's
present away from the others.
Yes, Bey.
We always take
our brothers' revenge, Titus.
We, too.
This war has just started, Gundogdu.
You are right.
But do not forget...
...even if only one man
from our breed survives...
...you will not have peace.