Episode 12 will start after 11:51 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
I have had a delicious
feast prepared for you.
In the honor of our little Shahzade's
liberation from the Templars...
...and of course, of the Seljuk
and Ayyubid Dynasty's union.
Here you are.
Faster, faster!
Please, help yourselves.
I shouldn't have sent
Ertugrul alone to the palace.
He wouldn't listen, Bey.
He does what he wants to do.
Tell me about it, Dogan.
When we were little..
Hey man, when did you grow up?
-Did I hear a mosquito buzz, or what?
-So, when you were little...
We used to herd the flocks
at that time. Three jackals came.
So crazy, their eyes were furious.
Like a well without an end,
they were looking so dangerous.
They caught the calf.
And this Ertugrul...
We said: “Give up, they have gone”.
He did not listen.
For five days and nights
he kept running after those jackals...
...in the freezing cold of winter.
So we said, “This is Ertugrul”.
He did not give up...
...and found those jackals.
Suleyman Bey was so anxious.
When Ertugrul was back,
he appeared before Suleyman Bey.
His father said:
“Son, what have you done?”
Ertugrul Bey replied:
“Bey,” he said.
“Today three jackals come, take the calf.
They are rapacious, the other day they
will come to take their mother Sarikiz.
And before you know it
they become frequent visitors. ”
Why did you tell us this story?
Knowing what sacrifices
he made for the calf...
...I considered
what sacrifices he would make...
...for his comrade Turgut and
for his loved one Sister Halime.
So?
So, I am filled with comfort, brother.
Damn their conspiracies
and their states!
Based on our relations
in the past, I request you...
...to get off my
and my daughters' backs.
Al-Aqsa Mosque, Jerusalem
This temple is the Prophet Muhammad
and Umar bin Al-Khattab's gift...
...for us the Muslims.
This site is our virtue and honor.
Jerusalem is our heart
and our heart is Jerusalem.
For God's sake, El Fatiha.
Euzu billahi minesseytanirracim
Bismillahirrahmanirahim.
Fa la menna hu.
La ilaha illallah.
Illallah.
KAYI NOMAD TENTS
The time has come. Be quick.
Is everything all right?
Yes, sir. We are ready.
Good.
There is blood on your face, sir.
I came across an obstacle.
I cleared it out of the way.
You know what you are going to do.
You will wait for my sign.
We dragged the Alps
at the marquee and the bridge...
...to different directions.
You will enter the marquee with my sign.
You will come upon two guards
and the head of the marquee Rahman only.
Finish them off quietly and fast.
Whoever is in the marquee, kill them all.
Your target is...
...Suleyman Shah...
...and his wife Hayme.
You will not surrender the marquee
until the new Bey arrives and settles in.
Aye, sir.
Oh God, give me strength.
We have fallen into the blind shafts
in the dark nights of Aleppo, Aktolgali.
My heart is on fire.
What rain or river may quench this fire?
What weapon may be the
remedy for my despair...
...while the jackals prey on
my young gazelle, huh, Aktolgali?
Your participation in this
humble dinner I host in the honor of...
...our little Shahzade's
rejoining us, honored me.
I can read my prospective wife
Halime Sultan's happiness from her eyes.
Thank God, Nanny,
God has shown us this day.
Now if you excuse me, I want to
give a small gift to Halime Sultan...
...for accepting a pitiful servant
like me to be her husband.
I had this necklace brought
from India to give to the woman...
...I had been looking for one day.
That day is today.
What about my brother Ertugrul?
Halime...
...are you fine, daughter?
Your nose is bleeding.
Excuse me.
Do not go alone.
Leyla shall come with you.
It is not a serious thing.
I can handle it myself.
Forgive me, Ertugrul.
Forgive me.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Son, you look so sad. Hope nothing is bad.
The doors are being slammed on my face.
The remedy is getting far away from me.
The sky has turned into a cage
falling down on my chest.
The wise call your situation as “qabz”.
Sometimes God gives discomfort
to his devout servants.
Wisdom is the child of patience.
There is no tutor greater
than patience for a person.
The seed which is not willing to let
it's shell rot, can not bear fruits.
Son, do you know who Hizir is?
I have heard his holy name. I pray...
...to see him one day, to kiss
his hands and to get his blessings.
My mom always prays
for Hizir to be my companion.
Hizir was a soldier in
an army jihading for the sake of God.
The army got stucked in between somewhere.
Enemies on one side, extremely high
temperature and thirst on the other.
They were all going to die.
One of them had to risk death
to find water, for the others to be saved.
Whereas, in the state of despair,
the mind abandons the head.
The brave turns into a coward.
The strong's hands weaken, eyes go blind.
While others were talking
about who should go for water...
...Hizir started running.
He hit the road putting his life at stake.
He reached the water supply.
When he came back
with water people realized that...
...this water was
something of a different kind.
The water he brought
was the “Water of Life”.
Hizir found the water
people had been looking for ever.
Do you know what
the “water of life” is, son?
I do not know.
”Water of Life” is the water
which makes you immortal.
While this body is dying...
...the soul that drinks the
“Water of Life” becomes immortal.
“Water of Life” is the faith.
”Water of Life” is love, son, love!
It is the thing that turns a person
into a human, the dead into alive.
It takes a person closer to God.
So, what happened then?
When they realized that
the water was the “Water of Life”...
...they forgot about the danger
and started looking for it.
But none of them could find it.
Because the “Water of Life”
is a gift from God almighty...
...not for the ones who go after it,
but for the ones who want to reach God...
...with love and faith
by serving all God's creatures.
You reach the “Water of Life”
by serving the people.
Get up. Shake off the soil on you.
Resuscitate like
how a man arises from dead.
Do not sit and wait for Hizir to come.
Be the Hizir for the people in despair.
Bring the “Water of Life” to
the ones who are thirsty for faith.
Your mission is this.
“Surely with that hardship comes more
ease” (Inshirah Surah, verse 6)
Surely with that hardship comes more ease.
Alps! You two go
and continue to guard there.
What did you do about
the guards on the bridge?
Did you clear out marquee?
Yes Bey. I sent out my Alp.
We also sent out the ones on the bridge.
There are only two guards at the gate.
This task must be
finished tonight, Alpargo.
Tonight it must be finished.
It will, Bey.
Otherwise, the Kayis
will vanish off the face of the earth...
...like a seed in the camel's rumen.
Fire! Fire!
If I am after his position as a Bey...
What is going on?
-No need to panic.
-Why do you care about my panic?
Check out what's
going on, hurry! Come on!
That glorious day has arrived.
That day has arrived.
Hit the drum!
Alps! Surround the tent!
Hurry up!
Surround the tent!
God damn it!
Move!
Sister!
What is going on?
God's justice has delayed again, Gokce.
There is a fire in one of the stables.
-Which one?
-The one near the merchant's tent.
Be careful Rahman. This may be a trap.
Aye, Bey!
Where on earth did this fire come from?
The drums roll.
We can not attack the marquee anymore.
Everybody is alert now.
Get rid of your Alp uniforms.
Hide the weapons too.
Help them put out the fire.
We must not draw attention.
Aye, sir!
God damn it!
Bey!
I smell a rat, Kurdoglu.
Put all the Alps in alert.
Tell them to secure
the nomad tents in full fig.
Aye, Bey!
Bloody oldster!
What happened?
-The fire ruined everything.
-How can a fire break out in this weather?
Dundar.
Suleyman's son Dundar?
He should have died.
What are you talking about, Titus?
Did you hear that?
The hounds of hell.
They are coming.
Their voices are the same as my brothers.
Sooner or later...
...they will perceive your smell.
Shut up, you evil woman!
Not only will they chew
your meat to pieces...
...they will also...
...chew your brain and soul
to pieces with their sharp teeth.
I can feel it.
Here.
They are also here, even in this dargah.
I can feel them revolving around us.
They will find you.
And when they do...
...they will throw...
...your amputated body into the pits of
hell for the eternal torment waiting you.
You cannot escape
from the hounds of hell.
There is no escape from them, Turk!
No escape!
If we die...
...shall my white bearded
father's place be in heaven.
Shall my white haired
mother's place be the skies.
As long as the
God's gift of hope survives...
...God shall not let us go astray.
You pity your sinister fate.
Bey...
...have you seen Dundar?
-Isn't he in his bed?
-No.
Maybe he went out for the fire.
But his bed is untouched.
Rahman!
-Yes, Bey!
-Have you seen Dundar?
I asked if you have seen Dundar!
He went out to meet with his friends.
What do you mean he went out at this
time of the night without my permission?
I thought, he is a young man...
He went out suddenly
so I just couldn't say anything.
Oh God! God give me patience!
Find him immediately! Bring him here!
Why are you so anxious, mother?
It is just a fire in the stable.
Does a fire break out
in the stable in the winter?
-Obviously, somebody did it.
-Who would do such a thing?
Don't you know
the situation we are in Selcan?
Can't you see that they are
trying hard to intrigue us?
-I shall go and have a look.
-Bey...
...be careful, will you?
Dundar! Dundar!
Son, son!
Bey!
-Son!
-Dundar!
My Dundar!
My son!
Dundar, my son!
I am going to call Akcakoca.
What do you want Kara Toygar?
We both want the same thing, Afsin.
We have a mutual goal with you now.
We can never have a mutual goal with you.
It does not look that way to me, Afsin.
I know everything, my former
comrade in arms. Everything.
And so does Sultan.
We know...
...everything you went
through since the first day...
...Ertugrul came in the presence
of El Aziz's Governor Sahabettin.
Who might have done this, Atabey?
I found Dundar near
the hayloft which was on fire.
He might have started it.
What does this mean?
Do you hear what you say?
In my opinion, he sacrificed himself
in order to save the nomad tent.
He might have wanted to
warn us to prevent another danger.
Rahman!
Yes, Bey!
Bring merchant Ebu Hisham to me! Now!
If it weren’t for Ertugrul...
...I would give way to the Templars
who were trying to settle in Konya.
In that case they would
all be under my patronage.
Mine and Sultan Alaaddin's.
Yes, you have spoilt
both mine and the Sultan's game.
They would be leaking information
to their emperor and the Pope...
...by the help of pigeons...
....but only as much as we wanted them to.
But the swarthy young man
of Kayis spoilt our game.
And you helped him.
I do not feel like
believing you, Kara Toygar.
I do not care a bit that
you believe me or not, Afsin.
We are both after the same thing.
What is it?
We both know that El Aziz's
and Halime Sultan's marriage...
...would start a new Turkmen riot.
Nasir and the Templars
would use the Shahzade.
Anyone who loves their state
would approve of this...
...while the Crusaders and
the Mongols are at the door.
Bey.
Suleyman Shah is looking for Ebu Hisham.
You go out, Alpargo.
Do you think the oldster has found out?
He is the most dangerous man
you can ever meet.
What shall we do?
If you run away, he will find you.
You are nothing compared to 100 Alps.
He will skin you alive.
Wait.
You helped them extinguish the fire.
Then I came and took you.
Kurdoglu.
If his cub hasn't died,
that means we are all in deep trouble.
If the boy speaks,
it will be disastrous for us.
Come on, let's go.
I heard you were looking for me.
The hayloft which was on fire...
...is near your men's tent Ebu Hisham.
Yes, Bey.
It was too late when we saw the fire.
They went to bed early because we
would hit the road early in the morning.
When they woke up with the noise, they
immediately tried to extinguish the fire.
I also did what I could do about it.
And did you notice anything suspicious?
No, Bey.
Bey.
A timber fell on Ebu Hisham while
he was trying to extinguish the fire.
If you excuse us,
I will take him to Akcakoca.
-Akcakoca is here, Kurdoglu.
-Hope nothing's bad, Bey?
-Somebody attempted to kill Dundar.
-What are you talking about, Bey?
It was Dundar who set the hayloft on fire.
He saved the nomad tent
from a big disaster.
May God heal him.
He shall get better soon.
Is there anything we can do?
I am sorry to say that I have had your
belongings searched as a precaution.
A servant's precautions
are recognised by God, Bey.
No need to apologize.
Put your mind at ease.
You did what needed to be done.
Leave the nomad tent
immediately with your men.
We are expecting an attack.
I will not feel comfortable
unless I provide your security.
May God bless you
for considering our well-being.
However you please.
-Kurdoglu.
-Yes, Bey?
Get some men to chase them.
They shall follow their every step.
Tell them not to get too close to them.
Aye, Bey!
Gokce.
Thank you Mother Hayme.
I know you want to know
what I am going to say.
Our boy Dundar is young, strong.
He is at the exact age
to become an Alp.
He is strong as stone, God bless.
We believe deep in our hearts
that God almighty will provide remedy...
...and we must pray for this.
The sword impact he took...
...may not be lethal...
...but there is another
matter that concerns me.
The blow he took when he fell.
That is my major concern.
What do you mean, Akcakoca?
Briefly...
...his body can endure
the sword's impact.
But...
But his brain...
...his brain...
Akcakoca.
Just say it.
So let us all know.
The impact he took on the head...
...may have damaged his mental skills.
Perhaps, from now on, our son Dundar...
...may have a long and painful life
to suffer while sleeping to death.
His Highness Halebi went to Aleppo.
The dargah is leaderless now.
We shall complete
this task today whatever it takes.
Lives of the dervishes' in the dargah
are at stake because of us.
We cannot handle if anything happens
to the dervishes because of us.
What would we say to Ibn'ul Arabi then?
Shall we...
Ertugrul?
We have to go immediately, brother.
You are not coming.
Brother, don't do this.
Ertugrul, they will not
let you in the palace.
And if they do,
they will not let you out.
It is better if I go as an ambassador.
What happened in the palace?
That spoiled brat Dundar...
...ruined everything.
He warned the nomad group...
...by putting the hayloft on fire.
He is just like his Brother Ertugrul.
I will come back again,
Kurdoglu, to finish this business off.
Dundar must die.
If he speaks...
...it will be your job
to kill Suleyman Shah.
And as far as I see,
you are not strong enough to do it.
What about El Aziz?
-His army is about to hit the road.
-I did whatever I could.
You should do whatever
it takes to stop El Aziz's army!
I hope your Bey agrees to surrender.
Have a blessed day, my Brother Kurdoglu.
May God speed you, Ebu Hisham.
My daughter, more beautiful
than the moon, crazier than me.
My brave daughter who took her weapons...
...to go after her man,
the nightmare of the cowardly.
-Welcome!
-Glad to be back. Father...
...I located where Turgut is being held.
Did you go there, daughter?
I did, father.
All right, daughter.
Let's go to our Bey now...
...and tell him what you know.
Permission.
I have been waiting for you to come.
I saw how you were waiting for me...
...to tell to tell you everything.
This is what you get if you collaborate
with men who cannot even kill a kid.
We are trying to to harvest the crops
without getting our feet in the mud.
Get your feet in the mud then!
Get in it up to the neck!
At that case you will feel my support.
So that is how much you trust me?
We share the same destiny now, Kurdoglu.
We will get what we want or they will
have our dead bodies eaten by vultures.
Ebu Hisham will come back again.
What is his self-interest in this?
We are practising on the same target.
Be careful, Kurdoglu...
...for the arrow you shot shall not
turn back and strike you in the buttocks.
It is time for you to leave.
Aykiz has arrived.
I shall listen what she has to say.
Alpargo!
Yes, Bey?
Take two men and go after him.
Do not get too close to him.
Ebu Hisham knows that
you will be following him with two Alps.
Return without arousing
the suspicions of Alps coming with you.
Suleyman will interrogate them too.
If he finds out that this is a plot...
He suspected Ebu Hisham for once.
That bloody oldster would not
stop until he solves this in his head.
Now go!
I saw that the Templars' castle is
impenetrable even with a massive army.
Like the Assassins' castle in Alamut?
Yes, Bey.
The real evil is in Alamut, Bey.
That demon is called Hassan al-Sabbah.
It was that demon's men who murdered
Alp Arslan and his son Malik Shah.
Those Templars learned
everything they know from them.
One of them poison the Muslims
by putting idolatry in the book of God...
...and the others poison the Christians
with what they have learned from them.
One is no better than the other.
That castle can only
be accessed with a trick.
We must discover that trick and enter
that castle as quickly as possible, Bey.
If Turgut is still in that castle,
it is our duty to go and rescue him.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
THE TEMPLARS' CASTLE
A willpower strong as steel.
If I had 10 knights like you,
Jerusalem would have been ours already.
From now on I will call you Judas.
Your name among us will be Judas.
Judas.
I am giving you the name
of the apostle who betrayed Jesus.
In order for you
to never forget who you are.
Judas.
Get him ready.
I will show
our new knight around the castle.
May God curse your hands.
What was your problem with this kid?
What did Akcakoca say, Mother Hayme?
He said that his wounds would heal slowly.
He said he was young...
...and strong.
Mother Hayme.
But...
...but...
...till the end of his life...
I have a request Mother Hafza.
I am listening to you, Ertugrul Bey.
The palace nanny, Ummul Hayr...
...is the sister of your husband Halebi.
You visit the palace frequently.
Can you tell Halime Sultan...
...that I would like to talk to her
and bring her to the carpet shop?
This is very dangerous.
Not only for you
but also for that girl.
I know.
But...
...if I cannot talk to her
it will be a disaster for all of us.
I will go to the palace for you.
But if she does not want to come...
...I cannot force her.
God bless you, Mother Hafza.
Now excuse me.
Why did you do this, sister?
Are you aware of the difficulties
he dealt with just for you, for us?
Are you aware how Brother Turgut
suffers in the dungeon for saving us?
How could you do this, sister?
I had to, Yigit.
For you, for my father...
I wish you had let them
kill me with Brother Turgut.
I beg you, do not speak like that.
Do you know what you did, sister?
You killed Brother Ertugrul.
Believe it or not, Halime Sultan.
The destiny is such a thing.
What the hell are you doing here?
I came to rescue you from
the bed of that idiot El Aziz.
I am your only friend
in this palace, Halime.
You are a despicable blood-shedder!
Welcome to your home, Titus.
I learned what happened, sir.
I must go to Aleppo immediately.
We all are under threat
while Eftelya is alive.
If her identity is revealed,
we will lose Aleppo.
I have always been proud of you, Titus.
I am glad that you infiltrated the Kayis.
Has the Cardinal completed the report...
...he has been preparing
for the Pope and Emperor Frederick?
No.
Or he is lying to me.
This task will be harder
than I thought, Titus.
If necessary, the Cardinal
may have to die by a Muslim's sword...
...like my brother Giovanni.
Do you understand me?
Titus...
...as you depart, take the gift
I had prepared for El Aziz with you.
It will be
the bloodiest wedding in history.
I wish I was one of the guests.
I will represent you
as good as possible, sir.
I have no doubt about it, Titus.
No doubt whatsoever!
What is Kara Toygar doing here?
Aleaddin must have learned
that you are going to marry...
...the Shahzade's daughter.
And to prevent it
, he sent his one eyed monster, sir.
Sir, be prepared for the threats.
Do not surrender.
What shall I do, Nasir?
Send him away immediately
from the court, sir.
And marry Halime Sultan without
waiting for the wedding preparations.
-You hold the wedding later on.
-Would it be convenient that way?
Helter-skelter without a wedding?
Would it beseem well for a ruler like me
and a Shahzade's daughter like her?
Sir, if the security of our state is at
stake, of course it would beseem well.
So glad I have you, Nasir.
May God keep you with me.
The Kayis have sent an ambassador.
We are keeping him
waiting at the palace gate.
Bamsi Beyrek!
Enough! Sit down I am feeling dizzy!
These women are all the same!
Has not a mother given birth to you?
Leave my mother out of this!
I am talking about sister Halime!
She was like that in the marquee
now she is like this in the palace!
She sold Ertugrul Bey out!
Shut up! Bey will hear.
Oh God!
I am not going to forgive her till I die.
Oh my!
This is a trick sister Halime is playing.
What a shame.
After all the trouble you
have gone through for her.
You put yourself...
...your Alps...
...your nomad group...
...at risk for her.
You even stood up against us.
Who are you talking about?
About that Shahzade's daughter.
About Halime Sultan.
Did you really think...
...a Shahzade's daughter would
fall in love with a shepherd like you?
She used you Ertugrul.
She made you come this far.
And when she found
an Ameer as noble as herself...
...she went to bed with him.
You are getting angry with me...
...but I knew things would end up this way
when you brought her to the palace.
Do you know...
...I was the woman
who El Aziz was in love with.
I was his favourite.
I know his tastes very good.
Halime is exactly how he desires.
He used to write poems for me.
For Christ's sake, I had to endure
those horrible poems everyday.
Now Halime Sultan will take my place.
He will find solace in Halime's young
and tender skin during long Aleppo nights.
I have never hit
a woman in my entire life.
God forbid that
I should experience such shame!
A man of honour would
never do something like that.
But you should keep this in mind
that whenever I remember you...
...I will pray for you to burn in hell.
Not only will I pray
for the lives you have taken...
...but also for your lies and slanders
to be the fire you puke in hell.
The son of Suleyman Shah, Gundogdu Bey!
I said I wanted to meet you alone.
Nasir is the most certified
person in this city after me.
Not only have I entrusted him my life
and the pudicity of my harem...
...but also my city.
Who are you to feel disturbed
by his presence here?
I can not get out of trouble since
I annexed your nomad tent anyway.
And you stand there and tell me
what I should do unashamedly!
Shame!
So you deserve to experience
the biggest betrayal possible.
You have already sold this city which
is one of the most beautiful cities...
...Saladin Ayyubid's dynasty
has established to the infidels.
How dare you...
Your Highness The Ameer.
Let him speak, Your Highness The Ameer.
As you said before, it is necessary
to deal with this unpleasant matter...
...without shedding any
Muslim blood by the religious means...
...and also for a clear conscience.
Well...
...although I am suspicious about
the faith of this inconsiderate party...
Nasir...
Once upon a time there was this Seljuk
commander who had betrayed his state.
The last time I saw him he was barking
like dogs in the center of our nomad tent.
It is such a shame that
you won't have the time for that.
His Highness The Ameer will soon
find out who you really are...
...how you have infiltrated the palace...
...and how you have been
taking orders from the Templars.
Enough!
If you are an ambassador,
behave like one!
Or regardless of the regulations...
...I will have your head
cut off from your body.
Sir.
You shall talk.
I can wait for you outside.
It is a lie!
You won't deceive me with those slanders.
If you have any courage...
...you find out the truth about the woman
named Eftelya who calls herself as Esma.
The only thing I want from you...
...is your permission to bring her
together with Leyla's nanny to you.
What is my nanny got to do with this?
She informed against Ertugrul
and got him put in the dungeon.
She loves you as if you are her son.
Also she is the one
whom Ertugrul and you both trust.
Your Highness The Ameer,
she would never betray you.
She only considers what is
best for you and your sister Leyla.
And she is one of the three
people in the palace....
...who know that are not
members of the Templars.
Who are the other two?
Your sister Leyla and you.
You said you could not make Esma speak.
What if she does not speak again?
How are you going to prove it out?
There is a cross tattoo in the back
of her head, hidden under her hair.
Remember.
The Templars who came to the palace
to kill Ertugrul had the same thing.
You will see it for yourself.
All right! Enough girls!
Leave the girl alone!
Come on, let the poor girl breathe.
Come on, come with me.
You've become so beautiful, God bless.
El Aziz is more than a son for me, Halime.
Get used to him.
You will see, you will love him.
He has a heart of gold.
He is respectful, polite.
He values women a lot.
You will experience the pleasure of
being loved and pampered with him.
Just give him the opportunity,
give him some time.
I saw Kara Toygar.
Do you know
what he is doing in the palace?
The Seljuk Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat...
...has sent him
as an ambassador to consult with El Aziz.
Consult about what?
Your marriage with El Aziz.
They say that the Sultan sent him
in person to prevent this marriage.
I see.
Being wordy is not a reliable behaviour,
Your Highness The Ameer.
Let me get straight to the point.
If you marry our Shahzade's daughter...
...we will assume that...
...you are willing to encourage...
...the Turkmen people to start a riot
by collaborating with the Shahzade.
Are you threatening us Kara Toygar?
Only the weak nebbishes
threaten, Commander Nasir.
The glorious Sultan
of our state Aleaddin Keykubat...
...does not threaten.
He does what is necessary.
We are in a war with your Sultan Aleaddin
Keykubat every single day, Kara Toygar.
Not a day passes
without a border violation.
Not a day passes without a clash
between the soldiers of both sides.
Come on, Your Highness The Ameer!
You know that...
...those are only simple arm wrestling
competitions between two states...
...by using their armies.
But this marriage...
...is not a border game.
Arm wrestling, not in the least!
This is definitely a declaration of war!
Did you really think you would lay around
in the dungeon? You will beg to die!
Come on!
So I was going beg to die
in the dungeons of Aleppo, huh?
Titus!
Isadora!
I am so sorry for your sister.
Her suicide affected us all deeply.
I do not know what to say.
My sister would never
ever fall into such sin.
What do you mean?
How did she die then?
Is there something you know?
You loved her, didn't you?
She used to mention
her feelings about you....
...in her letters all the time.
Take one of their swords
if it is going to make you feel safe.
Do not forget.
They are your real brothers.
Here is my chamber, Judas,
where I consult with knights.
My library which consists of
very precious pieces, is here.
Isadora! Come, my beautiful niece.
Let me introduce you to my new knight.
Judas.
He will replace
your little prince for some time.
I want you to take care of him
and teach him what he needs to learn.
He should learn
our language, for instance.
To read.
Is that right, Judas?
As you wish my dear uncle.
Take him to the room
where he is going stay.
Prepare him for his new life,
my beautiful Isadora.
Peace be upon you.
I have a carpet loom in Aleppo.
I would like to host you all there gladly.
Tell me!
Who am I?
I do not know.
So?
I don't know!
You want this one?
Come on, take it.
I said take it!
You want to kill me?
Come on, kill me.
Enough already!
End this game, Titus.
Don't you see, he is unconscious.
He is not aware of himself
because of the torture he went through.
I beg you, uncle, please.
Come on, kill me!
Or admit that I am your brother.
Brother?
Yes, brother.
We are brothers.
Brothers.
My name is Titus.
Judas.
Let's go Judas.
Come on.
If you hadn't come...
...you would have
turned my life into hell.
How could I not come, Ertugrul?
A baby gazelle sealed our fate.
And all the countries of the
world swore an oath to separate us.
I said no when
you asked me to be your wife.
I couldn't tell you
the pain of it inside me, Ertugrul.
I sacrificed myself
for my father and brother.
If you take me from El Aziz's hands...
...his rage will burn the entire
Kayi nomad tent to ashes, Ertugrul.
I know everything.
I was in the palace last night.
Ertugrul, my father is
compelling me to marry El Aziz.
But whatever the cost,
I am not going to marry that man.
I will wait for you, Ertugrul,
till you come and rescue me.
If I do not come...
...know that...
...the grim reaper has taken my life.
In that case, you should know
that I would also be dead.
I can neither go to his
bed nor be his woman...
...with the love I feel for you.
I can never put a shame...
...to the memory of the state my
forefather Seljuk Bey established, or you.
Go now.
Save your nomad tent
from the hands of those bastards.
Don't think of me.
May God speed you Ertugrul.
My heart will beat
for you until my last breath.
Halime!
Neither El Aziz nor the rest of
the world can take you away from me.
I would never
leave you to those tyrants...
...or let those tyrants
be Sultans of the world.
I will come to get you.
I promise.
El Aziz said he wouldn't
marry me until the wedding.
I will be waiting
for you till then, Ertugrul.
The others must be in there too.
They ordered more breads
than they usually do.
Enjoy the gold.
God bless you, sir.
Shah, could you please
tell mother to eat something?
She has not eaten
anything since yesterday.
I could.
I could but I am not sure
if she would feel like eating.
We were going to hold...
...Ertugrul's and your wedding
by the time we arrived at our new home.
We would hold and love
our grandchildren on this fertile land.
Everything is possible, Shah.
May God grant us
good health, in the first place.
These bad days will pass, if God permits.
If God permits, my girl. If God permits...
These are your good days.
The worse are yet to come.
They will kill you all.
If we get caught...
...you will die together with us Eftelya.
But your death won't be
an easy one, Ertugrul.
You will beg.
All the streets of Aleppo will
hear you screaming “Kill me!”
How are those demons to whom
you service like a dog going to kill you?
Silently?
Or by watching you foam at the mouth?
Huh, how?
How would you like to die, Eftelya?
Ertugrul!
Come on, time has come.
-Is Ertugrul in there too?
-Yes.
You wait here, Titus.
Nasir.
Don't you ever tell me what to do!
Ever!
This dargah has teeth on El Aziz.
Also on Ibn-ul Arabi.
I want this power replaced with the gold
you are going to bring and my army.
I will demolish this dargah
together with everything inside it.
I can not find an opportunity
better than this one.
Whatever the cost,
there is no turning back, brother.
We will not stop
even if there are casualties.
That woman named “Eftelya”s life is
more valuable than the rest of us.
We must save the
nomad tent first, if God permits!
Our emancipation is up to that woman.
If anything happens to me...
...do not let them keep
Turgut in their hands, brother.
May God help us.
Amen.
Please do not do this in this dargah.
It is a shame, please.
Please don't do it!
Don't do it, it is a shame!
What are you looking at?
Move if you do not want
to be killed like them!
Enter, come on.
That bastard Nasir
got a whiff of our smell.
There are too many of them.
End of the road, Turk!
You can not escape
from the hounds of hell.
You will get punched in the face.
We must take this woman out of here.
I will take not only this woman,
but also all of you out.
Aren't you coming with us?
They do not have the guts to touch us, Bey
Do not worry.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Here, be quick.
We can not leave you here, dervish.
I can not abandon this dargah, Bey.
May God speed you!
Open the door, who is in there?
Tell me, dervish!  Where are they?
They left, Bey.
Where did those villains go? Speak!
To the place where
God wants them to be.
Do not seek the malice,
which rots us inside out, in them.
Dervish, they are villains.
They are betraying
our state and our religion.
Be a dervish worthy
of the holiness of this dargah.
We have come here to reform Aleppo.
Tell us where they are.
And when it is said to them,
"Do not cause corruption on the earth"...
...they say: "We are but reformers."
Unquestionably, it is they who are
the corrupters, but they perceive not.
And thus, the people
you are looking for are not here.
I witness that...
You leave here with the soldiers.
I am going to the place
where Ertugrul and the nanny will meet.
My uncle tagged him
along behind us to protect me.
He won't harm us, do not worry.
Come on.
While you were in the dungeon you were
saying that you had seen a Muslim man.
A Muslim like you.
I do not remember.
There was a man...
But...
I do not know...
...where he is now
Where am I? How did I come here?
Turgut, Turgut!
Turgut.
You must be very careful Isadora
He is a Turk eventually.
He is a lone mountain wolf.
Do not forget that the mountain wolves...
...never let go of you once
they bite you with their teeth.
Turgut, are you fine?
Help him.
Eftelya will die tonight,
Your Holiness The Cardinal.
-What about the wedding?
-That job is done.
I hope you are right, Petruccio.
Your holy war...
...and also me becoming
the Pope are up to this.
Did I tell you how I killed the Pope?
I want to know it down
to the last detail, dear Thomas.
Come, sit
You must be tired.
A glass of wine
would relieve all my tiredness.
With pleasure!
You three go this way! You come with me.
That scoundrel named Kara Toygar.
How dare he come here?
To serve the purpose of Sultan Aleaddin's
goals. He is his ambassador.
He never serves for anyone but himself.
What are you planning to do,
Your Highness The Ameer?
I have consulted
this matter with consultants.
We will send ambassadors
to the Turkmen tribes.
We will inform the Turkmens that have been
supressed by Kara Toygar and such...
...that their lost Shahzade is with us.
We will invite the people who want
to stop the Aleaddin Keykubat's reign...
...to our wedding.
But this would be very dangerous,
Your Highness The Ameer!
As you would appreciate,
Keykubat will see this as an attack.
Anyway, we can talk
about this in detail later.
By the way...
...I wanted to do a small change
after the latest developments.
I decided that best thing to do is to
marry without the wedding ceremony.
If you do not mind, of course.
As you please, Your Highness The Ameer.
Your Highness The Ameer!
Shahzade?
I would like to talk to you,
if you do not mind.
Of course, I am listening to you.
My sister will never love you, ever.
She is in love with somebody else.
With whom?
With my brother Ertugrul.
Keep away from my sister and us!
Where have you been Ertugrul Bey?
Ertugrul, Eftelya!
Bamsi!
Don't linger around!
Don't!