Episode 24 will start after 12:18 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
The castle is surrounded by the cliff.
An on-target attack is nearly impossible.
The only way in is from that direction.
We know that they prepared two tunnels.
One of them is known to us but closed.
Wild Demir shall open that tunnel
so that our warriors can pass through.
We do not know the other one's location.
Omer went to find out
the second tunnel's location.
According to Isadora, no one but...
...The Master and Titus knows about the
second tunnel.
If we act hasty and try to get in through
the doors or over the wall...
...this shall be both the raid's
and our end.
More importantly, we must cut their
all communication with the outside off...
...and isolate them.
If we can get in the castle through
the tunnels with 40 warriors...
... we may able to open the doors
from the yard.
Just like the 40 warriors of Kursat,
40 warriors are enough, my Bey.
I would like to be one of them
if you do not count me as an old man...
...and let me join.
I saw my daughter's marriage too.
I have nothing to fear in this world.
You are right, Wild Demir.
Get us into this castle,
with God's permission.
Do not worry, my Bey. I shall succeed.
If they call for help from
The Principality of Antioch...
...we shall be caught in a trap.
If the tunnel opens
later than we anticipated...
...the isolation can be prolonged.
In that case,
women shall provide ammunition...
...and subsistence to the Alps.
We shall be at war on both sides then.
When we march, the nomad group,
ammunition and subsistence shall be...
...on Gundogdu's responsibility.
As you command, my Bey.
Come on, God is just!
Come on!
Hit it hard my brave ones!
It is the day of conquest.
Dogan, Dogan! Take wing, Dogan!
I hope it is all well, Bamsi,
you seem to be in a good mood.
Yes, brother, the goat came back too.
If we come back triumphants,
the time to marry shall come.
You bear, which woman would desire you?
Brothers...
...you are not able to fight
from quarrelling.
Come on.
You do not worry, my goat.
We shall level that castle
with the ground.
I should not be called as a man...
...if I do not turn that castle
into a dungeon for them.
I shall make it a hell for them.
-Come on. God is great! God is just!
-Come on, lions!
How is it?
You should wrap it tighter
so that when you release the arrow...
...it shall pierce the knight's armor.
Tighter, Dundar, tighter.
Try it again.
You did not get mad, did you?
How can I get mad, Aykiz?
Each arrow that does not pierce its target
means a martyr from our side.
I shall do it immediately.
My Alps, my brothers,
brave warriors of Kayi tribe.
Time to stop the enemy has come.
Now it is time for conquest.
The enemy hides in the castle.
This conquest is not a pitched battle...
...we shall fight the toughest battle.
If they have stone castles
we have chests full of faith.
If someone should scare, flee or
break down during the battle...
...they better stay home.
If I see a warrior, tired of
fighting the battle...
...I shall kill him with my own weapon.
Now go and take your families' blessings.
May God bless our way and conquest.
Long live, Ertugrul Bey!
Come on!
Come on, brave men!
May it be easy, may it be easy.
-Thank you, Mother Hayme.
-Thank you.
-Welcome.
-Welcome, Mother Hayme.
Sisters, listen to me.
Brave sisters of Kayi.
Today is a day of unity.
Today is the day we race for victory.
We will supply our men until they raze
that godforsaken castel to the ground.
We will work night and day.
We will not falter.
The battle belongs to us,
the victory is God's.
Hang on, sisters.
Hang on, in the name of God!
-How is it going?
-It is going well, Hayme Sultan.
Make them sturdy.
May it be easy.
Thank you, my Bey.
-May it be easy, my brother.
-Thank you, brother.
How are the preparations going?
We removed the venom of Kurdoglu
from the hearts of our Alps, brother.
-Wonderful.
-What about you?
Hamza Alp checks the ammunition.
I put men everywhere in case of
an attack from the outside.
Anyway, I have lots of things to do.
Brother, how is Selcan Hatun doing?
She is no longer my wife.
Thank you.
Son.
Me and my dervish want to be your Alps but
we may do more harm than good.
We expect your prayers.
Of course. My prayers are always with you,
Ertugrul.
Dervish.
Son, one must be shielded with prayers.
Thank you.
Son, the situation in Anatolia
is complicated.
The wild flame of Mongols is everywhere.
We must not leave Anatolia
to defend itself.
I came from Andalucia for Anatolia.
If Anatolia prospers,
the whole Islamic World will rise.
Do you suggest we go back?
I say straightening the ranks
is beneficial.
You seem to know what I will say.
I know but my heart tears itself
to hear it.
May God bless your way.
May the sun never burn your skin.
May no rain make you cold.
May no stone get in your way.
Come back to your tribe
like a flowing river.
You heard it, Ak Tolgali.
He will take me there and
bring me back in no time.
May God help me to bring
your brother Yigit back to our tribe.
If God permits.
May God bless your conquest, Bey.
You are going to this war as a brave Alp,
but may you return as Ertugrul Alp Ghazi.
Mother Hayme sent some food.
Thank you, sister.
Sit, eat with me.
Suleyman Shah hosts a dinner
in his marquee.
I will eat with them.
What's the occasion?
Who is invited for the dinner?
Suleyman Shah wants to see all of his
family by his side before the battle.
I should go now.
Enjoy the dinner.
Selcan Hatun,
what goes around comes around.
You reap what you sow.
You are not a member
of the family anymore.
My children, the future of Kayi tribe
and the hope of our people.
Tonight I will tell you a story
from the land of our ancestors.
Many centuries ago, our country
was divided into pieces out of animosity.
Our sky colored flag was abandoned.
Emperors of that time ruined our country
by being seduced by the silk dresses,
various gifts
and mostly the Chinese women
sent by the Chinese Emperor.
That enormous Turkish country collapsed
and couldn't resist Chinese tricks,
various gifts
and the venom of women.
Our nation was taken
prisoner, my children.
The captive Turks
started fighting to reclaim
our sky colored flag.
A brave warrior who saw his nation
being tortured under the cruelty of China
took an oath of vengeance.
He was Kursat, my children.
Kursat!
He was the nephew of the Khan
who was seduced by the silk dresses
and various tricks of China.
He decided to put his sword in China's
heart for the future of our nation
and the sky colored flag!
He choose only 40 heroes for this.
Each of them was a lion.
An army of believers!
Every one of them was a hero, ready to
sacrifice their lives for the nation.
Their target was the
cruel emperor of China.
Those 40 people would get in the palace
and kill that tyrant.
Even if they would fell,
the sky colored flag would be free.
One night, those 40 lions
left their camp in silence.
They struck the emperor's palace like
a thunder which was guarded by thousands!
And they slaughtered everyone!
That enormous palace was howling with
the battle cries of 40 heroes!
Battle cries of 40 heroes
echoed through China!
Even the Emperor had already fled
when he heard the blood curdling
battle cries of 40 heroes.
Kursat ordered their return, saying that
this much fear would be enough for them.
But tens of thousands Chinese soldiers
pursued them for their capture.
When Kursat and his men came by the river
it was pouring heavily.
The rivers overflowed and
the bridges fell down.
Kursat and his heroes were trapped.
Unable to cross the river,
they bid farewell to their brothers in
arms and charged into the fray.
And reaped the Chinese like wheat!
But the Chinese were endless
and sent them to the afterlife.
They died for the sky colored flag
and for freedom.
My children, Kursat and his heroes
made history when they died.
Their legend spread quickly.
Kursat paved the way of the Turks
with his actions and a nation was reborn.
They broke the shackles of China's fear
and returned to the stage of history.
This saga of independence
is Kusat's legacy to us.
May God never leave us again
without the voice of Azan,
our flag and our country.
-Amen.
And may he never let this nation
to be imprisoned again.
-Amen.
Amen, my children. Amen.
What is missing?
Go to hell, Selcan.
I will not be defeated by you!
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Hamza. Come in.
Suleyman Shah expects you for dinner, Bey.
Thank you.
I worked all day but
this was all I could prepare.
I hope you like it.
Let us try, Hatun.
Let us see if you did well.
Turgut.
Turgut, what is it?
-Give me water.
Aykiz, what is this?
What is what?
Did not you like it?
Even The Templars did not torture me
like this.
Even the poison they fed me
tasted better.
Is that so?
Go and drink their poison then.
Wait, wait. Sit down, I was jesting.
It was a jest.
You don't say.
Aykiz, sweeter than the moon itself.
How can these blessed hands
feed me poison?
It is so delicious
that I have never tasted anything
more halal, more delicious my life.
How do I know that you are
telling the truth?
I swear, Aykiz, it is very good.
Okay, stop.
Okay, you will choke on it.
I was so scared, Turgut.
I would never forgive my hands
if they prepare something
you won't like someday.
Tomorrow, we are going to bring
that castle to the ground.
If I become a martyr,
you will not shed tears.
Promise me.
If you become a martyr
know that I will not shed any tears.
I shall praise God
for giving us the honor.
-How are the preparations going?
-We are ready, Bey.
We are ready, Bey.
Let us see how will that castle
endure our weapons.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you. Come in.
Thank you.
We could not show you the hospitality
you deserve because of all the troubles.
You have accepted me to your tent,
tribe and heart, Suleyman Shah.
I need nothing more.
Thank you.
Tomorrow is the day of our holy conquest.
Yes, it is.
We will do battle in order to stop cruelty
and show our strenght to the tyrants.
May God grant Kayi tribe strengt to do
holy conquest until the eternity.
-Amen.
Amen.
May your tribe reign supreme
and show the tyrants the power of justice.
-Amen.
Bey, the dinner is ready.
Let us eat.
In the name of God.
Enjoy your meal.
The war begins now.
Don't get too excited now.
Or I will cut you down.
Come here.
Tell Titus that Ertugrul
he was looking all over,
has come to raze his castle down.
And tell him that,
Suleyman Shah wants to talk to him
and give him a chance and only once
to ask for mercy.
We are waiting for him here.
Hurry up.
What do we do about these heathens, Bey?
Keep them somewhere for now, Turgut.
Titus!
May God's light and Templar's faith
illuminate your path.
Kayi tribe blocked the roads
to the castle, sir.
They are locking us in.
-What?
Their Bey is in front of the castle,
he wants to negotiate with you.
Are you not going to tell us
what is happening, Master Titus?
Kayi tribe blocaded the castle, sir.
Double, no, triple the guards.
Make night's watch more frequent too.
Strengthen the portcullis, increase
the number of archers too.
What are you waiting for? Hurry up!
I was coming to congratulate you
for your new holy duty, sir.
This is too early for this, Claudius,
too early.
-Is something wrong, sir?
-Come with me, Claudius.
Soldiers, secure the gates, quickly!
Swords, shields, spears,
get all the equipment out!
What is going on?
Ertugrul surrounded the castle with
Kayi tribe.
How dare him?
They will pay the price of their bravery.
Alert everyone immediately, at once!
What are you thinking?
They attacked us first when we were
planning to attack them.
They must have found out about the
decision that we made in the council
that we were going to attack them
together with Principality of Antioch
and the Knights of Cyprus.
Apart from the masters, only the cardinal,
you and I knew about this.
Yes. We shall find out
who else knows soon.
It is impossible for us to have
an infiltrator among us.
I hope you are right, Claudius.
If they really have
an infiltrator inside...
...they are the cat and we are
the mouse in this game.
They are not capable of such a thing.
They managed infiltrate us before.
That Afsin and the Muslim spy
dressed as a priest.
I can expect everything from them now.
Strengthen the walls.
Put more men on the weak spots.
Come on, hurry up.
As you command, sir.
Come on, hurry up and
put your backs into it!
The Templars were not expecting us.
They must be losing their mind now.
We have come to teach them
how to fight, son.
They have tried many things.
They wanted us and here we are.
May we never go back to our tribe if we
fail to plant our flag on these walls.
Do not deem him as an equal
by negotiating, sir.
Maybe the best course of action is
a sudden raid. A break-out.
They have the upper hand.
Their numbers are at least
three times more.
Out horses are in the studs
outside of the castle.
They must have seized them too.
We are trapped.
They cannot get in the castle.
They cannot get in but they would
not let us out too.
We can finish them right here with
the army that is coming to our aid.
The pigeon should reach the
Principality of Antioch before noon.
The army will be here within two days.
You will negotiate with him then.
Yes. Let us find out
what their trouble is.
You come with me, Claudius.
Prepare the horses.
I give you until tonight
to surrender Titus.
What if we do not surrender, Suleyman?
Then we will kill every single one of you
and burn your castle to the ground.
Is this how strong
the goat shepherds have become?
You did not need to bother.
I was on my way to your tribe
to obliterate you.
I hope you know how to use a blade as much
as your tongue, Titus.
I would hate to see my Alps to be here for
mere training.
Why did you want to talk to me then?
Here is the castle,
why have you not attacked?
We Muslims show mercy for one last time
even for the heathens we fight.
So that they might find the true path.
Now, I ask you for one last time.
Surrender the castle.
Surrender your weapons with your soldiers
and go back to the lands you came from.
And your lives shall be spared.
You do not know The Templars at all.
We die...
...but we never surrender.
Come and capture my castle if you can.
Time is up, Titus!
You are going to die.
Here you go.
Mother, do I have your permission?
Yes, Selcan Hatun.
I am ashamed of sitting in the tent
while our men are fighting the enemy.
I want to help my sisters
with your permission.
Come and join us.
Come on.
May it be easy, sisters. May it be easy.
Mother, our preparations are completed.
If you are done here too, we may go now.
What is she doing here?
She said that she does not want to sit
in her tent while the men are fighting.
And I let her.
Selcan.
Leave immediately.
Get your filthy hands off of us
and leave.
-Gundogdu.
-I said now.
If you had let me handle Selcan before
none of this would have happened.
I would have set her straight.
Hugues de Payens, Godfrey de Saint-Omer.
The king of Jerusalem, Baldwin the second.
They have opened us this honorable path.
Our campaign started to defend
Christian pilgrims
but it will end today with the
conquest of Jerusalem.
Every single one of you
is a holy warrior of God.
We shall reclaim
Solomon's Temple in the Mount of Olives
next to Al-Aqsa Mosque.
Nothing can prevent this.
You are the followers of Jesus
and Solomon's Temple.
The time has come to teach
those heretical
and heathen Turks a lesson.
Jesus is by our side.
May God protect you.
Victory belongs to the lord!
There is no other explanation
for this, Cardinal.
They are not fool enough to just walk into
a castle protected like Alamut.
What do you have in mind, Titus?
We must have a spy among us.
You reap what you sow,
don't you agree, Titus?
We had spies among Eyyubis once.
Eftelya. Nasir.
Among Seljuks, Karatoygar.
And among the Kayi tribe, Kurdoglu.
Now they have prevailed
to seed spies among us.
How peculiar!
Look at this goat smelled shepherd tribe.
I shall find that spy no matter what.
The members of the council are tense.
They don't want to pay the price
for Master Petruccio's mistakes.
If this castle falls
the Crusades shall be endangered.
It will be much worse, Titus.
If what you say is true
heretics who wants to make
a deal with muslims will win
instead of crushing them.
That is when the real disaster
shall begin.
We have a big opportunity to dispose of
Turks once and for all, Cardinal.
I shall make use of this opportunity
that is handed to me in a golden plate.
Belt and braces, Cladius.
If the situation deteriorates
we must find a way to save ourselves
from this accursed place.
Do not be concerned, sir.
Only your corpse shall leave
this place, you bastard.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
What is the situation, Wild Demir?
Bey, the tunnels of the castle have proven
to be more arduous than we deemed.
Can't we break through, Wild Demir?
We can, my Bey, but we need more men.
And the noise shall be noticed
by the heathens.
Is there any other way, Wild Demir?
Then our task is even more compelling.
We now need to find the second tunnel.
Wild Demir, put your backs into it.
Break the stones with your weapons
if you have to but get into that castle.
As you command, my Bey. As you command.
If all of your signatures should be
on the letter I drafted
the number of soldiers coming
to our aid will be much greater.
Not even a single Turk
will be left alive on this land.
What if the Turks should enter the castle?
That is not possible, Master Ricardo.
They have neither the equipment
to breach the walls
nor the technique to approach portcullis.
Remember that they are mere shepherds.
Are you proposing that the Alps
and their Beys are fools, Titus?
I don't suppose they are here for
pleasure with so many warriors.
Masters, my name is Titus.
I will discover whatever
these rancid shepherds' plans are
and whoever their spies are hiding.
Do not have any doubts about this.
When this letter reaches
the County of Crusaders
everything will come to an end for them.
By signing this letter here
you shall be signing the
death warrant of Turks.
Who are you? What is your business here?
-I am Cardinal Thomas' knight, Cladius.
-What do you want?
There is a letter that must reach
the Church of Antioch.
It is the Cardinal's orders.
Without Master Titus' consent, I cannot
send any pigeons anywhere, knight Cladius.
You must excuse me.
I see.
Fly away now.
And send Ertugrul Bey my regards.
Omer has done his duty.
Now it is our turn.
Double the patrols and guards, Ertugrul.
They would do anything to send word
from the castle now.
If Omer cannot stop the messenger
of Titus, we must do so.
It's tip is bloody.
The murderer has tried to wipe it
but it' still bloody.
-So?
-So, the spy must be wounded.
He had wounded him before he died.
Inspect everyone
and bring me every wounded man.
As you command, sir.
Cladius, you inspect the Cardinal's men.
There would not be any spies
among the Cardinal's men, sir.
You will do as I command.
As you command, Master Titus.
God damned Turks, you all belong to hell.
All of you will die.
At least now we have comfirmed
that we have a spy in the castle.
What do we do now, sir?
We must send another messenger
to the Crusaders.
-There is a secret passage.
-A passage?
Yes, there are two tunnels.
Master Petruccio sealed the first one.
And only the two of us knew
the whereabouts of the second.
I could fulfil this difficult task
if you command me.
No, I need you more in here.
As you wish, sir.
Father said that he will hold yours and
Aunt Halime's wedding together.
Let us bring down the castle upon
the heathens first.
We shall see your wedding too,
in the future, if God permits.
I shall be like brother Bamsi.
I will take my weapon as my bride
and my horse as my child.
If God permits, I shall be a great Alp,
just as brother Ertugrul and Turgut.
When will you go to the mountains
for your Alp training?
As soon as he takes Yigit from the castle,
father will send us to the mountains.
Our training will begin then.
-If God permits.
If God permits, I will have
brave sons as you are.
If God permits.
Sisters! These supplies shall be
on their way in the morning.
Just hang in there!
Mother! Mother!
Sisters bring some water, quickly!
Come. Sit down, mother. Sit down.
Thank you, my daughter.
I am alright, no need to be concerned.
I only felt a bit dizzy.
Mother, you should rest.
We will ready the supplies in time.
I know how capable you all are.
Year ago, my father was the commander
of a castle in our ancestral lands.
He fought hard to protect our castle
from the Mongols.
My brothers became martyrs in that battle.
But we did not let a single Mongol
enter our castle.
Which of our men will become martyrs now?
That is why we must make our tribe ready
after the battle.
We will share the burden of our martyrs'
mothers, sons, sisters and wives.
And then there is Sungurtekin
whom I could not even see his dead body.
My heart says that he is not dead
and we will reunite someday.
If God permits, mother.
You will reunite, if God permits.
If God permits, my daughter.
If God permits.
Where is Selcan?
Gundogdu Bey told her not to leave
the tent, so she does not, mother.
I will see how she is doing.
Come, mother.
I can stand up.
Thank you.
My God, forgive me.
Forgive me first
so that your subjects
may share your mercy.
Let a drop of your mercy
fall in their hearts.
Amen.
May God accept your prayers.
Thank you, mother.
I thought I should check on you.
Thank you so much, mother.
Come, please sit down.
Selcan.
This tribe has been through so much.
Repelled so many enemies.
But none of them
hurt us as much as what you have done.
Thence, you should not expect people
to forgive you any time soon.
Whatever I say would be in vain, mother.
You are right.
But...
...what worries me the most is Gundogdu.
Will he marry?
Will he divorce me, mother?
If he does so,
send me away from the tribe.
From now on, it is Gundogdu's decision.
Do not expect anything from us.
Selcan, my daughter!
Are you alright?
I do not know, mother.
I hope I am not with child, mother.
What is it, father?
We came here to spare our Alps
at the base camp from sorrow, my son.
Father?
You should not have come like this.
If the Alps aren't led by a Bey
willing to be martyred
the battle would be fought in vain,
my son.
Besides, isn't it fate
what protects one from his death?
Look for any sleeping guards,
these Turks are unpredictable.
As you command, knight Cladius.
Ertugrul Bey, Omer is giving us the sign.
They are sending a messenger
from the castle.
Turgut, tell the Alps
to keep their eyes peeled.
Even if an ant leaves that castle
you will bring it to me.
As you command, my Bey.
What are you up to, Cladius?
We must stop Titus' messengers
at all costs.
I desire to fulfil this task,
with your permission.
Go at once, son.
Turgut, prepare the horses.
We will be moving.
-As you command, Bey.
I thought I should check the premises.
These Turks are desperate enough to
climb up the walls.
It would be better if I get some sleep.
Good night to you, sir.
And to you.
Cladius.
Bey, what if those wretches
have managed to escape?
They are without horses, Bamsi.
They cannot get too far.
This way.
Your success of being a disciple of Arabi
will open many doors
for our fight against the Islamic world.
We are not rivals anymore.
I thought I should check the premises.
Have you been wounded by this dagger,
Cladius?
The dagger you killed my knight with.
Why did you do this? Why?
There is no deity but God and
Mohammad is His prophet and subject.
Hamza, how are we standing?
Armors, quivers, ropes and swords
are all ready, Bey.
We loaded them all and lack nothing.
Great!
Thence, we will be on our way.
So that we can share in the glory of
this holy conquest.
Move along, cartwright!
Come on Alps, in the name of God!
Come on, in the name of God!
Gundogdu Bey!
What do you want, Selcan?
You are going to battle.
You may never return or find me if you do.
I wanted to see you one last time,
before you go.
You have crushed my beating heart, Selcan.
I didn't do anything to
deserve all this.
I have nothing more to say to you.
Have mercy, Gundogdu.
Mercy.
Selcan.
I kneel before you.
I disregarded my honor, I beg you.
Please forgive me.
Selcan!
It is over, understand this.
If I become a martyr in the battle
I give you my blessing.
Farewell.
Come on!
Turgut.
Search this one.
We have found the letter!
Come on, we are leaving.
Cladius! Cladius!
Damned man!
If Ertugrul knows where
the sealed tunnel is
it must be Isadora who informed him.
Then he is aware of the second tunnel.
Only I knew where that tunnel is.
It isn't possible for Cladius
to reveal it's location.
We cannot be sure
of anything anymore, Titus.
If your messenger can not reach
the County of Antioch
we will all die in here.
I shall leave with Yigit, right away.
You cannot get out of this siege alive.
Besides you don't have a horse.
I will take my chances.
Are you that much afraid Cardinal?
Jesus shall protect us.
I cannot leave it to Jesus, Titus.
He seems too busy with fools like you.
As you wish.
If you want to leave so much...
Sir, Ertugrul is approacing the castle
with three of his Alps.
Send the knights to the
sealed tunnel immediately.
Turks may try to get in through there.
-As you command, sir.
A single Turk outsmarted all of you.
Incompetent fools!
What do you want, Turk?
I brought back the letter
you sent to the Crusaders.
You will not survive this, Titus.
There is no escape.
Those walls will be your gravestones.
This is my present for you, Turk.
You may bury your first carcass.
Then I willl bury you one by one.
Now take your erratic renegade and go back
to hell where you came from.
I swear to God I shall kill you, Titus.
I shall not let you die on your own!
Your brother Dundar also said the same.
And you know what happened to him.
Dundar has healed, you ignoble!
You are inglorious enough to try to kill
a little boy
and incapable enough to succeed in that.
I will make you pay
for what you have done.
Inform Ertugrul Bey.
The castle is ready.
Someone is approaching!
Remove the bodies.
Kill him if he makes any trouble.
We have much to travel yet.
I cannot deal with this kid.
With the name of God.
Great God!
Great God! With the name of God!
We cannot reach the base camp in time
at this pace, my Bey.
The rest of the road is inclined,
the wagon should go faster.
We cannot leave our Alps without
water and bread or supplies.
Isn't this Shahzada Yigit's belt, my Bey?
-Are you certain?
-I am, my Bey.
It is as if he left us a trail on purpose.
Was not the Shahzada a prisoner
in the castle?
Someone may want to smuggle the Shahzada.
These tracks are fresh.
They are five or six people.
They had gone that way.
Tell the wagon to go to Suleyman Shah's
base camp, and we shall trace them.
Come on.
-Alright, my Bey.
You keep moving for Suleyman Shah's
base camp, come on!
Let's go.
Let us go back.
Were you escaping somewhere,
Cardinal Thomas?
Turns out we are destined to encounter.
He drank from the fountain of martyrdom.
God's glory is great.
He succeeded in this trial called life
with his honor.
He found the true way in his last days
and become a martyr on this path.
For this, we do not deem him as dead.
He is one of the alive in God's presence.
Amen!
We gave our first martyr.
He shall be the last one if God permits.
If God permits.
Wild Demir is coming.
I hope matters are fortunate, Wild Demir.
Not so fortunate, Bey.
They noticed that we found out
about the tunnels.
They demolished and sealed them again.
As you see, we have no chance
of getting through there.
There must be a way to enter this castle.
We must find the second tunnel.
Some way...
There must be a second way
to enter that castle.
Son.
Do not give rein to anger,
it is God who grants victory.
If we are destined to conquer
no one can stand in our way.
There is a way to enter the castle!
Brother!
Yigit!
-Ertugrul brother!
-My lad!
How are you, my lad? How did you escape
from the castle?
Shahzada.
Gundogdu, how did this happen?
The Cardinal, Bey, the Cardinal.
We caught him trying to kidnap Yigit.
Where is that demon?
Do not worry, my brother.
He is in the hands of our Alps,
carrying the supplies.
He shall be coming with them.
In short, there are news that our Shahzada
shall give you.
My Shahzada.
I know where the second tunnel is.
Cardinal Thomas tried to smuggle me
from there.
Brother!
My lion!
You came as a godsend.
Omer...
...you did not die for nothing, my lad.
You did not die for nothing.
This is it.
Take revenge for our Alps they killed
for Isadora and his father
for what they have done
to Turgut brother and to my father,
Ertugrul brother.
May God help you.
No one can defeat as, long as we have
brave sons as you, with God's help.
Come on Kursad's brave sons.
Let us show them the might of Kayi tribe.
Peace be upon you. Peace be upon you.
Get out of here, come!
Come, get out of here!
Come. Come.
Come.
Come, get out of here!
May God bless you! May God bless you!
Take these ones out. Out, out!
-May God protect you, young man.
-May God bless you.
Thank you. Go now. Go now. Go now.
Go now, take these ones out.
I will send new messengers
to the Principality of Antioch.
What if you cannot succeed in this too?
I will do everything I can for you to
escape from the second tunnel, Ricardo.
Kayi tribe has entered the castle, sir.
How? How is this possible?
They had found the second tunnel.
Cardinal Thomas, I should not have
sent you from there.
You coward!
Allahu akbar!
-God is only!
-God is one!
Allahu akbar!
-Allahu akbar!
Allahu akbar! Allahu akbar!
Allahu akbar!