episode 10 will start after 12:5 Minute
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
KAYI TRIBE
This is all, Mother Hayme.
Thank you for your efforts.
Go and rest now, we will manage the rest.
Fatma.
If we could sell these
in the Aleppo market.
The market in Aleppo is
a death market, mother.
While there is so much turmoil,
is that even possible?
Ertugrul will set everything right.
He has overcome so many things.
They say that he barely escaped
the hangman's noose of the Ameer.
What problem can he set right?
Let him return to his tribe
safe and sound first.
Gokce.
Yes, Mother Hayme?
-Can you tell Aykiz to come and see me?
-Yes, of course.
Your work and efforts
of one long year lies here.
I would not let them go to waste.
Tomorrow is Friday.
May it be a blessed day, if God permits.
Do not think evil.
Understood?
Do not think...
...so that our men can trust us.
Come on now, we have a lot of work to do.
Come on.
I was looking for you everywhere, Aykiz.
Mother Hayme would like to see you.
Aykiz, that is enough,
pull yourself together.
Tell me how to do it as well. Go on.
We both know what Ertugrul
is after in Aleppo...
...after abandoning Turgut to infidels.
-How can I pull myself together, Gokce?
-Aykiz, what are you saying?
What am I saying, Gokce?
I see that your sister was
right to be angry about Ertugrul.
She knew where this thing might lead to...
...but we were blind.
What thing?
You know who I am talking about, Gokce.
Halime.
Aykiz...
...are you out of your mind?
What are you doing?
Look...
Turgut's, Ertugrul's...
...and the tribe's fate depends
on this woman.
The woman is not talking,
Ertugrul is still in a dungeon at Aleppo.
Father, we should not have left
my brother in that palace all alone.
What were we going to do, Gundogdu?
Were we going to attack Aleppo?
The tribe has not settled yet.
Most of the people are still
on the road, tired and hungry.
Do the Alps have the strength
to swing a sword?
Are we going to go against
the big Aleppo army with 2000 braves?
Ertugrul will succeed in coming out of
the labyrinth he is in, with God's help.
But...
...the real problem is what to do next.
We set on the road as we thought
we would suffer too much in the winter.
But the land we arrived
is a worse hell than the one before.
Karatoygar will not give up his pursuit.
Crusader infidels on one side
and El Aziz on the other.
May God help us.
El Aziz cannot go to war without me.
Neither him or Nasir would dare to.
They cannot persuade the soldiers
who are loyal to me.
Vizier...
...if your soldiers
could show some courage...
...when you were
kneeling in front of an axe...
...Ertugrul would be with us now.
Does the Oghuz tradition include
talking without knowing the facts?
We are not going to learn
the Oghuz tradition from...
...the servants of Ayubi palaces, vizier.
As Ertugrul Bey said,
if the infidels' woman infiltrated...
...your palace from top to bottom,
you have long lost Aleppo.
That is enough.
The situation is known by all.
What is the use of fighting
each other like jackals?
We may be attacked any moment.
Tell Wild Demir to ready
the weapons as soon as possible.
The tribe shall take warring position.
We will have
a headquarter meeting tomorrow.
ALEPPO
Faster!
No one can stick a knife at my throat
in my palace. You shall die, Turkmen.
If you were my enemy,
you would have lost your head a long ago.
Moreover this is not a palace,
it is a Templar's nest.
Your coffin will come out of this palace.
Faster!
Throw down your sword, Turkmen.
If you even spill a drop of
his highness the Ameer's blood...
...I swear that you won't see
the daylight once again.
I am Bey of Kayi,
Suleyman Shah's son Ertugrul.
Our sword does not spill
the blood of Muslim Aleppo Ameer.
Take your guards away so
that I can go to my tribe.
Go on!
Quick, run!
It is no use...
...give up now.
Only your dead body can leave the palace.
We die on a horse in moorlands,
let a Kayi die in a palace once.
Stop right there!
Stay there!
Your highness!
Sir! Your highness!
Don't stop, catch that Turkmen! Quick!
Sir, get up!
Your highness. Wake up!
Sir?
Sir, get up.
Get up.
You fool.
Open the door! Open it!
We know that you are inside!
Open the door!
He is getting away.
Quick, inform the guards!
Permission!
Halime!
Halime, are you fine, my girl?
Are you well?
I apologize for the bother
caused by a goat herder, my Sultan.
My sister...
...Leila. My precious sister.
Piece of my moon.
Leila!
Are you alright?
Save your tyranny to your enemies,
your highness.
My precious sister has become a toy
in the hand of a Turkmen who turned...
...turned the corridors of our palace into
bloody ditches and collaborated with...
...Crusaders and all other infidels
to attack the Muslim world!
It is a lie! That is far from the truth!
I understand now. The woman at my traitor
Uncle Sahabettin's execution was...
...no one but you! I am sure of that.
You are the only unsure one, right?
My precious sister Leila.
Your highness, we are guests here.
But this does not refrain us
from stating the truth.
Leila Hatun speaks of the truth.
Then tell me...
...what is the truth?
Ertugrul is not an enemy or a traitor
collaborating with the Crusaders.
He rescued us from the Templars.
What?
Leila?
Leila will never set
her foot out of this room ever again.
Understood?
Never again!
Do you understand me clearly, Nasir?
If you ever fail again...
...I will kill and
hang your body on El Aziz's balcony.
I would do this. I swear!
How do you know that
Eftelya is in the tribe?
They know that they cannot
even breathe in Aleppo.
The tribe is their only refuge.
If Eftelya talks, Aleppo would fall.
We can never allow that.
Send one of your best man to the tribe.
Eftelya must die.
-I am going, Dogan.
-Bamsi.
How much longer are we going to sit?
Are we going to sit and get fat like
a breeding stock?
You mountain bear, what did our Bey say?
Didn't he tell us to wait?
Turgut is not with us,
Ertugrul Bey is not with us.
With what face will we go back
to the tribe?
How are we going to look
in the eyes of Aykiz and our Bey?
What will we say to Mother Hayme?
Bey?
My brothers.
Thank you Great God.
We saw our Bey once again.
Where is that woman called Esma?
Suleyman Shah sent her to the tribe
with the vizier, just in case.
We need to make that woman talk
in order to save Turgut and the tribe.
I missed my own sword.
Give Suleyman Shah three days.
If they do not leave our lands
I shall send our armies, your highness.
I know that my uncle is there as well,
hiding amongst the Kayis.
Do you think the soldiers would attack
while my uncle is there, Nasir?
Don't you know how loyal they are to him.
A finger cut by the sharia law
does not hurt.
Of course, they will all be punished
for what they did.
A blood to be spilled
cannot stay in the veins.
Dear God.
Help me keep my sanity.
It is so easy to lose one's mind.
I never felt so desperate in my life.
But we have a big opportunity
in our hands, your highness.
The Seljuk Shahzade and his daughter.
If you wed with the Shahzade's daughter...
...no one can stand against your power.
Then, Seljuk intrusions at our borders and
recklessness of the Templars would end.
You should take up this opportunity,
your highness.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS TEMPLARS CASTLE
You were right, sir.
They managed to infiltrate even here.
The newcomers.
I want both of them, Marcus.
Dead or alive.
Leila...
Governess, you betrayed Leila
whom you raised since she was a baby.
I did what was right.
For you and your brother.
We will all pay for your mistake.
Now, please go away.
I don't want to see you.
Permission?
Shahzade, the Ameer is expecting you.
Your daughter as well.
I will put you in a special room
for your safety, Shahzade.
Who are you protecting us from,
your highness?
From traitor Templars
and their collaborators.
What about Ertugrul?
You witnessed what he did
in my palace as well, Halime Sultan.
Nothing is as it is seen, your highness.
Is there anything
you want to talk with me, your highness?
If you give permission, yes.
I am listening.
Against this evil pact...
...against my emirate and
the whole Muslim world...
...I plan to start a big war.
That is why, I request your help.
I would do all I can, your highness.
In order to show
our alliance against friends and foe...
...with your permission, Shahzade...
...I want to marry your daughter.
Catch them!
Run, Afsin Bey, run. Finish your mission.
Do not leave our Shahzade to them.
Attack!
You two, that way!
You, that way!
Problem is not only Turgut.
Nor it is Kayis.
We fell into a big trap
set for the Muslim world.
Dying is a duty for all of us.
It is not right to cry after a martyr.
If he is living, to go and get Turgut
out of that castle is our duty.
But...
...if he is dead...
...then the duty is to take his revenge.
Understood?
-We understand, Bey.
Let us go and get benediction
from Ibn Arabi before leaving.
He left for Jerusalem, Bey.
He said that he would pray for us.
Alright.
Prepare quickly, we shall leave.
One of the traitors have been killed,
the other ran away, sir.
We will catch him as soon as possible.
Water only spends itself after a storm.
Marcus, Cardinal Thomas...
...should not know about this.
Come this way.
I am your only hope.
Quick.
Come on, my children, find that traitor!
Guard all the exits of the castle!
Bring him to me!
If someone does a favor to me without
a reason, it means I am in trouble.
It is not without a reason.
“Do not ask for help from infidels...
...who have strayed from the path of God”
says our holy book.
-Then...
-Wasn't Judas an apostle as well?
It is not known whether betrayal
or salvation comes from friend or foe.
You tell me then.
My uncle keeps my father
in a dark dungeon within this castle.
Why?
-Because he became a Muslim.
-What?
Are you telling me that
Ustad's brother is a Muslim now, woman?
Mohiddin Al Arabi from Andalusia...
...converted my father into Islam.
That is why my uncle is keeping him
in the dungeons.
My dear Isadora.
Beautiful Isadora.
Alone and innocent
just like our Virgin Mary.
I don't think your uncle would object to,
you coming to Constantinople with me.
My only wish is to complete my prayers
without getting out of this castle.
Even if the barbarians
are at your borders?
-Which barbarians?
-Kayis, Isadora. Turks.
The killers of your father.
I will wait for you.
It is not a problem for me.
Please help me.
Save me from this madhouse.
My Turgut.
Aykiz. My Aykiz.
Turgut.
My Turgut.
Aykiz.
My Aykiz.
Why? Aykiz?
Aykiz?
Aykiz!
Aykiz! Aykiz!
My brave, get a hold of yourself, my lion!
Are you well, my child?
Do not let yourself go.
Be strong.
A girl came to me.
He asked about an old man in the dungeon.
His name was Giovanno...
Giovanna...
Was it Giovanni?
Yes! Yes!
Was the girl's name Isadora?
Yes, Isadora.
How do you know her?
I am Giovanni and she is my daughter.
May God bless you.
Do not put God's name on your tongue.
I am innocent. I am innocent!
Someone must have tricked Ertugrul Bey.
If you don't tell me where my Turgut is...
...I will kill you here.
They are not touching you as you are
a woman, they are not torturing you...
...but you cannot deceive me
with this naive woman act.
You lowlife,
you will regret the day you were born.
Now tell me where the hideout of these
spineless creatures called Templars is.
Tell me!
Why don't you understand?
I am just a mere servant.
How can I know where their hideout...
If I knew, for the life of your brave...
Do not put my brave's name on your tongue
either, tell me where Turgut is!
Tell me, tell me!
All I know is... All I know...
They do very bad things
to the enemies they capture.
They pluck their meat out while alive
and feed them to the dogs and ravens.
And throw the rest into bugs.
Not only for myself,
I shall pray for your brave as well.
I pray to God that he is not
a prisoner of them. I pray to God!
You are lying! You are lying!
-I'm going to kill you! Kill you!
-Aykiz!
-Aykiz! Aykiz! Aykiz!
-Tell me! I am going to kill you!
-Come here!
-You are going to die!
-Enough!
-I am going to kill you!
While you die,
you will wish that I do it fast!
-Come here! Come on!
-Leave me alone, father!
Let me go! Let go!
Know that I will be your Azrael!
Know it well!
I wanted you to see the beauty
that I am seeing.
Is there something
you are hiding from me, father?
Is it...
...Yigit?
No, no. I am only thinking
how I can save your brother.
That is all.
Did we enter a Mongol tribe
without knowing?
What is this?
Nobody looks at us and give a reaction.
They probably forgot us
as we have been away for so long.
Ertugrul?
Welcome to your new home.
Thank you, father.
-Welcome, brother.
-Thank you, brother. Thank you.
Welcome, my son.
When you were in the mountains
all alone to become an Alp...
...when you fought with the Mongols...
...or when you were swinging
your sword against the Crusaders...
...I was never afraid.
But Aleppo is different.
I saw the betrayal there.
I was very scared that they would take you
away from me, not with their swords...
...but with their treacheries.
Thank God you have returned, my son.
Betrayal is not only
inside Aleppo, mother.
Some people killed our Alps
and falsely accused me.
Who is that person, father?
Kurdoglu.
I told him to rethink his words.
We shall ask him today
in the headquarter meeting.
Let us see whether he is insistent
on his claim.
Even if he is,
let him say it directly to your face.
Bey...
...Kurdoglu said what he said. Those
ominous words spilled from his mouth.
-Ertugrul, get out now!
-How dare you come to the tribe!
-You shall pay for what you did!
-Come out and face us!
Ertugrul!
This is my problem, father.
Rahman...
...allow them to come in.
-As you wish, Bey!
How could you spill
the blood of your brothers, Ertugrul?
-Where are our braves?
-Our sons are gone!
Where are our lions?
Why did you kill our Alps, Bey?
I heard that...
...someone presumptuous has put
a smear on our foreheads.
As if this was not enough,
with false witnesses and fake evidence...
...he added more lies to his lies!
If he was not aware of what he said,
the sin is on him.
But...
...if he was slandering on purpose...
...a day will come...
...where his throat would meet my hand.
What is the claim?
That I killed the Alps whom I fought side
by side against the pagan Mongols...
...and the infidel Crusaders.
And what for?
For nothing.
Slander makes a brave hard.
It strengthens his faith.
But...
...for some brothers
believing this slander...
...is what really hurts my heart.
And that hurt does not go away.
The truth is that...
...God is Great...
...and The Sole Avenger.
If there is still someone
who believes that this slander is true...
...he can pick up my sword...
...and cut off my head right here and now.
I would not even move a hair.
Instead of breathing the same air and
stepping on the same ground with them...
...I would prefer to die.
And my blood is halal to them.
Well done, Titus.
If you succeed in this...
What does Titus say, sir?
He wrote that it is time to make Ayubis
and the Seljuk fight with each other.
El Aziz and Halime.
He invited us to their wedding
that shall last 40 days and 40 nights.
Did you find that spy?
There is no way out for him.
Sooner or later, he shall get out of
the rat hole he hides in.
In the 99 names of our Great God,
Who creates with only saying “let be”...
...Who fills our hearts with faith.
In the name of God, most Merciful
and most Graceful. Please...
While I was laying on my sickbed...
...the unity and solidarity
of our tribe was damaged.
It is so sorrowful that
on one side my sons...
...on the other side my blood brother...
...accused each other in my marquee.
When dark clouds gathered
above our tribe...
...instead of standing straight
and keeping silent...
...they started arguing like women!
My son Ertugrul was accused of killing
the Alps of our tribe.
What nonsense is this?
First, I would like to solve this matter.
Tell us, Kurdoglu.
Bey, we are thankful to God as you have
recovered and leading us once again.
While you were fighting for your life
in those hard days...
...your son Gundogdu,
broke the rule you have set...
...and sent Ertugrul to Aleppo.
As I did not want
your rule to be overruled...
...I sent some men after Ertugrul.
And they were all slaughtered.
And I thought it was Ertugrul's doing.
But, when I personally went to see
our martyrs with my own eyes...
...I saw that they were killed
by the Crusaders.
And this...
...is the evidence.
Gundogdu.
Bey...
...your situation was critical.
Someone had to lead the tribe.
I put my trust on the dream you saw
and sent my brother to Aleppo.
The rest is known.
We had to deal with
the false accusations of our Emmi.
My words are the last words in this tribe!
No one can say a word on top of me!
No order can be given over my order!
Let this be known!
How can one be accused without thinking
twice and without evidence, Kurdoglu?
If my time comes to an end
in this mortal world...
...what will you turn this tribe into?
I am forgiving you for one last time.
From now on,
if you act against the tradition...
...you will not have a tribe to sleep in.
Now, let us hear you out, Ertugrul.
Tell us. What is the situation?
There is a price to pay in drinking water
from the poisonous well called Aleppo.
And we shall pay
more than what it is worth.
But...
...if we do not clean this
poisonous water...
...the Muslim world will be
swept into a catastrophe.
The Crusaders are preparing
for a new campaign.
That is why the Templars are trying to
clear the road to Jerusalem.
They try to eliminate the Beys, tribes
and statesmen whom they see as a threat.
We must clean Aleppo at all costs.
What does your tongue say, Ertugrul?
Are we to solve the problem
of great big Muslim world?
While we can't even find
a quarter to spend the winter...
...you talk to us about cleaning Aleppo.
If the cries of the oppressed
would fill the skies...
...if everything that is sacred to us,
our tradition, language, religion...
...our homeland,
will be trampled upon by the tyrants...
...what is the point of having
a wintering quarter or not?
I saw that, us coming to these lands
is not without purpose.
We will either live, without letting
the tyrants crush these lands...
...or be erased from history if we bow our
heads like cowards in front of the tyrant.
That is the situation, father.
What should we do then?
Our brother Turgut is imprisoned.
Aleppo is worse than imprisonment.
We have to make a will, gird our swords
and clean both of these worlds of tyranny.
That is the situation.
Ertugrul speaks of the truth.
From now on, our swords shall be
ready for battle at all times.
We shall take a thousand lives
of those who take one life from us!
That is my final word.
-Turgut Agabey.
-Yigit.
We will save you from here.
I know, Yigit. I know.
Now listen to what I have to say.
-You know the niece of Ustad?
-You mean Isadora?
You have to tell her what I tell you.
It is very important.
Child, get away from there.
Tell her that she is right.
The man in the dungeon is her father.
I said get away from there!
Go and take him away.
He became a Muslim and
took the name of Omar.
She has to help both of us.
Do you understand, Yigit?
His highness the prince should go inside
if he wishes not to be beaten up.
What did you think
you were doing, my girl?
Do you know what Ertugrul risked
to kidnap that woman out of the palace?
What if she died?
Who goes in the front stays in Damascus,
those who go in the back stay in an inn.
That woman sees this place like an inn.
You don't beat her up because
you are men, you are brave.
You treat this lowlife woman
like a royalty.
I know the language she would understand.
Let me do what is needed.
Stop right there.
Alright, you got your wild side from me.
But, you should have gotten
the patience of your mother.
Ertugrul Bey is back.
We will see what will happen.
The situation is very complicated.
He will of course find a way to save
Turgut from that castle.
Father, how do you know that
my Turgut still lives?
That they didn't throw him in
a ditch after killing him?
How do you know that they didn't
let him rot in that ditch?
Do we have permission?
Come in, Bey.
Turgut is alive, Aykiz.
If Turgut is there,
why are you here, son of a Bey?
Does it suit a brave to sit
in his tent like a nesting bird?
-Aykiz!
-Don't stop me, father.
Let me say him a few words,
maybe I can knock some sense into him.
-I said Aykiz!
-Wild Demir...
...let her spill the beans
she has been holding inside.
Did you forget my Turgut
just so that you can go after Halime?
You can deduce a good meat in a plate,
a brave in a war...
...and a friend from their advice.
If Turgut is still alive...
...I would bring him back.
If he is dead...
...I would make them pay.
But...
...I would not a shed a tear
after a martyr.
Let this be known, Aykiz.
If you ask me why
I haven't made them pay yet...
...the answer lies in the woman
you tried to strangle last night.
The matter is not about entering
the devil's den, it is about finding it.
My problem is finding that den.
Turgut...
...is a part of me,
even more than my heart.
Let this be known.
If my brave is alive, bringing him back...
...if he is dead, putting him in a grave
is your debt to me.
I sent you to death so many times
as if it were a celebration.
I entrusted my Turgut into you.
If you rot the flesh of my Turgut
in the lands of the infidels...
...my hands would be on your neck
in this world and beyond, Ertugrul Bey.
And you let this be known.
My apologies my Bey.
Seeing you safe and sound
is more than enough for me.
Have seat.
I've never felt
this kind of difficulty in my life.
I'd know what to do if I were faced with
40 wars, 40,000 enemies...
...but this is different.
Look my daughter.
You should continue this game
with Yigit, till I get some help.
I should go and explain
everything to Ertugrul Bey.
Our salvation is with Kayis.
It is no longer possible
to move forward in the castle.
Are you going to escape?
What about my brother Turgut?
-They are going to kill him.
-Hush.
This is obligatory my Shahzade.
I must leave this bloody place
and get some help immediately.
Would there be the new without the old,
and the good without the bad?
Is it only Ertugrul
that caused us all the trouble?
Did you not see how arrogant
he was when he entered the tent?
Placing a sword in the middle of otak,
saying “cut my head off”...
Your brother has become
the bastard of the system.
The bad he does is seen as if he did good.
Oh for god's sake, enough Hatun!
When I look at you I see a sluggish man...
...as naive as a man can be.
Hatun, what do you want from me?
What is bothering you?
I see the fog on a mountain,
a snake in sight Gundogdu.
Your brother Ertugrul,
whom you love dearly...
...is on your back like a scorpion and
ready to sting when he is done with you.
When will you realise?
These are all Seigniory games.
Enough! Enough!
I am sick of your Seigniory games.
You talk like
you do not know Oguz customs.
The person who will become
the Bey is the one who deserves it.
If I deserve I will,
if Ertugrul does, he will.
That is it.
My only concern is to get
this nomad group out of trouble.
Your only concern should be
giving birth to your child.
Sister.
Gundogdu Bey was furious.
What happened?
He is just an incongruous coward.
Gokce...
...in order to obtain what is ours,
you must go to bed with Ertugrul.
Sister, what are you talking about?
I know what I am talking about.
Before Ertugrul leaves,
you will do what you have to do.
But first...
...my beautiful and foolish sister...
...be a woman. A woman.
Do you understand what I say?
Be a woman, and take your man.
Otherwise you will rot
in this nomad group.
-Sister...
-I said go Gokce. Go, go!
Hush.
I will pray for my Han
For that, the black mountains
Shall not collapse
The tree of shadows shall not be cut
The beautiful river of blood
Shall not dry
The tip of your wings
Shall not break
Your destiny
Shall not put you in despair
Your white horse's legs
Shall not sprain
My Bey.
They are going to the tent
to force that woman to speak.
So...
...we should find a way to visit
the Templar's castle, Alpargo.
They are our neighbors now, aren't they?
There is a saying:
“Neighbors need each other's ashes.”
If you are planning
to be a bitch like Baybora...
...just tell me so that we know.
If you are going to show the white
feather, just leave me alone now.
Leave and herd your goats.
We are on our way my Bey.
We always keep our promises.
You'd better Alpargo.
You'd better.
Ertugrul?
You are surprised to see me, aren't you?
Thank God I have seen you
safe and sound my Bey.
You are the only one
who can save me from this disgrace.
What a coincidence,
I thought the same thing for you.
Don't do this, my Bey.
How could you think like that about me?
I am just an ordinary odalisque.
It is the same talk since this morning.
She didn't say anything else.
If you weren't a woman,
I'd know how to make you speak.
You made so many
sacrifices to catch her...
...bu she did not speak Ertugrul Bey.
Ertugrul.
All those years you have
been looking into my eyes...
...and betraying me?
Ata Bey, we need her alive.
Did you think we would allow you...
...to come from the steppes of Asia
and settle down in our holy land?
We won't stop until
we bury you in the desert...
...like all the other Muslims on earth.
You, horde of bastards!
You will all die!
Do not worry.
I will make her speak, sooner or later.
Even if it requires me
to cut my own tongue with my teeth...
...I would do it...
...but you will not hear a word from me.
You are not going to
make me speak Ertugrul.
O God!
Staying in Aleppo did you no good Bamsi.
You forgot how to fight.
So you think you can
beat Bamsi with moves like that?
You big head Bamsi, big head Bamsi!
The heroes are feeling alive.
Go on Bamsi!
Come on Hamza.
Knock that big head Bamsi down!
God is one and only, Bamsi!
It was me who first suggested
going to Aleppo first.
I went mad when my father
told me you were going.
You should have seen me.
I felt like a child
who stole his older brother's toys.
But now I know...
...my father's dream came true.
Thank god.
Perhaps none of these would have happened
if you were the one to go to Aleppo.
None of us will ever know this Ertugrul.
But there is something that I am sure of.
Whatever the cost is, we must find
a way to remain at this heavenly land.
Otherwise the Kayi Tribe won't survive.
They would exterminate us.
The only place
we can go is the desert after all.
Neither our animals nor us
can survive in the desert.
So, we need to
find a way to get over these...
...what the hell
they are called, the Templars.
This land will never
be truly ours, brother.
We will not find peace
until we establish...
...our own state on our own land.
So as soon as possible, we must
give these Templar's game away...
...which works against not only us
but also the whole Muslim world.
How will it be possible?
For the sake of Ucler,
Yediler, Kirklar my poet...
...tell us about our peer Ahmed Yesevi
so that all our hearts could warm.
So that we can feel our holy prophet...
...may God honor him
and grant him peace...
...is with us.
As I am burning with
The love of Muhammad
I am madly deeply following
The path of Muhammad
As I am burning with the love of
Muhammad
I am madly deeply following
the path of Muhammad
All the Islamic ummah is thankful
And praising Muhammad
I pray endlessly to God the almighty
For there shall be no love
in my heart other than Muhammad's
As I am burning with the love of
Muhammad
I am madly deeply following
the path of Muhammad
I choose to be possessed
By madness for Muhammad
And I, Yesevi the sluggard
Beg for mercy from Muhammad
As I am burning with the love of
Muhammad
I am madly deeply following
the path of Muhammad
As I am burning with the love of
Muhammad
I am madly deeply following
the path of Muhammad
Ertugrul.
Halime.
I'd like to talk to you.
I am listening Gokce.
I am not sure if my words would be
appropriate on these hard days...
...but our sorrow gets deeper
since we both are quiet.
-I...
-Ertugrul.
If you excuse me, I just
want you to listen to me.
Neihter your parents' decision...
...nor anything else I care about.
There is something I want you to know.
I have been in love
with you since I was a child.
All my life, I have always loved you.
You can say it is
a foolish or childish thing.
But it is what it is.
I will not...
...let Halime or anybody take away
this beautiful pain within me.
If necessary, I will
wait for you till the day I die.
While your heart is burning with
the dream of that Shahzade's daughter...
...my heart will be burning here with you.
This is my reality.
And I will not let
anybody take it from me.
I don’t want you to feel sorry or pity me.
I just wanted you to know all about it.
That is it.
May I come in Sister Gokce?
Come in Aga.
I don't know if I should be happy or sad.
You and Ertugrul
grew up together before my eyes.
While I was bringing two hearts up...
...I wasn't aware they were bitter.
I...
...have always loved
Ertugrul all my life long.
I was loving him...
...even when my father's blood was all
around the otak because of Suleyman Shah.
I loved him even I knew
he was not so keen on me.
He did not even notice me.
I was worthless than his horse's tail.
Even though, I loved him.
I loved him till that girl,
he did not even know or recognize arrived.
It is fine that
you don’t love him anymore.
I wish it was so.
Now, I am hurt each and every other day.
Woe, my heartsore Sister.
The bastards you were protecting
came here to kill you.
Will you go on protecting them?
Since it is a war they are after...
...they will get what they want.
Since they want to exterminate us...
...we will fight till we all die.
Tell me Bamsi...
...where do know this man from?
Your memory is impressive!
Remember, we were
chatting with Ibn'ul Arabi...
...and then this merchant
came, he sat with us.
Aha! He came when Ibn'ul Arabi
was talking about the devil.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
I am looking for a man named Kurdoglu.
Would you tell me where he is, Blacksmith?
I would but you might
curse me when you find him.
Excuse me?
I am not good at your language.
It is okay, you needn't understand.
You see that tent? He is over there.
Thanks.
I was wondering where you have been.
So, now we are like neighbors.
So I came to say welcome.
Welcome to you also, Titus.
Ebu Hisham.
Your presence is
a pleasure for us Ebu Hisham.
We completed all the arrangements.
The Alps are positioned
around the nomad group.
Rahman, they sneaked
in the nomad group twice.
They spread the plague.
This became a miserable place.
If they sneak in for the third time...
...I will hand not only you
but also all the guards..
...over to the Reaper myself.
Do you hear me?
May we come in my Bey?
My Bey, I brought you the most honorable
merchant of Aleppo, Ebu Hisham.
He is welcomed here.
But when did you get to know the
honorable merchants of Aleppo, Kurdoglu?
My Bey, while you were
busy dealing with the troubles...
...Ebu Hisham came
to visit our nomad group.
It was a difficult journey,
but you have arrived here safe and sound.
Your presence is a blessing for this land.
Thank you, Merchant. Thank you!
The souks of Aleppo will be very
lively with the goods of your nomad group.
My desire is to work togetger
to give joy to your souks and Aleppo.
We wanted to visit you in Aleppo,
but we could not find any traces of you.
I was away for finding
new goods for a long time.
You shared your bread with me.
I can never forget your good fellowship.
We are the heralds of the Ameer of Aleppo.
We have come to talk with Suleyman Shah.
Heralds have come from Aleppo, my Bey!
Let them in.
May I have your permission to leave?
Come on, Commander.
We have come to inform you about the order
of his highness Ameer of Aleppo El Aziz.
I am listening to you.
“I order you to leave...
...this land, which you have occupied
through craft and force, in three days.
Otherwise, you should know that my army...
...will slaughter you all
with their swords, Suleyman Shah.
This is my last warning.”
I suppose there is someone
important in that tent.
An dangerous woman is staying in it.
How many soldiers
does he have in his army?
Even the number of his palace guards are
over than the number of our men, father.
Praise to God, we are like in heaven.
The Templars at night,
El Aziz in the morning.
We must find a way to convince El Aziz.
My Bey, I learned that my brother's
nomad group is in the Seljuk border.
We can ask for help from him.
You know, he would give his life to you.
I know.
He would do it.
He would also come
with his soldiers but this is our war.
We must find another solution.
We must solve this matter
without shedding any blood.
There is a way, father.
Thank you.
Enjoy it Ertugrul Bey.
I am going to visit El Aziz.
Are you aware of what you just said, son?
I am aware, father.
I am going to bring
one of our guests with me.
The Templar's spy, who he thinks
is an odalisque in the palace.
Are you going to take Esma to the palace?
She can not deny the tattoo on her nape.
If we can manage to
take her to the palace soundly...
...we will be able to give
the Templar's game away.
My Bey, while we were trying
to get rid of Kara Toygar trouble...
...we bumped into Nasir trouble.
Unless we kill
Suleyman Shah and his sons...
...God knows what other
troubles we will bump into.
So what are we going to do, my Bey?
We will do what needs to be done, Alpargo.
What ever needs to be done.
Finally you have
the courage to confront me, huh?
You used that sorcerer whore
called Yiva to kill my baby, Kurdoglu.
And then, you killed Yiva.
She deserved to die, just like you do.
You broke our deal, Selcan Hatun.
When I went to kill Suleyman Shah,
you sent your husband after to kill me.
You'd kill two birds with one stone.
I did not realize how inept you are.
Anyway, as your baby is still alive...
...we are not that late to make peace.
Yes, if we collaborate...
What do you want from me?
I want my father's revenge
to be taken, Kurdoglu.
I was also there
when your father's blood...
...was dripping all around
from Suleyman's sword.
I did everything to stop him.
But Suleyman is a ruthless man.
Your father was more
than a brother to me, Selcan.
So, you will do
what needs to be done, Kurdoglu.
What about Gundogdu?
We will also talk about it
when the right time comes.
Now, you have a task to complete.
An important task which you have
to complete without messing up.
Ertugrul is going to Aleppo,
and he is taking that woman with him.
Where are they going to?
To the palace.
I am coming with you to Aleppo.
Brother.
At least one person should stay
in the nomad group with our father.
If we can not take
that woman there soundly...
...we will no longer have
a father or a nomad group to return.
As soon as I finish this task,
I will be going to the Templar’s castle.
Do you know what
you are talking about, son?
If Turgut is alive...
...I must bring him back.
But if not...
...if he is dead...
...I must take his revenge.
It is not that easy to go in there.
Let’s say you got in. You can't go out.
I request that you write
a short letter to those bastards.
It is not decent to drop by
without letting them know.
They should know that I am coming...
...in order to make
necessary preparations.
The good guest
is the one who informs first.
These are the best textiles I have seen.
It has been years
since I saw colors as vibrant as these.
Especially these rugs and carpets...
God bless.
Actually I wasn't expecting
them to be this good, Mother Hayme.
Thank you, Ebu Hisham.
It is the same technique that our
ancestors used throughout the centuries.
Without changing it, without any cheats.
That is why you have
a good reputation where ever you go.
Although I heard that things
did not go so well for you in Aleppo.
I have just arrived from Aleppo.
Everybody is talking about
the things a Kayi Bey’s son did.
He delved among the entire city.
Anyway, let’s get to business.
Those things do not concern me.
You certainly deserve the price you asked.
It is the reward of your labor.
However, the famine affected everybody.
If you excuse me...
...this is the last amount remaining.
If you accept...
...we can have a deal today
for 640 gold coins, not for 800.
Although Suleyman Shah sent you to me...
...I must consult our Bey.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Ebu Hisham, if you excuse me,
I will take you to our Bey.
You can deliberate
this subject with him too.
Let’s go.
-I have good news for you, Titus.
-I am listening to you Kurdoglu.
Ertugrul is going on a journey
with his Alps tomorrow.
Where are they going to?
The woman who works for you,
what was her name...
...Esma.
They are going to take her
to Aleppo, to El Aziz.
Did something happen, uncle?
We are going to have a guest soon.
So, come on Ertugrul.
I’m waiting for you to come.
The Master should know that Eftelya
is being taken to Aleppo by Ertugrul.
When will you tell me
the things hidden inside you?
Is not, what we both gone
through for days, enough?
I beg you to talk to me, father.
Halime.
El Aziz told me that
he wanted you as his wife.
What are you saying, father?
I decided that this is
the right thing for all of us.
This is the first time
I am asking something from you.
You must accept this proposal...
...not only for yourself but also
for the goodness of your brother.
Gundogdu.
Where are you going?
To Aleppo.
-Ertugrul was supposed to go.
-We decided to go together.
No way!
I can’t let you leave nomad group.
Our Bey has regained his health, Hatun.
The matter is not your father,
it is Ertugrul.
What did Ertugrul do again?
He is a sinister man,
who brings trouble to where ever he goes.
He will also cause you
unexpected troubles.
-I do not want you to go with him.
-All right, enough!
I am fed up with your sickly behavior.
I beg you, please do not go.
You can never know what
will happen if you follow him.
Gundogdu, I beg you.
Do not leave me alone with my baby.
Do not do this to us.
I beg you, please.
Hatun.
I have to go for you,
for our baby, for our nomad group.
I can’t leave Ertugrul alone.
No.
I don’t want you to go.
I beg you, do not go.
Please don’t leave us alone.
Don’t go please.
Hatun, enough!
You can’t go!
I say, you can’t go, Gundogdu!
Gundogdu, stop.
You can’t go, I beg you!
-Let go of me!
-No, Gundogdu!
Let go of me Selcan! Hatun!
I beg you, don’t go!
Please don’t go, Gundogdu!
Selcan?
Father.
I beg you father, do not let Gundogdu go.
Stop them, I beg you.
Selcan, what happened?
No, you can’t let them, father.
You can’t let them go.
Do not let Gundogdu march on to die!
Selcan, what is all this muttering about?
Is there something
you know but can’t tell?
Just say it.
Is there something that you know,
something you heard or you suspect?
Father.
Speak I say!
Speak!
You annoyed me and now you are silent.
Tell me what is bothering you?
Speak!
What happened to my sons?