Episode 20 will start after 12:16 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Kayi Tent
Help me!
Please help! Gundogdu!
Selcan Hatun!
Hamza, go and get help!
Gundogdu is dying!
Ertugrul Bey!
What is it, Hamza?
Gundogdu Bey is dying.
I am going let Suleyman Shah know.
Brother!
Selcan, what happened to my brother?
I found him like that. Please save him.
Do not let him die. God take my life!
-What is it? Ertugrul, what is it?
-Hamza...
Let us carry him to Akcakoca's.
-Tell the Alps to bring a stretcher.
-Yes, Bey.
God, take my life instead of his!
Mother, take her out.
-No, I am not going anywhere!
-Come on, brother.
-No! Please do not die!
-Selcan!
Come on, brother.
Come on!
Press on him!
Son!
-Gundogdu!
-Come on, brother! Press!
Son!
Son, do not give up.
My brave son. Hang in there.
Do not give up.
He will be alright.
-My girl...
-Let go of me!
Selcan, let them do their work!
Selcan, wait.
-Hold on, girl.
-Gundogdu!
Gundogdu!
-Selcan!
-Gundogdu!
What happened to him?
What did you do to him?
Do not worry. He is breathing.
-Selcan, wait, you are going to fall!
-Gundogdu!
Selcan!
Ertugrul and Halime
gave the breath he lost back.
Relax. Go to your tent with Mother Hayme.
Pull yourself together.
-We are already in a lot of pain.
-Let them do their work.
-Come on, let us go.
-No!
-I will stay by him. Let go of me!
-Selcan!
-No you cannot!
-I will stay by him!
Selcan!
Help me.
-Selcan Hatun.
Let go of me.
It is okay.
-Let me go, mother.
-Selcan, it is okay.
-Come on.
-Let me go.
Come on, girl. Come on.
So, you wanted to play a game with me,
Suleyman Shah and his sons.
I will show you what it means
to play with Kurdoglu.
What is it?
Gundogdu's Alp, Hamza
saw me getting out of the tent.
He can go to hell.
Allow me and I kill him, too.
Or I will be in trouble eventually.
No. We will draw more attention that way.
You will go to Duru Su Pass.
I will send them there
if they come after you.
How can I fight them by myself, Bey?
Do not worry. You will not be alone.
I will ensure your safety.
And here is your award.
Gundogdu!
Selcan...
Selcan, my girl...
Gundogdu is in safe hands.
But you must pull yourself together.
What happened to my man, mother?
Such a strong man,
withered up like an autumn leave.
We will find out about it.
Just some patience.
First my Gokce, then my Gundogdu.
What happened to us, mother?
I am begging you, tell me.
Selcan...
...do not let your anger poison you.
I remember the day
you came to the marquee with Gokce.
We were scared.
I was a child.
We were lonely.
We were desperate.
You brought us up like your own children.
You did not leave us alone.
I did not want to increase
hatred with hatred and grudge with grudge.
I brought up two rosebuds instead.
I had four children before,
and with you, I had six.
We laughed together, we cried together.
Sister!
Gokce...
What kind of evil is this?
I think my brother has been poisoned.
That is my suspicion, as well.
But how?
There must be something in his tent.
His tent?
Halime!
Let me give him some water.
Selcan...
Here, drink some water.
Come on, baby.
No! Do not drink that water!
The water may be poisoned, mother.
Kurdoglu!
Mother, I am begging you, wait.
Let us be sure first.
Still waiting to be sure?
Ertugrul?
What happened?
I will find out
if my brother has been poisoned.
Gundogdu Bey...
Gundogdu Bey... Is he alright, Bey?
I do not know, Dogan.
Thankfully, he is breathing.
Bey, is there anything
you want to say to us?
Find me a goat, Bamsi.
I will be in the stable.
Why are you still here?
I am thinking what I will do.
Has Bey not told you to find a goat?
-There is something in his mind, right?
-Of course. Why do you ask?
-Stop it, you confused me more now.
Come on, move! Be quick.
Dogan...
There is something
I want to talk to Ertugrul Bey.
Come here.
What is going on, Bey?
-Is it true what they say about Gundogdu?
-What kind of illness is this?
A very healthy man
suddenly loses his breath.
I do not know how a heathy man
falls into this situation...
There is a catch here, Karabudak.
What do you mean, Bey?
-Do you mean...
-I would expect anything from this tent...
...as long as the Bey is Suleyman
and the poison on his tongue is Ertugrul.
This will not go on with a father
who cannot take care of his sons.
You are right, Bey.
But I do not know if there is
a brave man to bite the date...
...which has ripened and
is waiting to be bitten on the tree.
This matter will be closed sooner or
later.
Beys will have to choose their sides.
One way or another,
this matter will be closed.
We are with you, Bey.
Wait to hear from me, then.
Keep your eyes open.
I am sorry, Selcan Hatun.
They say that Ertugrul and you
saved Gundogdu's life.
He did what was necessary,
and I helped him.
How is my son?
The midwives are doing what is necessary.
Let us wait for them to do their job.
If that water was really poisoned...
...you saved my life, Halime.
I hope it was not poisoned.
What if it was?
It means that even harder days
are waiting for the tent.
God help us all.
Excuse me.
Let me go.
I am scared, father.
He looks like...
...he relapsed.
Patience, my daughter. Patience.
Thankfully, he is alive.
Isadora turned out to be wrong.
Look how he struggles to survive.
If anybody else
went through what he did...
...he was long dead.
It is his love to you
that keeps him alive.
Something happened to Gundogdu.
Go and check him out.
I will look after Turgut.
Alright, father.
I am going right away.
Turgut...
Son...
Look, you are the only person
I have in this world.
You are my brave son whom I can trust.
Think about it,
if anything happens to you...
...what would Aykiz do?
Come on, my brave son.
Break that cage.
Break it and come back to us.
Spring has come and passed.
But we could not do your wedding yet.
Alright.
Break that cage, son.
Come back to us.
Alright, Turgut. Alright.
Hamza, what did Sarikayin say?
He said that he brought the things
Selcan Hatun brought to the tent.
Get a bowl and let us test this water.
Yes, Bey.
He did not drink the water.
The water is contaminated.
Poisoned.
Sarikayin.
Let us bring him to you, Bey.
Be careful.
If Kurdoglu finds out about it...
...he will not let him live
just like Baybora.
Do not tell this to anybody.
Yes, Bey.
Bamsi, come on.
Let us keep this a secret.
Understood, Bey.
I will not even tell Selcan Hatun.
Good.
Do not leave my brother alone.
Of course, Bey.
Yigit...
Where is this boy?
Halime!
What is it?
I cannot find Yigit.
I asked every child,
and looked at every place.
What is it? Is something wrong?
I was going to give him the good news.
But it will be you who hears it first.
Do you mean...
Yes!
Halime...
Suleyman Shah allowed
Ertugrul and me to get married.
But Gundogdu Bey...
...is struggling with death.
So, Gundogdu did not die.
It is Ertugrul again.
You could not succeed one more time.
Do not worry. The Shahzade
will bring Ertugrul to you.
Gundogdu is struggling with death.
If you keep your promises...
...there will be no better opportunity
to kick Suleyman out of his marquee.
Kurdoglu, this is your last chance.
It is the last chance
for all of us, Titus.
I will lose my head unless I succeed.
But you should know that, that father and
son will bring your castle down on you...
...sooner or later if I cannot succeed.
So, both of us needs each other.
We will not leave you alone.
You know we keep our promises.
Do not worry.
Take this present to Turgut Alp.
Alright.
I have one last request from you.
Kill Sarikayin.
Kill him, so that I will not be the one
to carry the blame of being a traitor.
Aykiz...
Bamsi...
Dogan...
Brother, I cannot find your wound!
Brother Turgut...
Are you alright, brother?
Brother...
You were my brother.
And you will always
be my brother, Turgut Alp .
Brother...
Aykiz...
Bamsi...
Dogan...
Brother!
My first child.
My Gundogdu.
Hopefully, he will overcome this
with God's help.
Hang on, son.
Hang on, my brave son.
Hopefully. Bey, hopefully.
What is it, Ertugrul?
Are you waiting for me to come back?
Where are you coming from, uncle?
Alps are everywhere.
Why? You know it.
It is because of the troubles
you have caused.
They keep watch for us,
and I do my duty on them.
How is Gundogdu? Did he recover?
Do you hold me responsible
for Gundogdu's illness, boy?
So, you will hold me responsible even if
goat dung gets stuck in somebody's throat.
Your elder brother proved me innocent
in the marquee, in front of all the beys.
But you are about to lose your mind
because of your delusions.
When will this suspicion in you go away?
It will not,
until you pay for what you have done.
Bey...
They say that Sarikayin went to
Dar Su Pass to grass the cattle.
Good.
Go. Do not come back without him.
Yes, Bey.
Bey...
Leave us alone.
I hope your son gets well soon.
Your son Ertugrul blames me.
He holds me responsible
even for Gundogdu's illness.
If you are responsible for that,
you will surely die, Kurdoglu.
Shame on you, Suleyman.
Gundogdu proved me innocent
in front of all the beys in the marquee.
I was brave enough
to be a candidate against you.
I lost and showed respect.
Gundogdu is like my son.
I see him as my son I have lost.
I love him this way.
How can you still be suspicious of me?
Open your eyes.
There are people in this tent
who want to provoke you against me.
See this reality!
Or the price will be high.
Are you talking about
paying prices, Kurdoglu?
Do you what keeps me calm
even under this situation?
The reason for me not nailing your head
on the poles of the tent?
I am worried that justice will be hurt
if I take your head without trying you.
But you should know that...
...if it gets proven that
you are behind this...
...death will be a prize for you.
Gunkut!
Yes, Bey.
I am giving you an important duty.
You will tell me
every step Kurdoglu takes.
You will keep your eyes on him.
If that snake's head
is under this stone...
...it is my duty to rip that head off.
First, my dear sister...
...and now, you.
Selcan...
May Selcan sacrifice her life for you.
The pole of my tent.
The man of my heart.
I am with you. I will not leave you
until death does us apart.
Say it, Bey.
Selcan...
Gundogdu...
How did I grow this anger inside me...
...in that great marquee,
besides this holy man?
Who is this Sarikayin, father?
He lives in the boundary of the tent.
He does not even have a tent to live in.
He sleeps together with animals.
You mean a bastard
whom anybody can buy.
If Hamza saw him going out of the tent,
he must have ran away.
We can never find him.
Father, Kurdoglu got this done.
He is innocent until we prove that.
So, we have to prove it
as soon as we can.
Selcan, my girl...
Day comes out of the morning.
And the day gets born into the tongue.
Blessings rain
when a branch lowers its head.
You got rid of the anger
and hatred inside you.
Clean your heart...
...so that blessings will rain over you.
My dear mother. My life.
This tongue and this heart
will clean theirselves from now on.
Go away!
Go!
I said, go!
You do not exist!
Go, father. Go.
It is all because of you!
Go away! Go!
Can you forgive me, Gundogdu?
Even if you can, will Gokce forgive me?
What about God?
Will God forgive me?
I would be ashamed to enter heaven...
...with all the burden of my sins
on my back.
What have I done?
How could I be so blind?
Sel...
Gundogdu!
My Gundogdu.
You will pay for this, Kurdoglu.
All the beys that we have been praising...
The ones that said "The world is mine".
The time of death took it,
while earth hid it.
Who stayed forever in this world?
The world with ups and down.
The world in which
you are meant to die in the end.
Greetings.
Greetings, Halime Sultan.
Would you like me to prepare your horse?
No, thank you.
I am looking for my brother.
I could not find his horse in the stable.
Shahzade went away riding.
Did he say where he was going?
He did not say anything.
But I saw him going towards Kel Tepe.
I am getting Kurdoglu followed.
You find Sarikayin. Be quick.
Bamsi and Dogan are after him.
I do not trust anybody anymore.
Be suspicious of everybody
and everything from now on.
Halime Sultan...
...wants to talk to Ertugrul Bey.
Let her in.
Suleyman Shah...
Ertugrul Bey...
Forgive me, I could not wait.
Yigit...
I cannot find my brother.
He is gone.
What are you saying, Halime Sultan?
Where did he go?
He has been talking about
taking my father's revenge since he died.
He got on his horse,
girded on his weapon and went away.
The groom said
he went towards Kel Tepe.
What is it, Kurdoglu?
Why do you look troubled?
Suleyman Shah holds me responsible
for my niece getting poisoned.
He will relieve me of my duties
in the tent...
...and look for a chance to get rid of me.
We will not let this happen.
Our Bey is Suleyman Shah.
I took my lesson in the election.
The only thing I want
is that the traitor is found.
I do not want to be called
a traitor in this age.
If the beys cannot see the truth,
there are many ways to make them see it.
I have only one truth.
I want peace
in these last days of my life.
You sold me out, Kurdoglu!
Tell me!
Who is the traitor in the tent?
Talk, you bastard!
Who did he make you kill?
What are we going to do now?
Get up. You could not hold a man!
Even if he went to Konya...
...we will send a messenger
to Sultan Alaeddin.
He promised us.
He will watch out for him.
He will prevent him do something silly.
This is what I am scared of.
Him doing something silly.
What is it, Ertugrul Bey?
This is Yigit's horse.
Are you sure?
It has a rider with Yigit's weight.
The horseshoes are one of those
which Wild Demir has made.
He came here with two riders.
Then three more riders came.
They are not from our tent.
They are not even Muslim.
These horseshoes are not
one of those Wild Demir made.
The ones coming from the tent
must be the traitor or his men.
They handed Yigit to them
and went back to our tent.
God help my brother...
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
THE TEMPLARS' CASTLE
You Turks are brave people.
You are too emotional...
...but do you know
what is worst, my child?
You do not know at all
how to take the opportunities you have.
What do you want from me?
Taking what you want.
Taking your father's revenge.
You can only take your father's revenge...
...when you behead Sultan Alaeddin...
...and hang it in the square of Konya...
...and come to his throne, Shahzade.
You know this as well, do you not?
Treat the Shahzade well.
I see Seljuks' future in him.
Good night, Shahzade.
Brother Ertugrul
will bring this castle down on you.
Brother Ertugrul?
Ertugrul...
Ertugrul.
I will bury you all
under the lands you were born.
Yigit?
-Yigit!
-Isadora?
-What happened to you?
-I know who the traitor is...
Let go of him!
The situation is as I told you.
He blames me because
he protects Gundogdu...
...who is from his own blood
just to cover up his mistakes.
He blames me of cooperating
with the Crusaders...
...to come into his throne.
Shame on him!
This must be a joke.
While Ertugrul brings
every kinds of trouble to our tent...
...his father turned our tent
into a shepherd's tent.
You are right, Kurdoglu.
You are right,
but what are we going to do?
It is not the same old world
that we have known, brothers... Beys.
Moguls are on one side,
and the Crusaders are on the other.
And we are digging our graves
by herding goats and shepherding.
We come from a warrior lineage,
so we can find our own way.
-Is there anybody who denies his essence?
-There is not, Bey.
While I am worried about my tent...
...I am being blamed of being a traitor.
Do I deserve this, brothers?
They taint my reputation
even though they won the election.
Alright, enjoy it.
What are the news, Gunkut?
Kurdoglu got together with the beys.
There is nothing wrong
with his loyalty to you.
He said he only wanted the traitor
to be found as soon as possible.
Keep on following.
Keep your eyes on him at all times.
This may be one of his tricks.
Of course, Bey.
If the traitor is not Kurdoglu...
...who is it, then?
I just wanted to sleep peacefully
just for one night in my bed.
I was so happy that
it was going to be this night.
My heart cannot even accept
that my brother is in the castle.
How can I tell you
to go and bring him back?
We did not let you, your tent
and us have some peace.
And now again...
Neither the armor I wear,
nor the weapon in my hand...
...It will be you who give me strength.
Do not say that.
I will go to that castle tomorrow.
God knows what will happen...
...after that.
Bey, may I come in?
Come in, Dogan.
Bey...
...the Templars killed Sarikayin.
We could not prevent it.
They must have found out that Hamza
saw him coming out of Gundogdu's tent.
They did not leave any trace behind.
Back to the beginning.
Who is the traitor?
It was not me!
Who did this to my Gundogdu?
Who poisoned him?
None of us will have peace
as long as Suleyman stays in the marquee!
Now, get the hell out of here.
If you come again, I will kill you!
Get out!
Sister?
Are you alright?
I committed very big sins, Gokce.
God is punishing me for what I have done.
I will be in trouble in both worlds.
I know, sister.
You broke everybody's hearts.
You threw your elders, your husband
and me, your sister into the fire...
...in the cause of your ambition.
Why did you hide the fact that
I will not be a mother?
You tried to marry me with Ertugrul
even though you knew that.
Why?
Forgive me.
I am begging you, forgive me.
Please forgive me.
Forgive me.
If only we had the mind of those infidels.
They turned a strong Alp
to an Indian macaque.
Did you wake up, Judas?
Good.
We will do great things with you, soon.
You will be my right arm.
Bey...
If you permit...
My girl...
This necklace was given to me...
...by Ertugrul's grandfather Kaya Alp...
...and his grandmother Burla Hatun.
And now I want to...
...give it to my daughter-in-law.
Mother Hayme, this is very valuable.
You are very valuable, too.
You are my daughter now.
You came here knowing very well...
...what it means
to be the bride of this marquee.
And Ertugrul brought you to us...
...knowing the difficulties of
marrying a shahzade's daughter.
Kayis always have trouble
in our marquee.
And now Seljuks' troubles will add to it.
It is alright.
We cherished you knowing that.
The only thing you will do
is to be resilient.
Yigit will come back to us
sooner or later.
I will carry the stamp of Seljuk
and the stamp of Kayi Tribe...
...with honor, Mother Hayme.
I hope you bring up so many children...
...and beys
who will honor our breed.
If you have sons...
...I would like you
to name them after...
...Savci Alp who gave his life for me
while fighting the Moguls...
...Gunduz Alp
who has been martyred in my arms...
...and my uncle Osman Alp
who has also been martyred.
I have always wanted the names of these
brave Alps to live on in our breed.
If we have sons by God's will...
...may the names of these great Alps...
...bring honor to our breed,
power to our tent and peace to our family.
-May God grant you happiness.
-Amen, father.
Come here, girl,
I will show you something else.
Sarikayin was our single opportunity
to take us to the real traitor.
The traitor will be revealed
sooner or later.
But I need to find a way to find Yigit,
and bring him back here first.
It is a gorgeous idea that the Shahzade
will be trained in Konstantinopolis...
...through the Church's education...
...and be the sultan of the Seljuks.
I admire you one more time.
My dear friend Petruchio...
...as I stated in the letter
I wrote to the Pope...
...you Templars are the biggest gift that
has been granted to the Christian world.
My prayers are with you.
I will give you my best knights
when you set off for Antioch tomorrow.
I would not like you to have the same
troubles like you did before.
My dear friend, I would be very glad.
I would never want to
meet that ominous Turk again.
Excuse me, uncle.
Isadora, I am aware that we got you bored
with our political matters.
Why do you not take a ride?
But be careful not to get lost again.
I know everywhere now.
I can go alone.
Good. Go, then.
But be careful. Do not cross
those barbarian Kayis' bounders.
Do not worry, uncle.
I want to see Shahzade Yigit.
Master Petruchio has his orders.
We do not let him see anybody.
Bring me Ertugrul.
What is in your mind?
Kurdoglu, Bey.
I am worried that he is up for
what Selcan's father could not succeed.
I will relieve Kurdoglu
off his duties tomorrow.
I will grant his duties to Ertugrul.
He neither eats, nor drinks anything.
He stares blankly.
He would say my name
and eat a little, a while ago.
Now he does not do anything.
We are on the richest lands
of the world.
We have plenty of water,
our animals are battening.
But we are unpeaceful
like we never have been.
Was it a mistake that we came down here?
We will not rest
until we settle in our own lands.
We draw the people that hate
and want to destroy us...
...like bugs that fly towards the light.
Bey... one of the birds
that we keep in the tent...
...came back with this.
This is Yigit's necklace.
My biggest fear was that he would
succumb to the icon of arrogance...
...and worship it.
But he brought the icon arrogance down.
He showed one more time that
he is a son that you would be proud of.
Our people want a young bey.
My Gundogdu did great things.
He tried so hard
for Kurdogdu to be the bey.
But they would select him instead of me
if he was the candidate.
But he broke Kurdoglu's game
by not being a candidate.
And now he is in this situation.
I will relieve Kurdoglu
off his duties tomorrow.
I would kill him with my bare hands
if I had only one proof.
But I do not.
Obviously, Isadora
found out about something.
She wants to see me.
Be careful, Bey. It may be a trap.
We will meet at a place
only the two of us know.
We determined it while she was here.
Be careful, anyway.
Alright.
Bey, let us come with you.
This is safer, Bamsi.
I was worried that
you were not going to come.
-Is Yigit in the castle?
-Yes.
My uncle succeeded
to get him out of the tent...
...with the help of the traitor.
Yigit knows who the traitor is, then.
You will find out who he is
if you rescue Yigit.
Yigit shouted at me to tell who is,
but the knights covered his mouth.
They did not let me see him
when I went to the dungeon.
How are we going to
get him out of the dungeon?
It is impossible to get him out.
But he will go to Antioch tomorrow
with Cardinal Thomas.
And then to Konstantiniyye.
They will use Yigit
to bring Seljuks down from the inside.
Brother, I do not understand.
You know who your enemy is
in the battlefield.
You either die or kill.
What kind of field is this?
You do not know who the sword will slash,
or from where the arrow will come.
The man you apparently share your belief
with betrays on you, and you fight him.
This is the biggest enemy.
Ertugrul Bey is here.
Get ready.
We are setting off for Antioch tomorrow.
Is there news from Yigit, Bey?
They are planning to take the Shahzade
to Konstantiniyye...
...and cause trouble for Seljuks.
Sir, thank God I became a Muslim
with your help.
I will owe you all my life.
I wanted to kill you...
...but you caused me to become Muslim.
And then started to see me as your son
instead of taking a revenge.
Son, the only cause is God.
Man is only a tool.
You should thank God.
Thank him, so that
he will complete his blessing...
...and accepts you as a believer.
When God wants to create something...
...everything is at his service.
He creates
known and unknown tools for that.
Just for his wish to be realized.
Our holy Prophet taught us that...
...the greatest blessing in life is Islam.
Sir, I feel that I owe you,
and I am embarrassed to you.
Even though I became a Muslim,
it is hard for me to forget the past.
I remember my mistakes
one by one.
I feel like I cannot breath.
Whenever I look at your face...
...I remember my past
in which I was a killer.
Son, becoming a Muslim erases the past.
Whatever you live in the past...
...you start a new life
when you become a Muslim.
You start to live
although you were dead before.
You gain a new name.
God erased your past.
You forget it as well.
Do not live with the past.
The past is where people
who escape from their duties live.
Do not let your present moment
be captured by the past...
...so that you will not regret it
in the future.
Human is "Ibn-ul Vakt".
That is, the child of the moment
he lives in.
The moment is now.
It may be a trap.
I forgot to breath without a trap...
...and  to take a step without
stepping on the swamp of betrayal.
I have no choice other than
being cautious.
Do not worry.
Take as many as Alps with you
that is needed.
I will only take Bamsi and Dogan.
We are planning to set off
in the morning before the sunrise.
They are observing every move of us.
If I set off with an army,
they will take precautions.
So, I will go with only my Alps.
The fewer we are,
the more we have chance.
Any news from Kurdoglu?
Not yet, son.
Does Halime know what is going on?
Not yet.
I will tell her, if you permit.
-Ertugrul...
-Yes, father?
I will relieve Kurdoglu
off his duties tomorrow.
I will grant his duties to you.
Father...
Do not ever tell me
that you are "after the hunt".
I will do my duty with my honor
at the risk of my life.
Thank you, son.
Sir...
...it is easy to forget
when the guilt is small...
...but to try to kill somebody
and ambush him is unforgettable.
Listen, son...
When our Prophet...
...was given the duty
to call the humanity to serve God...
...the Meccans reacted
very badly to his call.
Our Prophet told them that...
...God is one, he is the one
who created us all...
...there is no god, only him...
...and they were not supposed to
serve any other one...
...but the Meccans saw him as an enemy.
They were troubled by the fact that
their order was going to mess up.
They made plans.
They made tricks.
Since they could not succeed
to make our Prophet give up...
...they started to say "If only somebody
came up and saved us from Muhammad."
And somebody came up.
Omar Al-Khattab.
A fearless, brave young man.
He said "I will do it."
"Not that he messes with your peace...
...and breaks your unity...
...it is my duty to kill him
and save Mecca from this trouble."
The Meccans were so happy
after these words.
They will get rid of the biggest trouble
without anybody got hurt.
Omar girded on his sword...
...and sets off to kill our Prophet.
What he did not know was that
God creates everything with a reason.
While everybody sets up traps...
...God makes men's traps
a servant for his actual wish.
Suleyman will gather up
a meeting tomorrow.
He is planning to relieve me off my duties
and pave the way for Ertugrul.
And then he will go and
bring the Templars' castle down.
I would not get surprised
if they had their eyes on Konstantiniyye.
Now, the tents that we all know
will be surrounded in the morning.
The beys who say anything
will be taken out of their tents.
And last of all, you will go into the
marquee and take Hayme and Suleyman.
Gundogdu is ill.
He cannot cause any trouble.
But Ertugrul?
He will go with his Alps in the morning.
I know that.
I intentionally waited for him to go,
so that he will not cause any commotion.
I want to finish this without any blood.
After all, Suleyman
has been serving for us for so long.
He was our bey.
You are right, Bey.
Completely right.
Of course, Kurdoglu.
Thank you.
The Alps that I trust
will surround the marquee in the morning.
God help us.
What about the beys
that do not obey you?
They will either obey...
...or they will die.
While Omar was on the way
to kill our Prophet...
...he hears a sound
coming from his sister's house.
His sister and his husband
have become Muslim.
They were reading out verses
from the Holy Quran.
Omar rushed in.
He went mad with the scene he witnessed.
He slapped his sister and his husband.
He knocked them on the ground.
His sister, who was a brave woman...
...shouted the truth to Omar:
"We will not renege on our religion
even if you kill us."
Those words caused a spring come out of
his heart which was hard like a stone.
God enlivens the heart of the man
who came to kill his prophet with Islam.
He brings the living out of the dead.
He gives life to a dead heart
with the water of faith.
Omar becomes Muslim and says
the words of Islamic confession of faith.
He takes the meaning of life
from the man he went there to kill.
God works like this.
He brings the living out of the dead
and the dead out of the living.
Man should surrender to God
so much that...
...the person who goes there to kill him
would find life.
A Muslim should be
the reason of life for his killer.
This is what surrendering to God means.
Sir, I think
my situation is kind of similar.
Yes, son.
Your temperament is like Omar's.
God Almighty made you the one
who found the water of life...
...while you were going to kill.
I hope everything about you
will be similar to Omar's.
Let one of your names be Omar,
so that you will not forget this blessing.
How is my brother doing?
Thanks to you... he is alright.
God bless both Halime and you.
You gave life to her.
Do not worry.
Everything will be alright.
I will make the ones
who did to my brother pay.
Excuse me.
May I come in, Halime Sultan?
Come in, Ertugrul Bey.
Yigit is in the castle.
They will take him to Konstantiniyye.
If you cannot take him...
...kill him, Ertugrul Bey.
Both Yigit and me
will be grateful if you do this.
I know how to accept my fate.
But dragging you after it...
...renders me helpless.
The day that gazelle brought me to you...
...I understood that
my fate was not only for me.
You should understand this, too.
Our fate is one.
May God speed you.
May the Sun not burn your skin.
May the rain not make your soul cold.
May stones be away from your foot.
Go like water,
and come back to your tent like water.
May God protect you, Halime Sultan.
You too, Ertugrul.
May I come in?
Come in, Gokce.
I heard what happened
to the Shahzade, Halime.
I hope you come together soon.
Thank you, Gokce.
As to Ertugrul and you...
...you should know that...
...I loved Ertugrul more than my own life.
So much that I could forget him.
And he loved you
so much that he could not see it.
I hope you get married and be happy.
However, never forget this, Halime...
If you make Ertugrul unhappy...
...I will make you pay in both worlds.
May I come in, mother?
Come in, son. Come in.
We also talked like this...
...when your father decided to send you
to Aleppo. Remember? On the stairs.
I do, mother.
Your words gave me courage.
I could not have been as sharp as
the sword that Wild Demir makes...
...if it were not your words.
And maybe I would come back
without succeeding.
But you did.
Just like you could not turn your back
to that gazelle eyed girl's screams...
...you did your duty that your father
gave you successfully.
I could neither leave
my gazelle-eyed woman...
...nor come back without doing
the duty that my father gave me.
I've said "You could know neither
you would meet that gazelle...
...nor you would throw the tent
into the fire along with yourself."
Then, I said...
..."There are fires
that burn and turn the meal into ashes.
And there are fires
that cook the meal and feed you."
It showed you where you fell down.
Nobody has the right to rebel.
Neither you, nor the people of the tent.
This is a test from God Almighty.
You may either get cooked
and grow mature, or turn into ashes.
That is why I told you
to stand by your father's decisions.
You are right. You did, mother.
Thankfully, I did not turn into ashes
in the fire I got in.
And now, you must
stand by your father's decisions.
You will take over
all of the duties that Kurdoglu had.
You had three Alps before.
But now, all the Alps of the tent
will be at your disposal.
You will order them
not only to kill, but also to die.
Just like it is Halime
who fits this tent...
...you are the bey who fits here, son.
Just like you could not run away
from your duty, and from that gazelle...
...do not ever run away
from being the bey of the Kayis.
Your father wants this wholeheartedly.
But he does not tell.
I just wanted you to know.
Alright, go now.
May God speed you, son.
May God protect me from depraving, mother.
Amen.
May God protect you.
Amen, mother.
Gunkut is dealt with, Bey.
Good. Start, then.
Yes, Bey.
Hail to the horses running breathlessly
Hail to the ones that
Sparks come out of their horseshoes
For our tent, for our Bey
For our tradition
If I get scared to die
May my sword of black steel
Saw me in the sky
May the blue sky tear apart
And the black earth stave in
May my name be erased from monuments
And may my father Oghuz, my holy tent
Make me pay in the other world
May God be my helper
And my ancestor Hizir my companion
In this path of holy war
God, let Ertugrul be successful.
Do not leave him alone.
Grant strength to my brother.
Halime Sultan, you are under arrest
by the order of our Bey.
What are you talking about?
Suleyman Shah would never do such a thing.
Our bey is not Suleyman Shah anymore.
It is Kurdoglu.
Do not even think about it, Suleyman Shah.
Let us do this without any blood spilled.
So, my Alps whom I loved like my own sons
revolted against their fathers!
We only follow orders, Bey.
Was this order given by Kurdoglu to you?
Our bey is Kurdoglu from now on.
Let us change our clothes.
Get out.
Father!
Let him go! Traitors, let him go!
Bastards!
Let him go!
Father!
Move! Father!
-Father!
-Aykiz!
Traitors! Father!
Rascals! Bastards!
Father!
Did that low-down Kurdoglu send you?
Selcan Hatun, do not talk ill
about our Bey...
...if you want to be treated
like you deserve.
You can all go to hell!
But me, first.
I do not want to leave my bey alone.
The midwives will take care of him.
Kurdoglu gave orders. Let us go.
You never listened to me, Suleyman.
Since you sent Ertugrul to Aleppo...
...and you accepted that ominous shahzade
and his children to the tent...
...our unity has been broken.
And now, you will pay the price.
The price you say I will be paying
is nothing but my pride.
One who becomes a bey with tricks...
...and goes against the traditions
is no good to anybody.
How dare you will be on the seat of our
ancestors who left Otugen and came here?
This marquee will be your damnation.
You will see that
you cannot be a leader with persecutions.
Now, beware of God's wrath.
Nobody can escape his damnation.
We know who you are and who you serve for.
And now, the whole world
will know it, Kurdoglu.
Let Suleyman Shah go!
Our bey is Suleyman Shah!
Our Bey is Suleyman Shah!
Kurdoglu is not our bey!
Let Suleyman Shah go!
Kurdoglu, you are a traitor!
Long live Kurdoglu!
From now on,
Kurdoglu is the bey of the Kayi Tent!
If anybody has anything to say...
...he should say now,
if he has the courage!
Son!
Kurdoglu!
You betrayed to your blood brother.
You betrayed to the tradition and
the decision that the marquee has given.
If you have the least courage,
come and face me.
You were the hope of this tent.
You were clever.
You were brave.
I granted you a big opportunity.
But what did you do?
You sat on your father's tail.
You destroyed both your future
and the tent's for this old man.
You are a coward, Gundogdu!
And I have nothing to do with cowards.
Take them away!
Enough!
Stop it now!
I do not want any blood spilled.
Everybody go back to their tents!
What is necessary will be done
in the meeting.
If you lay a hand on my sons,
I swear I will kill you, Kurdoglu.
Do not worry, Suleyman.
The decision about you
will be given in the meeting.
I am responsible for both Dundar
and Gundogdu's lives until then.
Like all the rest of your family.
Now, take him.
Let Suleyman Shah go!
Kurdoglu, you are a traitor!
Traitors!
You are a traitor!
We are going to camp here.
Get out of the way, you infidels!
So we meet again, Black Priest.
So, Kurdoglu's intention is
to make our son kill us.
Please forgive me, sir.
I am begging you.
I am an ordinary farmer, sir.
They brought me and my son
here by force, sir.
It is over, Turk!
You are at the end of the road.
Who are you?
Grandmaster Petruchio Manzini.
I am Isadora's uncle.
It is over, Ertugrul.
You played dangerous games
a goat shepherd should not.
You lost!
And you will pay the price.
Surrender immediately.
I will not warn you again.
It is impossible for you to defeat us.
Do you understand me, Turk?
What do we do now, Bey?
We will smash them
like Wild Demir's hammer.
No stopping, no hesitating.
Understood, Bey.
Hey, Bamsi...
You definitely know how to fight.
Bey...
Like when you forged sword
with Wild Demir, right?
Oh, yes.
-God is Hayy.
-God is Hakk.
Ertugrul, surrender.
It is over!
-God is Hayy!
-God is Hakk!