Episode 23 will start after 12:22 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Show Kurdoglu to everybody
in front of my marquee until he is tried.
It will be an example for the ones who may
attempt to put us in this shame again.
We did not act together
with this bastard, Bey.
But we could not stand straight
and go against him...
...like our Alps and beys
who were martyred, either. Forgive us.
We would like to kiss your hand
if you permit.
Forgive us.
That bastard who has not
had his share from being fair...
...did every kinds of persecutions
to my family and my brave brothers.
However, I will never avoid
being fair.
He will be punished in the
headquarters meeting.
The punishment
will be executed as decided.
Nobody should doubt it.
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
Even though
we are surrounded by enemies...
...and the Crusaders give us trouble...
...we did not lose our unity.
The fire of instigation among us
has been put out as of today.
No matter how strong our enemy is...
...we will protect both our tent
and our religion, by God's will.
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
This drug will decrease your pain.
I am very sorry, sir.
I remember the infidels
I have poisoned all this time.
The ones from Ayyubids, Seljuks...
The Council of the Templars
will arrive soon, doctor.
This must be kept as a secret
between us until they leave.
Do you understand me?
Yes, sir.
May God protect you, sir.
God has left me, doctor.
And Kurdoglu whom I worked
so hard on with high hopes, lost the game.
Kayis are a bigger enemy now.
What I am curious about is that...
...where my niece Isadora
found this poisoned dagger from.
The great grandmasters
of the Council are here! Open the gates!
Excuse me, Grandmaster Petruchio.
Welcome, Grandmasters.
You honored our castle.
Thank you, Titus.
Where is Grandmaster Petruchio?
What is so important
that he could not come here to welcome us?
He will welcome you in his room, sir.
He is curious about how Isadora
found the poison on her knife.
I will tell him that I was the one
who gave Isadore the poisoned knife...
...when his tongue swells and he will not
be able to talk in a few days.
You can go now, doctor.
Grandmaster Petruchio
will die in a few days.
The Council members
will elect a new grandmaster.
Who will the new grandmaster be, Cardinal?
Titus, of course.
Tell Titus to secretly
come and visit me tonight.
When will you bring Ibn al-Arabi's relic?
I will visit him tomorrow.
Good. Bring it as soon as possible.
I want to take the Shahzade...
...and get away from this
ominous place as soon as possible.
Do not worry, sir.
My brave man.
My strong man.
Weapons, heroism and being a bey
befits you so much.
My moon-faced woman.
My life companion
who laughs and saddens with me.
Being a bey is a cloth made of fire.
Putting it on and off
are both tough ordeals.
You are right.
This marquee suffered so much.
There have been so many troubles.
Hayme, I thought about not coming back
to this marquee for a moment.
However, if he did not,
we would be obeying persecution.
If we did not struggle for the underdogs,
the pharaohs would have won.
Even one single breath
is too much for a persecutor.
You are right, Bey.
What will you do to Kurdoglu?
How he will end up is certain.
I only want to bring down the castle
on the Templars now.
Either that castle
will be destroyed, or us.
Dundar?
Son?
Mother. Father.
Your mother would give her life
for you, my son!
Thank God for this double joy.
I was so scared that
we would not get together again.
What would I do
if anything happened to you?
What protects a person from death
is their determined time of death.
See, we could come together again.
Thank God.
What is going to happen now?
First, Kurdoglu will be punished
like the way he deserves.
And then, those Templars' castle
will be brought down on them.
Gazelle eyes.
May sadness, grief and sorrow
be away from us.
My brave man.
Neither sadness,
nor grief or sorrow for us...
It is time for the meeting.
What happened to "The hunt is ours,
and the meeting is theirs"?
I am the one who is given duty now.
They are both ours.
Life without you was a dungeon for me.
Your love gave me life
in those dungeons, Aykiz.
Let us come together now, Turgut.
I do not have strength
to bear even one more day.
Let us talk to your father and our Bey...
...and get married as soon as possible.
Turgut...
We will get rid of this plague.
We will get rid of it.
If...
If I attempt to hurt you unknowingly...
Take this dagger.
Kill me.
You are scared that I would talk,
are you not?
That I would turn you in.
Would I not have thanked them
for killing me, if I did that?
I want to leave the biggest plague
as legacy to Suleyman and his children.
And my biggest fortune,
my biggest legacy is you.
By the name of the 99 names of God...
...who creates everything with only one
word and fills our hearts with faith.
Beys, I suffered a lot
during this last period of my life.
I lost my children and my first wife.
So many of my brothers
died in my arms.
However, none of these hurt me
as much as this last betrayal did.
That traitor overthrew me with tricks.
He defamed my woman,
my children and my sister-in-law.
He tortured them.
But the beys of the headquarters
did not say anything!
They did not stand straight
against the persecutor!
Why is that?
Forgive us, Bey.
Kurdoglu deceived us.
Then, I will not arrange headquarters
meetings with beys who were deceived.
All of you are dismissed!
We will have new beys here.
Ertugrul...
Kurdoglu's duties are yours.
Gundogdu...
Provision of food is your duty.
Now, bring Kurdoglu here!
You have long since
deserved to die, Kurtoglu.
No one will ever trust you now.
You are going to die.
Your punishment was determined, Kurtoglu.
Thank God.
Peace is upon our people now!
We got rid of this trouble, too.
Now, it is time to arrange your weddings.
With permission of our father...
...we do not want to have
a wedding ceremony, mother.
The war against the Templars
is inevitable now.
We are all aware of it.
If God permits,
we want to have our ceremonies...
...after the war.
When our men...
...and my brother, Yigit...
...return home safely.
Just like Halime Sultan says,
Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul Bey, Gundogdu Bey
will never come back
before they demolish their castles.
If they can not return home safely,
we will, at least, have the honor
to lead a life as their widows.
With our father's consent,
we would like to exchange vows
before the war breaks out.
Oh, my beautiful girls!
You are as brave as your men!
May God bless you!
We went all through this
because of that dog, named Kurtoglu.
We have seen his men die
one after another.
Now, it is his time to pay.
Just after he is punished,
I will convey your requests
to our Suleyman Shah.
Agreed?
We appreciate, mother.
Some of his men may still be alive.
Who knows?
There may be others who share his sins.
He will have to confess
in the headquarters.
May God protect us!
-Traitor!
-Hang him!
Kurtoglu!
Do you have something to say?
I spent my life rushing from one battle
to another for our nomad group.
I lost everything I had,
my sons, my wife,
while fighting for our people.
I did everything to enlarge our boundaries
and strengthen our nomad group.
To have our own lands
and found a seigniory.
I want these to be taken
into consideration, Bey.
You have ruined your bravery
with treachery, Kurtoglu.
There are no excuses for treachery
and it must be punished by death.
It appears that you have learned
to confess sins from Templars, Kurtoglu.
Yet, this is no place
to confess your sins.
I demand a punishment
that will not ruin my dignity, Bey!
How can you still
speak of dignity, traitor?
Beys! I demand mercy!
Show mercy! Please!
You'll be shown mercy
just as much as you did, Kurtoglu.
You will be shown
as much mercy as you showed
to Alps you have slaughtered
with Karatoygar and Titus.
Kurtoglu!
You are guilty of betraying
your people, Bey.
You have violated religion and traditions.
You are sentenced to death.
Take this traitor out.
Bey! I demand mercy!
Bey! For the sake of our past!
Send me to dark dungeons but...
...spare my life.
Spare my life, Bey!
Spare my life!
Bey! Spare my life.
Spare my life, Bey!
Spare my life!
-Kill him!
-Murderer!
-He murdered our sons!
-Traitor!
We promised to die for each other
while becoming blood brothers.
We promised not to use our swords
against one another.
I am going to keep my promise.
Because I keep my words.
I am not going to take your life.
I bear witness that
there is no god but Allah
and Muhammad is the servant
and Messenger of Allah.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
God!
-Allahu akbar!
-Divine Justice...
From now on,
none can stand against our next
and the biggest crusade.
Cardinal Thomas finished the report
that he has been preparing for Pope
and the Frederick, the Emperor.
His report is beyond our expectations.
He mentions our efforts with praise.
I propose a toast to you,
to the precious knights of our cult.
Welcome back!
What about Kayi tribe?
Do you think that we have not heard of
what the Turk, named Ertugrul did
and you cannot fight him back properly,
Master Petruchio?
We have heard of how he uncovered
our intelligence network in Aleppo
and how he slaughtered tons of our spies
and brave knights like animals.
Master Ricardo!
Please you all tell me this.
Did his apostles give up fighting
after Jesus was crucified?
I am sure you are all aware that
you have to face unforeseen obstacles
while marching to your destination.
How can we trust you, Master Petruchio?
How can we believe in your word...
...after all these defeats.
As Salam Alaykum
wa Rahmatullah.
God, give me strength!
Take my life but do not let them
hold me captive like my brother, Turgut.
Cardinal Thomas summons you.
Go tell that daemon
that I don't want to see him!
Don't make me hurt you, young boy!
He should have got this job done
when we captured Ertugrul
and his Alps in the forest.
Unfortunately, it was a big mistake.
I don't know what Arabi's relic is
but he destroyed ours to gather it.
Master Petruchio must pay for it.
You have to regain the dignity
that your cult lost
in Antioch and Aleppo, Titus.
I trust you can achieve it
with all my heart.
Do you have any idea about
how Isadora found that poisonous knife?
It is God's divine justice, my son.
Divine justice.
Come in!
Welcome, Shahzada!
What do you want from me?
I just wanted to discuss why you need
to come to Constantinople with me.
I will never be in your service.
Great emperors never serve
to anyone, Shahzada!
And you will be a great emperor.
Dundar Bey!
You are eating like a hungry wolf.
We have been away for a long time.
Let's act like a wolf so that
friends and foes see that I am back.
Dundar Bey!
People say you almost ate the Templars.
Boar meat is not halal to us, brother.
Almighty! We are grateful
for all your blessings.
You reunited us.
You protected our home, our nomad camp
from the evil of the enemies.
We appreciate.
-Amen.
Ertugrul! We need to gather
the nomad group immediately.
You're right, brother.
Our people are disorganized.
We need to provide order.
We will achieve it
with the help of God.
No one can stand in our way.
However, first things first.
You and Halime Sultan
need to get married.
Let me get some water!
-I can get some for you, mother!
-No, I got it.
Gokce!
Yes, mother!
Do you need something?
My beautiful Gokce. My sunshine!
Mother, please forgive me!
I can't resist him!
My heart hurts!
I just can't.
My beautiful daughter.
You are destined to suffer from it.
With permission of God,
you will find a man who loves you.
And you will love him deeply, too.
Come on!
Wipe your tears.
Thank God!
So?
I had told you my beautiful daughter.
We get through these cloudy days.
We fight our troubles away.
Don't be afraid of the winter,
Flowers bloom when the spring arrives.
Didn't I tell you that
the day follows the night?
Thank God, father.
Thank God.
My children!
I am so close
to the end of my mortal life.
I wish to see you married
before I pass away.
But things are very complicated
these days.
We can't afford a wedding ceremony.
We were just planning
to ask for your permission, father.
Thanks be to God.
Turgut?
-Turgut!
My son.
-Take my hand.
-Father?
-Give us some water.
Bring water.
Turgut?
Drink some.
-Turgut!
Open your eyes, my son.
Open your eyes.
Father, what are we going to do?
Bey! Turgut is having an attack.
He is in Otacı's tent.
Excuse me, Bey!
Elhamdulillah!
Elhamdulillah for everything
you send, my God.
His body reacted because he hasn't taken
Templars' poison for a long time.
Is he going to be okay?
What happened?
His body needs Templars' elixir.
He has resisted to take it
for a long time.
But, his body can't resist it any more.
-What do we need to do, then?
-Shall we give him some if necessary?
He will always need it
if we give him some more.
And, he will be closer to death each day.
We need to be patient.
God will be in his aid
with his name, El Shafi.
God help him.
We've done everything that we can.
Now, it is time to wait.
We found our brother but this sickness
wants to take him apart from us again.
These Templars are so coward.
They rely on poison
as they are too coward to fight.
They are everywhere.
They are full of tricks.
Their power comes from Muslims' weakness.
They are wicked cats
seeing lions in the mirror.
They try to spread fear.
But they could not defeat us
and they won't be able to.
If they are everywhere, so are we.
Brothers! Can you excuse me
to have a word with Afsin Bey?
I am all ears, Ertugrul Bey.
Now tell me who you are, Afsin Bey!
Where did you come from?
And, why are you here?
I was in Ahlat with the elderly.
Ertugrul Bey, Turkish tribes and states
have been born and grown
in the hands of the elderly
ever since the Oghuz Khan.
This will stay the same in the future.
Ahlat is our gateway to Anatolia
and the elderly stay there.
-I have a message from them for you.
-What is it?
Mongolians are getting stronger.
We must gather all Oghuz tribes together.
They ask you to take
the Kayi tribe back to Anatolia.
-Does my father know the elderly?
-It's a rare opportunity, Ertugrul Bey.
-I wish to know them.
-It is only possible if they wish.
We have to move the Kayi tribe
to Anatolia as soon as possible.
Mongolians are approaching
like a raged bull.
We need soldiers to stop them.
Your slit black eyes now taken by sleep.
Let them open.
Your twelve healthy bones
have been broken.
Let them heal.
Your soul all but flown from your frame.
Let it return.
If your body retains any life,
let me know.
Let my poor luckless head
be a sacrifice to you.
Kazilik Mountain, your waters still flow;
Let them, I pray, cease their flowing.
Kazilik Mountain, your grasses still grow;
Let them, I pray, cease their growing.
Kazilik Mountain,
your deer still run fast.
Let them cease running,
and turn into stone.
How can I know, my son,
if it was lion or a tiger?
How can I know, my son?
How did this accident happen to you?
If your life is still in your body,
my son, let me know.
Let my poor luckless head
be a sacrifice to you.
Speak a few words to me now.
Bismillah. Good appetite.
-Visit the loom to check the girls today.
-Sure.
We should give Gokce in marriage soon
so that she forgets about Ertugrul.
You are right, Bey.
Are you okay, Hatun?
Why are you asking, Bey?
You act like an angel this morning.
I tell you to go to the loom
and you don't reject.
I tell you we should give Gokce
in marriage, no objections.
What's going on?
Whatever you wish, Bey!
My Goodness. So weird.
The world is falling apart.
-Long live, Bey!
-Thank you.
-Bey.
-Oh, Wild Demir.
-Thank God, we have reached good days.
-Thank God.
-How is Turgut Alp?
-Fine, Bey. Nothing to do but to wait.
Bey, should you accept to listen,
I would like to tell you something.
I want Turgut and Aykiz to get married.
They have been waiting far too long.
I am also aware that it is not
the greatest time for a wedding,
considering we have a lot of problems.
You are right!
Our kids are in misery.
We get it done as soon as
Turgut Alp recovers.
May God bless you, Bey.
As Salam Alaykum
wa Rahmatullah.
May I come in, Sheik?
Of course, my daughter!
I want to talk to you
if you care to listen.
Sure! Please be seated.
Efendi! I did bad things.
I harmed a lot of people
and acted evil.
I'd like to retreat
from my sins and repent.
God's doors for repentance
are always wide open.
Beg God for forgiveness
and acceptance of your repentance.
However, you say you harmed people.
You must talk to them
and demand forgiveness.
Do not pass away
before you ask for forgiveness.
Because God does not forgive
one another's rights.
My dear sisters!
We  finally have peace among our people.
Now it is time for us to work hard.
Bismillah!
Halime, my daughter!
You are responsible for the prints.
You must search meadows,
find beautiful flowers,
and extract their colors.
Do not worry, Mother Hayme.
We will surely do our best.
Gokce, my daughter.
You shall be checking the looms.
We must get carpets ready
to be sold in Aleppo.
Sure, mother!
Take it easy, Hatuns.
-Oh, welcome Bey.
-Thank you.
-Please be seated, father.
-Thank you, I won't stay too long.
I just wanted to see Bacis.
So, Hayme Hatun?
How are things here?
They have promised. Everything
will be ready for Aleppo Bazaar.
If God permits, Aleppo Bazaar will be
ornamented with Kayi Bacis' handcrafts.
If God permits, Bey!
Bey, we can get everything done
under your command.
Thank you all, Bacis.
If you have complaints
about your husbands,
you should know that
I am always ready to listen to you!
-How are they doing?
-They are distracted, Bey.
We must train them
to be Alps in no time.
Alps seem to have forgotten how to fight
while electing Bey in the headquarters.
Train them day and night
and get them ready to fight.
As you wish, Bey.
-As you command, Bey
-May God give you strength.
God be with you, Alps.
You have honored us, Bey.
They are a bit distracted
because of Kurtoglu's promises, father!
We will get our nomad group aligned.
The threat from enemies
aids the unification.
It makes us get closer
and keeps us alert.
It covers our weaknesses!
Keep them in mind, son!
Should you be the Bey one day,
always keep your nomads ready to fight.
Thanks God, we have finally
seen a peaceful day.
-Thanks God.
Even though there are threats from
Templars, crusaders, and others,
it is important to have
peace at home.
We are grateful to God
for his blessings.
-Thanks God!
However, we are deeply
sorry for Turgut.
If God permits,
we will see him recover.
If God permits, father.
I suggest that Turgut and Aykiz
shall get married first, Ertugrul.
-They have waited for too long.
-I was gonna ask you the same, father.
I would also suggest that
they should get married first.
We should be quick
with happy events.
After all these sufferings
and with a broken heart,
we should proceed with the engagement
even though Shahzada Yigit is a prisoner.
We cherish our peace so that
we have strength against our enemies.
-If God permits!
Father!
I would like to have some words
with your permission.
To have peace in our marquee
and nomad tents,
all secrets must be revealed, Bey.
Selcan, what are you talking about?
Mother! To have peace
in the marquee of a...
...sacred father and mother like yours.
You all need to know about my sins.
Selcan, do you hear what you are saying?
Gundogdu! I aborted our child
long before you knew of.
I was too scared to tell you.
I did something even worse
and claimed it was because of Aykiz.
I blamed her for it.
She was whipped
before the eyes of people.
Even though I knew Gokce was infertile,
I made every effort to see her
married to Ertugrul Bey.
What have you done, Selcan?
I wish it were all about it, Bey.
I did not stop.
I collaborated with that traitor,
named Kurtoglu
and spoiled Gundogdu's soul
just to help him to be the Bey.
Although I knew that there might be
consequences for Gokce
and it might cost
my husband, Gundogdu's life...
I am sinful in all these.
Nothing less...
-Selcan, enough!
-Be seated.
Calm down! Be seated, son!
I want to hear what she says.
I don't want my darkened and defiled soul
to dishonor my husband's bed
and my parent's tent.
I want you to punish me twofold
in the same way I treated did Aykiz.
I must be punished equally as Kurdoglu.
I am grateful to Ibn Arabi
for not letting me kill myself
out of grief and commit a bigger sin.
He told me to tell you everything
and so I did, without keeping any secrets.
I am ready for any punishment you see fit.
Our beloved prophet, peace be upon him
said in a hadith that
all men are sinners
but the most favourables
among sinners are repentants.
Selcan wants to repent in the Nasuh way.
She regrets for those she had done before.
She is determined
to renounce her sins immediately
and not to repeat them in the future.
Our beloved prophet, peace be upon him
describes Nasuh repentance as
regretting all your sins,
fully committing yourself to God
and never going back to your sins.
Just like the milk, which never returns
to the breast once it flows.
Selcan submits to any punishment
you decide.
When all secrets were about to be covered
under a veil of lies
Selcan chose to confide her sins
instead of covering them up.
I advice you to listen to her pure heart.
Let Gundogdu decide.
I went to bed with you as my woman!
How could you do this to me?
I gave into temptation, Gundogdu.
Forgive me for God's sake.
Forgive me!
Get up, get up.
I went against my mother and
father for you.
What have you done?
You collaborated with that
traitor Kurdoglu.
How can I forgive you? How?
We wanted to have a baby!
We tried for years!
How could you do this to us?
God, oh my God! You...
How could you do this
to the baby inside of you
out of your greed and ambition?
How am I supposed to take you in my bed
as my woman!
You will leave this tent tomorrow!
I will not go to bed with you
as my woman again!
I am divorcing you!
No! No!
Please, kill me! Please, kill me
if you are going to say that word!
Kill me if you would say it, Gundogdu!
Take it and kill me!
Kill me!
Go to hell.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, Ertugrul.
Is Turgut Alp well?
He has always been well, son.
He always fought with the monsters
that wanted to take away his soul.
He was imprisoned within himself.
He was alone.
He could never ask for help or guidance.
The conflict between him and his enemy
that wanted to take his soul was so strong
he prayed to God, chanting his name
in the dungeon they put him.
He has already been one of
the victors, my son.
Now God will have mercy on him once again
as "The Healer" is one of his many names.
I would like to talk to you about Omer.
My daughter.
Are the rumours true, father?
Has Dundar really healed?
He got up as if nothing has happened.
He is like a blade quenched in water.
-Thank God.
-Father.
-Tell me, my daugther.
They say that the evil eye on the marquee
was lifted after Selcan's confession.
Not only the one on our marquee
but also the evil eye on our nomad tent
was lifted with God's will.
Turgut will get better, too.
If God permits, father.
What about her? What will they do to her?
Can they forgive her
after all the harm she has done?
Nobody knows what will happen,
my daughter.
Thank God, Ibn Arabi is here,
if it wasn't for him...
Gundogdu Bey's situation is
very difficult.
Even thinking about it is agony.
May God help them.
-Amen.
-How is Turgut?
-He is the same, my Bey.
Bey.
My lad.
My brother.
Turgut, my son.
Aykiz.
Thank God for his mercy.
I will leave tonight with your permission.
If you are still alive
know that it is thanks to Arabi.
Do whatever you want.
Be away from me and closer to God.
Sister.
Don't you hate me?
You were my mother...
...father and sister.
You were everything to me.
But I feel like you ripped
everything away from me.
I lost Ertugrul. I lost my heart.
Yet you killed a human being
inside of you.
My dear sister.
Gokce.
Don't you still trust me?
What kind of a stubbornness is that, Alps?
I do not know what you said
to convince Ertugrul Bey.
But you cannot convince me.
Even your stubbornness is nice.
I cannot get mad at you.
But...
...I don't know what do you have
against me, Dogan?
I do not trust you, Afsin Bey.
I trust Selcan Hatun
but I do not trust you.
She confessed everything one by one
out of regret.
But you are not like her.
I am afraid that some day
you will bring us together with Titus
claiming that he is
important to the state.
You showed up when our nomad group was in
deep trouble.
But heaven knows why
Halime Sultan's father was murdered
after couple of days.
You were nowhere to be found.
Dogan, Bamsi.
Afsin Bey has my and Ertugrul Bey's
full confidence.
You know that he was an
important commander in Seljuk Empire.
We do not want bad blood between you.
Besides, Suleyman Shah asked him
to come with us. Do I make myself clear?
I understood, my Bey.
Not quite, but so be it, my Bey.
Alright then.
Where is Ertugrul?
He went to visit Turgut Alp.
He will be back soon.
How is Turgut?
Thank God, he woke up.
Shall we?
Do you have time, mother?
Yes, Selcan.
Gundogdu cast me out from his tent.
I will look for another tent.
You should be thankful
that he did not divorce you.
Can Gokce stay with you?
Please do not judge my sister by my deeds.
We know what to see in a person very well.
Don't worry about it.
Come on, sisters! Hurry up!
Water is boiling!
Throw in the flowers! Hurry!
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Ertugrul Bey.
Brother, meet Omer.
Ibn Arabi said that he is a brave warrior
honored with Islam.
-Welcome.
-I am honored.
I am honored, Omer.
Cardinal Thomas wants to take
Shahzade Yigit to Constantinople.
I wanted to break him out of the dungeon
but it was not possible.
What about Isadora?
Unfortunately, The Master killed her, too.
She was a brave woman.
I will avenge her father and sister.
Cardinal will replace
The Master with Titus
with the help of the
members of the council.
Both of them do not want Kayi tribe
to get in their way before the Crusade.
They will attack your nomad tribe.
Will they cross the border
and attack the tribe?
Yes.
-May the faster one win.
-Exactly, brother.
We should hurry up and
raze that castle to ground.
Isadora drew everything we need
to get inside the castle.
We know how to get inside the tunnels
and navigate through the castle.
And most importantly,
you will be inside, Omer.
Do not worry, my Bey.
I will do whatever it takes.
Have your fill, my son, eat.
Mother, I will explode
if I take one more bite.
Son, we have fed you
with water for months.
Eat to put some muscle on you.
Eat, come on.
He will be his mother's Alp, my brave son.
Father, I would like to see the
new nomad tents with your permission.
Alright son, you may go.
You would burn what you ate too.
Thank you, father.
Dundar, take it easy and
hold onto what you ate. Alright?
Son, did you hear me?
-Alright, mother.
Bey, what are we going to do about Selcan?
Gundogdu told her to leave his tent.
What did you say to him?
I told him to give us some time
for things to settle down.
What do you say?
I don't know what to do
or what to say, Hayme.
I do not know after all these years
if we have been raising
a traitor or a dutiful child.
I would have killed her in my marquee
if it was not for Ibn Arabi.
I am not that merciful.
Maybe she was behind everything
that happened to Turgut and Dundar.
Gundogdu is devastated.
He does not know what to do.
Let us wait and hope for the best.
You should rest, sir.
I will represent you in the best way.
Yes, Titus.
What do you have to say about
the recent events?
It was a very big mistake trying to banish
Kayi tribe to where they came from.
We should have killed them all
when we had the chance.
Do you have any suggestions, Knight Titus?
Yes, I do.
We will not rest until Kayi tribe
drowns in their own blood.
They will perish to the last man,
including the babies in their cradles
so that our sacred duty will come to life.
What does Cardinal Thomas say about this?
He would like to host you in his
chambers and discuss that matter.
If you deem appropriate that is.
Dogan. Tell Wild Demir
to come to the marquee.
Yes, my Bey.
Do you have any news from Omer?
-Yes, my Bey.
-Good news?
The news are not good, my Bey.
Ertugrul Bey summons you
to the marquee, Wild Demir.
-What is the matter?
-News are not good, Wild Demir.
How is my brother, Aykiz?
My dear friend, Petruchio.
Such a great, divine man.
But the crusaders need a young
and inspiring hero
to rally us all around him instead of a
hero in deathbed like him.
And that hero is...
...Titus himself.
That castle must be razed down
on the crusaders
if we are going to ensure
our tribes future.
There is no other way.
They wanted to banish us from these
heavenly lands by using Kurdoglu.
Thank God, they failed.
From now on, their only goal
will be to kill us all.
Wild Demir.
Bey, I took a look at the drawings
Isadora brought.
What you ask is possible.
It can be done, but I do not know
how much it is going to take
to open that blocked tunnels.
If we are going to do this
those in the castle
must be completely unaware of it.
Is this possible, Ertugrul?
If we lay siege to the castle,
we can do it.
If we do it they cannot get out
or send message to
their wretched brothers.
While the castle is under siege
we can dig the tunnels secretly
and infiltrate the castle.
The number of our knights are not as much
as the Alps of Kayi tribe.
A sudden raid will surely
provide us a big advantage
but I don't want to put the war
in jeopardy.
What are you suggesting, Titus?
I will call for a legion
from Principality of Antioch.
A legion of 800 archers
will ease our cavaliers'
and footmens' work.
I will also muster
300 knights from Cyprus.
Where will you find the ships from, Titus?
They are also ready, sir.
I know that 15 galiots
Emperor Frederick sent
are located at the Kyrenian Harbor.
The navarch is going to do
what is necessary.
The ships will be in Alexandretta
in a week.
There are cliffs at the backside
of the castle, Bey.
Access is possible only through the front.
Accesses to the tunnels are
from the left and right sides.
If we surround the castle...
...from here and here, we have a chance
to get in from the tunnels.
Can we get inside of this castle,
Wild Demir?
Bey, I need to see the tunnels
with my own eyes.
You and Afsin go and take a look
at the castle.
Yes, my Bey.
Ertugrul...
...we must prepare our Alps for battle.
They are probably preparing
to attack us, too.
Reinforce the defences of the tribe also.
You want us to be ready for
attack and defence, Bey.
Gundogdu, you will try to find
coin for the battle.
We need gold for weapons and subsistence.
We can get the necessary weapons
with the gold we found in the tents
of Kurdoglu and his Beys, father.
Our goal will be to kill them all
using their own gold.
May God grant us victory.
The war has begun.
We will move after Turgut Alp's wedding.
I told you that Ertugrul
would cause trouble.
We had a big opportunity.
We should have killed him and his Alps
when we had the chance in the forest.
We could have gotten rid of them all.
But what have you done?
You missed the opportunity
for the chest of Ibn Arabi.
If Ertugrul had died
you would be alive now.
You would be in your office.
It is too late now.
That chest, we do not even know
what's inside of it
has already defeated us.
Only because of your stupidity.
Go to hell, Petruchio Manzini.
I met with Ibn Arabi, sir.
He said that he would go to Damascus
in a couple of days.
He wants me to go with him.
-Will the chest be with him?
-Yes, sir.
That is good.
I will go to Constantinople
with the little Shahzade.
I will meet you there.
Halime Sultan buried the chest here.
I did not touch it. I wanted you to know.
Thank you, son.
I knew that it was in safe hands.
That chest, I do not know
what is inside of it
and I do not wonder about it.
But both Black Priest Thomas
and The Templars are after it.
They quarrel among each other
because of it.
Our chest saved you
and your Alps' life, son.
Titus wanted to kill me
when they caught us
but The Master did not let him do it.
We are alive thanks to your chest.
If you wonder what is inside of it
I would say it is something
that has been entrusted to me.
As I told you, leave it here
until I leave the tribe.
As you wish.
I heared that you will lay siege
to the castle.
May God grant you victory.
May God give you strenght, son.
Amen.
I want to know something.
Didn't you have a twinge of conscience
when you did all those evil things?
I would not be able to if I did.
My father kept coming to me.
I wanted to avenge him.
Now everyone will ostracize me
as if I have the plague, because of you.
Gokce!
You defiled our honor
just like our father did.
You are right.
But from now on my tongue will be mute
and my eyes will be blind.
From now on, nobody will be harmed
because of me.
I do not want to see you
for a while, sister.
I don't want to ponder about
your evil deeds and hate you even more.
Welcome mad boy.
You are still like a bear.
My brothers.
I have missed fighting with you.
I hope, we shall fight with the enemy
soon.
If I do not take revenge from
The Templars...
...I shall die in disappointment.
You have a wedding tonight and you are
still wrestling us here.
Pull yourself together.
Otherwise Aykiz shall say,
"What have I done?
Have I waited for this the whole time?"
Brother, I do not have the dignity
to talk to my father or mother.
They do not talk to me too.
I do not know what to do.
Do not leave Selcan Hatun alone, brother.
No matter what she had done obviously
she is regretful.
She seeks the right way.
Ibn Arabi showed her the right way.
She needs your support too.
Give her a little more time.
Oh my brother.
You are so lovely, Aykiz.
I thank you girls.
I wish all of your desires come true.
You were patient.
You have found happiness at the end,
Aykiz.
You and Ertugrul Bey shall unite too,
Halime Sultan.
If God permits.
Is my cap ready, Gokce Hatun?
Let us put it on too.
It is ready.
Look.
God bless.
I told you I would give you a son.
I am carrying your child.
I shall give birth to a warrior
for our people...
...and a son of a Bey to Kayi tribe.
You tear my heart out, Selcan.
You tear my heart out.
This letter is for the
Principality of Antioch...
...and this one is for Cyprus.
Yes, my Lord.
Have a safe journey.
The chest of Ibn Arabi...
...I do not even care about it.
The Cardinal told me the latest
notices about the chest.
We are not rivals anymore.
You being a disciple of Arabi...
... shall open many doors for our battle
with Islamic world.
Congratulations.
It must be here according to the map
Isadora drew.
She says above the water.
She drew what she heard from her father.
If it is correct, this place is somewhere
under the bridge.
Do you mean that this may not be
the place?
All of Ertugrul Bey's plans can fall
through then.
In such a place full of heathens
there must be something deceitful.
You are right.
Here it is.
Dogan I have something to utter, brother.
Say it, brother.
Are not we three Alps?
Yes, brother.
We all have certain skills.
Yes.
Turgut brother is like a lion.
Much thanks.
I am a master swordsman.
Take no offence but what is your skill?
God give me patience. Look at Bamsi.
He became a cat and trying to eat us.
Stop it, do not grumble again.
I swear, I shall go back
to the dungeon of The Templar's.
Stop, brother. We found you so hard.
Do not listen to him.
He cannot face the truth
that he is unskilled.
Here you are, brother. Your hat is here.
Much thanks.
Aykiz should pray day and night
that she marries a warrior like you.
You have become very handsome, brother.
Much thanks.
My brothers.
Is it dangerous to open the tunnels then?
We can open them but I am worried
about the traps inside, Gundogdu Bey.
If we do not strengthen
the sections we dig...
...whole tunnel may collapse upon us.
This can take months, my Bey.
Can we endure a siege lasting for months,
Ertugrul?
If any help does not come from outside,
we can my Bey.
Are the Alps ready?
Yes they are, brother.
With God's help.
We shall march after Turgut Alp's wedding
then.
You go and say goodbye to Aykiz,
Wild Demir.
Try not to cry too much.
We did not have peace in our tribe
for a long time, my Bey.
Thank God, there is now, thanks to you.
I wish your mother was alive
to see these days.
My dear father.
I would give my life for you.
May you live long.
You raised me without a mother.
Give me your blessing.
I give you my blessing.
Listen to me, my daughter.
I have never fed you ill-gotten food.
You do not feed your children too.
Be faithful to your husband.
Do not utter ill words to him.
Do not make him repeat his words,
always be by his side.
Permission?
Yes, my son. Come in.
Listen to me, son.
I have always deemed you as my son.
Do not sadden my daughter.
Do not show her your manliness
by brute force.
She is entrusted to you first
by the Creator then by me.
Do not hurt what is entrusted.
I shall not hurt what you entrusted me
as long as I breathe, father.
It is an Alp's vow.
The day is ours, come on then.
Everyone shall open their hands...
...and not tie them...
...and utter as I do.
For all our sins...
...we swear not to repeat them.
We swear not to repeat them.
-We swear.
For He is the Greatest.
For there is...
...no deity but Him.
He is the owner of everything.
We ask His forgiveness.
We believe in God and in His angels...
...and in His books and in His Prophets...
...and in the day of reckoning
and in destiny.
We believe that goodness and malice
are all His creations.
There is no deity but God and Muhammad
is his Prophet and subject.
Amen.
You, Aykiz, daughter of Dukak's son Demir.
Do you accept your marriage with Turgut,
son of Konur Alp...
...with 10 dirhams of gold and
20 sheep...
...as alimony?
I do.
Do you?
You, Turgut, son of Konur Alp.
Do you accept your marriage with Aykiz,
daughter of Demir...
...with the alimony you pledged?
I do.
Do you?
Witnesses, do you witness this marriage?
We do.
May God bless your marriage.
Amen.
My God, we do witness this marriage
of these two children of ours.
You be a witness too.
My God, bless this marriage.
Let this couple be nice to each other,
and have persistence in their marriage.
Amen.
Do not give them hatred, dissension
and separation.
Amen.
My God, give this couple
the peace and fondness...
...that existed between Adam and Eve,
Muhammad...
...peace be upon him and
Khadija and Ali...
...may God be pleased from him and Fatima.
-Amen.
-My God...
...give this couple benign children,
long lifetime and plenty of sustenance.
-Amen.
-My God...
...make our wives and children
as lights for our eyes.
Make us pioneers for those
who are afraid to revolt God.
Amen.
My God, give us goodness, kindness
and blessings in this world too.
Amen.
Give us goodness, kindness
and blessings in the afterlife too.
-Spare us from the torment of fire.
-Amen.
Your God is the one with might and honor
and is distant from their accusations...
...and is supreme.
Greetings to the prophets.
-Amen.
-Glory belongs...
...only to God the deity of worlds.
My God who is supreme
and who is distant from accusations.
Greetings to all prophets.
Glory belongs only to Him.
Al Fatihah.
Amen.
May God grant you a long and happy life
with your children.
May God grant you eternal happiness
and bless your family.
May God make you happy and give
you a long lasting marriage.
Much Thanks, my Bey.
I hope the same for you.
Thank you Bey.
Be happy.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
May God consummate your engagement
with Halime Sultan.
Amen.
What has Turgut Alp done?
He put up a tent in the sky.
What has he done to make
the woman he loved happy?
He made a stallion from a horse
raised a camel and a ram.
Have they broken any hearts?
Have they utter ill words?
Neither they broke hearts
nor they uttered ill words.
They wed each other
and reached happiness.
May God make them happy then.
Amen.
Be in ever happiness.
May God grant you a long marriage.
What has Turgut Alp done?
He put up a tent in the sky.
What has he done to make
the woman he loved, happy?
He made a stallion from a horse
raised a camel and a ram.
Come on!
I prayed much to kill you
if you had lost your path...
...and became the tribe's enemy.
I also prayed much to die in your hands,
Aykiz.
They are all in the past now.
May God not let me live a single day
without your love.
This is what I know and say.
May God never separate us
my brave man.
When we take Yigit Alp back,
we should make a big wedding too.
If God permits, Ertugrul Bey.
I shall gather all people tomorrow.
Just like the old days.
I hope it is well, Bey.
I missed fighting, Hayme, fighting.
It is time for resurrection now.
We shall resurrect so that Turkish nation
shall wake up.
Turn your back, I shall apply
your ointment.
Even the boil does not hurt me anymore,
Hayme.
You shall overcome it too, my Bey.
Long live Suleyman Shah!
My Alps...
...my Beys.
My sword brothers.
My ghazis who are impatient to
become martyrs.
I summoned you in order to take
the life of the enemy...
...who wants to take away
our unity and peace...
...by using all kinds of
instigation and trickery.
We shall bring that big walled castle down
in which they hide from our anger.
We shall rumble the earth and sky
with the sound of our Alps...
...who shall enter blue and exit red.
God is Great!
For such a long time,
they have tortured our tribe.
They tried to kill our brave sons.
Now, it is time to pay the price.
You know the best how dirty, rotten
and rancid the Templars are...
...who spread fear...
...all over the World.
We shall bring that castle down
with our noble blood...
...and faith you possess.
God is Great!
Do you pledge to fight by my side?
We do!
Do you pledge to become martyrs
by my side?
We do!
God is Great!
May God bless you and be in our aid.
Amen!