Episode 15 will start after 12:10 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
We caught him, my Lord.
Our men are bringing him here.
We will see who is right, soon.
That man fooled you and my stupid sister
and stole your hearts.
The man even fooled my nanny.
But this is it, Halime Sultan.
What do you mean?
We caught Ertugrul.
He will be here soon.
What?
No!
Do not do this, I am begging you.
You will hurt not only him,
but also yourself and your country.
Do you know how
many of my soldiers he killed?
How many dervishes
in my sheikh's convent.
He ruined my reputation.
He deserves to die for sure.
No! Ertugrul would not do that!
But the pain you gave me...
...was the hardest, Halime sultan.
You will live in the hunting lodge
as my cursed wife for life.
Each day you live,
you will pay for your sins.
Ertugrul!
Halime.
No!
Halime!
Stop!
So, this is it.
Kayi Tent
My green-eyed baby.
It is no use to be sorry
if it is not meant to be.
Pull yourself together.
We have been longing for a baby
for so long.
And we lost it
the very moment we thought we had it.
The fire within me does not go away.
I could not be a woman
and give you a child.
Nonsense.
What are you saying, woman?
Do not say this again.
It is God who both grants and takes it.
Do not think about this anymore.
See, it is Nowruz again.
It is so sparkly around.
We will have lots of things to do.
You are a bey's woman.
You cannot be depressed.
I surrendered to God.
I hope God Almighty
gives another child to us.
Do not be saddened, alright?
Selcan, who am I talking to?
Come on, stand up.
Come on.
You will go back to work
and start working again.
You will show your face to everybody.
Alright?
That is it.
I go to the pavilion,
and you go back to work.
Gundogdu...
You are a brave man.
Be careful.
There are jackals everywhere in the tent.
How dare you talk to my father
like that, Uncle?
Did the man who backed you up
against all accusations deserve this?
-Listen...
-He is your blood brother.
How many times you fought together.
That great man
who saved my life so many times.
If you did not bring Nasir, and we were
stuck with Gulhan's soldiers...
...what would we have done?
All of us would have been destroyed.
The only reason for this is your father's
and Ertugrul's stubbornness.
We started to have troubles all the time
since Ertugrul went after that girl.
This is not a selfish fight, son.
Kayis' future is on the line.
How much longer is this going to last?
How many more lives will be lost before
Ertugrul takes the Shahzade's daughter?
Your father is following Ertugrul.
He was going to get him married
with Gokce.
But he does not say
anything anymore. Why?
And what about the death of the baby?
Was that fate, as well?
Or is somebody planning something
to allow Ertugrul to be a Bey?
What are you talking about, Uncle?
You have been waiting
for that baby for years.
And what happened?
Ertugrul's closest ones killed your baby.
If Ertugrul
takes the Shahzade's daughter...
...he will be relatives
with Sultan Alaaddin.
And if he convinces El Aziz
and show that he is right...
...he will be so powerful that not only
Kayis, but also Oghuz' will tail him.
But I don't know to which hell
this will drag him into.
As to your father...
I would do anything for the tent's future.
Kayis' future is so priceless that...
...it may not be left to your father's
fondness towards Ertugrul.
And this price's burden
is on your shoulders.
Move over.
I want the truth.
Only the truth, Ertugrul.
To whom and what are you serving for?
We would never serve to anyone
accept God, Hazrat Ameer.
As for the truth...
The most saddening
and pathetic truth...
...I have ever seen in my life is you.
You either sent to the dungeon
or exiled everybody around you.
Or killed.
May God Correct you, El Aziz.
Ertugrul must die, immediately.
If anything goes wrong...
Titus told us to kill all of them
if anything goes wrong.
What about El Aziz?
Him too, if necessary.
We are 8 people.
Share 11 people among yourselves.
If anything goes wrong, kill them all.
Yes, sir.
You may not die here and now, Ertugrul.
If you tell me and Halime Sultan how
you have been serving to the Templars...
...I will let you live.
And you will take your tent
and get out of my land.
There is only one thing
I want from you.
The truth.
The thing you want as the truth,
is only words full of lies.
If I give you those words full of lies...
...I can save both myself and my tent.
However...
...you are in so much dirt that...
...you are endangering
the whole Islamic world.
May God forbid me
from such a weakness.
If I die...
...I die for God.
And I do not get scared of this
even a little bit.
Shame on you!
Think of that poor girl,
if you do not think of yourself.
Look at the place she is at
just because of you.
She will rot in my dungeons
while she was going to be an Eyyubi queen.
What kind of a low-down man are you?
You will die here today, Ertugrul.
But your dirty blood
will not be on my hands.
Set up a scaffold.
He will be hanged.
Yes, sir.
God, help us.
Do not let them kill him.
The revolt that Nasir has started
in the Selahaddin Caravansary...
...stopped as soon as it started,
Hazrat Ameer.
How do you know that?
I have Nasir.
I took him to the tent.
I knew you did not have the courage to say
what you told me to your commanders.
You are a liar, Ertugrul.
Do not call my Bey a liar!
You, fruitless.
We know what you are, Nasir.
The armies will not attack us
since we have you.
Your Templar patrons
will not let you live anyway.
Just like they did not let Eftelya live.
All the Ameer's of Eyyubis
will unite and destroy your tent.
They will not let any of you live.
And you not, either, Sahabettin.
You disgraced Islam.
Do not dare talking about Islam,
you degenerate pig!
Take this pig.
I have one of your
two valuable commanders...
...and the other is together with us.
You are lying.
Come and visit us, then.
We will cook one of our meals for you,
and you will see it for yourself.
If Gundogdu did not bring Nasir,
our tent would be finished.
The army of El Aziz is under our nose.
They stopped for now,
but they can attack any moment.
And you will be responsible for that,
Suleyman Shah.
Not your Ertugrul.
What should I have done, Kurdoglu?
Throw my son in front of them
and watch them tear him to pieces?
Or give my son's blood
to the Crusaders' conspiracy?
It is you who is the Bey. It is up to you.
I will get your soldiers ready for war.
All of them are
waiting for your order to die.
We will not fight in the tent.
We will attack our enemies
outside the tent.
2.000 soldiers will attack an army
who is four times bigger than them.
But neither their mothers, nor their wives
will know how this will end.
Let us say we captured their commanders
and stopped the war.
And then?
Who knows what El Aziz will do?
We cannot wait anymore.
Our flock dropped like flies.
The way things are,
we will be starving in no time.
And you are the one
who is responsible for all this!
That is enough, Kurdoglu!
You are crossing the line!
Is that so?
I am with you since my childhood.
Have I ever said a bad word to you?
I never talked behind your back.
Have I ever undermined you?
No.
I always fought for you, for our tent.
I gave my woman's,
my children's lives to Mongols.
I am sick of Ertugrul's slanders
as if these haven't happened.
Things are not alright in the tent.
We cannot make both ends meet.
How many times
we have been stabbed from our back.
Why? Because of your
stubborn son, Ertugrul!
Enough!
You should know that
this will not go on like this!
My Lord...
...we should not lose
Kurdoglu's support.
He should not leave us in these hard times
because of Ertugrul's delusions.
If we lose the support of the beys
who obey him...
...this disunion will destroy our tent.
Father...
...we must have peace now.
I am not angry at my brother.
I am not, but it is your duty
to discipline him as his bey and father.
You know,
he does not listen to me anymore.
Ertugrul will come back with good news.
I know that.
What good news, father?
Don't you see?
He went there to take Halime.
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
That Ertugrul is that weak?
Is this what you are saying?
He is in love, father.
He is in love.
He does not know what to do.
We do not know what will happen.
Do not get surprised if he forgets
the tent because of that girl.
If he brings Halime to the tent...
...El Aziz will also get angry at us.
We will have the whole world as enemy
just because of a girl.
Excuse me.
Did you hear?
I did.
What are you saying?
My Bey, that blood brother of yours...
...is poisoning not only the tent,
but also your children.
Like Selcan?
Who knows when
she will get pregnant again.
Maybe never.
That is why
it is time to look for a new wife.
My Bey, if anything happens
to you or your children...
...our family does not have a heir.
Seigniory  will slip through
Suleyman Shah's children's fingers.
We have to get Ertugrul married
immediately.
And Gundogdu must have a child.
You still persist, don't you Halime?
You still cannot accept
that he is a traitor, can you?
Ertugrul!
-Stop her!
-Do not do that, I am begging you!
Do not do that!
You are making a very big mistake!
Tell me the truth.
Say that you have lied.
I swear to God, you will not be
the only one I kill.
I will let Halime Sultan rot in dungeans
that she have not even dreamt of.
Tell me the truth.
Wake up, Hazrat Ameer.
Open your eyes.
Imagine the disasters you will cause
in the Islamic world.
Imagine the innocent blood
that will spill.
Move over.
I want to know the truth, Ertugrul.
Tell me the truth.
I loved you so deeply that
I cannot be slave to lies, Halime Sultan.
Do not be sad that I will dye.
I will die with the shadah of God
in my words...
...and your love in my heart.
The day you die is the day
I am burried with my shroud, Ertugrul Bey.
I will pray everyday to come to you.
You will be in my last breath,
even when I am dying.
Untie him.
But, my Lord...
Do what I am saying.
We are going to Kayi Tent.
We are here, Bey!
Watch out, you infidels!
Did I not tell you not to follow me?
Bey, we were just wandering around.
We heard voices.
And we saw that it was you.
Why did you? Why did you do this?
You will die.
You, fool.
God...
What did I do?
You saw it yourself that the Templars
are all around Aleppo.
My closest guards. The soldiers
who have been protecting my life...
Were all of them Templars?
And their leader is Hisam,
who you knew as a merchant...
...and gave all your money.
And his commander Nazir.
But we can still clean this mess,
Hazrat Ameer.
What can I do, then?
Our prophet has said
"Wait for the doomsday...
...when you do not give responsibility
to the competent people.
Leave it to the competent people.
Your uncle Sahabettin Atabey...
...is waiting good news from you
in our tent.
You showed me that even death
cannot do lovers apart, Ertugrul.
May God not leave me without you,
Halime Sultan.
Commander Gunhan,
leave the command to Atabey Sahabettin...
...and pull the army
back to Aleppo immediately.
Atabey will punish Commander Nasir
in the harshest way.
And pass my apologies to Suleyman Shah.
May God forgive his sins.
We finished him
before he could commit a sin, Shahzade.
Take this necklace to Sultan Alaaddin.
For him to be sure he is dead...
and have a relief.
What about Shahzade Yigitalp?
What are we going to do about him?
He is at the palace for now.
You must kill him, as well, Afsin.
Aleppo
Do you have any news from my father?
No, Shahzade.
But I know somebody who has.
I can take you to him.
Who?
Afsin Bey.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
We did everything we can, Cardinal.
Our organization
is ready for the Crusades...
...in the
Jerusalem-Aleppo-Tabriz triangle.
Civil wars, plague, assassinations...
...sect wars.
As you would appreciate,
we went a long way in short time.
So, what about Konya?
There was a man named Kara Toygar.
What happened to him?
What was
the name of that Bey's son?
It will be dealt with soon, Cardinal.
Our preparations to set Turkmens
and Babais against each other...
...are about to finish.
Of course,
if Ertugrul does not get in your way.
The Aleppo army
has surrounded Kayi Plain.
The Kayis will not be a problem anymore.
You have been telling me for months...
...that you would bring me
Ibn al Arabi and his relic.
I trusted you and
made the Pope a promise.
But you failed me.
We know he is in Jerusalem.
We will catch him soon.
How can I call the Crusader army
for duty if you do not keep your promise?
This is your last chance.
If you want Jesus' brave knights
to go to the holy lands...
...I am sure you know
very well what to do.
What is this relic, His Holiness?
Eftelya, I want you to deal
with the Cardinal more closely.
I must know every step he takes.
It is certain that he has feelings
for you that he cannot suppress.
This way, he will also
stay away from my niece.
Yes, sir.
Titus...
Keep an eye on Claudius.
These unabashed people
are making a fool of us.
Knight, what is your name?
Judas.
Judas?
What a pity, Turgut Alp.
Godspeed, Claudius.
Ibn al Arabi's blood and relic
will enlighten our way.
I rely on you, son.
I will not fail you, sir.
Damn you, ominous Turk!
Damn you!
We should have killed Ertugrul
in the beginning.
Unfortunately,
you turned out to be right, Titus.
He collapsed our organization
in Aleppo just by himself.
He destroyed everything
we have been working on for years.
How can this be possible?
Ibn al Arabi and Ertugrul.
What do you mean, Titus?
Things that I am leery of even thinking
are on the tip of my tongue, sir.
Do it like this.
If you do it like this, it puffs up.
There is some mold on it.
It is still wet.
Let us not use this.
Air it thoroughly.
Do it tighter.
I see that you forgot your pain
so quickly, Selcan.
It is not the kind of pain
to be forgotten quickly.
Time does not pass in the tent.
I came back to work
in order to make it through the evening.
You are right.
Your pain is very big.
You cannot deal with the rugs
in this condition.
Gokce will deal with them from now on.
What are you saying, mother?
Are you trying to upset me more...
...or to punish me for the death of my
baby thinking I am responsible for it?
Since when are you
questioning my decisions?
Do not cross the line.
From now on, you will not do any work.
You will sit in your tent
and try to get pregnant again.
You will take care of your health.
It's high time for Gundogdu
to have a baby.
We cannot be late any more.
What if we do?
The Bey needs a child.
He needs a son,
so that his seigniory will go on.
And a woman who will give him
a child befits the bey.
Women!
Look at me.
From now on,
Gokce will take care of the rugs.
You will do whatever she says.
Her word is my word.
The spring has come.
The tent waits for new goods from us.
We must prepare these goods
with heart and soul.
Bismillah!
Kurdoglu is here, sir.
Bring him in now!
Sir, he is our last chance
to destroy Kayis and Ertugrul.
At least, he is not a fool like Nasir.
Welcome, Kurdoglu.
You already know Eftelya and Titus.
Titus...
Eftelya...
I heard you have been burning furiously.
I wanted everybody to know it that way.
Welcome, Kurdoglu.
I know why you came here.
But things are more complicated
then you think.
I do not want to think
anything worse than...
...Ertugrul bringing Nasir
into the tent.
Unfortunately...
Ertugrul got what he wanted.
Are you saying you could not do it?
Titus...
There was Ertugrul,
the little boy of the bey, before.
Whom I would punish
by laying him on my knees.
But now, thanks to you,
he is the tent's and Aleppo's new hero.
If you want to cooperate,
we need to re-think about the terms.
Hello.
Welcome, Bey.
Welcome.
How is my Aykiz doing?
She is well, Bey.
She is already back up.
The ayran is fresh,
would you like to have some?
I am thinking of the things you had told
me about Kurdoglu some time ago.
After that murderer has been stopped...
...I promised myself
not to talk about it anymore.
And I thought it was delusion.
However, the things he said
in the pavilion...
Sometimes I thought he was right.
I have said I pushed him too much.
But this time,
there is something different.
I know, Bey. I know.
Everybody knows about
his misbehavior towards you.
Our people are upset
because of our migration in winter.
And the relatives of our latest martyrs
are against you.
Some of the great and the good
of our pavilion are against me, either.
Not all of them, Bey.
I know lots of them
who would give their lives for you.
They all come by,
and we talk about these matters.
They are sad about what is going on.
All these things
remind me of someone, Bey.
Who?
Selcan's father.
Alptekin.
He used to play shady games in hard times,
and provoked the beys against you.
Until we raided his pavilion
and took his head.
He caused so much pain,
to our people and you.
Listen, Bey...
Your late father had given this to me.
It is time for me to gird on it again.
Not because I am afraid of the war.
It is because betrayal is close.
You are right, Wild Demir.
Hopefully, nothing like this will happen.
Wait until Ertugrul
comes back with good news...
...until the pavilion finds peace...
...until everybody is
full of the joy of Nowruz...
...than these anxious thoughts
will go away.
I hope so, Bey.
I hope so.
Of course, Kurdoglu...
I understand you very well.
2.000 warriors are impatient.
The opportunity of booty
will make them stronger.
We know each other's language
very well.
But I cannot convince anyone in the
pavilion to raid over Muslims.
Raid over Christians, then.
Is this a joke?
We are giving you a golden opportunity
to go after the infidel Orthodox people.
So, both of us will win.
While I get war booty with my soldiers...
...the Christians whom you call
infidels will seek help from you.
They will fall into your mercy.
Titus had told me you were clever...
...but I was not expecting this much.
And what is your offer for us, Kurdoglu?
My offer is to catch Oghuz Turks
from their weakest point...
...to set brother against brother...
...Ertugrul to Gundogdu,
Suleyman to his sons...
...and last of all,
to be the bey of the tent...
...and nail Ertugrul's head
to the door of this castle.
We are a poor tent
with brave soldiers and a weak flock.
This is all I can do.
It is a deal, then.
Do you have a plan?
You can start with giving a good price
to our tired flock.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
I am a traveler.
I heard that Hazrat Sheikh is here.
I would like to see his holy face.
Is there permission?
This is a place for the heart.
Our door is open to every heart.
Go ahead.
There was a man who wanted to
assassinate our Prophet.
When he thought he caught him alone...
...he asked audaciously:
"Who will protect you from me?"
The Holy Prophet...
Peace be upon him.
Said "God" in submission to fate.
The man's sword fell down from his hand.
Our Prophet said "God"
so strongly from the heart...
...the earth and the skies shattered.
That infidel was shocked
seeing the way he said "God".
A heart which has tight connections
to its creator...
...would know that in any dangerous
situation, help will come from God.
And prays for this
in any dangerous situation.
Our Prophet picked the man's sword up
from the ground...
...and asked:
"Now, who will protect you from me?"
However, the Prophet of mercy forgave
the man who came there to kill him.
Sometimes, the ones who set a trap
loose even though they seem to win.
May God protect us
from the ones who set traps.
Amen!
My Dundar.
Your brother Ertugrul
went after the enemy.
Like your brother Sungurtekin.
But they will come back.
They will both come back.
They will wrestle with you again.
You will shoot arrows.
You have three brave brothers.
Three brave lions.
And you will be the fourth.
By God's will...
...you will come back, as well, son.
My black eyes are full of sleep
Open them up
You are worn to the bone
Gather them up
The life that God granted you
Is on the move
Catch it up
Let me know, son
If you have life in your body
May my life be a sacrifice for you
Your water flowed down Mount Kazilik
Now it does not flow, unlike before
Your grass grows on Mount Kazilik
May it not grow now, unlike before
Your deers run on Mount Kazilik
May them not run now, unlike before
May them petrified
How do I know, son
Is it from a lion, or a tiger
Where these accidents came from
Let me know, son,
If you have life in your body
May my life, son
Be a sacrifice for you
Let me know, son
Just a few words from you.
It is time
to put the cradle away, Gundogdu.
Woman, God closes a door,
and then opens another.
He will give us a baby.
Yes, hopefully.
However, the people who caused this...
...should pay for what they have done
both in this world and in the other.
It all began
when that ominous girl came to our tent.
Halime Sultan.
But I know. This is the problem.
You are not Mother Hayme's own son.
If you were,
these would have never happened.
Selcan!
What are you saying?
Mother Hayme raised me.
I never saw even once
that she favored Ertugrul over me.
She is a righteous woman.
Of course she is...
...but a husband's son
cannot be the same as an own child.
Even a cat eats its other children
just to protect the one it loves most.
Mother Hayme  worries about Ertugrul
taking the seigniory.
Selcan!
If her son gets married with the
daughter of the Seljuk Shahzade...
...imagine what will happen next.
I was wondering, Bey...
I am listening...
Who builds these caravansaries
and what for?
Why do they spend all that gold?
They just feed everybody who comes.
Do they not have any reasoning?
Caravansaries are built
by the state in Seljuks.
Just for the commerce to develop.
They do not take any money
from the guests the first three days.
Bey, if we have a state one day...
...let us build caravansaries, too.
Yes, you would go there frequently
and eat for three days each time.
Go to sleep.
We will leave before the sunrise.
How can you sleep in a night like this.
Have you ever seen such a night?
Mind you, you will have to sleep here.
Maybe they have things to talk about.
Let me go to sleep, Bey.
Excuse me.
-Good night.
Your secret is about to be relieved.
You will be his, when responsibility
is given to the competent one.
Hey, traveler!
What are you doing?
I thought this was my room.
The guestroom is this way.
God bless you, brother.
The brave children of Kayi...
...I will tell you a story today.
There is less, but not more in it.
There is right, but not wrong in it.
Its name is story, but it is real.
Years and years ago...
...in a very hot August day...
...Sultan Alpaslan
took his army to Malazgirt.
He was facing the Byzantines.
His powerful army was waiting...
...gathered together like an armor.
The earth was going to move soon.
The blue sky was going to collapse,
and the brave earth was going to crack.
The armies were lined like a string.
The horses with white mains,
red tails and dark skins...
...were breathing deeply.
Sultan Alpaslan,
the brave soldier of the Seljuks...
...as the hero of the earth and seas...
...seven climates and all Muslims...
...has worn his shroud on
and got on his horse...
...whose breath could race the wins...
...and came before his soldiers.
He shouted with such a strong voice
that the seven climates could hear.
"My soldiers! There is no sultan
but God in this battlefield.
God is the owner of
all the possessions and lives.
If there is anybody...
...who does not want to
fight in this battlefield, he is free.
However,
he who fights for his tribe...
...or swings a sword for fame...
...or take heads
just to prove his might...
...should know that...
...he is not one of us.
Because our aim is to please God.
Our intention is only
to fly the flag of justice in the skies."
The brave soldiers in the battlefield...
...were so full of joy
after this outcry...
...the earth was so shaken...
...as these brave men cried out "God!"...
...the skies burst with their love...
...neither a mad man like me,
nor a thousand wise man could tell it.
The horses neighed
and the weapons tore flesh into pieces.
So many lives were lost,
men lying on the ground, lifeless.
And so many Alperens have been martyred.
And then, the army of justice
gained the victory.
The army of arrogance and persecution
was scattered, destroyed, defeated.
Then, Diogenes, the commander
of the Byzantine army...
...was brought to his knees.
Sultan Alpaslan went towards Diogenes
who was afraid to die.
He held his arms and
raised him up, saying:
"You are my guest now."
He neither broke his heart,
nor hurt his pride.
After a while,
he sent him back to Byzantine.
What happened then?
Let me tell you what happened then.
Diogen, the commander
of the enemy army...
...whom Sultan Alpaslan forgave...
...was not forgiven by Byzantine.
They poked his eyes,
made his wife a slave...
...and convicted him to death
in an island.
Long story short, the poison of
Byzantine is so strong that...
...you will neither drink it
nor be near it.
You will be like Sultan Alpaslan...
...so that God Almighty
will grant you conquers.
Who knows, maybe he already granted...
...the conquering of Byzantine
to one of you.
Your brother Yigit
can stay in the tent, if you like.
I would raise him as a brave Alp
as his name suggests.
Your father will understand
how he has been uses by El Aziz.
I do not know
how I can forgive my father.
Have some rest.
Tomorrow, we will have
a long way to the tent.
What is going on, Afsin Bey?
I will tell you everything
once we get out of this hell, Shahzade.
Where are my father and my sister?
They will join us when they get out.
Are all of their goods ready there?
Everything is here.
Let us go, Shahzade.
Going somewhere, Dervish?
Hopefully.
Where to?
Wherever my sheikh's heart leads him to.
Why do you keep asking questions?
I travel all around.
I would like to travel
with you all, as well.
Are we ready, Dervish?
Yes, master.
Let us go, then.
Can I come with you?
You can. We would accompany each other.
To accompany each other
is important, Dervish.
They say one's intention
is relieved while on the road.
Men know each other on the road.
Come on.
Thank you, master.
Ertugrul...
...must pay for what he has done, Titus.
Start with Aleppo.
You know what to do for us to establish an
organization that is stronger than before.
Good luck.
Judas...
I am ready, sir...
I am ready to go on duty like my brothers.
What do you want, Mario?
Father...
Isadora, my daughter!
Thank God!
Oh, thank God!
Let us take a rest here.
Prepare the food, and gather up some wood.
Let me have a talk with this traveler.
Yes, master.
Tell me, traveler.
What is going on around the world?
Where are you from
and where are you headed to?
I come from Turkistan.
Genghis Khan's army
destroyed everywhere.
My eyes saw
so many persecutions and bloodshed.
Our Prophet said:
"Infidelity goes on,
but persecution does not."
A hero will certainly come out
to stop them, hopefully.
Hopefully, sir. Hopefully.
Let me help the Dervish.
Who will protect you now, from me?
God has a lot of guardians.
"Lakum deenukum waliya deeni."
"For you is your religion,
and for me is religion."
But you need to help me
in order for this persecution to finish.
I saw what my low-down uncle did
with my own eyes.
I will do whatever you want.
I just want this persecution to finish.
But first...
...before saving me...
...we will do something.
I saw my sheikh Ibn al Arabi
in my dream.
They were talking about him upstairs.
My uncle and the Cardinal want to take
first his life and then his ark.
What did he do for that?
They have beds of fire in hell
for themselves, my daughter.
My sheikh Ibn al Arabi
came to my dream...
...and told me to protect the Kayis.
And I asked him
how I could do this in this dungeon.
He told me I would see
when the time came.
And the time has come with you,
my daughter.
Do not allow Petruchio to use Turgut.
Is the relic in this?
Talk!
I said talk, man!
Master!
Are you alright?
Yes.
Thank God we met again.
We have been missing  you.
We, too.
We, too, son.
Who is this rascal?
He is one of the trappers.
One of the ones whose trap
goes against themselves.
Infidel!
Where are you?
He runs like a bat out of hell.
Come on.
I see the lovers came together, Dervish.
May God keep them together.
Keep their generation pure.
Enhance their love towards each other.
May them have
such a good generation that...
...the humankind
reaches justice by favor of them.
Amin.
Where are you headed to?
To the Kayi Tent,
if you accept us as guests.
It would be an honor.
Let us go back together.
Thank you.
Bey, the infidel ran away.
We will turn up somewhere, eventually.
Are you okay?
Good day, Wild Demir.
-Thank you.
-No, sit down. Sit down.
I brought this to my Aykiz.
This will be good for her.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Did you talk to Aykiz
about Selcan's baby?
I did, Mother Hayme. I did.
What did she say?
Wild Demir, say something!
Say it, so that
nothing remains unsaid or unknown.
She walked up to Aykiz.
She slapped Aykiz.
And she wanted to walk away
because she was pregnant.
She grabbed her by the arm.
She pushed her around.
When Aykiz pulled her arm
to free herself, she fell down.
You know the rest.
Why did she walk up to her?
Say something, Wild Demir.
Say something!
She wanted to open the old crates.
Selcan's father. Alptekin.
Alptekin.
Selcan!
-Is there a problem, Ana?
-Take a walk, girl.
What is it? Now you came
to take your son out of my bed?
If the good dream became a nightmare...
...and your bed
swallows a man like a swamp...
...I will take my son...
...and throw your blackened blossom
to the ground, Selcan!
It seems that somebody has envenomed you.
Spill it, so that it will not
pile up inside you.
What did you hear from whom
and walked all over our tent?
What is it with opening the old crate?
The crates of the heart
have closed, Ana.
They are buried deep
in Euphrates' cold waters.
The last crate I opened
was my dowry crate.
I had taken my baby's clothes from it.
And now my fate is
to put them back inside.
So, what about Alptekin?
What about my father?
I heard that
his ghost is wandering about in his tent.
The people who said this
would also say...
..."The mother killed her baby."
It is just a matter of bad heart.
What is it, mother?
Mother wants to ask me
about her grandchild.
But she came to the wrong tent.
-Selcan, you...
-Mother!
What is Selcan talking about?
Nothing, son.
You cannot turn your back and walk away.
How can you hold the mother responsible
for the baby's death?
Gundogdu...
I want peace, son.
Just peace.
We all want peace, mother.
All of us.
But we will not find peace
as long as Ertugrul is after that girl.
There is no peace in the tent after he
came back from hunting with that girl.
What is Ertugrul trying to do?
Why does he want to marry
that shahzade's daughter?
Have you ever thought about it?
My brother is
on the dirty trails of politics.
There is no peace for us from now on.
What is it?
Nothing.
I could have been
neither a bey nor a man...
...if I could not see that
my wife is worried about something.
I talked to Selcan.
What did she say?
They know that Ertugrul
is in love with Halime.
Is there anybody who does not know that?
Everybody in the tent
waits for the words you will say.
The decision you will make
will either disquiet Gundogdu's tent...
...or Ertugrul's.
Does Gundogdu agree with his woman?
Yes.
What are you going to do?
I will wait for Ertugrul to come back.
What if he comes back with Halime?
What is going on, Bey?
Do not forget this moment.
Look at this young man who looks like
he will destroy Byzantine if they let him.
If my wit is telling me the truth...
...he is the new Bey of the Kayis.
What?
What are you saying, Bey?
I know very well what I am saying.
If we cannot prevent his,
he will also be the last Bey of the Kayis.
My Alps will attend to you.
I will visit you later.
Thank you.
Welcome, son.
Thank you, mother.
Welcome, my girl.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Bey...
Halime Sultan would like to greet you,
if she is allowed.
Welcome, Halime Sultan.
I would like to kiss your hand,
if I am allowed.
No, please.
Suleyman Shah, who I am does not matter
even a bit in front of you.
You did everything you could
to save my family's life.
You are always a Bey
whom I will always see as a father.
Thank you, my girl.
Mother Hayme  will take care of you.
Come on, my girl.
The Bey who saved the beautiful daughter
of the Sultan from the furious enemy...
...brought the girl to the tent.
He put the infidels in their place
with his sword.
What are you talking about?
You can see it only in tales.
Now, wait for the havoc.
Let us see what Selcan is up to.
Uneasy lies the head
that wears a crown, brother.
Let us go and slaughter a lamb.
I am so hungry that
I could choke down a whole camel.
Lovely!
Let us settle our guests in their tents
and then visit Nasir.
I want him to hear that
he is going to die from us.
Then we can eat
as much as we want. Come on.
Please, please.
So, Ertugrul, tell me what happened.
Bey, Commander Gunhan
would like to see you.
Let him in.
Let the commander in!
Commander, I am surprised that
you did not come...
...thrusting your sword
towards our face this time.
I came here to ask
you, all the beys and your people...
...to accept our apologies.
I apologize not only on behalf of myself,
but also on behalf of Hazrat Emir.
Our army will stop the siege immediately.
We will pay all the damage we have caused.
Atabey, Hazrat Emir
declared your freedom in his letter.
He ordered you to command the army
during the withdrawal.
Your seal.
And this is your declaration.
So, what about that demon
called Nasir?
We are here!
We did not want you to die
without seeing us.
You must have heard from the guardsmen.
El Aziz has written a letter
to Suleyman Shah.
What a letter, though!
Since he is a poet,
he wrote it in such a beautiful way.
Atabey Sehabettin came back to work.
He is taking the armies
you have sent for us back.
You will beg to die in their hands.
Do not worry about us.
We will take care of ourselves.
How would you like to die?
With saucy jokes
like you have been doing to our bey?
Or by burning like Eftelya?
Or like in the first day
we came to the palace ...
...which you wanted to chop our Bey
after drugging him?
Or with foams in your mouth
like a rabid dog?
Would you like me to tell?
The great and the good people.
The Beys of my tent.
My sisters, my brothers.
My brave Alps.
My Alperens.
We have overcome so many troubles...
...since the day we left Otukan.
We fought so many enemies.
We challenged so many persecutors.
Today, the Islamic world is being played
one against each other with traps.
The army of the thug named Cengiz...
...destroyed Samarkand, Bukhara
and so many other holy cities.
The Crusaders have been coming at us
for years in order to destroy us.
While the conditions are this hard...
...we are at odds with each other.
May God protect the brotherhood
of the Islamic world.
Amin!
The world waits for
a new resurrection from us.
They want justice and they do not want
the brotherhood to collapse.
The brave people of Kayi...
...from now on, our weapons
will not stay in their sheaths.
There will not be defense anymore.
There will be conquests.
Be ready for war anytime.
Ertugrul.
Punish this man who persecuted you
in Aleppo yourself.
It is you who has the right to.
Victory is with the man who has the sword.
The man who gains the victory,
takes the seigniory, Gundogdu.
God is the best of schemers.
God, you are merciful.
Forgive this man's sins.