episode 6 will start at : 11:44
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Halime!
Halime?
Halime! Halime!
Halime!
-Halime!
Halime. Halime.
Halime, my girl!
Hold down the rear! Let us separate.
We will meet in Aleppo!
We shall separate.
Halime.
-Sister?
-Come on, boy! Come on.
-Sister!
-Come on!
-Sister.
-Come on, we are going.
Go on. Quick! Quick!
Sir, they are running away.
Ertugrul is trapped now...
...let us catch the small Shahzade
to please Ustad.
Get the horses.
You carry on, Shahzade.
I will catch up with you.
Come on. Come on!
Bey, you catch up with them.
We will guard your back.
Quick, to the horses!
That bitch called Selcan shall regret
the day she was born.
She will pay for the trick
she played on me dearly.
I shall breath down her neck like death.
There is no end to tricks in Selcan.
She walks in the tribe
like a ball of fire.
She bellows the fire anywhere she likes.
And if my name is Kurdoglu...
...I know how to turn that fire into ash.
You shall take one life of
that double lived bitch.
Before she can hold her baby
in her arms...
...before she can brag about giving
a grandchild to the Bey bloodline...
...that baby shall die.
Get out of the way.
My dear lamb...
...I brought you water, get up.
Was it you...
...who killed my father Baybora?
Here you are, my girl.
May it be easy on you.
May it be easy on you, Baci.
With God’s permission, we are ready,
Gundogdu Bey.
What happened, Bey? Is there something
that clouds your heart, that worries you?
There are dangers everywhere, Wild Demir.
I will allocate some trusted
Alps for your journey.
You are son of a Bey, you are a Bey.
You don’t need to tell me everything.
But if there is something
I need to know...
...you would tell me, right, my Bey?
I always say that caution is a virtue.
We cannot even trust the clouds on top
or the wind that blows.
Anyway, you should start
your own preparations.
Don’t talk like that, Bey.
What preparation a man like me can have?
I just need to say goodbye to someone,
while there is still time.
I will handle that in the mean time.
Yigit!
Was it you...
...who killed my father Baybora?
Baybora was like a brother to me.
Your father was killed by those who
see us as a threat to their Seigniory.
What are you trying to say?
You should understand, the killer of
your father is Suleyman Shah.
Could those who we say Bey and Shah,
those who we crown, kill us, father?
But if I am your son...
...I shall make them pay for it.
Amen.
I am going, my dear wife.
We are migrating again.
The caravan is ready.
But this time,
you will not be in the caravan.
You will not see our new homeland.
When we set up our camp, the first thing
we will do will be to wed Aykiz.
That day...
...I shall cry quietly in a corner.
As you are not beside me,
you won’t be able to wipe my tears.
Aykiz will give me a grandson
when the time comes.
You won’t be able to hold
those little hands and feet.
My battle worn and battered heart...
...will be even more worn out
being without you.
But no one will need to say:
“Come on. Get up, Wild  Demir.
Who will make weapons for
the Alps of this tribe other than you?”
Isn’t this world a temporary moorland
for everyone, my loved one?
When the time comes, I shall join
the caravan that goes to the real home.
We will meet then.
Knowing this is enough for me, my love.
The woman I saw the first time I opened my
eyes, the woman I gave my heart and loved.
Until then, while you are under
this cold ground...
...I shall be feeling cold even
in front of the ironsmith’s fire.
I wanted you to know that.
May God bless you.
My sincere condolences, son.
The world is like that.
An inn with two doors.
Thank you,  Master Demir. The world is
the innkeeper, we are the travelers.
Those who finish the number of breaths
given to them go under the ground.
You are right, Bozok.
May God give you more patience.
Anyway, see you in the camp.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you, Master Demir.
May you have a good journey.
-Yigit!
-Don’t move!
Drop down the axe. I would cut his throat!
Tie him up.
Halt!
We need go faster, Shahzade.
She loses more blood
as the horse goes faster, Ertugrul.
We shall rest here.
Ertugrul and the rest...
...you caught them...
...right?
Sir, Ertugrul and others...
Did you let them escape?
Sir, spare us.
Gokce, put these ointments
in a place we can find easily.
-We cannot waste time during the journey.
-Alright, mother.
Selcan, don’t lift heavy things.
God forbid, you have pains as it is.
Do you know what I think?
It is not wise for you stay back with
the caravan while you are pregnant.
Come with us in this journey.
Thank you, mother.
I do not know what Gundogdu would say.
I do not think that he would oppose but...
...you are right, he is your Bey,
you should ask him.
You take the arms rack.
Gundogdu...
...Mother Hayme says...
...I do not want to worry,
you should come with us as well.
She is worried after last night.
How come?
What happened last night for her to worry?
Because of my cramps. She is afraid that
I would get tired in the caravan...
...and something might happen to the baby.
You are staying here as well.
After last night, I would get worried too.
I want you to be in front of
my eyes all the time.
So you worry for my son.
You want to be beside him.
As you wish, Gundogdu.
We tried to stop the migration,
we did not succeed.
We tried to kill Shah Suleyman,
Don't mumble,
talk clearly so you can have inner peace.
In the morning you sent that rabid boy
to Shah Suleyman but now we are going...
...to bid him farewell.
I cannot see any logic
in your actions, Bey.
If my mind could only see one step beyond,
my name would be Alpargu as well, my lion.
My name is Kurdoglu because I can
calculate where the arrow will land...
...before it is even set on the bow.
What happened, sister?
It is good news, my sister, good news.
It is good for you to get
on the road with Mother Hayme...
...but you have to obtain
a good result from this journey.
You've been looking after Suleyman since
he fell ill. If you carry on like this...
...during the journey and be
the leading helper of Mother Hayme.
Of course, sister,
you can be rest assured.
My naive sister.
You will impress Mother Hayme so deeply...
...that she will not even think about
a bride other than you. You will remind...
...her that you will be marrying Ertugrul
so that she cannot go back on her word.
What about Ertugrul?
Does Mother Hayme not know
that his heart is with that girl?
A word comes out of the mouth once, Gokce.
It does not suit someone like...
...Mother Hayme to play with the pride
and kill the dreams of an innocent...
...well-intentioned girl like you. If she
forgets it, you shall remind her.
Sister, do you know why I am always
beside the sick bed of our Bey?
You once told me that Ertugrul
would never go against his father's words.
This will be over after our Bey says
that the two of us should get married.
That is why.
I always pray so that Shah Suleyman
can get better soon.
-He should get better and...
-God forbid!
Instead of worthless prayers like that
you should pray that Mother Hayme...
...stand strong in front of Ertugrul.
Do all that is in your power so that
she insists on you to be his bride.
May you find a remedy in the lands
you go to, if God permits.
May you find a remedy so that you can
greet your tribe standing strong...
...in our new lands.
Get really close.
I ask for your blessing, mother.
I bless you, my son.
My father is entrusted to God first,
then to you.
We don't know who is a friend
or enemy anymore.
There are many jackals on the road.
Be careful.
And may you succeed in protecting
your tribe, your wife and your child.
When there is no peace and unity within
the tribe, migration is even harder.
Your job is very difficult, son.
May God help you.
Thank you, mother. Do not worry, from
the babies to goats, all life here...
...is entrusted to me. We shall reach
Aleppo safe and sound, if God permits.
If God permits.
Come on, Alps. In the name of God.
May you flow like water, mother.
May troubles be left behind as you go.
May you be blessed with new weddings
and grandsons in our new lands.
If God permits, my girl. If God permits.
If God permits, we shall hear that
my blood brother has recovered.
May God clear your road for this journey,
Mother Hayme.
-To salvation, Mother Hayme.
-Alps will with be with you, Thank God.
But you should still be cautious.
As you know, the enemy is everywhere.
You do not need to think about us,
Kurdoglu.
Do not forget, Rahman.
You saw it with your own eyes last night.
Snakes do not use doors.
Hold tight.
Halt.
How is she, my Shahzade?
It would be wise to check her wound,
Ertugrul.
Press this over the wound.
We should not stay here for long.
It might be dangerous.
We should leave as soon as possible.
We shall find help in Aleppo.
Alright.
Ertugrul.
Will you be able to bear the pain, Halime?
I can, Ertugrul Bey.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS TEMPLARS CASTLE
Please forgive my daughter
as she is innocent, Dear God.
Your Mercifulness has no limits.
You are The Most Just Revenger...
...You are The Winner.
You are The Most Powerful Revenger.
May You curse the tyrants.
I am not the tyrant here. You know that.
It was you who killed Elanora.
Even if you kill and
bring me back to life 40 times...
...you shall not get
what you want from me.
You were like this as a child as well.
Stubbornness makes you unlovable.
But I know how to break that stubbornness.
I am getting old, Marcus.
What was the name of the Bedouin
we met in Aleppo yesterday?
The famous Muhiddin Ibn Arabi
from Andalucía.
Instead of killing you 40 times, if I kill
him only once, would that break your will?
We both know that you cannot kill him.
You are right. You were stubborn and
clever like this as a child as well.
In order to get my hands on that chest,
I need both of you alive.
But this does not mean that I cannot throw
him in the dungeon opposite yours.
Will you be able to bear seeing him
getting weak day by day?
ALEPPO
Take this as well.
-May it be easy on you, Aykiz.
-Thank you.
How is our Bey?
-He will be better, if God permits.
-If God permits.
Is this your dowry?
The first wedding of
the new camp will be yours.
If God permits,
the second will be mine with Ertugrul.
Gokce, I know that
your heart is with Ertugrul...
...but you know very well
that he sees you as his little sister.
You start dreaming on your own
and start to believe your own dreams...
...you will be heartbroken at the end.
You are wrong, Aykiz.
This is not an illusion.
Shah Suleyman also told Ertugrul.
He told Ertugrul that
we shall get married after the migration.
Come on, get ready! Our journey begins!
Do you think Ertugrul would accept this?
His heart is with Halime.
You need to be blind
if you don't know or see it.
Please do not be so confident about this.
These things rely on fate and fortune.
Of course they do.
The world has so many possibilities.
Look at Turgut and yourself.
You've been sweethearts since childhood...
...but you are still not together.
Don't you forget about this, Aykiz.
On the way to the groom's house, the bride
still says "whatever fate may hold."
You will either talk here and now...
...or I shall feed you to the dogs.
I know that someone helped you
within the palace...
...give me a name...
...save your life.
What is happening to this man?
This is poison!
Where did he find the poison?
-Did anyone enter here apart from you?
-I don't think so.
No one knew he was here.
Even the guards don't know
who they are guarding.
I could not get a single word out of him.
I have to find the spies
who infiltrated the palace.
Esma...
...no one should see this body.
Whoever helped him die will come again
to see whether he died or not.
Efendi...
...with your permission...
...I can take care of the body.
I know how to take him out of here during
change of guard without anyone seeing.
Esma...
...I don't know how to repay my debt.
You saved my life once and
now you are risking your life for me.
It is an honor for me to work for
the vizier who sacrifices everything...
...for the righteous path of God.
You can be rest assured.
With God's permission, the traitor
who did this shall be punished.
Petruccio, my dear friend.
Cardinal.
I am deeply sorry for your loss.
I hope your niece's death was not in vain.
Elanora sacrificed herself for our cause.
Was your niece's sacrifice beneficial?
I don't think so. You are not even
a step closer to the lost chest.
Giovanni is still resisting...
...but he shall give in soon.
I know his soft spot very well.
How can you be so sure
that Giovanni will start talking?
I can tell our common friends in Aleppo.
-With your brother?
-No. Giovanni is not my brother anymore.
He chose to betray our cause.
And he is paying the price of this choice.
Petruccio, Petruccio,
not only the traitors...
...those who cannot succeed
in their duties also pay a price.
If you want me to persuade
our Holy Father for the Crusades...
...you have to take back the holy relics
Muslims stole from us.
I shall remind you of this everyday
until I return to Europe...
...my dear friend Petruccio.
-What is it, Marcus?
-Titus has returned to the castle, sir.
Get your hands off me!
Let go!
Well done!
You went with 30 knights and
returned with two Turkmen, dear Titus.
Big job, big success.
This child is not
an ordinary Turkmen, Cardinal.
He is a Seljuk Shahzade.
Isn't he one of the Shahzades
you let escape last time?
Well, who is this?
Your death!
Well done, Titus. You are
quite brave against a wounded lion...
...but when you encounter lions in the
forest, who'll look for a hole to hide?
I am going to Antioch.
I have some business to attend to.
I shall take back my guest when I get
back. Look after him well while I am gone.
May you have a good journey, dear Thomas.
Take our guest to his palace.
Take him to the palace as well.
This presumptuous Turkmen
shall beg for me to kill him.
First we shall visit a friend.
He will look after Halime and...
...we will receive his blessing.
-Alright.
Be strong, my girl. We are almost there.
You cowards! Why don't you untie me?
Are you afraid?
Do we treat your prisoners like this?
-Are you fine?
-Save your breath, young man.
They won't hear you here.
They won't understand your troubles.
Here, only God will hear you.
Who are you?
I warned you many times!
I told you that your personal revenge
should not overshadow your tasks!
But you went after that Turk anyway.
I lost 30 knights
because of your incompetence.
Forgive me, sir.
Didn't you see how
the cardinal was teasing us?
You humiliated me and
all the Templar Knights.
Never...
...ever ask me to forgive you once again.
I understand, sir.
-But...
-But what, Titus?
Ertugrul was going to Aleppo.
I thought you might want to know this.
He must be going to Aziz's palace
as an envoy of the Kayis.
I shall give you once last chance, Titus.
What is it you want me to do, sir?
Go to Aleppo immediately.
Talk with Nasir and finish this job.
Then clean your own mess.
I understand, sir.
First complete your tasks
for the Son of God, Titus.
Then, Ertugrul is yours.
You can do whatever you wish.
-Thank God you are here.
-Thank God we meet again.
Where were you, Bey?
We were worried when you did not show up.
Where is Turgut Alp?
-Father, where is Yigit? He is not here.
-Keep calm, keep calm, my girl.
I will call the doctor and
meet you in the lodge.
May the Son of God greet our dead brother
in His kingdom up in heaven.
Will his death make our job easier?
Aziz is really confused
about Sahabettin at the moment.
When the assassin is found dead
after accusing Sahabettin...
...this will confuse him even more.
The rest is up to you.
You must feed fears
and suspicions within Aziz.
I will be a guest of
the emir tonight as well.
In the sweetest moment of our night
I shall whisper Ustad's words in his ear.
He will be my slave from now on.
Eftalya.
Don't get carried away
while doing your job.
I am Esma to El Aziz and
Eftalya to you and your Templar Knights.
I'm only doing my job.
Shall I take the tray
if you won't eat, Efendi?
Father?
Yigit still has not arrived, father.
Father, Yigit has not arrived.
May God help and be with us.
Dear God,
please don't leave us in despair.
Amen. She shall recover.
May God bestow a speedy recovery upon her.
Hanim, how is our guest?
The doctor said that she should regain
consciousness by the morning, God willing.
We should go to the hall.
Our sheikh would like to see you.
Is Ibn Arabi here?
You can go, Ertugrul. I will wait here.
What is this outrage?
How can you come in without permission?
Kurdoglu, people are entering the marquee
not by the door but from the back...
...and you still request permission.
Get to the point, Gundogdu.
Say what you have to say.
I will not say anything to you until
my father opens his eyes, Kurdoglu.
But when he opens his eyes,
not even the candles...
...even if all the stars in heaven go out,
no one can take you away from me.
In the mean time...
...a bow and arrow are good.
You don't need to get face to face
like you do with a sword or a dagger.
Welcome, son.
You are always welcome here.
I am joyous I saw you.
May she recover soon. Our master's
grandson told us what happened.
Efendi, when I first came to Aleppo,
the Templar Knights wanted to kill me...
...but we were saved with your help.
I saw you in my dream.
Help is from God, don't ever forget
that He is the source of all favors...
...and don't ever tell
your brothers your dreams.
His highness Joseph also had a dream.
He told it to his father
for him to interpret it.
What was Prophet Jacob's
first reply to him?
Do not tell your brothers your dreams.
Do not forget...
...if you don't keep one secret, the Owner
of Secrets will not give you another one.
I understand.
Look, our guest is here.
He has secrets,
he respects the Owner of Secrets.
May God keep his blessing over us.
It was Sultan Geylani's statement:
"Birds fly with their own kind.
Eagles with eagles, crows with crows."
Our job was to bring the eagles together.
Thank God.
You are entrusted first in God,
then with each other.
You can discuss everything together.
What do the Templars want from you?
Brother Dogan?
Yes, my brother?
Do you think Alp Turgut and
Yigit will be here in the morning?
I do not know, Brother Bamsi.
We fended off so many troubles
while we were together.
The Mongols and Crusaders...
...wolves and bears...
...snow and winter did not stop us.
So those knights would have...
I do not know, Brother Bamsi.
My tongue cannot say
what is in my heart...
...my heart cannot accept
what my tongue might say.
Where is this Bey Afsin? He said he would
be back by nightfall but he is not.
I do not know that either, Brother Bamsi.
We do not know anything about him.
May God bless us with a good ending.
Is it true that there is
a black death plague in the Kayi tribe?
Plague?
I was surprised when I heard it as well.
But our commander Nasir said that
he got such an intelligence.
There was no plague when I left the tribe.
But we caught someone who was trying
to contaminate the tribe's food...
...with plagued meat.
She said that the Templars had ordered it.
Are they under every stone we turn?
If the news of a plague
in our tribe reached Aleppo before me...
...it means that
the Templars are behind it.
How much do you trust
this commander called Nasir?
I do not trust anyone
in the palace anymore, Ertugrul.
When I was just about to catch
the man who tried to kill me...
Stop, don't!
Nasir killed him for no reason at all.
That man did not die.
I questioned him when he recovered.
But yesterday,
he killed himself right before my eyes.
What do you plan to do?
First thing tomorrow
I will tell El Aziz about Nasir.
My nephew will not turn
a deaf ear to my warnings this time.
Do not touch her.
Do not touch and move away.
Midwife, what is happening?
For the love of God please help her.
Be patient, my soul
Don’t expect a remedy to your problem
Don’t throw yourself into a fire
and expect your lover to save you
Pearls of tears weep through
the mother of pearl of your eyes
Don’t expect anything from
the female with coral pearl lips
Come, do not rejoice
and cry, poor nightingale
Don’t expect anything from
the female with a mouth like rose garden
My Esma? My beautiful eyes?
My silky face?
Why are you so down?
What is it that bothers you?
Didn’t you like the poem?
Is it possible for me to not like a poem
from that enchanting voice of yours?
Is it possible for me to fall
into the darkness...
...while you shine my night by being here?
Don’t you know how anxious I wait for
the time we can be together and rejoice.
Well?
What is your trouble then? Tell me.
I seal my lips as I am afraid
that I might be presumptuous.
My Esma.
Tell me.
-Sahabettin.
-I don’t understand. Sahabettin?
Did he do something to you?
-Did he...
-No, not like that.
I am only a loyal and
trusted servant in his eyes.
But this is my fear.
I fear that I might have sinned
because of him, my sultan.
He trusts me more than anyone else.
All the secrets he hides from others,
he shares with me.
He didn’t even hide
the assassin from me, my sultan.
I was taking food to him every day.
But today...
...the man...
...died with foams
coming out of his mouth.
I think he was poisoned, my sultan.
Why didn’t you tell me, Esma?
I was afraid.
-And I am still afraid.
-What are you afraid of?
If Sahabettin...
...poisoned that man with
the food I took there...
What if I gave that poison...
...and committed a sin by killing him?
It is alright, do not worry.
My sultan...
...I knew that he was not an
innocent man...
...but why didn’t he punish him himself?
Why did he hide it from me?
I have not even harmed
an ant until this day.
-You know my heart.
-Okay.
-I can’t even step on an ant.
-It is alright.
May God forgive me.
What if I sinned and...
...killed him?
It is alright. Do not worry.
It is over.
Do not worry.
My daughter...
...looks like the moon.
Her eyebrows are like...
...a stretched bow.
When she waves her hair...
...she looks like a pony with long mare.
There will be a feast soon...
...her face will shine up the room.
She is just like a son...
...who will be a valiant Bey.
Hayme?
Mother Hayme? Mother Hayme, wake up.
-What happened, my girl?
-Do now panic, mother, it is good news.
Suleyman Shah called your name.
Bey? Bey?
Bey, I am here.
-Did he say anything else?
-No, mother.
He only said your name.
My girl, may God bless you.
You suffer with us.
You did not stay with your sister...
...you set on the road with us.
Please do not say that, Mother Hayme.
I see Suleyman Shah as my father as well.
He has every right over me and my sister.
Moreover...
...I will be his bride soon.
I will call him father.
I pray to God every time I see you two.
I pray to God for a life like
yours for Ertugrul and I.
When I learned that you found me suitable
for Ertugrul and wanted me as a bride...
...I was honored.
-Gokce.
It is late now.
You are very tired.
Go and sleep, my girl.
I am sorry, Mother Hayme.
I was tactless.
-I only...
-Gokce.
Look, my girl. This is a matter of fate.
It cannot be realized by my wishes.
Fate is what God has written for us.
Do you understand?
Go on, go and rest for a bit. Come on.
Do not fear, my Shahzade.
You will not be subjected to this.
You come from a noble blood.
Let my Turgut Aga go.
Noble people cannot be sad
over the fates of their slaves.
They can only be anxious for their cause.
You cowards!
Kill me without playing around!
Your end will not be so easy, Turkmen.
You will beg...
...but you will live.
In a way I want you to.
I have only one live and
it is borrowed from God.
How can you scare me?
Sometimes people even get scared
from themselves.
If they don’t fear for themselves, they
fear for the lives of their loved ones.
Isn’t that so, Giovanni?
Valiant boy.
Do not trust your youth and courage.
This is not a struggle.
There is no one here
other than God who can hear you.
Dear God...
...be my side and help me.
As you get desperate,
remember that God is The Ultimate Decider.
While you starve, recite that
He is The Giver of Prosperity.
You are with your God here.
Do not forget this.
And know that you are
in the School of Joseph.
If you turn your back on God
and turn to yourself...
...they will make you so that
you fear from your own self.
I will succeed with this miserable Turk
where I failed with Giovanni.
How long do you think it will take
for him to give in, sir?
According to the methods in this book,
he can only resist for 40 days.
And then?
I was not aware of your arrival,
dear Thomas.
You are like the angel of death.
You showed up suddenly once again.
How are our guests?
They are resting in their quarters.
Are you going to be victorious
through the mice you put in dungeons?
Even I have a hard time
in understanding you.
Dear Thomas...
...I do not stick my nose
at your business in Europe.
And you should not dwell
in the matters here.
That is your decision. I am merely
trying to convince our Holy Father...
...to a new Crusade.
I will find Ibn Arabi’s chest and
the sacred relics inside sooner or later.
This is a promise and
the Son of God may be my witness.
But I will not do it
with knights like Titus.
I will do it through people who think
they are still Turks but...
...I shall decide on what they shall be.
-How will you accomplish this?
With an old Asian legend.
We are about to pick
the fruit of our hard work.
The Vizier is as good as dead
for El Aziz now. Aleppo will remember...
...Sahabettin as a traitor
who collaborated with the Crusaders.
And I will reveal this betrayal and become
his highness Ameer’ s only trusted aide.
What about Ertugrul?
I mean Kayis...
...and their territory?
It will be resolved today, right?
Don’t you worry about it. El Aziz is
a puppet, which I hold the strings now.
Ertugrul will leave that palace
as a man who lost everything.
No, my friend. You are mistaken.
Ertugrul will understand
what he lost when he meets us.
Ertugrul?
Great God!
Ertugrul, be careful.
I thank God. You are better now.
Father?
Father, where is Yigit?
Did something happen to Yigit,
where is my brother?
No, my dear girl. Nothing happened to him.
He is with the Alps.
Calm down, your wound might
start to bleed.
Where are we, father?
We reached Aleppo, my girl.
We are at a secure place.
Father, why is Yigit not with us?
I want to see my brother.
You will see him tomorrow, my girl.
Sleep now. You should sleep.
Sleep and rest.
Dear God...
...spare these innocents.
Bring Yigit to us safe and sound.
The servant told the truth.
The man is indeed poisoned, your highness.
Akcakoca, what kind of a disaster
this plague is?
Didn’t we kill all those sheep
to fend it off?
We did, Bey. We did but...
...this is a child’s doing. She couldn’t
sacrifice her lamb and hid it.
We set on the road tomorrow.
What will happen to these people?
Bey, there is nothing we can do for them.
In a few days they will...
Will we leave them here?
I will stay with them.
Bey, I know there is nothing I can do...
...but I can relieve their pain
for a while.
Akcakoca...
...there are some who don’t want to
migrate. I need to talk to them.
If they stay here, it would be a disaster.
Whatever happens, they need to know this.
May God make it easy for you.
Your highness Ameer.
I brought the gratitude of Kayi tribe
and my father Suleyman Shah’s regards...
...for the new home you have given us.
About your tribe...
...some rumors have
reached my ears.
Are you going to say anything
about them, Ertugrul?
I talked with your vizier
Sahabettin Tugrul as well...
...these rumors are lies.
Templars who are not fond of the alliance
between us attacked our tribe.
Those who tried to spread disease
in our tribe and the people...
...who spread these rumors are the same.
You are lying, Ertugrul.
The enemy who you think is beyond your
borders are actually inside your palace.
You are not aware.
Your highness...
What are you doing here, Nasir?
Where is his highness the Ameer?
Guards.
How dare you?
Inform El Aziz immediately.
Calm down, Vizier.
This is actually the order of
his highness the Ameer.
He personally wants to question you.
Is Kurdoglu not here?
I do not know where he is, Bey.
He told me to pack his belongings
and make them ready for the caravan.
He is to solve an important matter
and join the caravan later.
He will join the caravan you say.
So Kurdoglu Bey will migrate with us.
Alpargu, tell me. Your Bey does not
do anything without informing you.
I really do not know, Bey.
He only said that it was
about Suleyman Shah...
...that was all.
The cart shook him up more than
we expected, Mother Hayme.
You are right, Master Demir.
It is good that we stopped to rest.
The horses will have a chance to
rest as well.
May God give him health,
so that he can walk while entering Aleppo.
If God permits.
-Hayme.
-Bey!
Bey!
Bey?
Come on, my girl. Stand back so that
our Bey can breathe freely.
Tell me, why is the Ameer not coming?
I really do not know why his highness
is acting like this, my Vizier.
I have insisted repeatedly
but he did not want to talk.
But he gave you an assurance.
You shall be tried justly.
And I shall be personally responsible
for your just trial.
You may leave, Nasir.
Dear God...
...I am ready to be hurt,
but don’t let the justice be hurt.
Do not give the tyrants an opportunity.
The tyrant may kill me if he wishes...
...but the order that shall dignify
Your name may live until eternity, my God.
Turkmen brave.
Ertugrul Bey.
You won’t regret it if you turn around.
Efendi Titus says: “The eagle is in
the cage, now it is the wolf’s turn.”