Episode 11 will start after 12 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Amanos Mountains
The Templar’s Castle
How many knights
are you taking with you, Marcus?
Twelve, sir.
They are waiting for me by the hillside.
Good.
-Godspeed you like Jesus and the apostles.
-Thank you, sir.
Eftelya must die, Marcus.
Not only her, but also Ertugrul.
If you succeed in this...
...we will have the control
of all the Kayi tribe in our hands.
Eftelya does not have to die, sir.
Now her true identity is revealed.
If she lives,
all of us would be under threat.
She was our precious and loyal sister.
Unfortunately,
this is the decree absolute.
God would grant her
what she deserves in His heaven.
I want Ertugrul’s head, Marcus.
It would be great
if we invited Suleyman Shah to dinner...
...and served his son’s head...
...as a welcome gift.
Hope nothing is wrong, Kurdoglu.
Why are you standing there like
a poplar tree at this time of the morning?
Go your own way, Wild Demir!
I am already worn out.
Just tell me if you need anything.
I would prune your branches,
I would water you.
I can even fertilize you if you like.
Selcan, take it sweetheart.
Selcan, my beautiful bride.
What happened? Tell me.
Who upset you?
What are you afraid of? Just tell me.
Is there a malice
on our men going to Aleppo?
If there is, just say it
so we can find a solution.
Your man, my two sons are on the way.
Come on, just tell your mother.
The road to Aleppo...
...had turned into
the river of blood, mother.
Our heroes were drifting along.
All the mountains...
...all the hills
were erupting with flames.
Blood was everywhere, blood!
Then I jumped in the river of the blood.
Then I looked in each
and every other face of our heroes.
I looked for Gundogdu’s dead body, mother.
Blood was everywhere.
No man has ever seen this much blood.
Selcan.
My beloved daughter was this just a dream?
It was much much real than a dream.
I saw Ertugrul’s dead body.
It was drifting along.
God forbid.
La ilahe illallah Muhammeden resulullah
Selcan, come on,
let me take you to your tent.
Come on sweetheart.
Bey, I will be right back
after taking her to the tent.
Do not bother, mother.
I am fine. I can go by myself.
I am fine.
I’m fine.
What is wrong with her, Hayme?
Are we supposed to deal with her lunacy
as we have so much things to worry about?
She is pregnant, Bey. It is not easy.
She is with a child
and doesn’t know what is coming next.
Living is hard without knowing
what tomorrow will bring.
Her man went to Aleppo.
Who knows what other problems she has.
These things are upsetting her.
Keep an eye on her.
Nothing is predictable.
May God help her.
I got stunned seeing her
like this early in the morning.
What do you think you are doing?
There is a saying: “Don’t go
on a journey with a woman’s mind.”
So it was true.
Gundogdu went with that bastard.
You must not let
this ruin my family, Kurdoglu.
How come?
Only Ertugrul was
supposed to go with his Alps.
My Gundogdu...
...convinced his father
in order to go with them.
They are aware of
the troubles this mission may cause.
Suleyman Shah has sent Hamza with them.
Do not worry. I will do anything I can.
Kurdoglu!
Are you not going
to tell me who is involved in this?
The less people know,
the safer we will be.
Both of us.
Sister, what was he doing here?
He came to comfort me
after hearing what happened.
What comfort, sister?
Gundogdu...
...is on the way to Aleppo with Ertugrul.
I have got loads to do
and Aykiz is not around.
Where is she?
Permission to come in, Selcan?
Come on in, Master Demir.
Good morning.
Thank you.
We were about to eat breakfast, join us.
Thank you. Next time,
if God permits. I'm looking for Aykiz.
I couldn’t find her so
I thought she might be here.
Why are you asking us?
Are we meant to stay together
all the time in this accursed nomad group.
If you excuse me...
Master Demir!
Forgive us.
My sister is a little bit nervous.
For what? Hope nothing bad has happened.
Gundogdu Bey went to Aleppo with Ertugrul.
Okay, girl, okay.
Master Demir!
Eftelya is escaping, sir.
Let’s move!
We might lose their tracks in the forest.
Tell the men, they must chase the Kayis.
And we will chase Eftelya.
Our main target is Eftelya, don't forget.
-Then you join us.
-Aye, sir!
Come on!
Aykiz.
What have you done, Aykiz?
Master Demir.
What is going on, Wild Demir?
Aykiz, Mother Hayme...
She took her weapons and left.
Be calm.
Did you check the drill field?
She may be there.
I did.
She is not there either.
Well...
...what is on your mind?
Obviously, she went
after Ertugrul Bey, to find Turgut.
What will you do?
Obviously...
...Aykiz has grown up, Mother Hayme.
Bey ordered me...
...we are in a state of war.
I am not going to leave...
...The Bey or the nomads
alone in these conditions.
I won't lock the door and go after...
...my daughter who is
crazier than his father.
May God save them all.
I have got loads to do. Excuse me.
Aykiz...
...has shown the courage
to go after her man.
My sons are with her.
Don’t you ever worry
that she will be in trouble.
We can’t go further with the horses.
Over there, sir!
Run!
Every night 50 Alps
should lay an ambush...
...on these two hills alternately.
El Aziz’s troops won’t
attack at night time, Bey.
The night ambush is for the Templars.
They are not that brave
to attack during the day time.
You can expect every malice from
them  in the darkness of the night.
What about El Aziz’s troops?
What shall we do for them?
The children and the elderly...
...shall gather in front of the marquee.
The women shall be located...
...across the river
to protect them with their pikes.
If El Aziz’s troops try to pass
across the river or the bridge...
...the women should defend
with their long spears.
Tell Wild Demir to prepare
long spears for them.
Aye, Bey.
As a matter of fact, if El Aziz’s men...
...reach to the center of the nomad group
and start to fight with our women...
...we're in deep trouble.
Bey...
...the warrior women
started their pike training.
You may all go back to your duties.
Aykiz has left for
Aleppo after Ertugrul.
Oh, Love.
Conquers all!
O God!
Oh my beautiful sister.
We were both raised by the Master.
We worked together.
We grew up together like we were siblings.
I wouldn’t want this to happen.
Who are you?
Suleyman Shah’s son Ertugrul.
As you can speak in our language,
you’d better start speaking!
I have got lots of questions for you.
Then, you have to work hard
to get the answers from me.
With pleasure. No problem for me.
Your hands are stammering. I got that.
But if your your tongue
is also stammering...
...I know how to cut
and make you swallow it.
You will not be able to hear
anything from my mouth!
You can never make a Templar knight speak.
I will not let you
kill yourself slobbering.
You are going to suffer every
pain your friends had suffered.
But unfortunately
you will not die easily.
Bamsi!
What do you want to know, Turk?
Let's think.
About the things your sister
who used the name Esma told us.
The real bastard,
your “His Eminence the Master”...
...is moving towards Jerusalem
by influencing and deceiving...
...King Frederick
with the Pope's lies, right?
He has already started to set up
an army of underage infants, hasn't he?
You infanticides!
Good.
So that is all true.
Let's continue.
The real bastard,
“His Eminence the Master”...
...is trying to give a lead to the
Crusaders by causing a conflict...
...between the Seljuks
and the Ayyubids, isn't he?
He has no tolerance for the small but
dangerous Kayi Group next to his borders.
Therefore, he even tried
to spread plague to the nomad group.
He had El Aziz eating the palm of
his hand by hiring a man called Nasir...
...for the Aleppo Palace, hadn't he?
Good.
The female serpent did a good job
telling everything she knew.
Since Eftelya told everything...
...what else do you want
to learn from me, Turk?
Eftelya.
So your sister's name is Eftelya.
Nice name. What is yours?
As soon as The Cardinal's
letter reaches Constantinople...
...Marcus' brothers will leave
no babies alive in their cradles...
...in your nomad group,
son of Suleyman Shah Ertugrul!
So Marcus it is.
Pleasure to meet you.
Since His Eminence
the Cardinalhas come here...
...it would be rude not to visit him.
Bamsi.
We have only one martyr.
No more injureds or casualties, thank God.
Take our martyr to the nomad tent.
Aykiz is also coming with you.
I'd rather die than go back to nomad
greoup  without taking my Turgut back.
I swore.
This is no longer the men's war,
it is all ours, Ertugrul Bey.
Sorry.
ALEPPO
That is the status, Afsin Bey.
And this news after Aykutluk's death...
...made us all sad.
How can the Schahzade hand over
his daughter to the palace, Sheikh?
Halime's condition was miserable.
He just couldn't bare his daughter
melt away before his eyes.
One of the reasons of his assent
for this situation, is our suggestions.
None of us could know
it would end up like this.
Let them in.
El Aziz has arrived.
Excuse me.
Sure.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Welcome.
-Have a seat.
-After you.
Ya Halebi...
...my commander Nasir lost
his way while looking for my uncle.
He has gone too far
by raiding your dargah.
He has saddened you.
I wanted to visit you in person.
I want you to accept my apologies.
I wanted
Sheikh Ibn'ul Arabi's blessings.
Also, I have one small request
to ask if he may accept.
You are welcome, but Sheikh
has departed for Jerusalem.
And about to Nasir's misbehaviour,
Sheikh is high-minded.
He has already
forgotten about that cruelty.
But the main thing which he deplores the
most is, your mercilessness on your uncle.
Ya Halebi, my uncle's
condition hurts me too.
But he went too far...
...and allied with the enemy
for his desire for the throne.
I want this to be known.
Otherwise, how can a man
sacrifice his own uncle?
Time is the remedy
for everything, Your Highness The Ameer.
Not only it shows the faults,
but also the good deeds.
You said you had a request
from Sheikh. Maybe we can help.
It is for an auspicious cause, Ya Halebi.
I finally found the wife
I have been looking for.
I want Ibn'ul Arabi to solemnize
our marriage if he approves.
God bless. God bless your intentions.
Who might be this angelic girl?
Halime Sultan.
The Seljuk Sultan!
Really?
Titus, learn our cuisine
as much as you have learned our language.
You can not find food this good
even in the the Pope's palace.
Do you know why I like you, Kurdoglu?
Why?
You Turkmens are very fond of guests.
But you can turn this into profit.
That's why it is easy to get on with you.
Our men must have captured Eftelya.
You must take action immediately.
This task must be complete by tonight.
The death of Suleyman Shah is not enough.
I need the power in order them
to obey what I say in the nomad group.
What is that power?
You should be more generous, Titus.
Tne nomad group is
on the road for such a long time.
The money you have paid for
the goods is not enough for the group.
A Bey should be open-handed,
feed the famished and equip the needy.
You are more noxious
than I thought, Kurdoglu.
I will have the gold ready for you.
But if I don't get what I want...
...I will make you swallow
every coin, one by one.
And you are more generous
than I thought, Titus.
When Suleyman Shah dies,
your nomad group will leave here.
And of course there will be a price for
the group to get ready to migrate again.
Speak you mutt, speak!
Who is the rat in the nomad group? Speak!
Brother. Brother.
Even our anger should
differ from the Satan.
You can't make one of them speak
just because she is a woman...
...and the other one because you pity him.
Brother, are you fine?
I am not fine Ertugrul, not fine.
Look at us!
Even Aykiz went berserk with anger.
If we let her, she would kill them both.
And me?
If you had not stopped me,
I would have killed the captive.
Rarely does a day go by
without having a martyr.
The nomad group
will be in deep sorrow again.
Look at the things we are talking about.
The Pope, the Cardinal, the Emperor!
My brother Ertugrul,
how on earth did we become such?
We used to look for
grasslands for the cow.
And now?
On one hand the Mongols...
...and the Crusaders on the other.
Is anything possible with a dozen
of Kayis and three dozens of Oghuzs?
Look what that infidel is saying!
He says that the Crusaders
would exterminate the Kayis first.
We already knew that, brother.
We were just not ready enough.
Our new homeland is a paradise, brother.
It is only a beaten track
in the destiny God has drawn for us.
We can never know if
the lives of us all will end here.
But still, we must be
thankful for this place.
If God has granted us this place...
...we must protect it as good as
God would want us to protect.
This place is a blessing.
Let's be thankful for this blessing.
Let's be thankful for it,
so that our hearts can find peace.
Giddy-up!
Aykiz!
I thought, perhaps the horse
could do what you could not...
...and make this bastard
say where my Turgut is.
Are you out of your mind?
Enough already!
You were about to kill the man.
We need him alive, not dead!
How will you make him speak?
He is not speaking.
They are not beneficial
to us, alive or dead!
It does not make any difference
if we save Turgut or not.
Aykiz can make anyone suffer, Dogan.
Woe, Turgut, woe!
Being held captive is tough,
but being free will also be tough for him.
I talked to my peer Halebi.
He told me everything.
Leyla, I made a mistake.
I did so much injustice to Ertugrul.
Forgive me.
I only had your best interest at heart.
Nanny.
We must save my brother
and our palace from them.
He is the only one who can help us.
What can he do against
the Templars all by himself?
He is so young.
I trust him, Nanny.
He is the only one we can trust.
Where is Halime?
Is she fine?
She is fine.
Your brother locked Halime
and his father up in a room.
He is hiding them from everyone.
What is my brother trying to do, Nanny?
He wants to marry Halime.
He also convinced her father.
When will this glorious
wedding in Aleppo be?
As soon as possible hopefully,
Your Eminence The Cardinal.
You have no idea how excited I am...
...for El Aziz and Schahzade's daughter
Halime entering the nuptial chamber.
It feels as if you are
entering it, doesn't it?
It will be a legendary wedding ceremony.
For 40 days and nights.
The bride and groom will get the biggest
wedding portion from Sultan Alaaddin.
Alaaddin's sleeping army
will be hitting the road soon.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
My Schahzade...
...do you allow me
to talk to your daughter?
I do.
I will be in front of the door.
Halime.
Beautiful Sultan.
I will cut the things you know short.
Your father is a Seljuk Shahzade.
Our marriage will change
the fate of Aleppo from bad to good.
These are the obvious
reasons of our marriage.
And also there are things
deep in my heart.
Things, I can not tell anybody.
Things, nobody knows.
Halime...
...the first time I saw you was in my
sister Leyla's room. You were wounded.
And since that time...
Your Higness The Ameer,
I only care about the obvious reasons.
And in return,
I have a request to ask from you.
I can only agree to marry you
if you are kind enough to fulfill it.
Whatever you wish Halime Sultan.
Say Aleppo, and I will
give the entire city to you.
Ask Aleppo as dower...
...and if I don't give it...
...may God punish me
in the day of reckoning.
I only want my brother.
If you bring my hero safe
and sound, I will marry you.
I am no different than
those demons, aren't I?
I acted so inhumane.
If you had let me...
Take this meat for them to eat.
Let's remember our humanity.
How will we learn who the rat is
and the way to the castle, Ertugrul Bey?
How will we take my Turgut away
from those demon's den?
Your Highness The Ameer.
Sir, could you talk to Halime Sultan?
Is there a problem
Your Highness the Ameer?
A problem?
There are plenty of them, Nasir.
Whatever they are,
let us solve them all immediately, sir.
For once in my life,
a girl didn't say “Yes” to me.
Don't you also see
this as a serious problem, Nasir?
To an Ameer  like me...
...to a poet...
...to a man of love full of emotions.
She must be acting coquettish to you, sir.
No.
No Nasir.
She doesn't have the slightest desire
for me or for the things I own.
For my wealth,
for my army, for my palace...
She doesn't have the slightest desire.
Did she say “No” to you, sir?
She said she had a condition.
If only I save his brother Yigit
from the Templars and bring him...
...she said she would marry me.
So, she requested
the impossible from me, Nasir.
It is another way of saying “no”.
A well educated Shahzade daughter's way of
refusing an Ameer  in a kind manner.
Your Highness The Ameer...
...Ebu Hisham has a gift for you for
handing over him the entire city's trade.
Our little Shahzade
will be in Aleppo by tomorrow.
Is this possible?
So fast?
Thank God.
So, Ebu Hisham is that powerful, huh?
We will see.
Look Nasir, you will see...
...it won't take long to conquer Halime
Sultan's heart when she marries me.
I am sure of it, Your Highness The Ameer.
Which woman can ever say
“no” to a man like you?
I am sure you will conquer
her heart as soon as possible.
Any news from Esma?
Unfortunately, Your Highness the Ameer.
We are searching
everywhere to find her body.
Unfortunately, our chance of finding
her alive doesn't exist anymore.
What about the Kayis?
I have had an army of
4000 special guards set up.
If they do not abandon
our land in two days...
4000 soldiers are not enough.
But the Kayi tribe
has only 2000 soldiers, sir.
Nasir, do what I say.
We must complete
this task without any blood.
In the end, I do not want any
Muslim's blood to be shed.
They must be so appalled...
...so that they would surrender
and shove of immediately.
As you wish, Your Highness the Ameer.
But if they don't surrender
and decide to fight...
...I wouldn't leave any of them alive.
This is no joke, sir.
How does it feel to
be separated, Aktolgali?
Seperated from whom you love, from
your companion, your blood brother.
How does it feel?
It wouldn't feel as much painful...
...if all the people on the world
gathered, shot arrows at you...
...tore your body down
to pieces, as that, Aktolgali.
My loved one is in the Aleppo Hell.
My blood brother is held
captive by the Knights Templar.
How will this suffering end, Aktolgali?
Huh?
It will!
It must!
My sword will not be put
into the sheath until that day comes.
I will make this world a hell for the
people who caused us all this pain...
...who turned this world into the hell.
My soul will not leave my body
before I bring the reign...
...of the tyrants to an end.
Oh God.
Give me the strength
to stand up against the tyrants.
Grant me your mercifulness
so that I am able to help the suffering.
Make my sword work for
the commandment of justice.
Predestine me and my race
to be at your service only.
Ertugrul! What are you doing?
Ertugrul!
Give this to your Master.
I wrote to him that I was coming.
He shall wait, I will be there.
Help him.
Give him my regards.
What is going on in your mind, Ertugrul?
I have the best tracker
in my mind, brother.
Hamza.
If you agree, I want to
send Hamza to chase him.
-He can learn the location of the castle.
-Good idea.
-Hamza?
-Aye, Bey!
If you will excuse me,
I would like to go with Hamza.
Learn the location of the castle, Hamza.
If anything bad happens to us...
...at least my father
should know where the castle is.
All right, my Bey!
May God speed you!
Let's wait till noon.
Everybody in Aleppo
must be looking for us.
Is the letter from Nasir?
I think so, sir.
Get Shahzade Yigit ready.
He is going to Aleppo
to witness his sister's wedding.
I am very sorry, Isadora.
How will I look at the face of that
demon who happens to be my uncle?
How on earth will I be able
to salute him when I see him?
How will I sit by the fireplace
and read books with him?
I feel like I am losing
my mind thinking all about it.
That monster murdered my sister,
buried my father alive in the dungeon.
May God help me.
We will have the power to stand till
my brother Ertugrul comes to rescue us.
What if he doesn't come?
What if Afsin doesn't succeed?
They never give up.
If necessary, they will
come for my brother Turgut...
...and make this castle
collapse around them.
What about us?
Me and my father?
My uncle Afsin promised me.
We will rescue you, too, believe me.
What is it?
We have come to take the little prince
by the order of your uncle.
Hurry up little prince,
we must depart immediately.
Where are you taking him to?
Please do not make this
difficult for us, madam.
-No, no!
-Please!
My dear uncle.
Where are they taking Shahzade Yigit to?
He will be coming back
again soon, Isadora.
Having the Seljuk Shahzade in our hands...
...gives us a great political power.
Don’t worry, I won't leave you
without company in my castle.
We only have a simple task
to complete in Aleppo.
What is this book, uncle?
It is by one of the Greek
philosophers, Aristotle.
I thought the church burned
all the pagans' books.
Yes, they burned them.
But those barbarian Muslims...
...had them all translated into Arabic
and they are reading them all.
They say it is their prophet's saying:
“Seek knowledge even if you
have to go as far as China.”
I will be right back after I send off
our guest, my beautiful Isadora.
Take your hands off me!
Where are you taking me to?
Brother Turgut!
Brother Turgut, pull yourself
together, I beg you! Save me!
Let go of me!
Let go of me I say!
Where are you taking me to? Let go of me!
Brother Turgut! Brother Turgut!
Your little Shahzade has left, Turgut.
Drink it!
You will feel better.
It is time.
Take him to the dungeon.
I will deal with him myself.
We will complete this task in silence.
Your duty is to take my men
out of here when it is all over.
Don't worry Titus.
I saw that your women
have been armed too.
We were born to fight.
We love to fight with
the infidels like you the most.
Our weapons become more
valuable with your blood.
Be careful not to drown
in that blood one day.
Titus, see the truth.
Don't you ever attack my tribe where
the women cook with their weapons...
...without letting me know.
That would be bad for you.
Bey!
What are you doing here?
Where are your Beys?
They tried to ambush us on the way.
Unfortunately, Binteki
has become a martyr, Bey.
What about the others?
Everybody is fine, Bey.
They will be departing for Aleppo.
Aykiz and Hamza
will return to the group tomorrow.
Ertugrul Bey has assigned them a task.
May God protect them.
Inform Ilyas Fakih.
Tell him to do whatever he needs
to do for our martyr's funeral.
You failed badly again, you big Kurdoglu!
It is either you or the men
you commissioned are duffers.
Are you going to wreak your anger on me?
Decide whose side
you are on, Selcan Hatun!
I am on the side of my revenge first,
and then my man's, Kurdoglu.
Now, do as you wish...
...but if my Gundogdu gets hurt...
...I will kill you with my bare hands.
I will take your liver out
and eat it myself...
...not letting any animals
or birds of prey have a single bite.
You know what I want from you.
Suleyman Shah's blood
will flow down from that marquee...
...like the Euphrates river.
What sort of a revenge is this, Selcan?
You even frighten me.
You saw what my eyes saw, Kurdoglu.
You also saw...
...how Suleyman Shah murdered
my father without blinking an eye.
All those years
I have lived for this revenge.
Now it is time for me
to see that glorious day.
Inform the Master. Marcus is coming!
We have found their location, Hamza.
-I failed, sir.
-What about Eftelya?
They are going to Aleppo.
Did you escape or did they set you free?
Ertugrul has sent you a note, sir.
Is this Eftelya's hair?
He knows everything, sir.
He knows everything.
He removed one shoe
of your horse in order to chase you.
Master.
Idiot!
We will come to rescue you soon, Turgut.
The Kayis!
Kayis have entered
the House of God, you idiots!
Hurry up! Hurry, get on your horses!
Find them for me!
A man, who can’t even
control his own castle...
...trying to guide the Crusaders?
Do not make me laugh, Petruccio.
I am going to Antioch.
I hope you sort out the chaos
you have caused till I am back.
As you would appreciate, the report
I prepared for His Holiness The Pope...
...and the emperor Frederick
is completely about this matter.
Kayis have turned up to your door, huh?
As long as the people like you exist...
...the Turks can go not only to
Constantinopolis, but also to Rome.
May God forgive all our sins.
Tell them to take care of
Ebu Hisham's guests, Alpargo.
We must make them comfortable.
Let them rest in a quiet place.
Don't worry Bey.
-Peace be upon you
-And peace be upon you
-And peace be upon you Atabey, welcome.
Peace be upon you
Wild Demir, who are these man?
They are the merchants
who have come to buy rugs...
...from the rug workshop, Ata Bey.
If God permits this new nomad tent
brings us abundance and richness.
If God permits.
Come on, son, go on.
Ata Bey...
...do you think Ameer  of Aleppo
will attack the nomad group?
That is unknown, son.
But if they do, these weapons...
...will tear their armors like paper.
They must put one of
these in them for sure.
And this goes well with this one.
Finally we are disposing
of these jinxed goods, mother.
The jinx has nothing
to do with our handicrafts, Selcan.
It is because of the people
who set their eyes on our nomad tent.
The pain of the heroes we lost in
the caravan raid is still in our hearts.
And we also know
who are responsible for it.
That is why I am glad
that these goods will be gone.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Mother Hayme...
...if you allow me,
as we have a deal on the price...
...I believe my men could load the goods.
Of course.
If God permits, you are not vexed
with me because of my fait accompli offer.
Not at all. It was a good trade.
Kurdoglu shall help you.
Excuse me.
They say you are a good merchant.
A merchant, who pays a
great deal for the goods of a nomad...
...who is in financial difficulty,
must be either stupid or playing tricks.
What else can we do,
besides saying “Good luck with it”?
Don't you think so, Kurdoglu?
It has to be with good luck, Selcan Hatun.
Neither the nomad group nor us
have patience for bad luck anymore.
She is definitely a Bey's wife.
So dangerous.
As dangerous as to have
Adam expelled from the paradise.
What did the merchant say?
What else, he is pluming
himself on the trade he plied.
What do you think about that?
What should I think, mother?
Good luck with it.
But, there is something
that I find distrustful about him.
As if he has some other
plans for Kurdoglu and us.
Oh God, please help us rise
from the fire that we are stuck in.
Guide us. Give us patience.
Give Ertugrul strength, oh God.
Considering they haven't killed Turgut...
...they must have other plans.
Please, what did Afsin Bey say to you?
What would they do to my comrade?
What would they do to my
faithful friend, my blood brother?
If you dried the meat,
it wouldn't be edible.
If it was a word, it wouldn't be talkable.
Please, say it.
Say that they killed him.
Say that they threw his
dead body out of the ramparts.
That is much bearable.
But if you say they did not kill him...
...that is unsufferable.
Please...
...if there is something
you don't say, please say it.
That was what Afsin Bey said, Dogan.
Bey.
Afsin...
If he came from
the Templars' den himself...
He should know where the castle is.
Where is Afsin?
Is there a different matter?
When he heard what happened to Halime...
...he could not sit still.
He went off in a hurry.
What happened to Halime Sultan?
El Aziz wanted to marry Halime.
But how can this be?
And Shahzade Numan Efendi...
...accepted His Highness
The Ameer's proposal.
Ertugrul!
You must be very careful, understood?
Nobody moves before my orders.
God gives the remedy as he gives
the suffering, my girl. Do not be sad.
The suffering is a sorrow, Nanny.
The remedy is another sorrow.
I was destined to be
thankful for my sorrows.
I first saw this filly when I went to
mountains to earn the title “Alp”.
She was different
than the other fillies.
She was wilder, more independent.
It was not easy to catch her.
Bringing her to the group was tough.
She used to have her way all the time.
Then she drank
the group's water, ate its bread.
She became tame.
As she believed...
...as she trusted, she understood
how important she was to me.
Now she is yours.
And if you approve,
I gave her the name Sultan.
God willing, you will never be separated.
We have a long way to go together.
Even if the end of it is apparent,
the way is still ours.
I will care for her a great deal.
She will live with me
till the day that I die.
You, over there.
You, to the other side.
And you come with me.
Ertugrul!
Do not act foolishly.
Remember why we came here.
I must talk to Shahzade Numan, brother.
We can’t let him be the Templars' toy
in order to rescue his daughter.
Wait for the morning.
Wait till I meet with El Aziz.
I can’t wait for the morning.
Too late. I must go to the palace.
Ertugrul, this is madness.
Remember what happened last time.
If you end up in the dungeon again...
...we won’t be able to
rescue you this time.
I must go to the palace, brother.
As you’re determined to go,
let me do whatever it needs to be done.
They are bringing Shahzade Yigit, Bey.
Okay, go back to your place.
Hush, they are coming.
Go to your ambush positions.
Trap!
Both of my sons are with Aykiz.
They are more than siblings.
I know Bey, I know.
They must have forgotten their problems
already trying to help my mad daughter.
Put your heart at ease.
What I fear is not
about my daughter, Bey.
Although it is the first time
she goes to war...
...she learned how to ride a horse,
fight with swords and shoot arrows...
...together with her brothers.
With God's help, she knows
how to shoot the infidels in the eye.
I'm afraid that...
...she'll get in Ertugrul
and Gundogdu Bey's ways.
Did I say something wrong, my Bey?
Don’t worry.
Turgut and Aykiz will
come soon, if God permits.
It's too late, Bey.
May I be excused? Good night.
To you too, Wild Demir, to you too.
I hope nothing is wrong.
As long as we have
these madmen in the nomad group...
...neither El Aziz,
nor the bastard Templars...
...nor the Mongols
can harm us, with God's help.
Hurry back my beautiful daughter.
Hurry back.
And take your man
back from those infidels.
Hurry back.
What is the matter, Dundar?
What happened?
Ebu Hisham's men don't seem
trustworthy to me, Master Demir.
I am not sure if I should tell my father.
Come on, go to sleep. It is late.
Let's see what the morning brings.
Aykiz and my brother Turgut...
...will be back, Master Demir.
My brothers will bring them to you.
Today, it is 18 years.
What, sister?
18 years ago...
...on a bloody night like this...
...Suleyman Shah murdered
our father with his own hands.
The days that everyone will get what
they deserve, are about to come, Gokce.
So soon.
Good night, father.
To you too, son.
Dundar.
Son, tomorrow you are going
to take the herd to the new grassland.
Go bed early
so you can wake up strong.
-Okay?
-All right mom.
Come on. Sleep tight.
My little Bey!
Dundar?
Oh Rahman Agha, please be quiet, please.
Your father will hang me
if he hears about it.
You can handle it, please.
Oh God almighty!
It has been 18 years.
I know...
...you don’t want  to talk about it but...
Time has passed, Bey.
Even the pots mildew with time.
There is no benefit
in living with self-torment.
Even his children have
never spoken about this matter once.
It has fallen through the cracks.
If you can’t get rid of the mildew,
you must break the pot and throw it away.
Is it so, wife?
I killed their father.
One of them was a baby
who lost her mother while giving birth.
The other one, was a grown up child.
Have they ever mentioned
about this matter to you, Suleyman?
Both Gokce and Selcan
knew everything about it.
Because you were right.
They kept quiet because
they knew you were right.
You didn't kill him...
...because you are a vicious
person but had no choice.
They know this very well.
I have never sat down and
talked to them about this matter once.
I didn't have the courage.
Sometimes the anguish of not talking...
...suppresses the anguish of talking.
You brought them up
as if they were your own daughters.
You even had your son
got married to one of them.
Gokce is another heartache.
Has Ertugrul talked to you about Gokce?
He is afraid to talk as much as I am.
He knows that I only say once and never
take a step back about their marriage.
Suleyman Shah...
...I couldn’t keep
your son's seed in my womb...
...but every single day
I kept growing my revenge inside me...
...like the grandson you always wanted.
The holy birth day has come.
I said I would take my revenge, brother.
Rest in peace in your grave, Bisol.
Untie him.
Kneel down!
If you want your magic water, kneel down.
Welcome among God's brave servants, son.
We have two martyrs.
We have to obstruct Shahzade's daughter
and El Aziz getting married.
Whatever it takes for it,
must be done. Understood?
You will do whatever it takes, huh?
If only every other villain
who has betrayed their state...
...was as brave and supporting
their state as you, Afsin.
Ertugrul Bey.
Follow me.
I am so sorry that
I have tattled on you...
...and my daughter Leyla
to His Highness El Aziz.
Forgive me.
I talked to my daughter Leyla, and also
to my brother His Highness Halebi.
They told me everything.
They helped me realize my mistakes.
That's why I volunteered the mission of
taking you into the palace myself...
...upon His Highness
Halebi's request. Don’t worry...
...I will take you to Shahzade Numan.
But, no one should know
that I took you into the palace.
Nasir took the precautions
in the palace to the highest level.
It is even impossible
to breathe in the palace.
We must be very careful.
I hope what you say and
what you have in mind are the same.
Or you would be putting
not only Leyla, but also all of at risk.
Including El Aziz, whom you brought up.
Sir, the Seljuks are involved in this.
They must have learned
that you are getting married.
They had ambushed Ebu Hisham's men...
...who are bringing the Shahzade
in order to obstruct it.
How did the Seljuks learn about it?
How could they set such a trap in my city?
Treachery is streaming
in the veins of my city instead of rain.
My enemies know
my most confidential secrets.
Is the little Shahzade fine?
He is fine, sir.
-He is ready to come into your presence.
-Tell him to come.
My Shahzade, here you are.
My Shahzade.
Welcome to my palace.
Can I see my father and sister?
Nasir.
Tell them to get
our little Shahzade ready.
Let's bring him to his loved ones.
Aye, sir.
My Shahzade.
After you. Let's go.
Ertugrul!
Seeing you are alive
made me so happy, son.
-Thank God!
-Thank you.
I learned what happened.
Halime and...
...El Aziz's...
Hasn't your daughter come?
She was sleeping.
I did not want to wake her up.
I can imagine that
this is not be easy for you.
But, as you would appreciate,
the final decision is my daughter's.
I didn't give a decisions
without consulting her.
They are trying to
drag you into a big trap.
Not only you but also
the Seljuk Empire and the Islamic world.
Don't you think this proposal is
noteworthy just before the Crusades?
What trap? What are you talking about?
This is nothing but a set-up
by the Templars, my Shahzade.
The great love you feel for my daughter...
...makes you talk like that, Ertugrul Bey.
And I respect that.
I am a believer devout enough to know
that the most sublime degree is love.
But, as I said, my daughter
will make the final decision.
A game is being pulled
on you by using your daughter.
Think about
the catastrophes that will follow.
The game they are willing to pull on
to set Seljuks against Ayyubids...
Enough!
Damn their conspiracies and their states!
Yigit is my son.
Decision is my daughter's.
Based on our relations
in the past, I request you...
...to get off my and my daughters' backs.
Go away.
If you ever dare to appear
before me again...
...I will surrender you to El Aziz myself.
Yigit!
Sister!
My Yigit!