Episode 19 will start after 12:26 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Beys, when the time comes,
the die will surely be cast.
Until that time, we will not say anything.
However, be ready at all times.
Brother Turgut...
Come on, get up, brother Turgut.
Let us go out and get some air.
See  your tent.
See your tent, so that you get well.
This time Gundogdu came against you.
This is how the Kayis are.
One of them dies,
a thousand of them resurrects.
Are you playing with us?
What do you mean?
We knew that
you won Gundogdu over.
How did he suddenly
happen to be our biggest enemy?
Gundogdu deceived me, as well.
But I will give him one last chance.
What do you mean?
I waved the riot flag for him
in the tent.
He will either do
what is necessary, or die.
And we are giving you a last chance.
You either finish this,
or just like Gundogdu...
This is the water of life for Turgut Alp.
The Grandmaster
does not want to give up on him.
He wants to use him when the time comes.
Isadora came to the tent.
Thankfully, she did not recognize me.
We know what she is up to.
She will pay for it.
May I take that gold you promised me?
Take that tent of yours, and get out of
these lands as soon as possible.
Here, Turgut Alp.
I thought some air
would be good for him.
His brother's mercy
will be better for him, Bey.
Bey...
I lost one of my children
to the enemy.
Let us not lose another.
Come on.
Come with me, Turgut Alp.
Sister...
What is it, Yigit?
I made up my mind.
I will accept Sultan Alaeddin's offer.
I will go to Kayseri.
Yigit, what are you saying?
I thought you wanted to be an Alp.
Sister, brother Ertugrul
loves you very much.
You will be happy here with him.
What about me?
I need to be near my uncle Alaeddin,
so that he would not get worried.
This is the best choice.
How can I remain separate from you?
May I come in?
Come in, Aykiz.
I brought you some of the meal
I just cooked.
Have some, while it is still warm.
Thank you, Aykiz.
How are you?
I am good, but
there are black clouds over the tent.
Anything can happen any moment.
Beys know and love you.
They also know
how much you love your father.
But do not stay hesitant in front of them.
Woman, do not worry.
Do you think I do not know the time?
Let this night pass first...
We will se
what we are going to do after that.
The time is now,
however, you do not see that, Gundogdu.
But you will see soon.
Bey, the fire inside you
will burn even me. Here.
I have not been saying anything to the
tactless people in the tent for so long.
But they started instigations
taking courage from that.
And the worst thing is that...
...the person who started the instigations
is my blood brother Kurdoglu.
Oh, Bey...
This is not the first time
Kurdoglu acts tactless.
Remember how many times
I have told you.
I have not been saying anything
for so long.
I wanted my tent to be in peace...
...while the Islamic world
is struggling with instigations.
Sometimes you have to disregard
the tactless acts when you are a bey.
Just like a father does not punish his
children every time they get spoiled...
...a bey does also not punish his people
everytime they make a mistake.
What are you planning to do?
Kurdoglu and his people
want to finish me as a bey in the tent.
They want to put Gundogdu forward.
And I will give them this opportunity.
Let us see if they will succeed.
Brother Turgut!
So many trainings
we have had here with you.
Do you remember, brother?
Keep your eyes open.
Be always cautious.
Bey, is it needless for us to get worried
that the storm is coming?
It is not needless.
May your eyes, ears and weapons
be ready for the storm.
May your weapons not miss
what eyes see and ears hear.
Understood, Bey.
-Understood.
-Understood, Bey.
Alright, take Turgut Alp to his tent.
Come on, brother.
Do you need anything?
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
The feast that Gundogdu Bey
is giving tonight...
Why is everybody so tense?
That is why
I could not talk to my father.
I will talk about his legacy
after the feast.
His legacy about Gokce?
Yes.
Anyway. Do not worry about these, now.
Think about the wedding preparations.
I am scared, Ertugrul.
Halime Sultan...
My beautiful eyed woman...
Do not let fear capture your heart
as long as I am with you.
I will make a very big wedding
in this tent for you.
Bey?
Is that not the sword you used...
...when Selcan's father Alptekin
started the riot?
My father gave this sword to me.
He said, while
he was giving this to me...
..."Son, there should not be two heads
in a seigniory.
If anyone has his eyes
on your marquee...
...you will not have mercy to anybody."
But, what if it is your son
that has his eyes on your marquee?
One takes even his son's life when
necessary, for the unity of the marquee.
So that lives will not be lost
for the fight for the throne.
-Peace be upon you.
People will see you as the holiest Bey...
...as long as you serve meat
and lay a bed under him.
So, you do not count any other man
other than Gundogdu as a bey.
It is important
what these people say, not me.
They already gave their decisions.
Brother... are these two not...
Yes. Kurdoglu's worms...
They gnaw on the flock owners
and shepherds.
I wish I could take them
and throw them into the boiler.
And let them gnaw on their own flesh.
Wait! You, suckling veal!
I thought you would not eat anything
that Gundogdu serves.
My girl, Gokce...
God bless you.
You saved my son's life.
Did you come
to ease your conscience, mother?
I would want to be forgiven my God
if I have committed a sin.
However, I do not have a guilty conscience
that I cannot freed myself from.
My sister took the risk of
giving her life for Ertugrul.
But you did not keep your promise
that you gave to Gokce.
You started to look for women...
...because I could not
keep my husband's baby inside me.
Even streaming water
has sweeps in it.
What kind of conscience is yours?
You have your eyes
on being the woman of the marquee.
That is why you cannot see anything.
You feel neither
my daughter Gokce's pangs of love...
...nor you keep track of
what you have done to my Gundogdu.
Or be sorry for your baby.
Let me tell you something.
Try to put a baby in your belly
immediately.
Otherwise, even you
cannot hold Gundogdu.
I will take your revenge, father.
I will.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-Welcome, Bey!
-Welcome, Gundogdu Bey!
Long live, Gundogdu Bey!
-Long live, Bey!
-Long live, Gundogdu Bey!
Long live, Gundogdu Bey!
My father is also angry at Ertugrul,
but he does not show it.
He thinks it is clear that
who the tent's future bey will be.
He keeps saying "It is clear,
but he is not aware of this."
You cannot make him sit in the marquee
and get worried about people's worries.
He is an Alp bey
who cannot fin into the marquee.
You see what he is going through
even though you are not his wife yet.
And what are you going to do?
You said it was not easy
to be an Alp's wife when I first met you.
I was aware of this
when I came to my brave man.
If we are meant to wait...
...we can only pray to God
to grant us to wait a lifetime.
Bey!
Your seat is ready here.
We are your guest tonight, son.
Our seat is alright.
-Peace be upon you.
Bey, I wish you have not invited us here.
We do not know why we are here.
It is not Karabudun's black tent, brother.
We are together with our elder.
-Bey, but...
-Anyway.
He is our elder.
He is our ancestor.
He is our superior.
He has my father's essence
within himself.
He will find the right way
when the time comes.
Alright, Bey.
Thank you.
Welcome all.
I am glad you all came.
Please. Enjoy it.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Thank you.
Do not worry about your father.
It is not easy. He has been
this tent's bey for so long.
The problem is not him withdrawing,
it is him realizing he got older.
You showed everybody
who you are with this feast.
Your father will eventually
accept this reality.
Bey, please eat something.
Beys, Alps...
...shepherds...
...the valuable people of the tent...
Thankfully, our tent
found a land for itself...
...after very hard times
with the effort of my children.
-Thank God!
After hard times, our weak flock
was sold more than its normal price...
...with the efforts of my son Gundogdu.
And this relieved you all.
Thank God for these days.
God bless our Bey,
our children and our Alps.
Amen!
Amen.
I have been serving to you
as the bey of tent for years.
We reached today
with all our good deeds and mistakes.
But we got older now.
I thought about it and wondered...
...if the beys and our people...
...would like to see another bey
in the marquee.
-Of course not, Bey!
We cannot do without you.
Of course not. You are our leader.
Of course not, Bey.
My decision is that...
...there'll be an election in seigniory
that is going to take place in two days.
If there is anyone among you
who sees himself fit to be a bey...
...this is his time.
He is more than welcome.
Wild Demir...
...give me some of that meat.
Let us benefit from our son's feast.
Here, Bey.
Is your sword with you?
Always, Bey.
It is always at your service.
Let us keep it this way.
When the game for being the bey starts...
...only God knows how it will end.
What is my father up to, uncle?
You do two things
when a bull comes running towards you...
...you either confront it...
...or run away.
If you run away,
you cannot escape from the bull.
But if you stand straight against
and confront it...
...there is a chance to be saved.
Good luck. Your time as a bey
has started, Gundogdu.
Bey, what is going on for God's sake?
My mother always said this,
but I did not get it.
Now I do.
You got what, Bey?
She said, "Make it or break it."
Meaning?
We will make it, if God permits.
God bless you, woman.
Enjoy it.
Do you think only the beys
are worried about all this?
Women also think it is enough.
Woman, I am aware of the situation.
But my father is still alive.
He is alive, but I did not understand
why he wanted to withdraw.
Your father got older.
He is aware of the reality.
You should be up for being the bey.
But why does he keep the seat
open for everybody...
...instead of leaving it to his sons?
You are right.
Suleyman Shah would not
throw himself into this without a reason.
You must watch around first.
Kurdoglu and the other beys
said they were going to obey you.
Do not expect anything from them
from now on.
Everybody waits for two words
that will come out of your mouth.
Where did this election idea
come from, Bey?
I wanted to see
if they can make a decision without me.
I wanted to see the hatred in them
to be revealed.
They think it is easy to be a bey.
I invited them to the field of contest.
Let us see
how much power and reasoning they have.
You surely know the best, Bey.
Aktolgali...
...our Beys bring the mountains
to their knees.
God gives your weapons
at your service...
...but he does not let the hearts unite.
When your heart starts to beat
for being the bey once...
...it is much better for you
to be captured.
When this ambition captures your soul...
...be sure that
you heart is thrown into the fire.
May God protect our heart
from that ambition.
Let us always pursue God's blessing.
Let us be the ones who are given duty,
instead of asking for it.
So that our heart will stay pure.
Let us hold our heads high
in this world...
...in which we cannot control
even a single breath.
Turgut...
My Turgut...
I brought you some food.
Come on, open your eyes.
Come on, I am begging you.
Come on, wake up.
Turgut...
The old man is clever than I thought.
You have to hand it to him.
That old man could put
50 men like you in his boots.
That is why I played on Gundogdu.
To create some space.
You are as clever as him, Kurdoglu.
You could have only
arrange everything like this.
Thank you.
I am just an old man waiting to die.
I would like to share my experiences
with Gundogdu.
So that our tent would not mess up
in the hands of Suleyman and Ertugrul.
Suleyman fell into the trap.
Let us start collecting men immediately.
I will give the gold necessary
to do this to you.
Both you and I will talk to the beys.
Leave the toughest ones to me.
Alright, enjoy it.
Aykiz...
Aykiz!
Aykiz.
Turgut...
Tie me up.
-Tie me up!
-Turgut...
Tie me up!
Tie me up and get out of here!
Get out of here.
Get out of here!
Aykiz, get out of here!
Get out of here.
I said get out!
Get out of here!
Drink.
Drink. Enjoy it.
So that you will get well fast.
I need you, boy.
Good.
Halime!
Aykiz, what is it?
I was thinking I wanted to die
by the hands of my loved one.
My wish was almost coming true.
Here. Have a seat.
What happened?
Take it.
Tell me, what happened?
He tried to strangle and kill me.
But I saw my Turgut in his eyes.
The devil inside him
was gone for a moment.
What if Isadora is right?
What if he is going to die because
he did not have that ominous potion?
How is she, sister?
Better, thankfully.
She will get well after tonight.
Thank you.
Ertugrul...
I knew you would not leave me alone.
You are my lifelong sister, Gokce.
I owe you a life.
I would like you to know
what will happen to you...
...if anybody hears my sister's situation.
Ertugrul Bey is inside.
I am glad you visited
my sister, Ertugrul Bey.
I would be ashamed
as a human being if I did.
I wish you also knew
who loves you and who does not.
To love is not to know.
To love is to feel.
I know whom I feel.
And who loves me.
Have a good day.
Gundogdu, there are
20 beys in the marquee.
Most of them will support you,
but it is not enough.
We must find more support.
You must get in the marquee
with all the beys' support.
Are there any more candidates?
No one will have the courage for it.
The majority wants and supports you.
I keep thinking, uncle...
...why did you not be a candidate?
I never had my eyes on the marquee.
If I did, I would have gotten on that
throne way earlier than your father would.
I want you to be the bey.
You are clever.
You stay out of trouble and you talk.
Now it is time to decide.
Then, for my tent's and tribe's future...
...I am a candidate.
That is my boy!
Let us set to work, now.
Maybe we will get out of the marquee,
and the new bey will settle in.
I am looking forward to see
those peaceful days.
Everything will be okay.
Do not worry.
I am doing the right thing.
You making the wrong thing
is unheard of.
-Enjoy it.
-May I come in, father?
Come in, son.
Have a seat.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, son.
How is your wound?
Which wound, mother?
I am good, mother.
I am good.
The beys are going
from one tent to another like bees.
They are making honey, son.
It is this way since my ancestor Oghuz.
Oghuz beys are selected
by not the sword, but by words...
...by not power, but tolerance,
counseling and consensus.
The people of the tent
talk to the beys...
...and the beys talk to other beys,
so that they find the correct way.
It is our duty to obey
this biggest tradition of ours.
However, I do not know
if it is the right time.
A Bey's duty is to see the instigation
before it enters the body...
...and take measures rather than
waiting until it enters the body.
When the instigation enters the body,
it will be bloody to pull it out.
So, I took measures
from the very beginning.
In the end, whoever wins the election...
...it will be the tent that wins.
If I could have foreseen it and taken
measures when Selcan's father...
...betrayed me, we would not have
those painful days.
Take it as an advice from your father.
When the time comes and
the path to be the bay is seen...
Will you be a candidate
for the election, Ertugrul?
What are you saying, mother?
Do I not tell you all the time
that I am after the hunt, not the seat.
Did you forget?
However...
...if peace does not
come out of this election...
...I will bring this marquee down
on not only my uncle...
...but also my elder brother Gundogdu.
Eykis Hatun...
Come here.
What are you hiding from me?
Why are you turning your eyes away?
Tell me.
I cannot, Gokce.
Why not?
What are you afraid of?
I am afraid of your elder sister
and things she will do
to me if she finds out.
I beg you, Eykis Hatun.
I swear on Quran that I
will not tell my sister.
That bastard Alpargu did
you such a big harm...
I want to talk to you
before I talk to my father.
If you are curious about
whether I will be a candidate...
...you know me, brother.
Well, I am not so sure about it.
I have long lost the young man who said
"I am after the hunt, not the seat."
You have changed a lot since
you went to Aleppo as ambassador
and your path had crossed
with Halime Sultan.
I am the same man, brother.
I am just trying to stand straight.
Both of us have always
had the same aim.
Both of us wanted the tent to
be stronger and more peaceful.
We had the same aim.
We did. However, you wanted
to go beyond the mountains.
Whereas you wanted to
go through the plains.
These decisions of yours
have caused us so much pain.
We lost a lot of lives.
Now my father sees this as well.
The road leads to truth.
No matter you pass through the
mountains, the snow or the avalanche.
The true eye sees the justice.
And a true man stays humble.
If one looks from higher
ground, he may be mistaken
If you are curious
about what I have become...
...I have not lost my mind
wandering the mountains.
I am still the same
Ertugrul you have known.
I would not oppose neither my
father nor my elder brother.
Shame on me if I speak
against them. Take my word it.
You have a big mouth, Ertugrul!
At least, I speak out
my own words, brother.
What do you mean?
The characteristics of a bey of
Kayi is to talk with his own mouth.
A bey who lets in his wife's greed instead
of her support and his uncle's lies...
...instead of his support
into the marquee is no good, Gundogdu.
Although it is not easy, there is still
time for you to find the true path...
...and to see justice
by being humble,brother.
I brought hot soup for you my sister.
You don’t care at all if I become
Ertugrul's wife or not, do you?
What?
It was all a game, wasn’t it?
Just to become the Hanim of the tent and
to be able to do what my father could not.
Gokce, what are you saying?
You are just a selfish
and two-faced woman.
I do not want to see you anymore.
Go away.
-What are you saying, girl?
-I know very well what I am saying.
I don’t want to see you anymore. Go!
-Gokce...
-Go!
-Get out of here!
I said get out!
Out!
Halime...
Your horse Sultan is ready for a ride.
I will talk to my father
after the election.
This issue must come to an end..
What if he insists on his will?
Then it is my duty to take you
and Yigit and leave the tent.
Did you think thoroughly?
What would I do if you be
unhappy after you leave your tent?
What would I do without
you Sultan Halime?
The tent means everything to you.
And you are this tent's future.
You will be this tent's
bey in the future.
This is the truth although
you don’t accept it.
Halime Sultan, what are you saying?
I only say what everybody
sees and knows but you.
I say what people know
but are scared to vocalize.
What does your heart say?
To run away with you.
A peaceful life far from everything.
But even if you left the tent,
the tent wouldn’t leave you.
Because Kayis are your fate...
...and you are Kayis' fate.
An Alp's duty is not only
to protect the tent...
...but also to go to war for God.
But for this, the tent
must be strong inside.
If an Alp keeps worrying for
the tent when he is away at war...
...the nonbelievers
sword will be sharper.
How can that be, Kurdoglu?
Alps shouldn’t go
around helping others.
Shahzade, Sultan Alaeddin, Ayyubids...
...we can’t help everyone.
The Bey should think of this first.
How many lives have we
lost since last summer?
How many widows and
orphans have we left behind?
We need a bey who watches
the tent's benefits first.
And that bey is Gundogdu.
-Yes.
-That is right.
Kurdoglu is right.
What is this old one talking about?
I used admire Kurdoglu when I was a
little boy because his sword was sharp.
But his tongue turned out
to be sharper than his sword.
He is done with poisoning
Beys now he’s after the Alps.
When did he appear in our tent?
We lost 15 lives when Gundogdu Bey's
caravan was ambushed.
We lost five Alps when Ertugrul Bey
went with Halime Sultan.
And many more. Why?
It was the father and son's fault.
None of these might have happened.
Right. It was all their fault.
These would not have happened
if Gundogdu Bey were in charge.
Now, brother...
Your only mistake is not coming
out of your mothers as snakes!
Go, I will catch up with you.
What are you going to do?
What are you doing?
Does a brother draw a
sword to his brother?
Bamsi attacked us
with no reason, Bey.
Was it not you who talked
behind our Bey's back?
Alright, enough.
Enough.
Good day, niece.
There would be no good
when you’re around Kurdoglu.
Keep your sinister tongue in your
mouth and do not cross the line.
You lured my brother to your side.
You put my father in
the place you wanted.
And now you are in a hurry
to get to where you want.
You will stumble and fall, Kurdoglu.
And I will be the stone that hits
your foot, the rust in your sheath
...and the wound on your tongue.
If you try to attack
me through the Alps...
...I will forget that you are my uncle and
bring the pole of the tent down on you.
Children...
My daughters with shiny eyes.
My brave sons who will be the
great men of my tent in the future.
Tonight we will talk
about Oghuz Khan's story.
The bravest man in the world.
The greatest khan of all.
Centuries and centuries ago...
...that is, years and years
and years and years ago...
...when we, the Turks still
lived in Otugen uplands...
...a ray of light shone in Ay Sultan's
eyes who is the mother of all of us.
And her labor pain started.
Then, a brave man
came into the world.
This child's face was
as bright as the sky...
...and his mouth was as red as fire.
His eyes were hazel, and
his eyebrows were black.
His beauty soon became legendary.
This child just sucked milk from his
mother once, and never wanted anymore.
He ate raw meat and drank mare milk.
He grew up and started
to talk in just 40 days.
He walked, played and traced.
His waist was the waist of a wolf,
his shoulders were the...
...shoulders of an otter
his feet was the feet of an ox...
...his chest was the chest of a bear.
He would herd horses,
ride horse and go hunting.
After many days and nights...
...he became an Alp who gave
hope to his allies...
...and spread fear to his enemies.
He swung his sword to many enemies.
He was the hope of the underdog.
He clothed so many naked man,
and fed so many hungry people.
After a very long time...
...his fame was spread
all over the world.
One day he prayed to the
one and only Creator...
"Where is my woman?"
Suddenly it got dark everywhere!
Then, a light brighter than
the Moon came down to Earth.
And a very beautiful girl appeared.
The blue skies smiled
when the girl smiled...
...and when she cried
the blue sky cried.
Oghuz Khan fell in
love with that girl.
And married her.
They had three children.
Day, Moon and Star.
Years and years passed.
Oghuz Khan was still
working for his tribe.
He got rich. He had
more weapons and horses.
One day, he went hunting.
He saw a tree in
the middle of a lake.
There was a hollow in the tree.
And there was an outstanding
beauty in the hollow.
Her eyes were more
beautiful than the lake.
Her hairs wavy like a stream.
Her teeth like pearls.
When Oghuz Khan saw
her, he married her.
They had three more children.
Sky, Mountain and Sea.
Day, Moon and Star were one arm...
...and Sky, Mountain
and Sea were another arm.
One day, Oghuz Khan arranged a
feast and called his children.
"My sons, this world needs one ruler.
And this man must come
from Oghuz generation."
He said, "The world must be yours."
"Extend the golden bow of our
tribe from sunset to sunrise.
Let me whisper the divine news...
...to more streams, to
more seas and to more earth.
What happened then?
Oghuz Khan's children were
divided into 24 tribes...
...and spread all over the world.
They whispered the divine news...
...to more seas and to more streams.
They swung their sword to the tyrant.
They stood by the the underdog.
So, children, your
grandfathers ruled the world.
No, we will either resurrect
like our ancestors...
...or we will be destroyed.
So, children...
...we need to resurrect.
Resurrect.
It is up to you...
...to take the bottom
line of today's story.
Up to you.
Ertugrul and his Alps...
...brought the tent to the brink
of a disaster before the election.
What do you think Ertugrul is up to?
He must have wanted to show the power
of his weapon before the election.
He may also be a
candidate in the election.
Let’s eat, enjoy it.
-Who will support Ertugrul?
-Who else but..
Mad Demril and his men.
I would not expect such
a thing from Ertugrul.
Tell Hamza Alp to gather whoever can
use a sword in front of the marquee.
You are right.
Hamza!
-Yes, Bey.
-Gather your Alps up.
Tell them to be ready
tomorrow for the feast.
Do not show mercy if
anything goes wrong.
Yes, Bey.
Come on, uncle. Here. Enjoy it.
Thank you, Gundogdu.
It is delicious, sister.
God, do not test us with
a burden we cannot carry.
Do not let us forget you
after you grant us power.
Do not let us fight for fame,
or break hearts with arrogance.
God, there is something
I wish from you.
Let me be a servant who
lives only for your blessing.
God, please do not take my tent's,
my tribe's, my family's peace away.
And do not let the ones
who want to do it succeed.
Amen.
This is the big day, Gundogdu.
This is the day you rise
above Kayis like the Sun...
And the day that
darkness will go away.
It is all because of you.
You did not want an election
because he is your father...
...but our people want
to see you as the bey.
Your father gave this opportunity
to you with his own hands.
Do you think it is right for me to against
my father when he is also a candidate?
You will not go against your father.
You will go against the beys
and request what you deserve.
Your father knew that Ertugrul would have
to pay for the things he had done.
Obviously, he wanted to be
cautious before it is too late.
If he still wants to be the
bey, it is his responsibility.
Ertugrul Bey...
Halime Sultan?
Your sadness is reflected
on your face. What is it?
I heard that you and Kurdoglu
went against each other.
I am worried about
you and our future.
Why?
We have been running away for years.
It is all because of that damn throne.
Neither my father would have died
nor we would suffer that much...
...if it were not for it.
If you will be enemies with Gundogdu Bey
just because of that, please do not.
Do not be in that fight.
Leave the world to them.
Our love is enough for both of us.
My gazelle-eyed lover.
Do not worry.
This man will not behold anything
other than God's blessing.
Today the truth will reveal.
-Is everything set, Karabudak?
-Everything is set.
We gave gold to those beys.
We talked to everyone.
It is all set, Bey.
We will see Gundogdu Bey
as the new bey.
My brave niece!
The tents will see a real bey
after you come to the throne.
Thank you, uncle.
Are the men ready?
Everybody is ready.
If anybody makes a scene,
he will be punished.
-I will never forget your support on this.
-Thank you niece.
You will see how it is like to be
overthrown by your own son, Suleyman Shah.
Shall we go in?
By the 99 names of
God the Almighty...
...who fills our hearts with
blessings and who rules the world.
The great men of my tribe...
Peace be open our prophet.
God bless Turks' great ancestors
from Oghuz Khan to today.
Amen!
May they rest in peace.
May our martyrs, our
great ancestors...
...and elders bless us.
Amen!
May our mothers, our sisters...
...our brave warriors
always be on the true path.
Amen!
This is the head council.
May this council
always express justice.
And make decisions freely.
We believe that no soul
is superior to another.
A shepherd and a
sultan is equal to us.
Everyone in this council
will give his decision freely.
Therefore, I abdicate the throne...
...until the election end.
-What?
-How can this happen?
I am also in the election.
The decision is yours.
Beys! It is time for
our tent to elect a Bey.
If there is anybody who wants
to be a candidate or name one...
...he should speak now.
I there’s anyone else
above our Suleyman Shah.
I hope Ertugrul Bey does not
put himself into trouble.
Do not worry. He is a clever man.
But I have not seen a day like
this for years in the tent.
Let us see who our new bey will be.
Do you still not know
who our new bey will be?
Do you?
I married him because I had known.
Our candidate is... Gundogdu!
I am not a candidate.
While Suleyman Shah
is still the Bey...
...I don’t qualify for it..
Kurdoglu thinks I do not
see the games he is playing.
He does what he can to
create trouble in the tent.
Son, he will play mostly on you.
My request from you is
to do whatever he says.
We can only break Kurdoglu's games
by using his games against him.
I show mercy to him because
he is my blood brother.
I want him to find the true path.
Now, you will cooperate
with him and rebel against me.
And you will announce that you
are a candidate to be a bey.
And then you will
renounce in the election.
Of course, father.
Your words are my orders.
Now that my niece broke his promise...
...I am the candidate.
Beys...
...in this case...
...who says
our Bey is Suleyman Shah?
-Yes, Suleyman Shah.
-It is Suleyman Shah.
-Suleyman Shah.
-Yes, Suleyman Shah.
Our Bey, the leader of our marquee...
...is Suleyman Shah
by unanimous decision!
Long live, Suleyman Shah!
Long live, Suleyman Shah.
-Long live!
-God bless you!
Long live...
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
My God...
My flag...
My weapon...
I swear on them.
I will give and take life...
...for the sake of my people's faith...
...in order for the justice to be made.
If I fail, let my sword
be drenched in my blood.
I will always feed the hungry,
and clothe the naked.
From sunrise to sunset...
...I will struggle
for the world dominance.
I will carry the holy news...
...to more seas,
more streams and more lands.
I will fight for the holy words...
...for the sake of world order.
May God be our helper.
Amen!
My book is my witness.
My flag is my witness.
My weapon is my witness.
God bless your duty, Bey.
Thank you, Wild Demir.
I was worried
you were going against my father.
There are so many games in this path.
Sometimes you win the fight
with these games, rather than weapons.
God bless you, Bey.
My brave son.
May God give you
a good generation of children.
I wish you a long time duty, Bey.
May you always win victories, son.
May God give you
a good generation of children.
Long live Suleyman Shah!
I am your Bey again.
Let us take our bows and shields
May this be a sign for us
May the grizzly wolf be the guide for us
May we be blessed with our hunts
May we have more seas,
more streams and more lands
May the Sun be our flag
Under the blue skies
Allahu Akbar!
God bless this for all of us.
Amen!
I will make your life miserable,
Gundogdu.
So, you played a game against me!
I will make your life miserable!
You collaborated with your father
and tarnished your name.
I collaborated with my father
and I nipped in the bud, Selcan.
Oh, Gundogdu...
You failed the beys who trusted
and started this journey with you.
Nobody in this tent
will follow you from now on!
Selcan!
As long as my father is alive...
...this tent's bey and leader is him.
You and this tent's people
should know this very clearly!
You are neither a man nor a bey!
-Easy!
-Shame on you!
-Do not cross the line, woman!
-It is enough!
Shame on me
to take you to my bed as a man!
They sent these
from the rug shop, mother.
-These are the lastly weaved fabrics.
-Alright, my girl.
May I come in, Mother Hayme?
Come in, Gundogdu.
Leave us alone.
What is it, son?
Mother Hayme...
...I want you
to find me a woman as soon as possible.
Are you sure?
There will be no way back.
I am, mother.
I want it as soon as possible.
What is going on, Kurdoglu?
Are you leaving just because you lost?
I do not expect
anything from the tent, anymore.
Your coward husband
disgraced me in front of everybody.
I am through with everything now.
I am devastated, too.
Suleyman's children turned out to be
dishonorable like himself.
I know how to keep myself off of them...
...but I do not know
what you are going to do.
May God help you.
Thank you.
Gokce? My girl, wait...
Wait...
You are wounded.
You are in so much pain.
You saved my son's life
with these hands.
You gave life to our family.
God bless you.
I gave my life to Ertugrul Bey,
whom I love more than my own life.
But father...
...I do not want to
listen to you anymore.
If I do...
...I deserve Ertugrul
whom I love more than my own life...
...and cause you
who brought me and my sister up...
...and Mother Hayme pain,
and a big lie to myself.
-Gokce...
-Forgive me, father.
My girl?
Ertugrul...
...is my elder brother from now on.
I made a mistake.
He found the owner of his heart.
If you permit...
...I want Ertugrul to be happy.
You could not overthrow
Suleyman Shah again, Kurdoglu.
I made Gundogdu a candidate.
I talked to all of the beys one by one.
I said I would drive a wedge
between the father and the sons.
But Gundogdu sold me out.
Do not be upset.
We know how difficult it is.
No tricks or lies from now on.
It is time to let the weapons talk.
There is no other choice.
First, hunt your enemies one by one.
Do not let your anger
to lure you into a trap.
What would we do without Kurdoglu?
Do you have any advice?
Finish Gundogdu first.
You must show the whole tent
what happens to a man who sells you out.
We defeated so many enemies
with this poison.
And do not forget
to bring the young shahzade to me.
I will never forget this.
The young shahzade
will be in your hands as soon as possible.
Being not to be able
to do anything is killing me.
What if Ibn al-Arabi does not come?
What if something happens
to my brother Turgut until then?
How can we get ahead of God's will,
brother Bamsi?
Let us pray that
Ibn al-Arabi comes as soon as possible.
Water...
He said "water".
I am here, brother.
Water, brother. Drink it.
Bamsi...
He said "Bamsi". Did you hear?
He said "Bamsi"!
Drink it, brother! Drink it!
Drink water, brother!
He said "Bamsi". He said my name!
Thank you, God.
You made me so happy.
My brother...
I had promised you.
And now I am keeping it.
Who is my father's murderer?
If you listen to me carefully,
you will take our father's revenge.
I am listening to you.
Who is my father's murderer?
Afsin Bey.
You are lying.
I will tell you how you can find him...
...and you will go and ask him yourself.
The rest is up to you.
Believe it or not.
What is it, Yigit? What is wrong with you?
You do not talk. You seem sad.
I am good, sister.
I am very good.
Halime Sultan.
Suleyman Shah is waiting for you
in his marquee.
You wanted to see me, Bey?
Come here.
Pour this into Gundogdu's water.
Consider it done, Bey.
You will see what it means
to play with Kurdoglu.
Your father wanted to see me.
He wanted me, as well.
I hope nothing is wrong.
You wanted to see us, Bey?
Have a seat.
There is something I want to talk about.
I talked to Gokce.
Gokce said...
..."Ertugrul is my elder brother
from now on.
I made a mistake.
He found the owner of his heart.
If you permit, father,
I would like my brother...
...to marry Halime Sultan and be happy."
Mother?
May God make you two happy.
Along with your children.
May God make you happy.
I wish you a happy marriage.
Amen, father.
Be happy, my girl.
May I come in, Gundogdu Bey?
Wait!
What are you doing here?
Selcan Hatun sent goods
from the rug shop.
Alright, then.
Take me to Afsin Bey.
Of course, Shahzade.
Alper, is everything ready?
It is, Bey.
Good. Shahzade...
...these Alps will escort you.
I would like you
to punish Afsin Bey the way he deserves.
Everybody will pay for what they did.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Gundogdu!
Gundogdu! Help me!
Help! Help me!
Gundogdu! Help!
Help me!
Is Afsin Bey coming here?
Yes, Shahzade.
Where is he, then?
The dagger does not look good
in your hand, Shahzade.
Help me!
We are together, at last.
Yes, gazelle eyes.
Shahzade Yigit will be very happy.
What is going on? Let go of me!
Bastards!
I will make you two pay!
I will make all of you pay! Traitors!
Let go of me!