episode 4 will start at : 12:35
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You will free Gundogdu, Karatoygar!
Are you threatening me?
If something happens to Gundogdu...
...Ertugrul will take them outside
Seljuk territory.
You will never find them again.
Not you, not the Templars you work for.
If you free my son...
...I will take them to you.
Where are they?
Ertugrul is guarding them
so they don’t run away.
If something happens to us...
...Sultan Aladdin will be
informed of everything.
Shahzade wrote a letter
about everything he faced in detail.
How he was a captive
in Templars hands for months...
...all the tortures he went through
for refusing to claim being the Sultan.
How he never betrayed his state
despite the torture.
How you cooperated with the Templars.
In short, everything.
The decision is yours.
Father?
My son.
What happened?
-Did you give the prisoners to Karatoygar?
-No.
-Father?
-Karatoygar freed you.
Go to the tribe.
-Father, that man would not let you live.
-Do as I tell you, Gundogdu.
Go now.
Father.
-Be quick.
-Go on.
I said go!
What happened, Akcakoca?
Is there someone inside?
What is happening here?
What is this outrage?
Get out of the way, Akcakoca.
We want to see who is inside.
-What is it to you?
-I said get out of the way!
The things we heard are true!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
What do you think you are doing?
Our sons have died, Mother Hayme.
All because of them!
They ambushed the caravan
but you hide it from us!
So you violate our customs and our Bey.
-Shame on you all!
-That is enough, Mother Hayme.
You are saying customs but how many more
lives shall be sacrificed?
Where are the bodies of our sons?
-Where is Suleyman Shah?
-My son has died, not yours, Mother Hayme.
Everyone in this tribe is my child,
my heart!
A tribe can only stand strong
when they are united.
If there is no unity, you would be
condemned to lose against the enemy...
...and be wiped out! Has Suleyman Shah Bey
ever put his own live before yours?
Has he ever put his own sons before yours,
has he ever chose a path other than...
...the goodness of the tribe?
Whatever he does, he does for the welfare,
for the future of the tribe.
Breaking the unity of the tribe while
he is gone, to cry out mutiny...
...is this what you see befitting
for yourselves?
If you try to crush the customs...
...you will be crushed one day.
From now on, anyone stoning them...
...would be stoning me!
Anyone who faces them, would be facing me!
Let this be known!
Come, my girl!
KARATOYGAR INN
They are playing with you.
How did they learn our relationship,
Titus?
Ertugrul.
It was a matter of time for him
to connect the dots.
God damn! I need to kill them all.
What will happen to the letter
Shahzade wrote to the Sultan?
My friends in the palace will make sure
that letter is not seen by the Sultan.
I hope so.
They will see who the game
and who the hunter is.
God forbid, I was scared that
something may happen to you.
If something happened to you,
what could I have said to Suleyman Shah?
Stay here until they return.
We can be companions while
waiting for our loved ones to return.
With prayer, with belief, with patience.
This tribe has survived through
so many hardships.
All the pain is still here...
...in my heart.
God knows that I have never felt
so desperate in my life.
My two sons...
...my man...
I lived through so many hardships
in this short life of mine.
People who want to kill
my father and brother...
...the states who wanted to use them
because they were Shahzades...
...the nights we rotted in dungeons.
I lived with the anxiety of losing
my loved ones every day I breathed.
Ertugrul Bey woke us up
from that nightmare...
...he put us in a beautiful dream.
Mother Hayme...
...I found the peace I yearned
for my whole life in your tribe.
Your wish is accepted.
Now it is my turn, Suleyman Shah.
Mother Hayme, why do you take
this ominous girl into your tent?
Aren’t they the source of all problems
we are facing today?
How can she have the face
to stay in our tribe?
How can she sit in our marquee?
How dare you question my decisions?
Get out of here now! I said now!
Beys, come on, let us talk inside.
Everyone in the tribe is informed.
What is happening?
How dare you enter your Bey’s
marquee like this?
They wanted to talk with their Bey,
Hayme Hanim.
And I accepted their request.
State comes first or
else you get eaten by crows.
Walk. I said walk along!
Whatever happens do not show yourselves.
-Yes, sir.
Walk.
Send the Shahzades, Ertugrul.
And you send my father!
Come on.
Kill them all!
What if Suleyman Shah does not come back?
What will we do, Bey?
Bey, what can we do if this Karatoygar
is not satisfied attacks the tribe later?
We see that the tribe has
so many endless problems.
We did not know...
...that the beys who have
many jobs to do are anxious to...
...gather the headquarter meetings
every chance they get.
For you to show your courage, you wait
for your Bey to sacrifice himself.
We were not aware of this, until now.
If Suleyman Shah who returned from
countless battles tired and sweaty...
...saw you in this manner,
I am sure he would have been proud.
Kill them all!
Why aren’t you attacking?
Why?
Take them away.
I told you to kill them all!
Kill them all!
This is treachery! Treachery!
You cowards! You will pay for all this!
Attack!
Your brother is still in my hand,
Ertugrul!
If something happens to me...
Save your breath, Karatoygar.
No one will come to your help.
I want to talk with you alone,
Ertugrul Bey.
Leave us alone, Alps.
I was a commander in the Seljuk army
for years.
For the Great Seljuk state
I fought inside and outside the country.
I spilt blood, then fate flew me
to my Shahzade.
From now on, my only wish, my only duty
is to protect my Shahzade and his family.
That is why I contacted with the soldiers
I know within Karatoygar’s legion.
That is the situation, Ertugrul Bey.
This is what I want as well, Afsin Bey.
To protect my tribe, my family, Halime...
...and Halime’s family.
As our wish and desires are the same...
...we should stand as strong as mountains
against this dog called Karatoygar.
You are a valiant man, Ertugrul Bey...
...to fight side by side with you
is a pride, an honor for me.
Then tell me, Afsin Bey.
Those soldiers you are in contact with.
How effective are they?
Let me tell you like this, Ertugrul Bey...
...they are so effective that
when Karatoygar calls for help...
...he will not find
a single soldier behind him.
Then our job is to make him call for help.
This means that in the life and death
situation at Kartal Tepesi...
...we shall be the sword and
you shall be the shield, Afsin Bey.
We will attack and you will keep
the Seljuk soldiers with Karatoygar...
...on the right side.
Of course, Ertugrul Bey. We shall be.
Today, we shall be on the side of
the oppressed against the tyrants.
The Owner of the oppressed is our Witness.
May God be on our side and help us.
Sari Bolu.
Sari Bolu!
You will pay for this.
You lowlife scum!
May you burn in hell, Karatoygar.
You will all die along with the Shahzades.
I shall exterminate your progeny!
Those days are over, Mother Hayme.
It is time to think about
how we will pass the cliff in front of us.
Alpargu! Know your place!
Of course we have things to talk about,
for the future of our tribe.
But this place is also
the private quarters of our Suleyman Shah.
It is not suitable to bother Mother Hayme.
She is in enough pain as it is.
We were inconsiderate.
Let us carry on in my tent.
Carry the Bey symbols to my tent.
We are all sorry for our losses, brother.
The ambush on the caravan, the Alps
getting killed were not your fault.
Did you know beforehand?
Did you know that Numan was
a Shahzade beforehand?
No, I just learned it.
But it is obvious that
they had a good reason to hide it.
He played you just like he played us...
...but you still defend them!
Let me go, you goat herders!
Who do you think you are?
Let me go!
Banditry is not eternal, Karatoygar.
Your tyrant rule is over.
You talk about banditry.
The Turkmen tribe who ambushed
and captured a Seljuk commander.
When Sultan Aladdin hears about this,
who do you think he will see as bandits?
Do not waste your breath, Karatoygar.
We will set a court and your verdict
will be given according to our customs.
When custom speaks, Beys stop talking,
as well as the sultan.
-Father?
-Are you fine, Bey?
Would you like to rest a bit?
I am fine, Wild Demir. I am fine.
Are we returning to the tribe, father?
No. First we will take back the goods
this lowlife looted from our caravan.
Afsin Bey,
you know that I would die for you...
...but what if this court ruling goes bad?
Do not worry, Sari. Trust me.
It is obvious that Kurdoglu
was waiting for a chance like this.
How else could he act so quickly
to take over the post?
Shameless man.
He even took the Bey symbols with him.
And we are sitting here
with our hands tied.
Enough, Aykiz. Enough.
You make a fuss without
knowing how the state is run.
-Do we have permission, Mother Hayme?
-Come, my girl. Come.
What happened?
You all wait with the pain inside you,
you do not think about your hunger.
I wanted to bring you something to eat.
Thank you, my girl. Put the pan on
the table and you sit down with us.
We all wait with anxiety.
While Suleyman Shah is leading them,
they will all come back safe and sound.
But my sister is worrying a lot
about my brother in law Gundogdu.
You all wait for your fathers...
...and I pray for Ertugrul Bey.
You are correct.
I know the sorrow your sister
is going through.
But let her be rest assured...
...we shall leave the tribe soon.
If God permits, they will all
return safe and sound.
We can only pray for them.
You bloodless dogs. Lowlifes!
I will kill you all! Kill you all.
You will pay for all of these!
I will destroy you all!
Not only your tribe, there will be not
a single person left who remembers Kayis.
I will kill you all!
You shall leave immediately.
You will catch that dog called Gundogdu...
...before he reaches his tribe...
...and you'll bring him to Kartal Tepesi.
-Kartal Tepesi?
-Kartal Tepesi, yes.
Those Kayi goat herders are
setting us a trap there.
Did you hear, Sari?
They think they can finish Karatoygar off.
Bey, if you like we can go beforehand
take precautions.
Yes, Sari Bolu...
...place your most trusted
soldiers to the rocks of Kartal Tepesi.
When I give the signal...
...I want to turn that place
into hell for Kayis.
As you wish!
Sari Bolu.
We checked the warehouse where
the goods are, they are all there, Bey.
Are you fine, father?
Yes, I am.
Bey, you are tired...
...I arranged a room for you to stay here
and rest for the night.
We can go there if you wish.
Thank you, commander.
Ertugrul...
...you stay here. I will go with Gundogdu.
Ertugrul Bey...
...there are some issues
we need to talk about.
As if the problems they created for us
are not enough...
...she goes and takes refuge with
Mother Hayme. Wolf in a sheep’s hide.
But if my name is Selcan, I shall make you
pay for all you have done, Halime.
Sister.
Gokce, where were you?
Which corner did you hide in?
Sister.
The foreign girl goes and takes refuge
with Mother Hayme but my sister is...
...all alone in a corner...
-Sister! You are mistaken!
I am not hiding anywhere.
I am coming from the marquee,
I was with them.
Look at my sister.
I approached them with
an excuse of bringing food.
I said what I had to say and
I heard what I wanted to hear.
What did you hear?
Kurdoglu took the Bey symbols
and carried them to his tent.
It is obvious that they lost hope of
Suleyman Shah’s return.
-Did he take the Bey symbols to his tent?
-Yes.
Kurdoglu.
What is your intention?
You wait here.
Sister!
Stop, Gundogdu.
Today, I saw how you looked at Ertugrul.
You are his brother.
A brother should not look
at his brother with hatred.
Moreover, he risked his life to save you.
Father, what are you saying?
He risked his life, is that so?
I do not know whether he risked his life
for us or for his valuable guests...
...but I know one thing, if we were
put in this bind, Ertugrul is the reason.
You have hate in your eyes
after the ambush on the caravan.
You look for a scapegoat to blame.
Are you comfortable, Kurdoglu?
Are you satisfied with sitting on Suleyman
Shah’s throne instead of saving Gundogdu?
I do not reply as I know
you worry about your husband’s life...
...but know your place, Selcan Hatun.
I know my place,
that is why I am questioning you!
Why don’t you do anything
to save Gundogdu?
Do you see what is going on in this tribe?
Do you hear them?
We faced many problems, if I didn’t act
fast the tribe was going to be divided.
Who was to blame for those many problems?
Wasn’t it you who stirred up the trouble?
I told you the things Suleyman Shah was
keeping secret, I committed an offence...
...but what did you do? Nothing!
-What did you expect me to do?
Do you see me as a traitor? Did you think
that I would share the secret plans...
...of my tribe with the enemy?
What will happen to them?
If that dog called Karatoygar
kills my husband...
We will pray for them to be spared.
This is all we can do.
We need to get out of the Seljuk territory
before all hell breaks loose again.
Not for myself, for my son who sleeps
unbeknown to all that is happening.
I understand you, my Shahzade. I guess
this is the best course of action...
...for the good of everyone.
But you may need to give us
horses and weapons for us to go.
I have another plan in my mind.
After the funerals, I shall request
permission from my father to go to Aleppo.
I can take you there
safe and sound with my Alps.
-After that...
-Thank you, Ertugrul Bey. Thank you.
I shall always be thankful to you
and your family.
Tomorrow we shall talk with Suleyman Shah
and set on the road as soon as possible.
Ertugrul?
You are not asleep.
You are not asleep either.
We managed to win this time as well...
...but there is something eating
my heart from inside, Wild  Demir.
How did Karatoygar learn that
we were at Kartal Tepesi?
The thing that is eating your heart inside
is eating my heart as well.
Look...
...I will say something to you but...
Tell me, Wild  Demir.
That night when those dogs
staged an ambush on Halime’s tent...
...the person who drove me away
from the tent...
...was Kurdoglu.
I don’t want to blame anyone
without proof, even Kurdoglu but...
...this is a problem of the tribe.
You should be informed.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
-You have a message from Titus, sir.
-What did he write?
Fools.
They could not do one thing properly.
Check...
...and mate.
Do not forget, when the game ends...
...the king and pawns
are put in the same box at the end.
Only the ones who clear the table
know who is victorious.
Be careful and don’t make me angry
before you go in the box.
Send a message to Titus, immediately.
He should not sacrifice
Karatoygar for anyone.
Can Titus still prevent
Kayis from coming to Aleppo?
I do not know where he can succeed or not.
Not being able to see the future...
...is torturing my soul.
Tell them to get prepared, Marcus.
You are coming with me to Aleppo.
We have some business to attend
with Nasir.
Do you have any other
orders for Titus, sir?
He should make the wrath of Karatoygar
fall upon the Kayis.
He can either do this himself
or use Kurdoglu.
This shall be his decision,
as he will be responsible for the outcome.
Where is Suleyman Shah?
They say that our caravan was ambushed.
Where are the bodies, Bey?
He is right. Where is Bey, where are
the bodies? What is happening, Kurdoglu?
Beys of Kayi.
Today is not the day for complaints.
We still have no news from our tribe’s
pillar Suleyman Shah and our Alps.
God forbid, we need to be prepared
for all possibilities.
The unity and future of
our tribe is under threat.
And this Aleppo issue
in the middle of all these troubles.
The decision our Bey took in good times...
...should be reconsidered under
these harsh conditions.
What else can we do, Kurdoglu?
What is on your mind?
Before I state the thing on my mind,
I would like to remind you that...
...Suleyman Shah Bey appointed me as
the head of the tribe before leaving.
-My words are our Bey’s words.
-Of course.
My heart is not in peace with setting foot
on the unknown path of Aleppo.
To migrate, we need to find...
-Suleyman Shah has returned!
-Suleyman Shah is back!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Do not do anything
that is indecorum to Kayis.
We shall talk about
the trial in the headquarters.
The verdict shall be from our customs.
Tie him up to the log.
Let me go!
I will kill you all!
-Kill him!
-Don’t make him live!
Thank God, you are back safe and sound.
God has accepted my prayers.
Suleyman. Suleyman.
Suleyman.
Dear God.
You will pay for this.
Your tribe will be exterminated!
You won’t have any daylight to see.
Look at that lowlife dog, still barking!
Stop! What are you doing?
Didn’t you hear Bey’s orders?
Would a Kayi member violate
his Bey’s order?
Suleyman, you are not well,
let me call Akcakoca to come and see you.
Do not worry, Hayme. I am only tired.
Where are the Bey symbols?
Kurdoglu’s doings. Come on.
Lay back.
Never mind.
Do not frown, Hayme.
Let us catch our breath first...
...we will talk about what happened later.
He swung his sword and...
...cut the enemy’s throat.
I wish I could have been there
and saw it with my own eyes.
You know, when I grow up I will be like
my brother Ertugrul...
...as strong and as brave as him.
See?
If you keep this up,
you will surpass all the Alps, Dundar.
Brother? Yigit was telling me
how you fought with the enemy.
He was very brave as well,
did he tell you those as well?
I will go and check on my father.
Tell me now.
Did you do the job I gave you?
After you left,
something happened to the tribe.
They stoned Halime Abla’s tent.
-They stoned the tent?
-Yes.
-Halime Abla was inside.
-Inside?
Thank God my mother came
and scored them off.
Then she took Halime Abla to our tent.
I know you are troubled.
I know you went through a lot.
But these are all temporary,
you know how to pass these difficulties.
I did not only make a problem for myself,
I made a problem for others as well.
Be more gentle, Hatun.
I don’t know whether I should be angry
for the death of Alps who were with me...
...or that I was taken
prisoner by Karatoygar.
Should I be ashamed of our Bey,
my own father, to surrender to save me...
...or Ertugrul to become
the hero of the day.
They sowed the seeds,
Karatoygar mowed you.
Are you blaming yourself
for being grinded in the millstone?
The real culprits are enjoying themselves.
Brother.
Welcome, Ertugrul Bey.
I was coming to see you.
Brother, mother should have prepared
some food, let me go and check.
My heart was right.
You kept your promise once again.
You brought my father and brother
back to me safe and sound.
May God bless you, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank God, we had the chance to return.
I heard about what some people did
when we were gone, Halime Sultan.
I heard that some presumptuous people
did some unforgivable things.
They betrayed their Bey and
customs to stone a tent.
You were not here but...
...Bey’s wife, most gracious Mother Hayme
stood before them like a mountain.
-She took me under her wings.
-They will pay for what they did.
You have returned safe and sound,
that is enough for me.
As I am thankful to God, I have
no place for anger in my heart or tongue.
Do not dwell on those tactless people,
Ertugrul. They were in pain.
They lost their loved ones because of us.
You have such a pure heart, even the evil
things done against you cannot defile it.
In the lifetime allocated to us,
there are things which are good or evil.
We thank God, when He gives a sorrow,
He gives a remedy as well.
My father told me that you will be with us
until we leave the Seljuk territory.
If God permits.
I will be beside the tree.
With your permission, I would like to
introduce you to a very nice girl.
Gundogdu Bey...
...if there is someone who should be
ashamed, that person is not you.
Ertugrul should be ashamed
as he led this curse upon our tribe.
Look at the situation I am in, Hatun.
Look at the place I fell down to
in the eyes of the tribe.
My honor is crushed.
Do not worry, people knows the truth.
Wind cannot rock a stone,
only takes the dust on it.
Giving up does not suit you.
Now come to the table.
Your father expects all the family
to be there.
What will happen now, Bey?
What if Karatoygar talks?
We will do whatever is needed.
The arrow has left the bow.
It will hit whoever is on its path.
Bey, even if we deal with Karatoygar...
...we fueled the fire in the tribe while
Suleyman Shah was gone.
Won’t he ask about the culprits?
If he starts to investigate the matter,
my head will be on the line first.
Baybora, we are in a storm
at the moment...
...if you shiver like a dried leaf, you
would be blown away. Try to stand strong.
What can I do, Bey?
Go and hide for a while.
I will call you back when
the storm subsides.
-Alright, Bey.
-What will we do, Bey?
What can we do? We'll deliver the symbols
we secured while he was away...
...back to Suleyman Shah.
-Where is your brother?
-He is talking with Halime Abla.
I am sorry that I am late.
Gokce, come on my girl, you sit as well.
In the name of God.
We delayed it due to these
recent events but...
...I need to take the signed letter
back to Aleppo, father.
The guests would like to go as well.
I do not know their destination...
...but we discussed that
we can at least go to Aleppo together.
If you give permission.
After the feast meeting and the funerals,
we shall think about it.
Baybora.
There it is, Alpargu...
...we brought back the Bey symbols to
where they belong.
-What is happening, Rahman?
-Kurdoglu. Brought back the Bey symbols.
He asks for permission to come in.
Tell him to wait.
Now, tell me.
Who told you the tent Hamza was hiding in?
Come on. I am listening. Tell me.
Who was behind this malice?
I cannot talk, Bey.
If I do, they would kill me.
So they would kill you.
Who told you that
we would spare you if you don’t?
Go on, talk, you dog!
The stones you threw to Halime Baci’s
tent, were they as big as these?
Talk...
...so that you have a chance.
Who provoked you to attack? Who? Tell me!
Dogan...
...these valiant people
do not deserve small stones like pebbles.
Big rocks like this one are more suitable.
It was Baybora.
It was Baybora’s doing.
Mother of a son...
As if my brother’s madness,
my father’s stubbornness...
...and the cruelty of the enemy
is not enough...
...we have a traitor within us.
A traitor who sells
his own people to the enemy.
Who is this traitor?
If I knew...
If I knew,
I would punish him with my own hands.
But he must be very close.
So there is a traitor nearby teaming up
with the enemy but you still...
...hide in your tent and keep quiet,
is that so?
Don’t you understand? You are
the only hope for this tribe, Gundogdu.
Don’t leave the field empty for others
to roam, don’t let unity of the tribe...
...fall apart for those faceless people
who we don’t know anything about.
You know those people
who you call faceless...
Who?
They are from the Seljuk dynasty, Hatun.
The man called Numan is a Shahzade and
that girl you look down on, is a sultan.
Now I understand everything
that has happened.
The trouble Ertugrul brought
to our tribe overwhelmed him as well.
Will you sit here and watch like
an outsider or will you get up...
...show what you are made of?
-Don’t you understand, Hatun?
He is the one who is protecting
Shahzade and his family...
...he is the one who saved me,
he is the one who saved my father...
...he is the one who captured Karatoygar.
-But...
-There is no but to it!
Enough. I am tired.
After we leave the Seljuk territory
safely with the help of Ertugrul Bey...
...the rest is my duty, my Shahzade.
You can be rest assured.
You have helped us greatly
in our time of need, Afsin Bey.
-Thank you.
-Not at all, my Shahzade. It is our duty.
Father...
My son?
I am fed up of running away.
We are always on the road.
We are always running away.
I get scared while running away, father.
This is the first time I had a friend.
For the first time I played games.
I don’t want to leave, father.
Let us stay here.
But we have to go, my son.
For your sister, for your future...
...we have to go.
I saw this mare in the mountains
where I had gone to become an Alp.
That is why she was different from the
other mares. More wild, more maverick.
She was very hard to catch,
even harder to bring to the tribe.
She was very stubborn.
Then she drank the water of the tribe,
ate its bread. She was tamed.
As she believed and trusted,
she understood her value in my eyes.
She is yours now.
If you give permission...
...I named her Sultan.
God willing...
...you shall never be separated from her.
We have a long journey ahead of us.
Even if the end is imminent,
the road is ours.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
I shall look after Sultan
as if she is my eyes.
She will be by my side as long as I live.
With my apologies, Bey.
We found out the person
who provoked the public.
-Who was it?
-Baybora.
I hope you did not get bored of waiting,
Kurdoglu. I know...
...you don’t like to wait.
Not at all, Bey.
We would wait for you
until our last day if needed.
May it be easy on you, Bey.
God spared you for us.
What happened is in the past.
You tell me now, what happened
in the tribe while I was away?
Some people saw Hamza, Bey.
They got suspicious.
They created a bit of
a havoc in the tribe.
Thank God, Mother Hayme came out and
put those tactless people in their place.
Hayme may have put those tactless people
in their place, what did you do, Kurdoglu?
First I gathered the Beys
in the marquee to calm them down.
I did not want them to see
the marquee empty and to think that...
...no one is leading them. Otherwise,
things might have gone out of control.
We did what we had to do and
controlled the situation, thanks to you.
Well...
...what about taking
the Bey symbols out, Kurdoglu?
Bey...
...while Hayme Hatun was dealing with
her own troubles here...
...I didn't think it would be wise to deal
with the tribe issues here as well.
Thank you.
But, there is a traitor in the tribe,
this is obvious.
As I said, Bey...
...some people saw Hamza. They must have
seen him while Akcakoca was going in...
...and getting out of the tent.
This is not one, not two, Kurdoglu.
When they ambushed the tribe,
someone showed them the way.
The same person informed Karatoygar about
the trap we set at the place of exchange.
If Ertugrul did not change the plan...
...we would have been killed
at those rocks.
If there is such a traitor, Bey, I would
skin him alive in the middle of the tribe.
Do you have any other orders for me, Bey?
We will gather the Beys at
the headquarters and talk about the trial.
My wish is to send Karatoygar
to the Sultan for him to convict.
Support me in the headquarters. Help me.
We need to calm down the public.
This is the wisest decision, Bey.
Do not worry.
Hayme...
...my valiant wife.
We passed through a very difficult time.
Do not over think these things. Kurdoglu
did what he had to do. Do not dwell on it.
You know best, Bey.
What are you doing in my tent?
There is a ring of fire all around us,
what would people think?
Do not speak negatively, Kurdoglu.
We are partners of crime now.
We will either rise together
or we will sink together.
Moreover, when you hear the thing
I came here to tell you...
...you will be thanking me.
Do you know who those migrating birds
that took refuge in our tribe really are?
Yes, Kurdoglu Bey. I shall inform
Gundogdu Bey that you will visit him.
He will be glad.
What happened, Ertugrul? Why did you
fall on my tent like a lightning?
Do you know where Baybora is?
How should I know, Ertugrul?
But if you need him, I can send someone.
Do not bother yourself. I will find him.
Sister...
-Sister.
-What?
Ertugrul and Halime were together
under a tree all alone.
It is obvious that Ertugrul Bey
is determined to go with them.
I saw them with my own eyes.
-He gave that girl a horse as a present.
-Enough!
I have to take matters
in my own hands once again.
You can sit and cry, Gokce.
Ertugrul has connected the dots.
Finish off Baybora.
We have to break the chain before
it gets tangled around our throats.
Do we have permission, father?
Come in, my girl, come.
How are you, father? Do you need anything?
Thank you, my bride. How are you?
How is Gundogdu?
He is sad, father. I am afraid that
he may not recover from this.
He is in great pain but the worst one
is the Alps who got killed.
He came up with the idea of
going to Aleppo. He found a new home...
...but he did not even have the chance
to be happy when he heard the news.
When Ertugrul said that he will return
to Aleppo, he got even more depressed.
If Gundogdu can go to Aleppo,
he might recover somewhat.
I do not know what to do.
I just wait without a direction.
Gundogdu on one side
and Gokce on the other.
When she learned that Ertugrul and Halime
will go to Aleppo, she got depressed.
You know how sensitive she is.
She worries that a shadow might
cast over her happiness with Ertugrul.
Look, son...
...the thing you are beating is
a bar of iron, not Karatoygar’s head.
It is as if you have a problem
but you do not talk about it.
What use would talking do?
What use would keeping quiet do?
Look now...
...there is one problem
which is beyond all other problems.
It is beyond migrating or
fighting in a battle.
Bey...
...there is someone who wants to see you.
-Who?
It is such a big problem that many Beys,
many valiant Alps cannot handle it.
My problem is such a problem
that it cannot be said, Wild Demir.
I do not know the words
that can describe this problem.
The tongue is only
a messenger of the heart, son.
The problem is not in the tongue
but in the heart.
If your heart is in the right place...
...your tongue and your words
would find the right path.
But your problem is obvious, son.
There is only one problem
that scares a brave...
...and that is love.
If you open your heart
to the one you love...
...you would grow like an sycamore tree.
If you do not...
...a worm would start eating you alive
from inside.
Even if you are a great sycamore tree,
you would fall down.
How can I do it?
She can never abandon her father or
brother and I cannot abandon my home.
Tribe is a tribe with loved ones.
Home is a home with loved ones.
You are Ertugrul with your love...
...if you do not have love,
any place you call home...
...any sword you swing to the infidels
would not be satisfy you.
Come on,
break that chain on your tongue...
...so that your heart can have some peace.
-The corpses of our Alps are coming.
What is your benefit in this?
We don’t want you to settle on our borders
and be trouble for us. That is all.
According to Karatoygar,
you are an intelligent man.
If he is right,
all three of us want the same thing.
The thing that will save Kayis and you,
is Karatoygar to be the head commander.
He is the only person that would make
you Bey and let your tribe migrate...
...to anywhere you like. You are in a hole
of dirt up to your throat, Kurdoglu.
The blood of the Alps, which you will be
burying soon is on your hands.
You cannot clean your hands without
becoming the Bey of the tribe.
It is not possible for me to make
Karatoygar escape from the tribe but...
...if you are as strong as
you claim to be...
...you can save him.
Why did we need to meet secretly, Alpargu?
Ertugrul...
...found out that you provoked the public.
-How?
-He probably made your dogs talk.
You lowlife! I warned you all!
I told you that we cannot get away
with it! You did not hear me!
It was you and Kurdoglu that made
everything come to this point.
What will I do now?
Get on your horse and run away.
Don’t ever look back.
Where will I go? Where?
I have children.
How can I leave them behind and go?
You shall return when
we set everything straight.
This is not a dirt on the hand
that can be washed away in a few seconds.
So many Alps died,
all the goods in the caravan are gone.
-You think Suleyman Shah would let it go?
-Control yourself, Baybora!
How can I go without them?
How can my children live
in the tribe with this shame?
You lowlife!
Do not worry...
...I will look after your family.
For the men who died...
Our brothers ask for your
blessing one last time.
-Do you bless them?
-We bless them!
If God permits,
they will forgive us as well.
For our Great Prophet
Mohammed’s assistance...
For the souls of our brothers...
For the unity and blessing of our tribe...
For God’s mercy...
...recite Al Fatiha prayer.
My Beys...
My braves...
Wise men of my tribe...
...I know what is in your hearts...
...we have the right for revenge
from this lowlife.
He should not get away with the blood he
spilt and the curses he got for cruelty.
But...
...executing this lowlife is not for us.
His sentence should be given
by Sultan Aladdin.
Suleyman Shah...
...how many mothers are mourning now.
They think about their loved ones
who died at the hands of Karatoygar.
Your words are burning through our hearts.
You are so unaware! When did you see
our Bey make our tribe bow down in shame?
Our Bey knows what is best for all of us.
My Beys...
...we have the right to blood,
that is a fact but...
...practicing eye for an eye
is not an honor for us.
The sentence for collaborating with
the Crusaders and betraying the state...
...should be given by Sultan Aladdin.
Does anyone have an objection?
Commander Sari Bolu shall take Karatoygar
to Konya and deliver him to the palace.
The lowlife dog will understand
before his last breath that...
...treachery would be punished
sooner or later.
Commander, you are a lucky man.
You will see this black pig drowning
in his own blood.
We have to set on the road
to Aleppo in two days.
Are the preparations completed?
We have packed everything, Bey. Only
the dismantling of the carpet workshop...
...and the tents are left.
The herds have already
started the journey, Bey.
I sent some trusted Alps
with the herders as well.
Then the job of taking the agreement to
El Aziz and building the stables...
...and sheep pens shall be...
...yours, Gundogdu.
Father, with your permission...
-Father?
-Suleyman!
Suleyman!
-Bey?
-Father?
Now it is up to you.
You will go to Sultan Aladdin
and tell him everything.
You will tell him that Kayis...
...kidnapped the traitor Shahzades
you were taking to Konya...
...then used their names to get support
from other Turkmen tribes for an uprising.
They want to rise up
and overthrow Sultan Aladdin.
I could not acknowledge such a thing,
so I set off on the road again...
...to take the rebellious
Shahzades to Konya.
They ambushed me. Killed all my soldiers.
My most trusted commander, Sari Bolu.
They cut his throat, right in front of me.
You will take an army from
Sultan Aladdin and bring them here.
Kayis will understand
why they call you the Fire of Wrath.
Then you will return back to
Konya and become the right hand man...
...of the sultan you have just saved.
I did what I could do.
Unfortunately his fever is not going down.
They only thing we can do now is pray.
Our Bey...
...would like us to do our chores
and jobs whatever happens.
We all know our jobs and chores.
When he opens his eyes...
...he should see that all is done.
We have a long road
ahead of us to Aleppo...
...but none of us shall give up.
ALEPPO
Welcome back, my Sheikh.
Thank you, grandson of my master.
May God have his mercy over us.
Your heavenly grandfather had said...
...“every bird flies with their own kind.
Eagles with eagles. Crows with crows.”
Aleppo has become very crowded.
Eagles are at one gate
and crows on the other.
They all have different problems.
Some are after their food, not caring
about whether it is lawful or not...
...others are after a post. They don't
care whether God has given consent or not.
If they have traps or bad intensions...
...God has a reckoning as well.
-But God is the most dutiful Trap Setter.
-Dear God. Of course.
Good news for you, Selcan Hatun.
Your intuition was right.
From now on you will not only live for
your husband, but for your son as well.
A long journey awaits Ertugrul and us.
We are impatient to leave...
...but this will be the hardest
journey I will be on.
I know.
Be my confidant, my comrade, Sultan.
-If only things were different.
-If only.
I heard that...
...Suleyman Shah is not well.
They say Azrael is walking around him.
They say he waits for
his time in his deathbed.
We piled more problems over his troubles.
We became a big burden for him.
May God help him.
Amen.
Suleyman Shah said that...
...Gundogdu Bey will be going to Aleppo.
She will take you there, Halime.
Gundogdu Bey?
Do not forget to dismantle this.
Tie them well.
We have a long road ahead of us.
So you came, Kurdoglu.
When you hear the things I am going
to say, you will be surprised.
The identities of our valuable guests
who brought...
...nothing but dark clouds over our tribe
are revealed.
Numan who claimed to be a trader
was actually a Seljuk Shahzade.
But what is your intention
in telling me this news, Selcan Hatun?
I saw what you can do with
a small bit of information, Kurdoglu.
My father and Uncle Kurdoglu
went on a hunt one day.
They were both around our ages then.
-Uncle Kurdoglu fell of his horse.
-Why? Did something happen to the horse?
The horse had startled because
there was a big bear in front of them.
What did Kurdoglu do?
My uncle could not do anything
because his leg was broken.
When that bear was about to
tear my uncle apart...
...my father came and
killed the bear with his spear.
You father is very brave.
They became blood brothers then.
Yigit, you will be going tomorrow.
When you go, please don’t forget that
you have a brother in Kayi tribe.
Let us go.
Yigit...
...look.
Run.
Dear God, Who has given secrets
to us herbalists...
...spare us from troubles without remedy.
They are upstairs.
Welcome, Nasir.
You called for me, sir.
Go to El Aziz immediately and tell him to
stop Kayis from settling at our borders.
-But, sir, Titus...
-I cannot waste time by talking about...
...the stupid decisions Titus made.
He is only a pawn
who thinks he is a vizier.
It is very hard to dissuade
El Aziz from his decision.
He really liked the Kayis.
Is his love for Kayis so big that
he is prepared to let black death...
...roam over Aleppo?
Did you manage to find the person
who sent the spies to kill Ertugrul?
According to the information I have, the
Templars have mobilized all their spies.
I am trying to uncover
their sources within the palace.
Come, Nasir, come. Come.
Sir, the problem is important,
I did not want to wait for the morning.
Intelligence have been informing
about the plague in Anatolia.
I wanted to be sure whether our potential
allies have been plagued or not.
Sir, I know, you liked Kayis very much.
I also believe that they are
most suitable for holding our borders...
...if a new Crusader campaign starts.
-But...
-But what, Nasir?
Sir, unfortunately
most of their livestock have perished.
Don’t...
...reject them from our borders, Nasir.
Do you understand? Don’t.
When he brings the agreement,
I personally want to talk with Ertugrul.
Come on now, Gundogdu.
All the Beys have gathered in the tent.
Today is the day.
Do not talk like
my father has died, Kurdoglu.
You are the tribe’s son as much as
you are your father’s son, Gundogdu.
Will you sit in your tent like
a woman while your tribe is in trouble?
As we move down to the plains from
the highlands the troubles shall cease...
...and my father will get well.
I have nothing else to say, Kurdoglu.
Do you know what you will face while going
down to the plains from the highlands?
What are you trying to say, Emmi?
I am saying that...
...this path we are taking
is not wise, son.
This is the headquarter’s decision
and my father’s order.
This is my final word, Kurdoglu.
Do you think that I want to be
the acting Bey...
...and to sit in the marquee
under your father’s shadow?
Don’t you know me, Gundogdu?
Wasn’t it you who said your father is
too old to perform his Bey duties...
...and asked me support you
to become the new Bey?
Didn’t I tell you that I would be
supporting you until the end?
What is your cause now?
I am an old man with only
a few years to live.
I told you numerous times that the tribe
needs a brave, determined Bey like you.
I would like you to trust me
until I save you from these problems...
...and make you a Bey in our new home.
Come to the point, Emmi.
I have learned the real identity
the ominous guests Ertugrul brought here.
I know that Numan and his son are from
the Seljuk dynasty, they are Shahzades.
Those people who you call faceless
are from the Seljuk dynasty, Hatun.
The man called Numan is a Shahzade and
that girl you look down on, is a sultan.
If we deliver them...
...the Sultan would award our tribe.
We can settle in the best places of
Seljuk territory.
What do you want from me, Kurdoglu?
Give up on Aleppo.
Aleppo will be our doom.
We should take them tonight...
...and deliver them
to the Sultan, Gundogdu.
May God spare you for us and Kayis.
Bey...
...we are ready for the ambush.