episode 5 will start at : 12:57
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
At least say, peace be upon you.
Alpargu, you go out.
I was expecting you.
But I was not expecting you, Gundogdu.
Kurdoglu will go at night
to ambush a tent and kidnap a Shahzade...
...and I will miss this party.
How can this be?
Have you become a guard to the tent of
the people whom you were crying out...
...for them to leave yesterday?
In a tribe where you try to collect
support to become a Bey...
...let us become a guard.
Emmi...
...this tribe should have a guard.
So that bandits and dogs don’t roam
about inside the camp.
Now tell me, where did you learn
this Shahzade issue?
When I went to Karatoygar
as a messenger, I inquired around.
I connected the dots.
Why did you keep it a secret until now?
The same reason as why Suleyman Shah
kept it a secret from his own son.
You lie.
You asked, I answered.
Whoever sowed the seeds of suspicion
inside you, go and ask them!
Those people who you call faceless
are from the Seljuk dynasty, Hatun.
The man called Numan is a Shahzade and
that girl you look down on, is a sultan.
-Brother, I need to talk with you.
-Not now.
-Brother!
-I said, not now, Dundar!
Gundogdu...
...did something bad happen?
Was it you who told Kurdoglu that
Numan and his son were Shahzades, Hatun?
-What happened?
-Answer me. Did you tell him or not?
What Shahzade, Gundogdu?
What are you talking about?
What made you so angry?
Kurdoglu learned that
they are Shahzades, Hatun.
What did he do then?
I don’t know his intention
but he wanted to imprison them.
-Where are the Shahzades?
-They left with Ertugrul.
I want you to take the agreement
to El Aziz, Ertugrul.
But brother,
my father gave this duty to you.
Very well, and I am giving it to you.
We should both do the jobs we know best,
Ertugrul. Don’t you always say...
...let the headquarter be yours
and hunt mine?
-And you let them go? What are you up to?
-What is it to you?
-Did you tell him or not?
-I did not tell, Gundogdu.
What business can I have with Kurdoglu?
Did Kurdoglu tell you
that he heard it from me?
He said that it was someone else.
But if it was you, Hatun...
...may God be my witness that...
You were not like this.
Something happened to you.
Don’t you trust the woman
who is carrying your child in her womb?
To your wife who is going to
give you a son?
Bey, Ertugrul and his Alps have left.
Round up the men you trust,
they should go after them.
Tell them not to refrain from
spilling blood if needed.
ALEPPO
You wait around here.
I will be back shortly.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
I am looking for a book.
“Mawaqi al-Nujum.”
The Twilight of the Stars.
Do you have it?
Of course.
What do you expect to learn
from that book?
I am after what everyone else
is seeking to learn.
I want to look in the sky and
foresee the things of tomorrow.
Maybe the author did not write
the book with that intention.
I want to buy this. How much is it?
Accept it as a gift.
In the name of God,
the Most Gracious and Most Merciful.
Then I swear by the setting of the stars.
And indeed, it is an oath.
It is of course a valuable Book.
None touch it except the purified.
God always states the truth.
They say that...
...after the sun rises, you cannot
look at the stars to find direction.
Do not dwell on the stars.
If you want to see...
...the Sun is in my hand.
None touch it except the purified.
That is the Quran.
But It does not state
what will happen tomorrow.
For the eyes that can see...
...the secrets are Here,
as well as the secret of the secrets.
The book you took just now is only
a drop from the Ocean called Quran.
I never saw you before in Aleppo,
stranger. Are you from nearby?
I am a poor traveler.
I set off from the countries where
the sun sets to look for the country...
...where the sun will rise from.
I am the writer of the book
which was given as a present to you.
What happened, sir?
The man was Ibn Arabi.
We should not be late.
People are waiting for us at the lodge.
We will go by the stream,
you take the hills.
Great God.
Turgut, you carry on.
Carry on.
Shahzade, carry on.
You tactless people!
What is the meaning of this?
How can you shoot
an arrow at Ertugrul Bey?
We do not know, Dogan.
Kurdoglu Bey gave a direct order.
Surrender without a fight.
And the arrow was just a warning...
...otherwise I could have hit him
right on the neck.
Your tongue has overgrown! I will cut it
for you to take it back to Kurdoglu.
Go back to our tribe.
I do not want to spill your blood.
We don’t want to spill
the blood of our brothers as well.
If you obey us and return to the tribe,
our brotherhood would continue.
I shall not obey you or Kurdoglu.
I only obey my forefather’s customs.
Even if Kurdoglu sends a thousand man
here, I would not give up those...
...who took refuge nor
I would spill a brother’s blood.
Ertugrul Bey, I hope you did not face
another trouble because of us.
I prefer to be sleepless
instead of seeing a nightmare.
We put you in a bad situation but
we set off early as a precaution.
You are right as well.
If a lion goes hunting,
it gets blamed for spilling blood...
...if it lays down,
it gets blamed for being lazy.
Ertugrul Bey, when we left the tent,
Gundogdu Bey was in the tent alone.
Would he face a problem?
Do not worry.
My brother can overcome all difficulties.
Those four have died.
There is only one way for you to be saved.
If you tell me where
Ertugrul Bey is going, you will be free.
Aleppo. They are going to Aleppo.
This much freedom is enough.
Go to the castle, take the knights.
We shall set a trap for them
on the Aleppo road.
So he is taking the Shahzades to Aleppo.
Sister, what are you saying?
Sister, this thing is over.
Ertugrul will never come back.
How can he not come back.
His tribe, his father is here, Gokce.
-Do not burn down your heart yet.
-But, sister...
May you have a good morning, Master Demir.
May you have a good morning, my girl.
Is Gundogdu inside?
He did not sleep all night.
He must be asleep.
May you have a good morning, Gundogdu Bey.
May you have a good morning, Master Demir.
-What is the matter?
-Not good news.
Come on.
Wash your face, then we have to talk.
Let us talk.
Your young brother Dundar...
...came to me early in the morning.
He wanted to say something
to Ertugrul but he did not listen.
You did not listen to him either.
He face was all white from fright
when I saw him.
What happened? Why was he frightened?
Not good news.
They found Baybora’s dead body with Yigit
at the Karadere stream.
-Baybora’s body?
-Yes.
Who would kill him and why?
I don’t know. But my mad mind
races on and thinks that...
...they have lost control,
thinking the tribe’s Bey is gone.
The only thing they did not have was
blood on their hands.
Do not think like that,
would this tribe ever be without a Bey?
Don’t worry. At the headquarters, they'll
learn that the Bey of the tribe is alive.
Don’t you worry.
Bey, in order to get ahead of Ertugrul
we went up the trail at Kiziltepe.
When our team did not arrive,
we got suspicious and went back.
When we came here, they were all dead.
Alpargu, bury them all
before anyone sees them.
Whatever happens, don’t forget that
you have swore obedience to Kurdoglu Bey.
He is Suleyman Shah’s acting Bey.
Then why are we coming here, Alpargu?
What business do we have
at the headquarters called by Gundogdu?
We came to give a lesson
to our Bey’s incompetent son.
You support our Bey whatever happens,
that would be sufficient.
Kurdoglu Bey...
...Baybora’s place has been empty
for such a long time.
We cannot see him in the headquarters.
What happened?
Where is he?
I will say it before you.
Last night he was found...
...at the banks of Karadere stream,
stabbed to death.
On the night of the day Ertugrul
came to you and inquired where he is.
What do you insinuate, Gundogdu?
Talk openly.
Be quiet, Alpargu. Keep your mouth shut.
Your master will keep quiet as well...
...I shall be talking now.
You created factions within the tribe.
You caused discord.
You made people stone our guests’ tent.
Tell me Kurdoglu...
-...is attacking guests customary?
-Come to the point, Gundogdu.
Are you trying to accuse the person
you called Emmi until yesterday?
Aren’t you burying Suleyman Shah
even before he dies and...
...go out to collect obedience
from tribe’s Beys?
In our customs, questioning belongs to
the headquarters and answering to the Bey.
God help us.
We are not going to learn
our customs from the children.
We know what headquarter members
may ask and how to answer them.
You want to be Bey
and call us to account...
...but you could not even steer
the caravan that was entrusted in you.
You call me to account
for the death of Baybora...
...but do you know what Ertugrul did?
Listen to me well, Beys of Kayi.
Ertugrul...
...killed five warriors of our tribe.
-That is a lie!
This is slander.
Mother Hayme, Ertugrul would
never do such a thing.
This shameless person
has lost control, my girl.
The slanders are only
a reflection of his own dark heart.
And thus...
...Gundogdu who caused our Alps
to die in the caravan ambush...
...and Ertugrul who slayed our Alps
cannot challenge me at all!
Decency, Kurdoglu, decency!
Enough!
Aren’t you ashamed of
slandering our Bey’s sons?
Don’t you have shame?
Calm. Be calm, Wild Demir.
There is no lie in my words.
God is my witness.
Ertugrul kidnapped Suleyman Shah’s
guests last night.
Their fate is unknown. In order to learn
what happened to our Bey’s guests...
...I sent some of my Alps after them.
In the morning,
news of their death reached me.
You are so anxious to stir up trouble
inside the tribe, Kurdoglu.
Aren’t you ashamed to take advantage
of my father’s illness?
Gundogdu do not talk like you don’t know.
You set this up with your brother.
You disobeyed the order and gave the
agreement given to you, to Ertugrul.
One of us has to stay in the tribe
and fight against Kurdoglu’s doings.
Kurdoglu?
He learned that Numan and his son are
Shahzades. Now he is trying to convince...
...the Beys in the headquarters to migrate
somewhere in Seljuk territory, not Aleppo.
You are the one who is trying to take
advantage of your father’s illness.
You are the one who sits in his place,
while he is laying in his bed.
Thank God that my blood brother’s eyes
are closed and he doesn’t see these days.
Let us go, Beys of Kayi.
A headquarters not called by
Suleyman Shah...
...is not a place we want to be in.
What will happen now, Bey?
The order given by Suleyman Shah
is still valid.
Preparations for migration
to Aleppo shall continue.
We will not give up on our Bey’s words
or his guests. With the help of God.
We are almost out of the Seljuk territory,
we can rest our horses here for a while.
-How is he, mother?
-The same, my son.
Did you hear our voices?
I am going to say that we should
send your father as soon as possible.
You are right, mother. We should have him
reach our destination...
...before he gets really distraught
during the migration.
You are right, Gundogdu Bey.
I can check and fix the old cart...
...for a more comfortable journey
for Suleyman Shah.
Thank you, Usta.
If he goes to Aleppo sooner,
we might find a remedy as well.
But I cannot come with you. You know that
the tribe is like a witch’s cauldron.
Don’t worry, Gundogdu Bey. I can take
Mother Hayme and Suleyman Shah...
...to Aleppo safe and sound.
We will leave early in the morning.
If God permits.
Look at Ertugrul.
I would have never thought that
he would kill the tribe’s warriors.
You have been my assistant for nothing
all these years, Alpargu.
Bey...
...this is a Crusader arrow.
Bravo, Alpargu.
You start to understand slowly.
-Turgut Agabey?
-Yes, brave boy?
How are you related to
Bamsi and Dogan Agabeys?
They are my blood brothers.
I have a blood brother as well now.
Who is your blood brother?
Dundar.
But you blood brothers
are always together...
...Dundar and I are separated.
The world is not so large, my friend.
Mountains may not meet...
...but people can meet again.
The hillside is quiet. There is no one
in sight. How was your side?
The downside is clear as well.
This is a secure place.
Everywhere is clear, why are you frowning.
Because you couldn’t find an enemy?
No, this man called Afsin
is making me anxious.
Do you know who he is?
I don’t know either
but it is not very important.
Don’t tire your pea sized brain out
with things like this.
Your mind is not used to thinking.
Look now, we are in the field
beside the water, right?
Shall we wrestle so that
I can crush you to the ground?
Alright. Alright but...
...do not cry when you lose!
Let me go! I said let me go!
Let me go!
What about you and Aykiz Abla?
She is my sweetheart.
Are Ertugrul Agabey and
my sister Halime sweethearts too?
Yigit Alp?
What are you saying?
-Get the dried meat from the saddlebag.
-But, sister.
Go on.
-But sister...
-Go on.
I will send Ertugrul to you, my brother.
Your soul will not be tormented anymore.
Are you fine, Shahzade?
Yes, thank you.
I am listening to my inner voice.
What does your inner voice say to you?
I think about my forefather Oguz.
He saw a dream, our Oguz Khan...
...and he pulled his golden bow
from sunrise to sunset...
...and said
this world is too small for two rulers...
...enough for one ruler.
And our Great Bilge Khan said...
...as long as the blue sky
does not fall down...
...or as long as the great earth
does not split apart...
...no one can overrule your customs.
Then my grandfather Tugrul Bey...
...after the Dandanaqan Battle...
...called for the Great Council...
...and opened up
new horizons for our people.
And opened the road to
Rome territory for us.
And in the Rome territory, in Manzikert...
...Sultan Alparslan...
wore his shroud for a new world order
and turned these lands...
...into a state.
Do you know what my inner voice says,
Ertugrul?
We need an another hero who will unite...
...lead and set a new vision
for these people.
Talk!
Who gave you the order to kill Ertugrul?
Answer me!
Who ordered you to kill
Suleyman Shah’s son?
Has not this lowlife confessed yet?
He will soon.
We know that you are not alone.
Who helped you inside the palace?
Tell him, uncle...
...if he talks, I will spare his life.
Answer me.
Who helped you to attack Ameer’s guest?
It was you!
Answer me properly!
Who helped you?
Who? Who was he?
El Aziz’s vizier,
Sahabettin Tugrul helped me.
Uncle?
What is this man saying?
He will talk soon.
Someone is coming!
Get prepared immediately!
Master Titus is waiting for us!
Exercise is over! Order the knights
in the barracks to get ready!
My father used to say that you were
his most trusted man. I trust you as well.
That is your kindness, your highness.
I trust you more than my uncle.
Please, your highness Elanora,
do not compare Ustad-i Azam with me.
Titus talked about a dungeon
before he left the castle.
Did he want to say that my father was
thrown to a dungeon before he was killed?
I do not know, it would be best
if you asked this to Master Titus.
Before my father died, you were always
with him but you did not tell me...
...about a dungeon. Maybe my father
is still in a dungeon somewhere.
I am ready to hear and
know the truth, Mario.
-No, both of you would...
-Both? My father and I?
No, no. I meant you and Master Titus.
You are lying to me as well.
Alright, put it right here.
Right here.
If it is ready, untie the ropes.
Children, take your lamb somewhere else.
We need that chest.
You help us as well, alright?
You old goat. I would have never thought
that Ertugrul Bey would dwell in these...
...love issues like you.
My brother, these things cannot be known.
It may happen to you one day as well.
You would think that you can stand up
against the whole world...
...but a pair of eyes would come
and smash you to the ground.
Which girl would like this log?
Moreover you need not a pair of eyes...
...but a pair of wrists to smash him
to the ground and I have that.
Stop right there Dogan,
stop clowning about.
I need to understand this.
Doesn’t Ertugrul Bey love this girl now?
He should ask permission
from her father to get married.
Are these things so easy, brother?
I don’t understand. If Ertugrul Bey asks
for her hand, wouldn’t her father accept?
If that is not possible,
we can abduct Halime Sultan.
What does your heart say?
State your troubles so that
we can help you if we know a way.
My Sultan, he wants to escape from the
hell we call palace as soon as possible.
So that he can focus on praying to God
in the Prophet’s mosques.
Is your desire, leaving behind
the throne like Shah Ibrahim ibn Adham...
...and to reach enlightenment?
But would not leaving this post
and going away mean...
...leaving behind the ones
who trust you as well?
You give your services in the palace.
But what will happen to the Muslim world?
The owner of this world and Islam is God.
Your duty is to work on the path to God.
I have never refrained from duty.
I did all that was asked from me
without hesitation.
-But...
-What is the despair in your mind?
Ameer  El Aziz, my nephew.
He is just like a child.
I consume all my energy
trying to contain him.
But...
...messengers bring news every day.
From Abbasi Khalifa’s palace,
Khwarazmshah’s throne...
...from Cairo, Baghdad.
Wherever there is a vizier, a mayor who
cares for the problems of the people...
...they are being killed one by one.
Even in our own palace, we do not know
who is acting according to whose agenda.
Are the things you said...
...an excuse to resign from your duty...
...or a reason to work even harder?
When you continue in your efforts
without questioning yourself...
...God will bring you assistants and the
people whom you will help sooner or later.
My sheikh...
...could you do a favor
for this God’s subject?
Favor?
When a man asks for
a favor from his father...
...the father would say
“give service, my son.”
Do not forget...
...those who are ready to sacrifice
themselves for their invalid beliefs...
...would always win over the Muslims
who are not prepared to fight for God.
This is God’s justice.
God’s Son is waiting for you
at His kingdom in heaven.
You suffered, just like
He suffered in order to save us.
What is inside it?
Argos. It will take you to God’s Son.
When you see me again,
it means you are on your way to God.
What is the latest situation
in the palace?
We have someone from us
in almost all the posts.
What about the vizier?
Sahabettin.
His eyes are always on his nephew. But...
...I have some plans for him as well.
Good.
Soon, death will fall upon
all Muslim capitals.
Everyone will ask for help
from their neighbors.
It is of utmost importance that the
replies to letters that come to Aleppo...
...are stamped with El Aziz’s seal
but written by you.
Before calling for the Crusade army...
...we should take hold of all
communications within the Muslim palaces.
I understand, sir. Do now worry.
If you don’t have any other orders...
...I would like to return to the palace.
I would not like them to miss me.
What did you do about the issue of Kayis?
Will you be able to send Suleyman Shah’s
tribe to another place away from us?
When I deal with Vizier Sahabettin,
that issue will be solved as well, sir.
Titus also said things similar to this.
He said Kayis will never
settle under our noses...
...but they will be starting
their journey soon.
Sir, why does the existence of Kayis
at your borders makes you worry so much?
Why are you so anxious about a tribe that
can only gather 2000 warriors at most?
When I clear the road between Antioch and
Jerusalem for a new Crusade campaign...
...the last thing I want is
a warring Turkmen tribe settled nearby.
If we close our eyes on Kayis today,
tomorrow they would close our eyes.
Do not forget Saladin Ayyubi.
He was born in one of
the thousands of farms within Iraq.
Then he became a soldier under
the command of Nureddin Zengid.
He was promoted.
He was only a commander amongst
hundreds of commanders.
You know the rest.
If we could stop him in time...
...Jerusalem would still be
in our hands now.
And I would not have needed to bother
with people like you!
I understand, sir.
Tell them to prepare the horses, Marcus.
We are going back to the castle.
Once upon a time there was
a famous carpenter in Baghdad.
During his last days,
he carved a very beautiful pulpit.
A very beautiful one. From walnut wood,
decorated with mother of pearl.
It was so beautiful that everyone
would be enchanted by its beauty.
The news of the beautiful pulpit spread.
Everyone who came to Baghdad would go
and ask him to sell the pulpit to them...
...to take it to their mosque.
His answer would always be the same.
He would say: “No,
this pulpit belongs to Al Aqsa Mosque.”
People would get bewildered as Jerusalem
was occupied by the Crusaders.
The carpenter would give
the same reply every single time.
This is all I can do. I am a craftsman.
I make pulpits.
Let one valiant warrior take back
Jerusalem, then the pulpit can be placed.
As time passed, the pulpit story
was heard in all the cities.
While everyone was telling each other
how beautiful the pulpit was...
...the story was heard by
a boy only seven or eight years old.
But he focused more on the will of the man
rather than the beauty of the pulpit.
40 years passed and he took that pulpit...
...and placed it in its rightful place
in the Al Aqsa Mosque.
The tongues spoke of him
as Saladin Ayyubi.
These matters are like this.
We carve out new pulpits
like that carpenter...
...the valiant people who will put them
in their rightful place will come out.
-Gundogdu.
-Yes, Usta?
If Suleyman Shah would have seen you
at the headquarters, he would be proud.
-I just want you to know that.
-Thank you.
We will break through
this ring of fire together.
Do not forget, you are his son.
When your origins are a wolf,
your heart is a wolf as well.
-Gundogdu Bey?
-What happened, Akcakoca?
There are some things
I need to talk with you.
Aykiz...
...Gokce is not well.
Her troubles are deep
but she still keeps quiet.
She refrains from talking to me...
...can you talk with her?
I see her condition as well, Mother Hayme.
But you know as well...
...the remedy of her troubles
is not with me.
I know.
I know but...
Gokce is like her late mother...
...she keeps silent and burns within.
But being so silent is not good.
Aykiz...
Gokce?
Let me help you.
There are only a few things left anyway.
You are in sorrow because
they accuse Ertugrul Bey.
Do not worry, the truth will come out.
Of course it will.
We should pray that they are well.
We could not say goodbye when Turgut left.
I have a feeling that a bad thing
is going to happen.
My mind is always with him.
Hope is the best medicine for even
the deadliest nightmares.
You know very well...
...Turgut will return to the tribe.
His return will be returning to you.
You will rejoice with your loved one.
But the separation between
Ertugrul and I is not distance.
Even if he returns...
...even if he sits beside me,
I will be the furthest one from him.
It will be like looking at the sun
behind the insurmountable mountains.
Bey...
...first I thought it was because of
the famine and did not gave importance.
But, the matter is grave.
What is your opinion?
Plague.
Black death?
What do we need to do?
Bey...
...I checked the whole tribe.
I stamped the ill animals with red paint
and gathered them all here.
If we exterminate all of them...
...with God’s help,
we can avoid this disaster.
If God permits, Akcakoca, if God permits.
If God permits, Bey.
Do whatever you need to do.
Find someone trustable
and keep it a secret.
The tribe is in the brink of havoc,
we don’t need criers of disaster as well.
-May God turn it into a good deed.
-Alright, Bey.
Everyone is nervous as it is,
why do you call me here, Selcan Hatun?
Why do you worry
when you see me, Kurdoglu?
You should think about what
you will do when Suleyman Shah wakes up.
That is not my problem, your husband,
who tries to take advantage of...
...his father’s illness should be worried.
You think I am one of the Beys
you convinced at the headquarters.
Don’t I know the things you are up to?
Don’t lose your breath and tell me...
...you beat Gundogdu at the headquarters.
What will you do when
Suleyman Shah wakes up?
Don’t you worry about these things,
Selcan Hatun. I will find a way.
Suleyman Shah will be leaving tomorrow.
They will be going to Aleppo,
to find a remedy for his illness.
If he gets up again...
...think about your fate then.
What are you trying to say?
Speak clearly,
do not beat around the bush.
If our Suleyman Shah who sleeps
with high fever, God forbid...
...gives his last breath tonight.
Even I would say Azrael was the culprit...
...I would mourn and cry at his grave.
How will it be done?
Tonight...
...I will take Gundogdu and
Mother Hayme out of the tent...
...the rest is up to you.
If Suleyman Shah dies, I would revenge my
father’s death and you would become Bey.
30 knights have been sent
upon Sir Titus’s request.
Ustad-i Azam, you have a guest
from Vatican in your room.
He is waiting for you.
My dear friend Petruccio.
Cardinal Thomas.
It is an honor to see you.
You should have informed us beforehand.
I did not want to interrupt
your Aleppo escapade.
You are still being the eyes and
the ears of our Holy Father.
His highness the Pope appreciates
your efforts but he has some reservations.
He needs to be convinced for
a new Crusader campaign.
How can he be convinced?
You have to take back the holy relics
those infidel Mohammadans stole from us.
I am guessing you know
who is hiding those holy relics.
-Hello, my brother.
-Brother?
Very wrong. Very.
I remember the day our mother
gave you birth. Shame.
Brothers should not treat
each other like this.
Get out of here.
You did not only shatter your brother.
You shattered your whole family.
Was it worth it?
You went after a bedouin.
And destroyed your wife, your children...
...your cause and everything else
with your own hands.
But we are brothers.
If you can bring me the items
in Ibn Arabi’s chest...
...I can grant you your family.
Do you still have hope that
I would serve for your goals?
Don’t ever talk to me about loyalty.
When you abandoned the Son of God
and sold out the Templars...
...you proved your loyalty.
Why should you not do the same again?
I promise you...
...if you can bring back the items
in that chest...
...you can see your family again.
I know that you don’t trust me anymore.
For you to trust me once again...
...I can arrange you to meet
your little daughter at midnight.
Is my Elanora here?
Good.
All the birds are in the same cage.
-Gokce, you go and sleep now.
-Alright, sister.
Sister?
-Hatun?
-Sister?
Quick, call Mother Hayme. Bring her here!
Gundogdu, something is happening.
Alright, Hatun. Alright. Calm down.
I will run and bring the midwife.
Be quick, hurry up!
Mother Hayme.
Come, my girl.
Gokce, what is the hurry? What happened?
Mother Hayme, my sister is in great pain.
She asked for you.
I hope it is not a bad thing.
Akcakoca, midwife Hatun,
do we have permission?
Yes, Bey? Akcakoca is outside.
I hope there is no bad news.
No, Selcan has some bad cramps.
We have to go to the tent immediately.
I will just get my cloak.
-Is Selcan Hatun pregnant, Bey?
-If God permits, come on.
-My girl.
-I can’t stand the pain, mother.
Come on. Keep calm, my girl. Calm down.
Let me check.
Calm down, I am just going to check.
Don’t do it, don’t!
I hope it is not serious.
Don’t.
Is my Bey father alone, mother?
No. Rahman is with him. Do not worry.
You go to my father, Gundogdu.
He should not be alone.
I said go.
Kurdoglu.
You have passed the Alp trials.
You fought with wolves and bears, faced
many dangers to return to your tribe.
You now have the right to carry
the title of Alp with honor.
But now the lesson you have to learn
is much more important than all these.
Being an Alp is not finding food
in times of need...
...but to stand strong
in the face of difficulties.
Suleyman Shah...
...Kurdoglu...
...Alpsungur...
...take an arrow from your quivers.
Break them!
Take one more arrow from
your quivers and give them to me.
If you take the advice of
your forefathers and always be united...
...you would be unbreakable
just like these arrows.
From now on never let your names
and selves be separated.
Those who talk about you,
should always refer to your togetherness.
Why is it dark in here?
Rahman!
Yes, Bey?
Why are these oil lamps not lit, Rahman?
I don’t know, Bey.
You would not be aware
even if doomsday had started.
Bey?
-Find something and block that tear.
-Yes, Bey.
No one will know about what happened here.
Don’t ever leave my father alone.
Yes, Bey.
Thank God. The cramps were a good news.
Road to motherhood is painful
but the end is a blessing.
You made us happy in these hard times.
May God permit us to hold
the child in our arms.
If God permits, mother.
If my Bey father recovers soon,
he would be happy too.
Of course he would. We were yearning
for a grandchild for a long time.
Of course he would be happy.
-Sister.
-My Gokce.
Gundogdu...
Son, we have good news.
Our bride Selcan is pregnant.
He will continue our progeny and
become Bey of the tribe, if God permits.
If God permits. Thank you, mother.
-May you be blessed.
-Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
You should not have left
my Bey father alone.
He is not alone, Hatun.
Rahman is with him.
You take care and do not worry
about other things.
What a bitch.
First she sent me to the tent.
Then sent her husband after me.
So she wanted Suleyman Shah dead in order
to take revenge for her father Alpsungur.
And she was going to make me
a bait for Gundogdu at the same time.
Two birds with one stone.
I could not work out the bitch’s game.
When a wolf gets old,
it becomes the laughingstock of the dogs.
What do you say, Alpargu?
Are we too old now?
Their cries tear my heart apart. I wish
we could kill them before setting on fire.
This illness is not like
the ones you know, son.
If you touch the meat or blood of these
animals, the whole tribe would be doomed.
Our Holy Mother,
give me a sign to bring a tinge of hope.
If my father is alive
and if I can meet him...
...give me a sign.
Your highness...
...are you here?
Amen.
You told me that you were prepared
to learn the truth.
Then come with me.
-Is it here?
-Yes.
You never saw me, your highness.
Is my father behind this door?
-Father?
-My daughter?
-Father!
-My girl!
Father!
-Father!
-My girl!
Father,
I thought you were killed years ago.
I always thought of you.
Hope of seeing you again kept me alive.
Father, why are you here?
Your mother, your sister and
you are in my dreams every night.
-Mother...
-What happened to your mother, my girl?
We lost her to plague last year.
Father, why are they holding you here?
Uncle told us that you were dead.
Does my uncle know that you are here?
I will talk with him and
take you out of here.
My girl!
Father?
-Father.
-My daughter.
My baby!
My baby! My Elanora!
My baby, my Elanora!
Help me God!
In short, Ertugrul Bey,
just like the poet says...
I burned and turned to ash
I became a guide for the sufferers
I was a Shah and became a subject
With the fire of your love
With your permission, Bey.
It is your turn to take watch.
I could not sleep.
Halime.
You know that...
...I have a thousand problems.
Their solutions are in my power...
...and my power is in my belief.
But there is one problem.
It is the most beautiful problem...
...but it burns my heart.
And its solution is only with you.
That beautiful eyed gazelle swept away
my feet and made me join its path.
It took me to you
and threw me to the sea of love.
I was just about to kill it but...
...it burned my heart with a fire of love.
What I am trying to say is...
...since the first moment I saw you...
-Please, Ertugrul. Stop.
I shall not.
I cannot send you away with my own hands.
Do not go.
Stay with me.
Be the sultan of my heart,
the mother of my children...
...and my companion till the end.
You are a valiant and honest brave
with a good heart, Ertugrul Bey.
We owe you not one but a thousand lives.
But my fate is sealed a long time ago.
I cannot leave my father and brother
in a world of unknown to go after love.
When I could not even become
the sultan of the palace I was born in...
...I cannot be the sultan of your heart.
This is your tongue talking.
What about your heart?
What does your heart say, Halime?
My heart and my tongue talk the same.
Don’t go.
Halime!
Halime?
Halime! Halime!
Halime!