Episode 16 will start after 12:13 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
FORT OF THE TEMPLARS
Uncle, stop this.
That is enough, Titus.
Are you ready, brother Judas?
I am.
Rise, then.
Afsin Bey.
I respect your age, however you should
know that we do not trust  you.
Whatever. Just be cautious.
Titus will bring Turgut soon.
Are you ready?
I am always ready, son.
You cannot escape God's will.
Ertugrul Bey, just let me
smash this monkey's face before the trade.
We promised them, Afsin Bey.
If they do not keep their promise,
his blood is yours.
Let us get on the horses.
You know how to communicate with me
if anything happens.
We cannot trust them.
They will do something wicked for sure.
We will see.
Bey...
Be careful.
You, too, Dogan.
You, too.
We will walk for the rest of the way.
I do not know
why our Bey trusted this man.
Let us see how it turns out.
They say that you killed the Pope.
Is it Afsin who told this to you?
I am surprised I am even famous here.
I first met Afsin Bey in Konstantiniyye.
Let me tell you something, Ertugrul.
Shahzade Numan...
Who do you think killed him?
Do you think Afsin is the
dark hand of the state?
We will go on alone.
They are coming.
Of course they are.
I am more valuable than your Alp.
To me, you are not
anything more than a leech...
...that sucks the blood of
poor Christians.
I hope it is not a trap.
What is it?
Enough. Enough nagging at me.
My brother Turgut can take him by himself.
If there is any problem with him,
Ertugrul Bey will take care of him.
Maybe Turgut is the trap itself.
What is he talking about?
So we meet again, Turk.
THREE DAYS AGO
-Oh my God.
-Oh mey Goodness.
The time has come, Wild Demir.
The time to revolt
against persecution has come.
We came to this land
with so many hopes, Bey.
We wanted to be happy,
but everything went so bad.
I would not want to be called a man...
...unless I make the ones
who put us into trouble pay for this.
What is in your mind, Bey?
I will take Turgut.
Aykiz says that nobody
can pass through that castle.
Neither through its walls nor its door.
There is a key for each lock,
and a brave man for each wall.
If we cannot take Turgut,
then we will die for the sake of it.
If you bring Turgut back here,
Aykiz will be happy again.
I gave my word to Aykiz.
We will marry them in this land.
Hopefully, Bey. Hopefully.
I am setting off.
We are leaving with the Alps.
Good luck, Bey.
I will see you before we leave.
Thank you, Bey.
Kara Toygar walked over everything,
but El Aziz destroyed everything.
And there are the Crusaders.
What are we going to do?
My flock was more well-fed
when the Mongols were after us.
Now we have
only 40 skinny cattle. Why?
Because there is not anybody
we did not challenge.
All our children's livelihood is lost.
-That is right, Bey. That is right.
-That is right. This is unacceptable.
I will sell these cattle.
I tell you that.
What would you expect
from this flock, Bey?
The mother did not give any milk.
We could not benefit from it in any way.
Who will buy them?
Nobody would want them.
Merchants from Aleppo
have long stopped trading with Turkmens.
Feed up your cattle
in this beautiful tent...
...so that everything goes on well.
Do not worry. I will sell them
with a good price.
We know that you are different, Bey.
You talk the language of our people.
You know what the flock
and the shepherd wants.
We saw you passed through treacherous
waters without losing even one of them.
-That is right, Bey.
-That is right.
You want peace, not war.
Only you can do this, Bey.
However, if we cannot sell this flock,
it will be very bad for us.
Go and feed up your cattle, now.
It is my duty to deal with this.
I will see you.
What are we going to do?
The shepherds' trouble
is the tent's trouble.
There will not be peace in the tent
unless they are pleased.
Tell me about it.
There is a way, but I do not know
what your father would say.
Listen to me carefully, Gundogdu.
I see it is time for travel, Atabey.
Ertugrul Bey,
I owe you not only my life...
...you also saved Aleppo.
You destroyed the Crusaders' order.
One day, the Islamic world
will remember this hero with gratitude.
Thank you.
However, if we cannot unite
Anatolia and this land...
...the Crusaders will have
more and more traps for us.
You are right.
Aleppo, Jerusalem,
Damascus, Mosul, Kirkuk...
...and Bagdad... and Konya...
...and so many other cities
are like a mother's children.
Whoever tries to separate them
from each other...
...will pay for it.
You are right.
Aleppo is your home
whenever anything is needed.
Its door is always open
to you and your tent.
And our weapons are always ready
to be pulled out of their sheaths for you.
My girl, we know
what you have gone through.
We all know the troubles
that you have had as a family.
And we know what you had
gone through, Mother Ana.
Being the daughter of a shahzade is not
something I care even a little bit about.
There is nothing I want
other than being a girl in your tent.
Everybody knows very well
what it means to leave your father...
...as the daughter of a shahzade
and come to the tent with a man.
I have asked this to Gokce before.
Now, I will ask you the same.
Are you willing to do anything
for Ertugrul?
Yes.
Do you know that
a women who really loves him...
...should be ready for any trouble
that comes from her pavilion and family?
I do.
Do you know that this girl should only
worry about this pavilion's troubles?
I do, Mother Ana.
So, tell me,
would you disregard your own happiness...
...for the sake of Ertugrul's?
Would you leave Ertugrul and go away?
If I am meant to be together
with Ertugrul, I would be with him.
If am meant to be sad for him,
I would not complain, Mother Ana.
After being educated
in a madrasa in Konya...
...I am trying to help the people of the
tent by Suleyman Shah's request.
Thankfully, the people of the Kayi Tent
serve with heart and soul.
This tent has a different smell, son.
And such a soul that...
...God will create order in the
whole world by favor of them.
Hopefully.
May I come in?
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Are you comfortable?
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
Fakih Ilyas welcomes us very well.
I will set off tomorrow
after the Friday prayer.
To where, son?
To save my brother Turgut.
I am going to collapse
the Templars' castle onto them.
The Devil's children
have so many traps to set.
Son, you are young,
your are powerful, you are an Alp...
...however, you must be a ruler.
Pens solve what weapons cannot.
You must see the tricks.
Be careful.
The Devil has lots of tricks.
If I wonder the snowy mountain ahead
Whose highland is that
If I wonder its cold, cold waters
Whose spring is that
If I wonder those camels row after row
Whose load is that
If I wonder the black skied pavilion
Whose shadow is that
Why are you asking that?
If it gave me news
About the girl I am meant to be with
I see.
What are you going to do
if it gives you news?
I would say
"I would give my life for you."
Did you remember Cicek Hatun when you saw
Mother Hayme's son in the caravansary?
Do you think I ever forget her?
Did you ask about Cicek Hatun
to Korkut Bey when you saw him?
I did not have the courage, brother.
Your troubles will not end, brother.
Listen, I do not have a woman,
but I gird on my weapons instead.
I do not have children,
but I love my horse instead.
How could we want women
when our people have so many problems?
Sister...
What?
Mother Hayme asked
if I would do anything for Ertugrul.
What does this mean?
She wanted to know if I would stand
anything for the man I love.
Meaning?
She asked if I would love him
to the extent that I would forget him.
And what did you say?
I said that the die was cast.
Well done, sister.
You will never give up.
If you do,
she will oppress you all your life.
Gokce...
Do you think Mother Hayme  wants to marry
her son both you and Halime?
What are you saying, sister?
May I come in?
Please, Bey.
Good day.
Good day, Bey.
I heard that my niece passed away.
Went to his last home.
May him be our savior in the other world.
Amen, Bey.
I am very sorry.
May God grant you other children.
And may Him grant our tent some peace.
Ertugrul Bey, Halime made
quite an entrance to this tent.
We lost so many lives because of her.
So many mothers were devastated.
Aykiz lost Turgut. She lost her mind
and made me lose my baby.
Your brother and me suffered for this.
If more souls will be wounded
because of this girl, do not let this.
Be a man and send her away.
You lost your baby, and you are in pain.
However, this tent has a tradition.
Men act like men,
and women act like women in this tent.
If women interfere with men's business,
there would be no order in the tent.
And I never let a woman
who messes the order say a word.
Have a good day.
I just came to offer my condolence.
Ertugrul, leave off this ambition
for Halime Sultan.
There is no peace in the tent anymore.
Ertugrul Bey...
I am grateful that you came back safe.
Gokce...
You know there is something
regarding the two of us.
My father.
He wants to see you
as his daughter-in-law.
But my heart beats for someone else.
You are my sister
whom I grew up with.
There is nothing beyond this for me.
I just wanted you to know that.
I know, Ertugrul Bey.
Your heart only says "Halime Sultan".
One who waits for the loved one
is bound to be saddened.
I can only accept this saddening now.
I will not come to you
unless you tell me to.
I will wait for you until I die
if necessary.
Do not worry.
This matter is between you
and your father from now on.
Keep in mind that I accepted my fate.
Excuse me.
May I come in, Aykiz?
I heard what happened.
I just wanted to say I am sorry, Aykiz.
Selcan is a dangerous woman.
You can expect anything from her.
You are right, Halime.
Everybody knows she is dangerous.
And there are dangerous people
whom nobody has seen or known of.
The ones that are the main reason
of the troubles we have had.
What do you mean, Aykiz?
Don't you see the situation we are in?
You are responsible for everything.
Don't you ever say yourself "All the
troubles started after we set foot here"?
You are right, Aykiz.
We put you into trouble
while our troubles were still going on...
...but that was not what I wanted.
I made a decision.
I came here leaving my family back.
Halime, you are still
talking about yourself.
My Turgut is a captive
in the Templars' hands.
We do not have any news from him.
While I am in this situation...
...Ertugrul Bey has been chasing you
for the past few days.
May I come in?
Please, Bey.
We will set off to take Turgut
before the sunrise.
And you should know that
we will not come back without him.
If we die...
...give us your blessing, Aykiz.
Of course, Bey.
Give me some information about the castle.
Whenever you want, Bey.
Excuse me.
We will set off.
There are preparations to be made.
I was hating you.
I thought Ertugrul Bey
has forgotten Turgut because of you.
Of course he did not.
A brave man would never forget his Alp.
He will bring Turgut back to you
at the risk of his life.
-Stay in our tent tonight.
-What about your father?
He will take care of himself.
He could lay a bed
by the side of the stove.
Alright.
What did you talk?
He said he loved Halime.
Come here.
Take a walk, sister.
My pure and beautiful Gokce.
Trouble is back in our tent.
Let us see what more troubles
that ominous woman will cause us.
Obviously, she intends to settle in here.
But I know how I will make her go away
without even looking back.
As for you, you will listen to
what I say from now on.
You will do whatever I say.
Otherwise, forget Ertugrul.
Since when are you ruthless so much?
Forget whatever has happened
in the past.
Drop the burden on your shoulders,
and your hatred.
Nobody will love us
as long as you break everybody's heart.
Gokce, behave yourself!
Watch your mouth!
Selcan...
What is it?
You are turning the place upside down.
Nothing, Gundogdu.
My sister was showing me
how impudent she was.
There is enough trouble around.
Do not cause any more troubles here.
Do not worry, Gundogdu.
Bey, Mother Hayma says that...
...Suleyman Shah wants to
have a meal in the pavilion...
...with his children and daughters in law.
ALEPPO
Is Hazrat Ameer in his room?
He is waiting for you.
Thank God we saw you here. We saved
ourselves from being their headquarters.
Thank you, Siddik.
Hazrat Ameer...
Uncle...
Can you forgive me?
All is left behind now.
It is over.
Do not torture yourself
by thinking of the past.
How can I live with this
guilty conscience, Uncle?
With so many people's burden
on my shoulders.
The dervishes that have been martyred...
...the soldiers that have been martyred...
How will I be able to atone for
all these sins?
My sheikh Ibn al Arabi who took over...
...the dervish's coat of Gavs ul Azam
Seyyid Abdulkadir Geylani...
...told me one day:
"Be determined to not commit the sins
you have repented for.
As for the good deeds you are doing, do
them to death, and never give them up"
Welcome.
We will have so much to talk at dinner.
Hopefully, Aziz.
Hopefully.
May I come in?
Yes, come in.
Suleyman Shah invites you
to the family dinner.
Me, too?
Yes.
Would it be appropriate?
Suleyman Shah deemed this suitable.
He said "Ertugrul will go
to bring back Turgut tomorrow.
You never know if he comes back.
Let us be all together in this meal."
He also wanted Wild Demir and Aykiz.
We are coming.
Come on.
The Brave Beys of the Kayi Tent.
You honored my meal.
Thank you all.
You made me so happy.
Thank you.
We have been traveling for so long
to find a land for ourselves.
For our sons and daughters
to be happy.
You are right, Bey.
There is not any piece of land
we have not set foot on.
However, we could not find a land
to live on without any fear.
All our hopes are on Aleppo.
And it is turned to hell
because of Suleyman Shah's son, Ertugrul.
We cannot stand anymore, Kurdoglu.
We found ourselves in baseless fights.
That is what I am worried about.
If it goes on likes this, I am afraid
our children will not be happy anymore.
-You are right, Bey.
So, what are we going to do?
What is the remedy?
The only man who is experienced enough
to save us from this trouble is you.
Karabudak and Kutlu.
You have always been
brave and direct.
And you still are. Thank you.
Thank you.
I knew I could trust you.
What about the remedy?
The remedy is
going against Suleyman Shah...
...and saying
"The Bey should be Gundogdu".
What?
Alright. Please.
God, give us power
so that the infidels will not succeed.
Strengthen our faith and bodies.
Give us the victory.
Deem the soldiers who have died
in this war as martyrs.
Forgive the sins of El Aziz.
Amen.
Your body will enliven Aleppo,
and your head will enliven the Kayi Tent.
I will show you all
that you are bound to be defeated.
The war is just beginning.
What is wrong with you?
-Nothing.
-What do you mean, nothing?
Do not walk around like that.
Pull yourself together.
These three spoons
that have been left on the table...
So, that was the problem.
One of them is for Ertugrul's
elder brother Sungurtekin...
...and the other is for Dundar.
That is, for the ghosts who will
never be able to sit on this table.
As for the last spoon...
...obviously, you are afraid
that it might be for Halime.
Sister...
Suleyman Shah would not do
such a thing, would he?
Clearly, you haven't known
that old man enough yet.
He can even kill a man
he calls "my friend"...
But not that much.
Look...
...your future husband
will come soon.
We will eat together.
He saved the tent from disasters...
...Aleppo from the Templars...
...and the Islamic world
from a big war.
They sacrificed the biggest ram
in the tent for the sake of him.
Mother Hayme cooked his son's
favorite meal.
This night's king is him,
and the queen is you.
Pull yourself together.
Who else is coming?
Let us see who is going to
come out of your father's bag.
Where is my father?
He is inside, with your mother.
Let me check Dundar out.
Here.
When my brave brother wakes up...
...we will show everybody
in our new land...
...how to shoot arrows
and how to use sword.
Did I do something
to break your heart, brother?
Do not get on me, Ertugrul.
What are you thinking, brother?
You never see Gokce's tears,
do you, Ertugrul?
How she is heartbroken.
You do not care about anything at all.
Neither Gokce
nor this marriage that my father wants...
You always do what you want
and get what you want.
After all, our Bey is very fortunate.
He falls on his four feet
like a Persian cat.
He does not care about the Templars.
Who is my father
who went against the great Seljuks?
And Gokce who is crazy in love with him?
Who is she, compared to the
daughter of the Shahzade?
Only this would suit our Bey.
Do what suits you, Ertugrul.
We will see how this will end.
Aykiz, that is enough.
You are not well. Have a seat.
I am good. Do not worry.
I was going to go
to the Templar's castle with them...
...if Ertugrul Bey allowed me to.
Is this not the mirror
that Ertugrul gave you?
Yes.
Be happy whenever you look at this mirror.
I hope your happiness increases
whenever you look at it.
Amin, Aykiz.
But it will not be easy for you.
Was it not you who told me once
that being a woman was hard...
...but the hardest is
being an Alp's woman?
I do not have any place to go anymore.
I do not have any place to shelter in
other than Ertugrul and your tent.
I came here leaving my family behind.
I am not a Shahzade's daughter anymore.
I am the daughter of this tent.
May I come in?
Come in, father.
Come on, my girl, let us go.
Father, let me stay here...
To sit on the same table
with that woman...
...when the whip wounds
are still on my back.
There is surely something our Bey knows.
We will look at each other's faces
all our lives.
You cannot be angry at each other.
Come on.
Uncle?
Get up.
Get up, get up!
Do not do it, Bey.
I will see his face.
They beheaded Atabey.
Unfortunately, I could not find his head.
Uncle...
Uncle, get up.
Uncle!
Ertugrul.
Come here, brother.
Sit down, sit down.
Welcome, my children.
Father, they do not look like
they knew we were coming.
Mother, you did not say
we would have guests.
They are not our guests, Selcan.
They are family.
Please. Welcome.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
It is Nowruz time.
Suleyman Shah told us
to leave all the bad feelings among us.
We will pray for our new land's
safety and wealth.
Welcome.
Sit down, sit down.
Hayme, sit down.
Halime Sultan, I am very happy
that you accepted my invitation.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Please.
As my late father said...
...a mountain's side is a road
even though the mountain is very big.
I remember the day we left
the Toros Mountains to come here.
I understand that it was not about
coming down the winter range.
We came to our new land fighting the
Crusaders' plots and losing our soldiers.
Migrating is never easy.
It was not easy this time, as well.
God bless our martyrs and their families.
-Amen.
Even my youngest son Dundar...
...stood out to the Crusaders
and saved our tent from a big disaster.
He was brave like his elder brothers.
Hopefully, we will see him as well
on this table.
-Hopefully.
Hopefully.
Not everything will be a bed of roses
in this land, of course.
We will always struggle
to be able to stay here.
I will give important duties
to Gundogdu and Ertugrul for this.
Both of them showed that...
...they are candidates to be
the Bey of this tent in the future.
I would like our tent to know
Suleyman Shah's sons better.
The one who deserves better would be
the Bey of our tent when the time comes.
From now on, Gundogdu
will deal with our tent's livelihood.
The sales of our animals...
...the sales of our goods
in other cities...
It is a difficult duty in which
he has to struggle thousands of thugs.
Obviously, they will give us
a hard time in our new land.
Ertugrul will be ready at all times
with his Alps...
...to protect our tent
against the Crusaders' attacks.
By God's will, he will take Turgut
and bring him back here tomorrow.
Hopefully, Bey. Hopefully.
I appreciate my sons one more time
who brought our tent a victory.
We are all grateful to them.
-Thank you, father.
Halime Sultan...
It was very grueling for you.
Thankfully, you are healthy.
However, people who wish to use you...
...and the shahzades will always exist.
Suleyman Shah, if you see fit...
...I do not wish to be my father's
daughter who betrayed his country...
...I wish to be this tent's daughter.
To get older together with the
brave people whom I see as my family.
You will make us very happy if you attend
Ertugrul Bey and Gokce's wedding.
Suleyman Shah, may I come in?
Bey...
Afsin Bey and Shahzade Yigit are here.
Yigit...
Let them in.
We have room for them on our table.
Father, as I told you before
about Afsin Bey...
Let us listen, son.
Sister!
Welcome.
How dare you come here Afsin Bey?
Ertugrul!
I came here to let you know that
I did my last duty to the shahzades.
Where is my father, Afsin Bey?
Is he alright?
Shahzade Numan. The state
does not forgive the one who betrays it.
Your father...
...passed away, Halime Sultan.
I buried him myself.
I did my last duty.
Halime...
How did it happen, Afsin Bey?
The Seljuq Empire did
what was necessary Ertugrul Bey.
Halime...
Halime... I...
He was my father
even though he betrayed his country.
We scattered our lives
into pieces for him.
We had all kinds of torture with my
brother while we were running away.
We always resisted.
Even that little boy resisted.
But my father was weak.
Maybe he wanted to protect us.
I do not know.
And I will never know, anyway.
He is gone now.
But I will remember him
with his courage while he was...
...running away from the people
who used him to establish the state.
He was our father.
With his sins and good deeds.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
We would like to read Quran for my father
with Yigit if you allow us to.
God forgive his sins, Halime.
I am sorry.
Amen.
Yigit.
Wild Demir is building a tent for us.
I am taking a bed.
How is Halime Sultan?
Are going to go to save Turgut?
Hopefully, Yigit.
They caused so much pain.
Make them pay, Ertugrul Bey.
May I come in?
Come in, Ertugrul Bey.
May God speed you.
You should know that I will not
come back without him if he is alive.
I also know that you will not come back
without a revenge if he is martyred.
I am sorry.
Thank you, Ertugrul.
May God forgive his sins.
Do not make me grieve for you, too
after my father, Ertugrul.
Do you remember what I told you
when I first separated from you?
"May God speed you.
May the Sun not burn your skin.
May the rain not make you cold.
May stones stay away from your feet.
Go like water, and come back like water."
Aktolgali will fly me like a bird,
and bring back within a short time, then.
-I heard that you were going for Turgut.
-Why do you care?
It is me who knows the castle best.
Let me come with you.
I learned what was necessary
from Aykiz and my brother's Alp.
I will not have any business with the man
who cooperated with the killer of my Alps.
I brought a message from Kurdoglu.
Talk!
Talk, man!
Is he going to come?
Yes, he will.
But I did not come here to tell that.
Why did you come, then?
The two men you are after...
Both of them are guests in our tent.
Who are they?
Shahzade Yigit and a dervish named Arabi.
Kurdoglu asked me to tell you that
a guest is going to come, as well.
Who?
Ertugrul.
Precious Muslims...
...God Almighty says
in Surah An-Nisa...
"Whoever obeys God and the Lord,
will be companions of the Nabis...
...the loyal ones, the martyrs
and the rightly guided ones...
...whom Allah has blessed.
And excellent companions they are."
The most important quality
of a Muslim is loyalty.
What is loyalty?
To be righteous at all times.
To say the truth when you talk.
To go the right way.
Loyalty is the strongest way
to reach God.
Righteous people
are the true travelers of this way.
Precious Muslims...
The most important secret that has
protected Hazrat Noah from the flood...
...Hazrat Yusuf from the well...
...and our Prophet from the infidels
was that they were loyals.
May God let us be the righteous ones.
Amen.
And protect us from the ones
who set traps at all times.
Amen.
Now look at me and repeat after me.
Uccello.
Uc... cell...
...cillo.
Uccello.
Bird.
A very beautiful bird.
Wonderful.
It is you who is wonderful
and "molto bello".
If you go to Genova one day, all the girls
will be dying to talk to you.
You are so beautiful.
I would never think of
talking to another girl.
Never forget where you came from.
I am...
...Judas.
Never forget where you came from.
I am..
...Judas.
I would say you were a mother
to the rebirth of Judas, but...
...you look like his lover,
instead of his mother.
It is you who sleeps with everybody
by order of my uncle. I am not you.
Women.
Judas.
One day...
...just like Judas
who brought Jesus to the crucifix...
...you will pound the nails
on Ertugrul's body.
This is your fate.
My... fate.
Stupid bird.
-Give me your blessing, father.
-My blessing is yours.
-Give me your blessings.
-It is yours.
Bey, they sent this from Aleppo.
The carrier said
this is a present from Sehabettin.
Open the chest.
May my sword be drenched in my blood...
...unless I make your life unbearable...
...and unless I burn you
in the hellfire in this world.
Give me your blessings.
It is yours.
Do you have a death wish?
I told you not to come.
You do not think of
entering the castle, do you?
You want to save Turgut,
but you do not know how to do it.
Will you let me come with you
if I tell you how to do it?
How?
Cardinal Thomas.
Tatos Harput?
His very self.
And who are you?
Gundogdu.
You are from the Kayis.
What was his name...
Kurdoglu.
You are his niece.
We can go and see the flock if you want.
Of course I do.
However, I would like to know
the man I will trade with better.
What would you like to know, Gundogdu?
For example, if you are
one of those low-down Templars.
I like you, son.
I like you better after this question.
Sit down, sit down.
Would you like some soup?
It is Harput's famous soup.
Alright, I would.
It would warm us inside.
Give some soup to the Bey.
Templars?
As an Orthodox,
I can only hate the Templars.
A hatred so much that, your hatred as a
Muslim would be pale in comparison.
That is good.
I am glad we have some common ground.
Me too, son.
We can talk business, then.
They would not settle behind those
big walls if they were brave men.
Not everybody is as brave as we are.
Can they make the sky a shield,
and the earth a weapon?
We will crush their heads
with those big stones.
Many Templar bases like this castle
control the whole Mediterranean.
They would test even the Pope
for their own profit.
The Cardinal is the man
whom they want to be the Pope.
The infidels are everywhere,
Uncle Afsin.
In the tent, in our pavilion,
in the palace.
And the Islamic World is disunited.
We do not even have a conqueror state.
Nothing is like it seems, Ertugrul Bey.
The black clouds gathering above us...
...are for the rain to pour over us.
Our states will survive forever.
Our state becomes Oghuz
and bursts out to the world.
The next thing you know,
it becomes Gokturk and makes stones talk.
Then it becomes the double-headed eagle
and gives life to the great Seljuk.
What I am saying is that...
...Turks will never live
without call to prayer...
...a flag and a state, Ertugrul Bey.
Once we take that Cardinal...
...we will talk about the state
with you.
Help me!
Brother Abdurrahman!
Abdurrahman, what happened?
Suleyman Shah...
...has sent us here, secretly.
We were trapped.
Two of our Alps have been martyred.
I have been watching here
for days without any food and water.
Rest in peace.
Amen.
Tell me, how did this happen?
Did you do your duty, Titus?
Yes, sir.
Are you upset because
you lost our organization in Aleppo?
Maybe a little.
Because of what El Aziz caused.
Our knight that will replace Sehabettin
will make us stronger than before.
It is not only about Aleppo.
Bran Shefoth from Bordeux...
...Aman from Provence...
...Toroya from Aragon...
...and last of all, Montegu.
I would prefer dying
instead of being unsuccessful...
...against the great memories
of these great masters.
We will not allow this, sir.
You are the Grand Master of Antioch.
When we have Jerusalem,
and we will...
...your name will be scraped in hearts.
Let us see if our guests
will say the same thing.
Who is coming, sir?
The commanders of
Jerusalem, Akka and Tripoli.
They are coming
by order of Grand Master Montegu.
We cannot stand
any more failures, Titus.
From now on, we must be harsher...
...more reckless...
...and at least as brutal as
those barbarians.
Do you understand me?
By the way, everybody we look for
comes to us by himself.
Sir...
Come in.
Jasmine.
My favorite odor.
What do you want, Eftelya?
I want to be forgiven, Cardinal.
To be purified from my sins.
Sometimes our sins
are our medals of honor, Eftelya.
We carry them proudly.
If you want to read the letter
I wrote to the Pope...
-...I will scratch your eyes out, bitch!
-No!
What do you want?
Just...
...some mercy.
She said, "If I am meant to be
with him, I will live it.
If I am meant to be unhappy,
I will accept it."
Is that so?
Sometimes I cannot help thinking that I am
casting a shadow upon my son's happiness.
It is clear that
they both love each other.
However...
However, you would not
break your promise, would you?
You know me. I would not.
But if someone from their side does,
it is a different story.
Bey!
Bey, are you alright?
I think this boil starts to relapse.
I could not stand this pain one more time.
There was some ointment left there.
Wait. Never mind.
Are you alright?
I sent Abdurrahman and his Alps
to the castle.
Still no news.
I hope nothing bad has happened.
Bey, please do not
think about these things.
You are alright, are you not?
I am. I am.
I will pray for you
to come back from Antioch fast, Cardinal.
And I will do everything I can
for your prayers to come true, Eftelya.
What am I doing in this ominous place?
Damn!
Damn you!
Wait, I will be back.
Who are you?
Ertugrul, the son of Suleyman Shah
from the Kayi Tent.
You gained Aleppo.
You gained the Taurus Mountains.
Do you want to be
a Crusader count, Ertugrul?
Do not worry, we do not have
our eyes on your land, priest.
Cardinal.
Cardinal Thomas.
I know very well who you are.
You are committing a big sin, son.
I am a reverend who is at God's service.
A Turk like you
should not do such a thing.
You will only be my guest
until I get what I want.
Come on, are you not going to tell?
May I come in?
Come in, uncle.
Good day.
Thank you.
I missed sister Selcan's food.
You can always have our food
if you be a good uncle.
Okay, enjoy your meal.
So, tell me, good niece.
What did you talk with Tatos Harput?
I took the cattle to him.
He liked the flock.
He found them a bit skinny
but he thinks he can sell them.
We made a deal with a good price.
Good.
Our people will be very happy.
Your reputation in the tent
will increase.
-However, he will sell them to...
-Why should we care?
He could throw them into the sea
as long as he pays the money.
Uncle...
He will take them to Antioch.
To the Crusader earldom.
His customers are there.
So what, Gundogdu?
Do not talk like
you do not know my father.
If you can convince your old man
the tent will be in welfare.
If there is welfare, there is also peace.
Whoever brings peace to this tent...
...he is the one
who deserves to be the Bey.
Thank you.
Afsin?
So, it is you.
Here we meet again
after all those years.
Not after all those years, Thomas.
I was in the castle months ago.
So, that monk was you.
Well done, Thomas. Good guess.
You came to the castle to take Turgut.
And now you took me captive.
So, you will trade us.
Well done again, Thomas.
We knew you went to Antioch
every Sunday.
We decided to take advantage of this.
Good idea?
What can I for you?
You can start with
giving me your cross.
What if Master Petruchio
does not want to give Turgut to you?
We will take Turgut Alp
one way or the other.
But I do not know
if they can take you from me.
Tie that black priest up.
Take Abdurrahman with you
and go to the tent.
Tell my father what happened.
Him?
Send him to the castle
and we finish our business before sunset.
Stand up.
They only saved me, sir.
What do they want?
They want Titus
to bring Turgut Alp to them.
Turgut Alp for the Cardinal.
Yes, sir.
Is it true, sir?
On the one hand,
I see the Devil grinning mischievously.
He says, "Let that ominous Turk
kill Thomas."
On the other hand, the Angel says...
..."Let Turgut do what is necessary."
Do you think I should listen the Angel...
...or the Devil?
TRADING DAY
So we meet again, Turk.
Since I promised you...
...and as far as I see,
you kept your promise...
...you can take this black priest and go.
But next time, one of us will die, Titus.
Sometimes I think about
how similar we are.
Both of us are stubborn.
We never give up.
Both of us fight for our
sacred values, our big family.
Both of us lost our best warriors
because of each other.
Both of us are the killer of our brothers.
You may be right, Titus.
But not about being killers.
Your brother Bisol died fighting me
honorably, with his weapon in his hand.
However, you attacked
an innocent child viciously.
Dundar is still alive.
However, my brother
has not opened his eyes.
But I know it very well that
he will come back to us...
...the day I kill you.
And you will die ingloriously.
You will die in pain because you could not
take your brother's revenge.
Take the bag on Turgut Alp's head off.
Untie the Cardinal.
Send Turgut Alp.
Untie the Alp's hands
after we are gone.
I am looking forward to the day
we will meet lastly.
And fight them until
oppression is lifted from the believers...
...and the Religion becomes clearly
apparent and acknowledged.
If they abandon
(oppression and prevention)...
...certainly God is Basir
over what they do.
Halime?
Ertugrul!
Why?
Why did you do this, Turgut?