Episode 13 will start after 12:20 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Ertugrul, this woman...
Eftelya.
What are we going to do?
We are so much defeated that
we can not even surrender.
Their oppression shall increase
so that our victory be more glorious.
There is no giving up, brother!
No way!
Where is our Bey going to?
We need to be
fast Arabian horses to catch him.
Come on!
AL-AQSA MOSQUE, JERUSALEM.
Ertugrul Bey!
Nanny!
Where is Esma?
Esma burned herself alive.
So what will we do, son?
I must have El Aziz
sit and tell him everything.
If necessary...
...I will beat him up like a spoiled brat,
till he comes to his senses.
How are we going to do that?
You must get him out of the palace.
Look.
El Aziz wants to marry Halime before
waiting for the wedding ceremony.
Their marriage will be solemnized soon.
This is El Aziz's family tradition.
The men take their wives to the
hunting lodge right after the wedding.
That will be the only time that
he goes out of the palace.
That will be the only time
that I can bring you together.
Wait till I report you.
Ertugrul!
Yo go nanny, hurry up!
Who are you?
The brother of Bisol whom you murdered!
Titus.
Ebu Hisham!
Ebu Hisham in Jerusalem...
...a commander in the Aleppo Palace...
a Bey in the Kayi nomad tent.
So what, are you baffled?
You are just a pitiful demon, Titus.
Created by the smokeless fire...
...who ambushes on the right way,
putting fear in the weak hearts...
...and infiltrating the strong
and deceiving them.
And you buzz off as soon
as you hear the God's name.
The Alps that I killed
in your nomad tent...
...the Beys who I blinded by my money...
...and Turgut, who is begging
to be killed in my castle...
They all said the same thing.
They are where they deserve to be.
And I am before you, Ertugrul.
You will also get what you deserve.
Bey!
What happened to Turgut, Afsin Bey?
I entered...
...into the Templars' castle for Turgut
Is Turgut alive, Afsin Bey?
We can not help but pray for him
to die as soon as possible.
But there are things you should know.
But...
But what? Speak Afsin, but what?
There were two sisters
from one of the Oghuz Tribes.
Like you and me?
Like the two of us.
Those sisters were so smart,
so beautiful that their father said:
“Only God can solemnize these girls.”
Did our father use to think like that?
It was your father saying that, Gokce.
One day, the Bey...
...took his daughters to a place
where no man has gone before...
...and put them on the
peak of a high mountain.
While the sisters were
waiting on this mountain...
...a grey wolf came
into sight around the mountain.
The wolf got married to the elder sister.
Brother Gundogdu!
And the younger sister got married
to the younger brother of the wolf.
Both sisters got pregnant one day.
Their sons voices sounded
like the grey wolves.
Both sisters' sons reproduced
with the soul of the grey wolf.
Their tribe descended from these sisters.
Just as the Kayis will grow
and descend from us one day.
Ertugrul Bey!
Don't do it, just listen.
You should know that I am meeting
with this bastard just because of you.
Oh my.
-What is all this about brother?
-Ertugrul?
Brother.
Everything started the day you saved
the Shahzades and Halime Sultan.
You made such a big mistake.
Too many people from the Kayis,
the Seljuks and also the Ayyubids...
...paid the price for your
mistake with their lives.
Too much Muslim blood
has been shed, Ertugrul.
The Templars brought
Shahzade Yigit to El Aziz themselves.
Do you know why?
Because they wanted
him to marry Halime Sultan.
How do you know all that stuff?
Halime Sultan demanded
her brother for dowry from El Aziz.
So the Templars sent him.
That was what we wanted to prevent.
If we had managed to take the Shahzade...
...we could have prevented this marriage.
Unfortunately,
the situation is such, Ertugrul.
What is your interest in this matter?
We are on the same side, see it!
You ruined the trap we set
to spoil the Templars' game!
El Aziz met Halime just because of you
and now he is going to marry her!
Nasir's only concern was to get
Sultan Aleaddin and Ayyubids in a war.
Thanks to you, that is also accomplished!
You have spoiled not only
my game, but also Sultan Aleaddin's.
So?
Let us...
...liaise together to save
your nomad tent and the state...
...from this danger.
That is her lying down there, Eftelya!
Nasir.
Ertugrul...
...will do anything he can
to prevent Halime from marrying.
Keep your eyes open, Nasir!
Love will be his biggest weakness, Titus.
I have nothing to talk with a man
who has my Alps' blood on his hands.
Ertugrul.
They burned the dargah down.
They killed tens of dervishes.
The army will be
heading to your nomad tent...
...together with
Nasir's commander Gunhan Bey.
They will burn your nomad tent down.
Will you just sit back and watch?
Reaching the destination is impossible
by giving up the right way, Afsin Bey.
You have lost your way,
just like this bastard.
If you also ever dare to appear before me
again, I will walk over both of you.
What are we going to do now, Kara Toygar?
What we need to do.
Gundogdu is a smart man.
We shall not lose contact with him.
KAYI NOMAD GROUP
My fellow Templars.
I hope you welcome me
to your temple with open arms.
You have a nomad tent,
but your homeland is uncertain.
I have four sons...
...but I know not
if they are dead or alive.
For how much longer, Bey?
For how much longer?
Dundar is my youngest
pride and joy, Hayme.
If he is not defeated in this bed,
the battlefields shall be afraid of him.
Our other sons will return to
the nomad tent healthy and strong.
You do not need to worry about it.
You stand tall.
Stand tall so that the nomad
group's peace shall not breach.
The nomad group needs you.
Giddy up!
The mirror that shows my reflection...
...show me my man, Ertugrul.
...so the fire inside me shall be put out.
Reflect how I am to Ertugrul... ..
...so he shall rescue me
from this dungeon.
What if Kara Toygar told the truth?
Kara Toygar has only changed his body.
His soul remains the same.
I do not think that
Sultan Aleaddin is trusting him.
So what is he after then?
We will see.
But first we must capture Nasir.
That is the only solution.
El Aziz must have already reached
the nomad tent with his army.
We need to find a way to figure
it out as soon as possible.
The nanny has changed her side.
I am meeting with her today.
We shall decide on what to do after that.
Ertugrul, you can not
go to Aleppo by yourself.
If I am not back till night, you go
back to the nomad tent, brother.
Do not leave my father alone.
We have no other option left.
Dear God, I beg you
with all my existence...
...give strength to Ertugrul.
Grant us a faithful marriage.
You own endless possibilities.
Grant us the blessed ones, oh God!
Dear God.
Give patience to Halime,
give strength, oh God!
Ertugrul burned Esma alive when
he realised his lies would be exposed.
I tried to conceal it
so that you would not be sorry but...
Your Highness The Ameer.
What did the nanny tell you?
What could she tell?
Ertugrul's lies, excuses.
It is now out in the open
what sort of scoundrel he is.
Murderer!
Poor Esma.
How could he kill you?
And by burning, huh?
Unfortunately, sir.
Oh, God!
But, her last words were about you.
The name “El Aziz” echoed in the streets
of Aleppo in the darkness of the night.
What about the dervishes?
How could you kill those dervishes?
My city's dervishes!
Have you gone out of your mind, Nasir?
Sir, They want to deviate from
the sharia law and overthrow you.
For God's sake, Nasir!
We have had enough of those
mystic sufis' harm to Islam, sir
Those raving dervishes stood against us...
...because of
your kindness towards Halebi.
While we were looking
everywhere to find those Turkmens...
...they dwelled in the Halebi's dargah!
Your Highness The Ameer.
I am afraid this matter
will lead us to Ibn'ul Arabi.
Beware!
If you ever mess this job up...
...you will be replaced with someone else!
Get this into your head, Nasir!
You are excused!
Your brother fell in love with Halime.
Only his love can save my brother
from the debauchery he engaged in...
...and the treacheries around him.
Halime will love your brother, she should!
She has to!
We shall not overshadow
your brother's happiness.
We must let him marry Halime and be happy.
So they are resisting
to surrender, aren't they?
Then, the army shall not wait
any longer, Commander Gunhan.
I can never accept the existence
of an occupant force on my land.
Go and get this job done!
As I feel thankful to God when
the morning sun fills my room...
...when I see you, I feel as much thankful
for granting me this light as yourself...
...to this worthless servant as myself.
Welcome, the Sultan of my heart!
Seeing you in the early morning
hours is worth everything.
You have asked me
what I wanted as a wedding gift.
Order me, I shall bring
the world at your feet.
Halime Sultan, you order me,
I shall prostrate myself before you.
I want you to forgive the Kayis,
Your Highness The Ameer.
My sister will never love you.
She is in love with somebody else.
With my brother Ertugrul.
Why do you want this from me?
We owe so much to them.
Any harm you do to them would hurt me.
And it is not possible for them
to immigrate in the winter time.
At least allow them to stay till spring.
All right.
As you wish, Halime Sultan.
I would rather get hurt
a thousand times than hurt you.
Also I do not wish
to shed any Muslim blood.
I would rather have my own blood
overflowed on the streets of Aleppo...
...than shed any innocent
women's and children's blood.
I will show the necessary
clemency as much as I can to them.
I am grateful to you,
Your Highness The Ameer.
Tomorrow...
...I will take you to the hunting
lodge after the wedding.
It is a family tradition.
The men of the dynasty take their wives
to the hunting lodge to get some rest.
We would be alone together
and get to know each other better.
Excuse me, Your Highness The Ameer.
Halime Sultan!
You haven't replied to me.
However you desire,
Your Highness The Ameer.
What is it, dervish?
You are lost in thought constantly.
Which ocean are you sailing across?
Dream of which place came to your mind?
Not at all, sir
I am just a weak-minded,
unimaginative dervish.
But the grievances of the
Muslim engage my mind.
I am thinking about
the situation the Muslim world is in.
We are surrounded with enemies
and to make matters worse...
...Muslims clash within each other.
Siblings ambush each other, they betray.
They surrender their brothers to the
tyrants for the ephemeral world.
I deeply resent these kind of things, sir.
Whenever our prophet comes to my mind,
I feel ashamed of how we are.
The earthly affairs have always
been such since our father Adam, son.
There is no reason for hopelessness.
Avarice and selfism
caused Cain to kill his brother.
All the clashes
and the fight in the world...
...started with
one brother's blood being shed
Whatever the reason,
any person who sheds blood is Cain.
A person who kills anybody,
kills his own brother actually.
One of your brothers may be God's friend
while the other one is a murderer.
If you pay attention
to Abel rather than Cain...
...you would be the Joseph
who came out of the well.
Done.
Your letters are very successful
and convincing, Shahzade.
It is obvious..
...that you will get support from
the leaders of the Muslim world...
...as well as the infidel world.
I will be glad to announce
that you are a candidate for the throne...
...when I meet
with the Turkmen Beys tomorrow.
I will get you in touch with the Beys who
are eager to collaborate, Shahzade.
Please wait for my report.
Excuse me.
How can you do this, father?
How can you endanger the state
my grandfathers have established?
How can you trample the
holy memory of my ancestor Seljuk...
...our grandfather Alp Arslan,
Malik-Shah down like this?
Halime.
I am doing what is necessary, my daughter.
I cannot even recognise you any more.
Even that little child understood what
sort of betrayal you are involved in.
But you still do not understand it.
Betrayal?
Betrayal, huh?
You stand there and tell me
I am involved in betrayal unblushingly!
You talk as if
you do not know how I struggled...
...for our survival for many years!
How many times did they
attempt to kill your brother and me.
You were here with us.
Now as you have forgotten everything, how
dare you call me to account unashamedly?
Enough already! Understand?
I have had enough of living
with the fear of you getting killed!
From now on, I am going
to take what I deserve...
...or perish trying!
At least, I will not
run away like a coward.
I will regain my right over the throne!
I saw how...
...you behaved heroically
while we were escaping...
...from the murderers after us
or the states trying to use you.
You fought against every
difficulty to save our state and us.
And now?
In fact, you are acting
like a piteous coward now!
You are fluttering
desperately like a poor bird...
...trapped by the people
trying to use you.
What does it matter now...
...if you stood before me
and roared like a lion?
Shame on you, father.
Shame on you.
Sir, I considered Jerusalem.
I considered other Muslim countries.
Everybody is claiming rights
on these holy lands.
The Christians fight over Jerusalem,
the Jews say “It is ours”.
Everybody is claiming rights,
everybody say it is theirs, sir.
Yes, son.
People's delusions are never ending.
God will let his righteous
servants inherit the earth.
It is the God's promise.
Do not be sad,
faith is the reason of hope.
Everyone may see
themselves worthy of something.
The people who will inherit
the earth are the ones...
...whose aim is to protect
lives even in the war.
Whoever is able to control
his desires during his challenge...
...will be the caretaker of the premises.
Whoever is
more equitable, more merciful...
...will inherit that holy place.
Wherever may the
tyrants name be written on...
...they are doomed
to be erased as black writings.
But the name of Joseph
is written on God's sign.
From there it flourishes
in the humanity's heart.
If God permits, sir.
Come on, we have a long way to go.
We have rested enough.
It is time to hit the road.
-All right!
-We missed Aleppo.
We see Aleppo as our homeland.
The love for the homeland
is a requirement of faith.
Most probably, Aleaddin's soldiers
would come from this line.
Shahzade, come in.
You look sad and anguished.
If you tell me what the matter is,
perhaps I may do something about it.
If my father gets what he deserves
and becomes the sultan...
...it will be thanks to you.
I will be his only successor.
Of course, Shahzade.
So, why am I not alongside
the Turkmens who are supporting us?
Why are these hidden from me?
Tomorrow I will take you to the meeting
in the Selahattin Caravanserai myself.
But the Turkmens need to be
convinced first to support you father.
That means Shahzade,
you need to be patient.
If you want to be a great Sultan,
you will learn to be patient first.
I have news, you need
to inform brother Ertugrul. Now!
What news, Shahzade, tell me?
Nasir is planning to start
a new war by using the Turkmens.
He will be hosting them
in Selahattin Caravanserai.
Good morning Selcan Hatun!
Men in the trenches, women at work, eh?
But you would rather not work
this hard as you are pregnant.
You should put on
some weight Selcan Hatun.
You need to have some milk for your baby.
You should be more interested
in the army that is about to fall on us...
...rather than my baby.
If El Aziz attacks with his army, neither
my baby nor my nomad tent will survive.
I have brought you so much
gossip and news from the marquee...
...for you to be a good wolf and get this
job done, but you could not accomplish it.
Because of Suleyman Shah's
improvidence and your incompetence...
...we will all be under trouble.
Abdurrahman!
Are the weapons ready, Wild Demir?
Thank goodness! They are ready Kurdoglu.
Sisters will distribute
them to their owners.
So, are your soldiers ready?
They are all tired.
How can you expect them to be lively!
You can either expect the soldiers
to kill or die unless you throw them...
...into the fire or get them
chilled to the marrow, Kurdoglu!
Oh holder of the earth
and the sky, oh God almighty.
Definitely every servant of yours
has something they wish for from you.
What I wish for is...
...that you protect our nomad tent
from the encroachment of our enemies...
...like you protected
the heroes in the Battle of Badr.
Make us victorious against
our enemies all the time.
Make the land that we came and that our
descendants will go, the land of peace.
Grant us your blessing
We seek refuge in you
and you alone we ask for help.
Amen.
They raided on the dargah
and killed the dervishes all.
If Sheikh Halebi hadn't gone to
Damascus, they would have killed him too.
That despicable Nasir
is so blinded with anger!
Oh God, protect us
from the infidels' wrath!
My brother is sitting on Nasir's tail...
...they are going to
subvert the state together.
And nobody sees this like we do.
I do not know what to do, Leyla.
Ertugrul is our only solution.
Oh God help us!
Hey, stop! Where to?
He is my helper, oh heroes!
Let him come.
Woe is me, woe! Poor me!
If His Highness The Malik
hears about this, he would kill me.
Be calm Efraim! Remember, you owe me.
My lady, you can take everything
I have but you shouldn't have done this.
What are you talking about Efraim?
You helped these lovers come together.
Can there be a better deed than this?
You can never know how much
I missed you, Commander.
You are a fearless warrior
but not a good lover.
-I...
-I was worried about you.
I was so scared that
something bad has happened to you.
I would have already
been dead if you didn't exist.
We learned something new.
Yigit brought us this information.
Is Shahzade Yigit fine?
He is very well.
But the things he said about
your brother Turgut were so worrying.
I know everything.
-What is the information you brought?
-Nasir.
He is going to meet with Oghuz tribes.
His intention is to gather
the Turkmens around Shahzade Numan...
...and make them rise against the Seljuks.
-Where will that meeting take place?
-In the Selahattin Caravanserai.
I must go there immediately.
This.
This is very dangerous Ertugrul Bey.
I must give this game away.
We have no other options.
Where is my uncle?
Do not worry.
He is in a safe place.
I will bring him safe and sound to you.
May God help you, son!
Hold tight!
Hold so tight that both the horse
and the rider shall be baffled.
Come on! Up, up!
First you have to hold it tight.
Hold it good!
Hold the bow first, then the arrow.
Aykiz, Turgut is alive.
I believe it with all my heart.
What keeps him alive is your love.
You should hold your ground
here so he can hold his there.
Ertugrul Bey has forgotten about
my Turgut long time ago Gokce.
It is all about Halime!
What are you talking about Aykiz?
Have you not seen, how he struggled to
save the nomad tent with Gundogdu Bey?
Have you not entered that bastards den,
shot arrows at their castle yourself?
You are saying these
just because you love Ertugrul bey.
And you do not know
what you are saying because of your pain.
Aykiz.
Ertugrul will save both
the nomad tent and Turgut.
Believe me.
For God's sake, Banukiz!
We are not in the rug workshop!
Hold the bow correctly,
you must draw it like this!
All right? Hold it good.
First you draw the bow
and then release it!
Come on, who is next?
Do you humiliate the rug workshop girls,
because your man is held by the infidels?
And you probably lost your mind completely
just because your husband left, Selcan.
Nobody is uttering any word to you
because you are pregnant, but not me.
And I am wondering what
sort of baby is that in your tummy.
.It is not getting any bigger or taller.
Sister! Don't do it, please
We are all nervous.
Stop mollifying, Gokce.
Don't you see! How dare
she talk to a Bey's wife like that!
It is time I took you down a peg or two!
Someone will take
you down a peg or two so good...
...that you will remember
where you came from.
Selcan!
Aykiz.
Bey, we haven't fought for a long time.
Who gets bored of fighting, Alpargo?
We killed or lost lives in vain
because of Suleyman Shah and Ertugrul.
And Gundogdu? He lost his way!
If we lose, the folks will flee,
the Kayi tribe will cease to exist.
I will fight at all costs, Alpargo.
I will try to stop this from
happening without hesitation.
Welcome Shah!
Draw your sword Kurdoglu!
We can feel the breath
of the enemy on our napes.
If we lose, our heads will beg
for mercy under the enemy's weapons.
Our pride...
...honor and dignity...
...will be at the enemy's weapons' mercy.
Now either you roar
like lions and get ready to fight...
...or not only shall you lose your
independence but also everything you have.
May God help us!
You are good Kurdoglu.
Your wrists are strong, God bless.
Thank you!
A commander from Aleppo
is coming to talk to you.
I shall meet him first,
with the soldiers of my army.
Let me confront him first.
Oh Atabey!
You have finally found your home!
I feel ashamed of myself for serving
under a man like you for years.
Not only me, but also my men.
Are you also fooled by Nasir's lies?
I only believe what I see, Atabey!
If you weren't a traitor,
you wouldn't be here now.
You would be in Aleppo leading the army.
Now stay out of my way, I shall
talk to Suleyman Shah for the last time.
Because from now on,
only the swords will do the talking!
Let them go by.
Suleyman Shah
is waiting for them in his tent.
Your weapon!
It is alright Abdurrahman, it is alright.
No need to fuss.
If I wanted to behead your Shah,
you would be unable to prevent it.
You carry your tents everywhere you go.
However this land is not going to allow
you any longer Suleyman Shah!
When are you going to stop immigrating
and find a homeland to feel at peace?
We left the peace to you
among the stone walls.
We left it to you so
that you could raise Cain...
...thinking you are here
to stay on this world.
Plant the seeds of arrogance!
Raise the icons of arrogance!
Suleyman Shah, I came here
to collapse the sky around you!
You disturbed our peace!
I came here to to make you pay for it!
We love paying for prices.
We also love thrusting our swords
in sky blue and taking them out red.
Your peace is going
to be disturbed many times.
Oldster.
I see that you are ready to be beheaded...
...but I have mercy for the young boys
and girls of the nomad group.
Now and for the last time...
...shall deliver His Highness
The Ameer's words, and you shall listen!
What is it Commander?
Firstly, His Highness The Ameer
does not want to shed any Muslim blood.
But he wants
his treacherous uncle and Ertugrul Bey.
And then, you to unite under
his flag against Sultan Aleaddin...
...like the other nomad Turkmens.
And if you agree with that, you will
get a share of the gold of Aleppo.
Learn the conversation
manners first, Commander!
I, who you call an oldster, beheaded
so many commanders like you!
And I do not hesitate
to do it again if necessary!
Off you go now!
Tell El Aziz that Suleyman Shah
would never give him anything.
Suleyman Shah would give his life
for Sultan Aleaddin if he ordered...
...but wouldn't
even give a dime for El Aziz.
He would pave the gold of Aleppo...
...on the muddy roads of the
nomad tent instead of stones.
Off you go now!
It will be a pity!
Suleyman, I will behead you
with my bare hands!
Commander.
Only God will decide our fate
when we meet in the battlefield!
Off you go!
What are we going to do now, Bey?
We will for Ertugrul
and Gundogdu to be back.
We will be patient...
...till my sons tear down the dark curtain
of hypocrisy in El Aziz's eyes.
This is our sole remedy.
Bloody woman!
Say it now.
Say it, don't keep it within!
Go your way, Selcan.
Do not glower at me with your baby.
You were just twaddling
about my baby. What happened now?
Why have your tail between
your legs when you are faced with me?
Selcan, I said go.
Or this won't end good.
This won't end good, eh?
What will you do
so it is going to end bad?
Say it now.
Say who is going to take me
down a peg or two? Huh?
Say it, where have I come from
and who is going to remind me? Huh?
Say it I say! Say it, you coward!
It is easy to talk
behind me like a cheap whore.
Come on, say it to my face now!
Who will remind me where I come from?
Or are you talking about the collaboration
between your father and Suleyman Shah...
...to murder my father? Say!
If you ever dare
to hit me again, I will...
What will you do, huh?
What will you do to me, huh?
Selcan!
Selcan are you fine?
Begone! Begone I say!
Oh God, what have I done?
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
THE TEMPLAR'S CASTLE
We must learn
all the tricks of this trade.
I do not think so.
The Muslims call it “the strength
of faith”, my dear uncle.
We will also deprive them of their faith.
We will do it like how we stripped
Turgut off his Alp uniform...
...and made him wear
the knight uniform instead of it.
Kurdoglu!
There are so many infidels among
them ready to sell their faith off.
Well done, Judas!
Let's go, Judas.
You should get some rest.
No fire can burn the soul of a man
like the fire of youth, Petruccio.
Do you understand what I mean?
Numan invited the Turkmens
to encourage them to revolt.
It was obvious that
it was going to be like this.
Where is this invitation to?
We do not know it yet.
So Shahzade Numan
agreed to collaborate with Nasir, eh?
Aleaddin would not hesitate
to hit the road to Aleppo...
...with his army when he hears about this.
Too much blood will be shed, Afsin.
This will stand the Crusaders
at most in the good stead.
Do not forget about the Mongols either.
Suleyman Shah, I am ready to give my life.
Too many people shall not die.
A guest who took shelter can not be given
to the enemy in Oghuz customs, Atabey.
The arrow is already off the bow.
It is going to hit
either their hearts or ours.
Their army is massive, Bey.
We must certainly find a way.
The less may defeat the many,
don't you know Kurdoglu?
I know, Bey.
If you know it, your mind and
your wrists should work for the fight...
instead of praising
the puissance of the enemy.
You said you had
your men in the army, Atabey.
Even the commander who
I trusted the most thinks I am a traitor.
I would like to get out of
the nomad tent and observe the army, Bey.
I want to know how many people
are there, where did they locate...
...what they are doing.
We should know these
in order to react accordingly.
Take the Alps you trust the most with you.
Bey, if you permit me, I would
like to go there alone in disguise.
She killed my baby!
Died, my baby died!
Aykiz, Aykiz!
She is the murderer
of my baby! Murderer!
You killed my baby.
Where is the murderer of my baby?
I am going to kill you!
She killed my baby!
She did kill my baby! Where are you,
you murderer of my baby?
-Sister!
-Aykiz!
You killed my baby!
As you have done this to me, I hope
you suffer a thousand times worse.
-I am going to kill you!
-Sister!
Damn you!
You killed my baby, I hope
you suffer a thousand times worse.
May the curse be with you!
You bloody woman!
Damn you, you killed my baby!
Aykiz, you go to the tent.
She killed him.
You all saw, didn't you?
She killed my baby!
She killed the son of a Bey!
She did it! Murderer!
-Be calm!
-All right, come, hush hush!
The devil would say
"What am I to do," if he saw you!
She did it again, bitch!
Mother Hayme!
Bey, Bey!
Gokce, what happened?
My sister, sister...
What happened to your sister, Gokce?
Her baby...
That Kurdoglu I mentioned about earlier...
...has sent a message
with one of the pigeons...
...that Ertugrul has taken away from us.
He wants to meet me.
That is very good, Petruccio
That means you are going
to reap what you sow.
Well, has that Nasir besieged
the nomad tent with his army?
Yes.
That job will be done soon.
And then?
Everything is for Jerusalem,
isn't it Thomas?
The name I am going to take
when I become the pope...
...came to my mind when you said Thomas.
You have an idea?
I am thinking “Leo”, dear Petruccio.
In which order the Leo will you be?
Leo the Tenth.
Well, why Leo?
He was the holy man who stopped Attila
the Hunnic emperor in front of Europe.
I chose this name for his holy memory.
The Pope Leo the Tenth!
Let's celebrate this
awesome idea of yours! Wine?
Please.
Well, should I take the name
Dionysus the God of wine?
Dionysus the First!
Suleyman Shah...
...how could I kill that
innocent baby knowingly?
Do not you think I fear God?
Selcan does not know what
she is saying because of her pain.
Selcan.
Aykiz says that
she did not do it knowingly.
In that case retaliation can not be made.
But she will be given another
punishment upon your decision.
No punishment I decide would relieve
the pain of losing my baby, father.
That is why I want her..
...to be whipped.
As I will remember my baby
whenever I see her...
...she should remember what she has done
to me every time she touches her back.
Tomorrow you will be...
...whipped 30 times
in the nomad tent square.
Do you have anything to say?
I bought it for my niece.
I wanted his first gift
to be from his uncle.
My brother! If God permits,
we will see your children also.
If God permits.
-Any news, Bey?
-Yes.
The Turkmen tribes
are going to unite around Numan...
...and start a war against the Seljuks.
So, Kara Toygar was right.
If Shahzade Numan
was not deceived by Nasir's game...
...they would not have made
this invitation to the Turkmens.
That means, Numan is
a candidate for the Seljuk throne.
What are we going to do now, Bey?
We will go and prevent this war.
Whatever the cost,
we will get Numan out of there.
Thus, we will save
Aleppo and the nomad tent.
I hope this doesn't
end up like Eftelya's end.
Let's go.
Thanks to you, we managed
to rescue the little Shahzade.
And thus, no obstacles exist for me to
marry Halime Sultan, Ebu Hisham.
Conformingly, Your Highness The Ameer.
Would it be possible without
the discretion of God almighty?
Thanks.
But your decision to delay
Gunhan's attack the nomad tent...
...has not been a good one.
As you are aware,
nobody knows what tomorrow will bring.
I gave Kayis another chance.
And also you know that
I want to solve this matter...
...without shedding
any Muslim blood, Nasir
You are right, sir
-But...
-But?
You consult the matter
with the Turkmens, Nasir.
Tomorrow I am going to
marry Halime Sultan.
God bless.
Then we will go
to the hunting lodge together.
I am so tired, Ebu Hisham.
I want to work on my poems there.
When I am back we can consult
the matter about the Turkmens with you.
Aye, sir.
The millstone around your neck
is so massive, your excellency.
Anyone would be overwhelmed by it.
Not at all!
Selcan Hatun...
...may God bring you and
your children together in the afterlife.
Amen, Mother Fatma, amen.
Permission to come in, Selcan Hatun?
Come in, Kurdoglu.
I came to say I'm sorry for your loss.
Nobody knows the pain of losing a child
or a loved one better than me.
The Mongols killed my children and
my wife who was my heartfelt companion.
What I buried in soil were
not them, it was my heart.
From then on,
I have been running away from war.
I would never want a family suffer
the pain of losing a child.
So, you would never want a family suffer
the pain of loosing a child, Kurdoglu?
Who would want it?
I am an oldster with
one foot in the grave, Selcan Hatun.
I would like to give
my service for the last time.
Gundogdu should get what he deserves also.
In order to do that,
I will meet with the Templars.
If I can not get some support
against El Aziz from the Templars...
...I will kill Suleyman Shah,
Ertugrul and Sahabettin...
...with my bare hands.
Do not ever forget these words!
Excuse me.
You are the killer of my child Kurdoglu.
I will never forget that at heart.
Never.
Oh woe is me, father!
While I could not bear
the pain of Turgut...
...they say that I killed
the grandson of the Bey.
What have I done wrong
to stumble down the well of the unknown?
No need to whine, daughter.
Our words are about God.
The God that turned
Abraham's fire into a lake...
...will have mercy on your fire some day.
My dear daughter,
more beautiful than the moon.
These days will pass, they will.
Then you realise, you have become
a bride, those days will come.
Huh?
I will pray for my Han
For that, the black mountains
Shall not collapse
The tree of shadows shall not be cut
The beautiful river of blood
Shall not dry
The tip of your wings shall not break
Woe my sorrowful girl.
I know how it feels like to lose a child.
Do not worry.
May God make him your paraclete
in the afterlife, if God permits.
I have been...
...waiting to give
a child to my man for years.
What am I going to say to Gundogdu?
How am I going to say
that I lost my baby, mother?
Selcan, my beautiful bride.
Neither you nor Aykiz have fault in this.
This is the will of God.
You will see,
Gundogdu will say nothing about it.
That ignoble girl went so crazy.
So she killed my own baby
to get her Turgut back.
How could Aykiz do this
to the Bey's grandson?
How could she commit such a sin, oh girl?
Have mercy,
whipping is a severe punishment.
And also we shouldn't leave
Wild Demir in a difficult situation.
Show mercy, daughter, so to be shown.
What are you saying, mother?
Are you aware of the things you say?
I buried a descendant of yours in soil.
Instead of saying an eye for an eye,
are you expecting me to show mercy?
Woe, woe is me!
My Shahzade.
Yes, Your Highness The Ameer?
There was something I promised
Halime Sultan as a wedding gift.
I have come to say
that I have fulfilled it.
I have extended the time I gave to Kayis.
You are a noble-hearted
and benevolent person.
God bless you.
We will be off to the hunting
lodge after the wedding.
I have put two odalisques
under your order, Halime Sultan.
From now on, they will take care of you.
My sons, for whom I have always...
...prayed for to raise families...
...are stuck between
the claws of the grim reaper.
After my Sungurtekin whom
I have waited for to return for years...
...my Dundar, my Ertugrul,
my Gundogdu...
Who knows how they are now.
Whilst expecting
to hold my grandson in my arms...
...without feeling his smell
the black soil became his cradle.
What a sorrow this is, what a misery...
...what a pain, Bey!
The trouble and the compassion
both come from the God almighty
Holder of our sons are him also.
He takes their lives if he wishes.
It is our duty
to be patient for the trouble...
...and be thankful
for the compassion, Hayme.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Who is that?
He is from the Beydili Tribe
from Kayis, sir.
Suleyman Shah's brother in law Korkut Bey.
Peace be upon you, Korkut Bey
Welcome.
And peace be upon you.
They said it was a request from the Bey
who gave grasslands to the Oghuz...
...so we came.
It is very kind of you.
Welcome.
Please welcome.
Stay strong, daughter.
Here is the Harem corridor.
Halime Sultan's room is ahead.
I must go now.
All right, girls.
We shall leave the father
and the daughter alone.
May God grant you happiness, daughter.
May God grant you a long lasting marriage.
You did not give your daughter
away as a bride, father.
You buried your daughter
alive in this palace.
This belt I am wearing
on my bridal gown...
...shall be the belt of my burial gown.
You no longer have a brother.
Yigit!
I will take you out of here, my Shahzade.
Now, take me to your father.
Enough!
That’s enough, I said!
Take it, daughter.
Drink it, drink it, daughter.
I have obviously
cut you some slack, Selcan.
From now on, fear me.
No mercy for the merciless!
My Oghuz Beys, straight as a die!
We are very glad to have you here.
I have brought you the greetings and the
prayers of El Aziz, the Ameer of Aleppo.
Our magnate, who
welcomes you with open arms...
...despite all the hardships and the
opposition of the Bedouin tribes...
...expects you to be respectful,
convivial, and loyal all the time.
Thank you, Commander Nasir.
But the Bayats, the Dodurgas,
the Alkaevlis, the Dogers...
...and we, the Beydilis...
...are from the Bozok
branch of the Oghuz tribe.
We are the branches of a large family.
The big mountains are not enough for our
herds and we do not fit through them.
Although we are dispersed around,
we are one, thank God.
Excuse our curiosity...
...we would like
to know two things, immediately.
Why hasn’t His Highness The Ameer,
who invited so many Beys,
made it to the scene?
Why hasn't he honored his guests...
...even though he invited
so many Beys here on this cold winter day?
His Highness The Ameer couldn't leave
Aleppo because of a good cause.
He is getting married to Halime,
the daughter of the Seljuk Shahzade Numan.
You have become so beautiful!
Where is your father, the Shahzade?
He is out having important meetings to
subvert the Seljuk State Your Highness.
Yes, please.
Estagfurullah, Estagfurullah,
Estagfurullah, e'l-azim el-kerim.
La ilahe illallah Muhammeden resullulah.
The first issue we understand.
Not only is His Highness The Ameer
determined to play with fire...
...but also to enter the nuptial
chamber with fire, obviously.
Korkut Bey, so you say, whoever
is entering the nuptial chamber...
...should also be here to eat dinner.
Let's proceed with the second issue.
Why isn’t the worldly-wise Bey
of the Kayi Tribe, Suleyman Shah...
...here with us?
Moreover, we heard that you have
given them land right beside Aleppo.
Suleyman Shah is not with us because
not only has he not kept his promises...
...but he has collaborated
with the infidel Crusaders.
Liar!
Ertugrul!
I, Ertugrul, son of
Suleyman Shah from the Kayi Tribe!
This man is a dishonored scoundrel.
He is casting aspersions upon us!
His only aim...
...is to make way to the Crusaders by
making brothers fight among each other!
How did you get here?
From whom did you receive word?
Malik Aziz, son of Zahir, do you
take Halime, daughter of Numan...
...to be your wife?
-I do.
-Do you?
I do.
Halime, daughter of Numan, do you take
Malik Aziz, son of Malik Zahir...
...to be your husband, in return for the
two towns of Aleppo, the vineyards...
...and the souk of Aleppo as dowry?