episode 8 will start at : 11:22
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
What will we do, Bey?
Will we return?
We cannot turn back now, Wild Demir.
The tribe must have started the migration.
We should not worry them.
Rahman!
Yes, Bey?
Is there a place we can stay around here?
Have a look around.
Yahya! Come with me.
What will happen now, father?
Won't we go to Aleppo?
Do not worry, my son.
Your brother Ertugrul will
bring us the news sooner or later.
Then we will get to know
the truth about this issue.
What did we hope when we started
the journey and look what we found.
I am sure something happened to Turgut.
Do not say things like that, my girl.
Do not fuel your anxiety.
Brave women of Kayi...
...shall stand strong like a mountain...
...so that the brave men of Kayi
can roar like a mountain lion.
Mother Hayme is right, Aykiz.
If there was a problem,
Ertugrul would have surely found us.
I know that she is right as well.
But this time Turgut went
without even saying good bye.
That is why I feel anxious.
My brave girls.
Please be rest assured...
...they have overcome so many battles,
so many troubles.
Even if they are in trouble, even if they
are in distress, they will come back.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS TEMPLARS CASTLE
Aykiz. My Aykiz.
What are you doing here?
Turgut. My Turgut.
-Turgut.
-What are you doing here?
My Aykiz? What are you doing here?
My son! The voices you hear are not real!
Do not surrender to them and go.
Whoever you are hearing...
...is not in the dungeon with you now.
You have to resist the poison they gave.
How? How?
Hearts can only be satisfied
with reciting of God.
God is your friend and
the rest is in vain.
Run away from the lies they gave you
to take refuge in the truth.
What do I need to do?
Recite with me!
My Turgut.
Our journey is long.
Our destination shall bring us joy,
if God permits.
Come on, Hatun. You should smile.
Should our child see his mother frowning
when he is born?
That is it.
You will give birth to our child
in our new homeland.
-If God permits.
Aleppo will bring peace to us.
Vizier, do you have a last word?
Do not remember me as a traitor!
Whatever I did,
I did for the future of our people.
Quran is my guide and God is my witness!
My head is up!
My cause is God!
If I need to die for this cause...
...whether in sleep...
...or with an axe!
-Murderers!
-Liars!
Great God!
Stop them! Do not let Sahabettin run away!
Nasir, what is happening here?
Do not worry, your highness.
There are guards in every street.
They cannot run anywhere.
Catch him!
Don't let Sahabettin run away!
-Great God!
Up!
At last, Nasir.
We managed to come back to our home.
Your highness, we are talking about
the snakes who sneak up into...
...our warm and secure home.
We should never forget this.
Please stay away from the balcony.
Your highness...
...you saw today what a bowman can do.
God forbid, you might be
an open target in the balcony.
What is happening to our precious jewel...
...to our one and only Aleppo, Nasir?
Behind you!
Today people died right in front of me.
My uncle Sahabettin was kidnapped.
A group of rascals have caused havoc
in my city.
Who are the people
helping Ertugrul, Nasir?
Sahabettin's collaborators,
the remainders of the Crusaders.
The goons they hired. The tramps they fed.
Infidels who hid themselves
under a Muslim identity.
Today they united against you.
Find them and bring them here, Nasir.
I want to see them die in agony
with my own eyes.
Do not worry, your highness.
But you should still be careful.
Traitors have infiltrated everywhere.
Even if Sahabettin is one of them...
...you can comprehend the rest.
Even the least expected people
might be your enemy.
Thank God we meet again.
What happened, brother?
Nothing.
I was worried about you.
Are you fine, Leila?
I am. But...
...you do not seem so well.
You look pale.
Is there a problem?
I am just fine...
...my beautiful sister.
I am fine.
Who is she?
A wounded girl.
When the physician said
that she needs to be looked after...
...I could not turn my back.
I wanted to look after her.
With God's permission, when she recovers,
she can be friends with Leila.
You thought well, governess.
But this news surprised me.
It is known that my beautiful sister is
distant to all strangers for years.
I wish it was not like this
so that I would not make you sad.
Do not talk like that, my child.
Leila is trying hard to get better.
We should not remind her
of such anxieties.
You are right, governess.
With God's permission, this poor girl...
...should recover quickly.
She is very beautiful. God Bless.
God Bless. God Bless.
My Leila...
...rose of my heart.
It gives me great pleasure
to see you so ardent.
Where were you? You had me so worried.
Governess...
...they were really going to
execute my uncle.
But then...
...he showed up.
I am very grateful to you.
You jumped into a hell hole for me.
Do not worry, Bey.
Us Turkmens have a saying...
...you know it as well.
Those who are friends with cameleers
build their door accordingly.
We could not find Sahabettin and
the people who abducted him.
It is as if the world split apart
and they fell in.
At every street, at every corner
you shall have guards.
Give special importance to places like the
lodge or bookseller where he frequented.
And put extra watchmen
at the gates of the city.
They should not get out of Aleppo,
whatever the cost! Understood?
Is there any news about Afsin Bey?
Haven't you learned how Afsin Bey is, Bey?
We cannot hear from him
unless he wants us to.
He put on his shroud and infiltrated
into the heartland of the infidels.
We do not know whether he'd surface
in Frank territory or in a Persian city.
ANTIOCH CRUSADER COUNTSHIP
What do you want from God's door,
stranger?
I would like to cool down a bit
under the shadow of a pear tree.
Afsin Bey?
-Saltuk Kardes.
-It really is you.
Come on in.
Come on, tell us, Saltuk Kardes.
How do the days pass at the war zone?
How can they pass, Bey?
Amongst these icons, I recite
the Ali Imran surah to conserve my belief.
Fate loves the effort, Saltuk Kardes.
A day will come when the troubles
you went through becomes a blessing.
Did you bring me good news from Ahlat?
Did the time come for
the holy call of the great saddhu?
No, Saltuk Kardes,
the time has not come yet.
But you have to take on
a very important mission at the moment.
Just say it, Bey.
Your wish is my command.
They imprisoned some of our people in the
Templar castle at the Amanos Mountains.
I have to go in to see how they are.
There is a way.
It made you so handsome.
You look just like a prince.
Didn't you like your attire?
No, I liked it very much.
Are you thinking about your Turgut Agabey?
Only he can take me
to my father and sister.
Alright.
I will talk with my uncle for you.
He surely would know
where your Turgut Agabey is.
No, don't ask him.
They would put me in his cell as well.
Do you know where he is?
He is here. In the castle.
But they treat him very badly.
If Turgut Agabey wanted to,
he can beat all of the up.
-He is very strong but...
-But what?
But the knights tied down
his hands and feet.
Maybe your Turgut Agabey committed
a big crime and that's why he is there.
Never! Turgut Agabey did nothing else
but just protect me.
Did you see a man
who looked like a madman?
Do you mean the man
who went past before you?
He went that way.
I have to go upstairs, Bey.
We should not leave the shop empty.
Bad eyes should not get suspicious.
There is no news from my madmen,
can you ask your madmen?
Where they are, is there any news?
I saw the spark
in the eyes of your men, Bey.
They are probably still
beating up the guards outside.
You can be rest assured.
But I will still inquire about them.
It is obvious that the Templars'
only aim was not killing me in the palace.
What is behind the game
they are trying to play on you?
Their problem is not me. It is Aleppo.
When the Crusaders invaded Jerusalem,
this group called Templars came to life.
They tricked the Pope and
then all the Christians.
They made everyone accept that
they were the only guards of Jerusalem.
They collected gold and land
from thousands of people.
Then with greatness and permission of God,
Saladin Ayyubi conquered Jerusalem...
...and no one cared for them anymore.
So now, they are trying to regain
the reputation they had lost.
That is why they try to spread venom
and create chaos everywhere.
Let them play their game.
We always say “tyranny spoils the game.”
We shall first clear your name from
the slander you have been imposed to...
...then we will hit them
when they least expect it.
For the love of Jesus.
Look what happened when we thought
that we got rid of Sahabettin.
-Did you find a clue?
-No.
But I'm looking for them in every hole.
I will find him sooner or later.
I will find him and
the wild herders who saved him.
What about El Aziz? Was he terrified?
He was.
He ran away from the those killers
and hid in his room.
-But then...
-Then?
He is in a strange mood.
Don't neglect your visits to him.
Where is our Ertugrul Bey?
Under the ground.
Come with me.
Where were you, Dogan?
You know this bear, Bey. When he sees
a fight, he can't get enough of it.
You were not followed, right?
Can we be followed, Bey?
We also have a pair of eyes on our backs.
Bamsi speaks of the truth, Bey.
As he broke the arms, legs and heads
of the people who were to follow us...
You have an important job
tomorrow morning.
Nasir may do anything for revenge
because of the thrashing he took today.
Tomorrow, you gave to go to the lodge and
take the Shahzade and Halime out of there.
Who is she?
Where did she come from, governess?
She was a guest at the lodge.
I don't know what happened to her
but her wound was infected.
When the physician said that she should be
treated in the palace, I brought her here.
Yes but why did you bring her
to my room, governess?
She is a poor, little girl.
I hoped that she would be your friend.
Leila...
...if you are angry...
-Not at all!
But don't you know that
I don't like to be friends with anyone?
Let the poor girl come to herself first...
...if you still don't want her,
we can take her to another room.
Thank God you are fine. I was so worried
about you when I heard what happened.
If I came at a bad time...
...please, forgive me.
Those who hear my sighs
Should ask what this noise is
Those who are wise
Should say it is the sound of love
May my name be erased
El Aziz be unheard
Those who read our poems
Should say a passionate nightingale
Magnificent. The most beautiful poem
I have heard to this day.
Because the pretext was a feeling
that I had never experienced before.
I have grown miserable with my yearning
for you. When everyone goes to sleep...
No.
I will call for you when I am available.
I was succumbed by my feelings.
I didn't know my own place.
Please forgive me. With your permission.
My dear Esma.
Poor girl.
Bey? I found an inn on the way.
-Is it far away?
-Not very far, Bey.
We will spend the night at the inn.
We will think everything through
and make a decision.
You are very tired, Bey.
You know better but you should rest a bit.
Come on.
I am guessing that the little prince will
be more collaborative than his father.
I see the treasure inside
a person with just a look in the eye...
...and I never made a mistake about this,
my dear Petruccio.
It is great that he found
a friend inside the castle.
The more people he likes from us,
the easier our job will be.
The chests can stay here, Marcus.
Make sure that everything is ready
before the monks arrive.
They will be more trustful
when they see the gold.
-We wouldn't want to be embarrassed.
-As you wish, sir!
How are you, my beautiful niece?
I am fine, uncle.
I am hanging out with the most handsome
man of the castle, how can I be not fine?
How are you, your highness prince?
I am not a prince.
I am a Seljuk Shahzade.
You are right, my Shahzade. Our tongues
might slip like this once in a while.
Please accept my apologies.
Isadora.
You were a cute little girl
the last time I saw you.
But now...
...you have turned into
a very beautiful young woman.
A sparkling, magnificent transformation.
Unfortunately I could not remember you,
your highness Cardinal.
So, you have seen my before.
Beautiful Isadora.
The last time I saw you, you were holding
the hand of my dear friend Giovanni.
I will get rid of Sahabettin.
Then Ertugrul can be yours, Titus.
Wasn't that so?
Nasir?
I don't have time for this,
come to the point.
-Is there a new order from Ustad?
-Yes.
Ustad wants us to start the main attack.
When you run after the big glory...
...these small unfinished jobs
will hold you back.
If you are talking about
Sahabettin and Ertugrul...
...they cannot even peek out
from the hole they are in.
You know the witness you bought and made
them sing like a nightingale in court?
Do you think Ertugrul will not
try to reach them?
My men are in all the streets of Aleppo.
Even if his shadow comes out,
we'd be onto him immediately.
El Aziz is in our palm at the moment.
Even if all those witnesses
come together...
...his highness the Ameer
would still believe us.
After all, I am his only savior.
And Eftelya is his dear Esma.
Nasir, Nasir, Nasir.
When you speak like this...
...I am reminded of Karatoygar.
I hope your end won't be like his.
This is a place
where God's name is recited.
The dervishes think that
your manners are not befitting.
What do the dervishes think about
a traitor who collaborates with infidels?
His highness the Ameer believes
that his kidnappers are hiding in here.
Don't try to stop our search...
...then we will not use force.
Let them in.
If you are a God lover,
come in and have a place in our hearts...
...if you are a denier,
look from the door and turn back.
-Master...
-Talk, grandson of my master.
Commander Nasir came.
Some people saved
your dear son Sahabettin.
And our child called El Aziz has believed
the things whispered to his ear...
...and sent Nasir here.
-Is that so?
A boy in Andalucia, with his uncle...
...took some wheat to a non-Muslim miller.
They were to give 100 kilos of wheat
and take 90 kilos of flour in return.
And the miller was
a cheater on the scales.
He weighed 80 kilos and put it in a sack.
The uncle of the boy wanted
what was his right.
“What kind of a man are you?” he said.
They started arguing.
Then the argument turned into a fight.
The boy didn't know what to do.
The miller and his uncle were unstoppable.
The sacks got burst...
...and they were both covered
in flour from head to toe.
The boy went and took a piece of stick
and stood in front of them.
Which one is infidel,
which one is my uncle?
Which one is infidel...
God looks at His subjects from outside
and sees what is in their heart.
There are so many who are Muslim from
the outside by infidel inside...
...or infidel from the outside
and Muslim within.
Just like our Great God states
in the Bakarah surah.
Those are the ones who have purchased
error in exchange for guidance...
...so their transaction has brought
no profit, nor were they guided.
Ertugrul Bey was right.
This guy called Nasir is like a rabid dog.
We need to take Halime Baci
and the Shahzade out of here.
That would be the best for them
and for the people in the lodge.
Peace be upon you.
May it be easy on you, Gundogdu.
Do not tire Selcan Hatun too much.
She carries two lives...
...and the voyage is hard as it is.
Is it your job to think about our baby?
Of course, we think about our nephew.
Our blood will flow in the future
generations thanks to Gundogdu.
I may not see our nephew become a Bey,
as I am an old man but...
What kind of a game
are you playing now, Kurdoglu?
My dear son...
...I don't know how
you came to despise me so much.
Yes, I did say some words to you as well,
while my blood brother was ill...
...for the unity and future of our tribe.
I even resented some of your words and...
...replied in an unbefitting way.
But you know that I love you more than
I love your brother.
It is your turn to become
the Bey of the tribe.
I want this from the bottom of my heart.
I am putting everything that happened...
...in the past and say that
it was due to your youth.
Here you are.
This honey is very valuable.
Our girl Selcan should eat and be strong.
May it make our nephew powerful.
Thank you, uncle.
Kurdoglu is such a twofaced man!
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Our daughter Halime is in good hands
at the palace now, Numan Efendi.
It is time to pray
for her to get better as soon as she can.
You are right.
But...
...when the palace is
in turmoil like this...
...leaving her and coming here
is not easy.
This is the first time we are separated,
maybe since her birth.
That is not the only problem.
Yigit.
God who has put a distance
between you today...
...will of course bring you together,
when the time comes. Do not worry.
If you accept...
...I would like to go to the palace
and give your name at the door...
...to ask permission from your sister
to see my daughter.
Of course.
Your highness...
...the famous trader I told you about,
Abu Hisam awaits to be accepted by you.
Tell him to come in.
Is what Nasir told me true, Abu Hisam?
Do you want to undertake all our trade
in the Mediterranean region for us?
Yes, your highness, I do.
Why should I give you such a privilege?
Make me responsible for all
the sellable goods of Emirate of Aleppo...
...all its commercial ships
and caravans...
...so that I can double
the income of your treasury.
That is my promise, your highness.
What do you say, Nasir?
Can we trust Abu Hisam?
Of course, your highness. He is one of
the most honest people of this world.
I trust the person who you trust, Nasir.
Then, all the veins of commerce
in Aleppo...
...is in your hands from now on,
Abu Hisam.
Where is the Shahzade?
Where is Halime, Dogan?
You were right, Bey.
Nasir came with a platoon
to look for us in the lodge.
Nasir came out of the lodge empty handed
as well as us.
What are you saying, Dogan. Speak clearly.
Do you mean that Halime and
her father ran away?
No, Bey. But...
...while we were away,
the wound of Halime Baci got worse.
The people in the lodge found a contact
from the palace and brought the physician.
Come to the point.
Bey...
...Halime Sultan...
...is in the palace.
You can be rest assured. You can visit her
anytime you wish, Numan Efendi.
Do not worry about her state. Our girl
Halime should get up in a few days.
Ummulhayr Hanim,
I am very grateful to you.
Our Halime's father, Numan Efendi.
Is that so? This is a great honor.
I came...
...to inquire the health of our guest...
...and to visit my beautiful sister.
Do not worry.
Our guest is looked after really well.
I am hosting her personally in my room.
What more can I do?
My beautiful and peevish Leila.
What can I do to see you smile once?
You can tell me the fate of my uncle,
your highness.
If you have the time...
...I'd like the honor to
converse with you.
I feel bad that you walk all through
Aleppo to visit your daughter.
Should I assign a room in the palace
for your personal use?
Then your daughter Halime can find
her father by her side anytime...
-...she wants during her recovery.
-Do not trouble yourself, your highness.
What trouble? Not at all.
Shahzade. It is me, Shahzade.
At the lodge they told us that
you went to the palace.
I was very worried about you.
We are fine. Do not worry.
How are you?
What is Halime's condition?
She is still unconscious.
Shahzade, you must know that the
conspiracies within the palace are...
...much more dangerous than
the physical wounds of Halime.
How did you throw her inside
such a ring of fire?
You are right, Ertugrul. But...
...Halime's situation was very critical.
And just a while ago,
I talked with El Aziz.
They are taking very good care of her
for her to recover.
I think...
...it is best that she stays
there for some time.
El Aziz is nothing but a headquarters
in the hands of evil people.
You might be throwing yourself
and Halime into an unknown.
I wouldn't even want to think about
what they could do to you...
...if they learn your real identity.
That palace is a dangerous snake's nest.
You have to get Halime and
yourself out from there. Believe me.
I do believe you, Ertugrul.
Tomorrow, I will elude El Aziz somehow
and solve this matter.
What about you? What will you do?
Do not worry about us, Shahzade.
All the Gordian knots shall be
untied very soon.
There is someone
who has captivated the mind of El Aziz.
She is staying in El Aziz's sister,
Leila's room. Her name is Halime.
I don't know where she came from
or who she is but I am sure that...
...El Aziz is visiting her sister
just to see this girl.
Are you sure, Eftelya?
I told you that I saw it with my own eyes.
El Aziz and the girl's father
came out of Leila's room together.
He offer the man a room in the palace.
Do not neglect to follow him. You should
breath on El Aziz's neck at all times.
We need him to be in the palm of our hands
more than ever now.
More than ever?
Are you trying to tell me something?
We need to silence the false witnesses
at the vizier's trial.
You deal with Sahabettin's old guard in
the palace tonight.
We will deal with the rest.
You can say that the guards are silenced.
First I have to go and save El Aziz
from drowning in the open seas.
Are you looking for me?
Can you stop for a moment?
-Is the food for Leila Sultan?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Give it to me. I shall take it.
-As you wish. Here you are.
Do you have anything on your mind
as the first step, my vizier?
The only thing I know is that I have to
clear my name and I have to do this...
...in front of El Aziz.
I have a plan in my mind, vizier.
You mentioned about some witnesses
who made false claims about you.
If we can catch them and make them talk
about the people who forced them...
You are so smart, Ertugrul.
We will be the ones who will spoil
their game, the Alps of Kayi tribe.
We will first save Vizier Sahabettin
first, then the homeland of our tribe.
Your hand reaches to
all parts of Aleppo, Aykutluk.
Right.
Can you also reach inside the palace?
There are a few madmen
who can infiltrate, Bey.
I didn't mean that, Aykutluk.
Can you take us inside?
It would have been easier if you asked
the whole of Aleppo from me, Bey.
-It is difficult. Very difficult.
-Difficult...
...but not impossible, is that so?
Yes, Bey. That is so.
May it be easy, Governess Ummulhayr.
Who is this sick girl?
A guest of God, my girl.
From which family is she?
I have never seen her before.
Son of God was covered in blood.
The crown made of thorns was more valuable
to him than the golden Roman crown.
Even while he was being crucified,
even at that time, he was saying that...
...he was sacrificing his body and blood
for the sins of all believers.
When you reach those lands and kneel
before the memories of the Messiah...
...you shall pray to save our sacred
Jerusalem invaded by the infidel Muslims!
And we shall be praying here to
find the opportunity to sacrifice...
...our body and blood,
just like The Messiah.
His highness Cardinal Thomas.
He came from the presence our holy father,
the Pope to our humble and...
...distant castle
to honor his Templar brothers.
I would like to introduce you to
Father Daniel, your highness cardinal.
His passionate sermons enabled
many sinners to turn to The Messiah.
The power of words is more important
than anything else.
Just like our Holy Book says...
...first there was the word.
Please, sir, you are embarrassing me.
At your presence, all we can do is
to fall silent. Would you like to say...
...a few words to these believers who are
on the road for the sacred pilgrimage?
You are all blessed souls
as you have chosen this holy path.
Welcome.
I thought you would not come.
Aren't you happy to see me?
How can I be not happy?
Why did you call me here?
Why do you think I called for you?
There is something I hope for...
...but you wouldn't prefer us.
We are not the Ameer of Aleppo.
How do you know this?
Didn't you think Sahabettin would track
who went in and out of his nephew's room?
Did Sahabettin know as well?
No.
I know when and what to say to whom.
You must have seen that
during the vizier's trial.
Well done. I like smart men.
At least, they deserve a quick death.
Please allow me, my sons,
to give the sinner inside...
...a part of Jesus's compassion,
who was God's lamb.
The healing breath of The Messiah,
which cured many wounds...
...should touch the souls of those
who suffer.
Ustad's direct orders state that no one
from outside shall enter the dungeon.
I am not an outsider, my son.
Aren't we all moths
who fly around the same light?
Wouldn't you like that light
to fall into this dark dungeon as well?
Let me in, my son.
Please stay and converse
with our guests, cardinal.
My dear friend, Petruccio, as you will be
leaving this nice conversation behind...
...I really wonder where
you shall be going.
I have a small duty to fulfill.
We shall continue from
where we left off when I return.
-Where are we going, sir?
-The dungeon. We are going to the dungeon.
My dear poor and suffering sinner.
From His kingdom up in the skies...
...from our Father in heaven...
...I bring you rejoicing news.
Go down your own way, monk.
Open your shop somewhere else.
I wouldn't come near your stands.
If you come close to those who follow
the path of God...
...you would not regret it, my son.
Afsin Bey.
-What are you doing here?
-It's not the time to talk, Turgut.
You are in great pain, I know.
We will get you out of here
as soon as possible.
May God forgive you, my son.
What is happening?
What are you thinking so deeply?
We did not want our Bey to notice...
...but being turned back from the doors
of Aleppo pierced our hearts, Wild Demir.
All the troubles Kayi is going through
does not look like a blessing to us.
That is why the Alps are depressed.
You unwary people,
you may not trust yourselves...
...you may not trust our Bey,
our Suleyman Shah...
...don't you know what being an Alp means?
Would an Alp be intimidated?
Don't lower your heads.
Look up.
Now all of you gather around me now.
Our stories are not
for the children all the time.
This time they are granted
to big men like you!
I shall tell you the story of
Master of the Alps...
...bravest of all braves,
his holiness Ali's story.
Once upon a time, there was
a fortress called Hyber.
Our great Prophet, peace be upon him,
lived in Medina, near this fortress.
The commanders of that fortress
were people with a dark soul...
...siding with the evil.
They did not believe our Prophet
and had a grudge against the believers.
As if that was not enough...
...they even dared to fight
against the Muslims...
...in the Battle of Khandaq.
-The lowlifes.
As time passed...
...the battles ended...
...and peace was sustained.
Our Prophet...
...wanted to conquer
the lands of these dark souls...
...who stabbed the Muslims from the back.
The warriors who grabbed the black flag of
Mohammed, who's a good name and person...
...gathered in front of the
fortress' gate.
But the fortress was on
a steep and impassible hill.
Its walls were impenetrable.
They tried once again, once again...
...but no. They could not succeed.
They lowered their heads,
rolled up the black flag of Mohammed...
...and went back to our Prophet.
When our Prophet saw the believers
who had lowered their heads in despair...
...He said, “this flag shall be
given to its rightful owner.
Then the conquest would be inevitable.
That owner would never back down from
a fight, never lose hope from God!”
He called the owner of the flag to
His presence.
Who did He call, Master Demir?
The one who swings his sword
with God's name on his tongue...
...the master of the Alps,
His Holiness Ali.
Ali came to His presence and
our Prophet ordered...
...“go and take Hyber, Ali!”
The horse's feet are fast,
the poet's tongue is cast.
To cut the long story short...
...God's Lion went onto Hyber!
He did not hesitate from those great walls
nor from the infidel soldiers who...
...breathed fire like man dragons!
He reached the gate of the fortress!
He took refuge in God and
barged so hard with his shoulder that...
...the gate which armies couldn't demolish
came down like rotted tree trunk...
...and fell down in front of him.
They took the city.
And they raised the black flag on
the highest tower of the fortress.
Thus, it is God who did not open
the gates of Aleppo to us...
...it's God who opened the gate of Hyber
to Ali when armies couldn't bring it down.
Alp is such a man that when he loses
a fight, he should not feel sorry...
...when he wins a fight,
he should not brag.
He should know that his responsibility
is not victory but the campaign itself.
He should always take refuge in God
and never refrain from trying.
Only then, those who carry
the title of Alp will see that...
...the gates of cities, fortresses
and hearts shall be opened to him.
Let it be known like that, Alps!
Let it be known.
Your witness, your old guard...
...our madmen found him in a state where
he won't be able to lie anymore.
Nasir.
We have to act fast and
reach the other witnesses before them.
Come on, get up, Alps of Kayi.
That Jewish trader. I can find him in
the hole he's hiding in, no matter what.
You can go and check the old barkeep.
Come on.
Everyone in Aleppo is looking for you
at the moment.
It is better for you to stay here.
In the name of God.
At this time of the night.
I bring you news from Master Nasir.
I told him before...
...if you open the tavern that was closed,
it is sufficient for me.
My only expectation was to revenge the
closing of my tavern, my only income...
...from that enemy of fun
called Sahabettin.
When you take into account the risk
I faced, I do not thing that asking for...
...my tavern to be
reopened is a big reward.
Master Nasir's news to you is not
about your reward but about your death.
Let's pray that Aykutluk
can reach the other witness in time.
Titus, did you know that our dear friend
signed a will stating that...
...all his wealth shall be donated
to the Templars after his death?
Maybe that is our friend's
way of repentance to crucifixion of Jesus.
When we think about 1200 years of
compound interest as well...
...the price he pays is acceptable.
-What did you do? Did you finish him?
-Yes, sir, but...
...after I killed the barkeep
and went out...
...those Turkmens, Ertugrul and
his men went in.
-Did they see you?
-No, sir.
I ran all the way here without being seen.
I thought that I should inform you...
...as quickly as possible.
-Good.
Now, form a platoon from your best
and most reliable men.
Take this body as well
and wait at his shop.
Then come and find me again.
When Ertugrul comes, we should be prepared
for a very warm welcome.
Yes, sir.
Titus, let us go.
We have more enjoyable tasks for tonight.
We failed. We couldn't reach in time.
We could not catch
any of the three witnesses.
What will we do now?
There is a blessing in what
we see as evil...
...and evil in what we see as a blessing.
It is better for them to think
that they have won.
Let them be complacent for now.
Did you manage to arrange
our entrance to the palace, Aykutluk?
I did, Bey.
But it is very dangerous.
It's no different from
embracing a monster.
We shall set on this road,
knowing all its consequences.
There is no other way.
If everyone fulfills their own task...
...there will not be a problem. Trust me.
Yigit.
Ertugrul save Yigit.
What is she saying, governess?
Who is she talking about?
She was saying the same name
while we were bringing her here.
It is not very understandable but...
...she wants someone to save Yigit.
May God help her.
With God's permission,
she and her loved ones should find peace.
Dogan brother...
...we left our Bey all alone.
I feel really bad.
If we left him alone in the fog or
in a desert, I wouldn't feel this bad.
I hate this city.
There is poison in every single hole.
Our Bey can take care of himself,
Bamsi brother.
If you want to worry about something,
our tribe must have started the migration.
Worry about where we will show
them as our homeland.
Our Turgut brother is a prisoner
of the infidels, worry about him.
Worry about how we will
explain this to Aykiz.
What are we going to do?
I cannot tell her.
I cannot bear Aykiz Baci's sorrow.
Everything will be solved, Bamsi brother.
God is great.
You are right, Dogan brother.
Aykiz is a very strong girl.
She would not cry and
throw herself left and right.
Let us finish the job at hand first,
we will think about the rest later.
Put these on, braves. We are going.
Turgut.
Turgut?
Aykiz. Aykiz, wake up.
-Turgut.
-Aykiz, wake up. Wake up!
-It's over. It was only a dream.
Gokce. Gokce.
My Turgut is not well. I know.
I know it in my heart.
Turgut is in trouble, Gokce.
Turgut is not well.
We shall be as silent as the night.
Do not make a sound, go slowly.
Thank God.
If something happened to Ertugrul
and the agreement had not reached...
...the palace,
it wouldn't have been like this, Bey.
It does not look like
the doings of a few guards.
It is obvious that something unknown
by us is going on in Aleppo.
We need to find out the reason why
we were not accepted into the city.
The tent must have started the migration.
We cannot sit here with our hands tied.
We need to find a way to enter Aleppo.
If you give permission, Bey...
...can I try to enter the city all alone?
Maybe we can pass the guards this time.
It does not seem likely but...
...there is nothing else to do but try.
I can go.
If you give me permission, Bey.
We do not know
what is going on in Aleppo.
We cannot send you into the unknown.
You know much better, Bey but...
...no one would suspect
a young woman on her own.
I can say that I am from another
tribe and came to the city...
...to find a cure for my mother's illness.
If you give permission,
I would like to accompany Aykiz.
We can be more cautious
when we are together.
When the situation asks for it,
the Kayi women can be...
...as brave as their men
and fight as good as the Alps.
Thank God.
We had the chance to stand up like men
for our tribe when we were young.
Bey, you know better.
We know that the Kayi women have always
enabled their men to be more powerful.
But...
...we cannot leave our young girls
alone in a foreign land.
Wild Demir...
...take Aykiz and Gokce with you...
...set off together.
Let us pray that the guards
show mercy to a man...
...who is traveling
with his daughters.
Of course, Bey.
The weather is getting worse.
This time the journey
will test our limits.
Do not worry, woman. We shall reach
Aleppo with God's permission.
I am scared for my baby.
How can I endure
the cold in this condition?
You will.
All three of us will overcome this.
Do you think they reached Aleppo?
They must have, with God's permission.
I wish I listened to my mother
and send you with them as well.
It is better this way.
To be together for better for worse.
Nothing will happen to me
as long as I am with you.
We should be on our way
without too much delay.
Hamza!
This is strange.
Do you remember the address
Ertugrul gave in Aleppo, Wild Demir?
A bookseller in the Aleppo market, Bey.
The owner of the bookstore is
Abdulqadir El Halabi.
We will ask him about Ertugrul.
May God speed you.
Go fast and come back fast.
May the sacred hand of our Mother Fatima
be on your backs all the time.
Amen.
Return with good news.
-May God be with you.
-Amen.
Go on, my girl.
God, protect them.
Bey...
...you seem calm like still water.
Small ponds of water ripple
when a man blows a bit hard.
But are the big seas like that, Alpargu?
Do you not remember the Caspian Sea?
It may be calm sometimes
but when it heaves up...
...nothing can stop it.
Do not be sad because
it is the time of the low tide now.
The time will come for the high tide
and we will heave up once again.
Up until this day I never doubted
even a word you said.
But I do not understand
how you can be so hopeful.
Whatever we tried,
we failed and returned to our tent.
That is correct.
You are right, Alpargu.
We almost lost our own lives
while trying to take lives.
But your Bey...
...has not played his last card yet.
We still do not have
any news from Karatoygar.
Maybe Karatoygar will return
from Konya with good news.
Of course the good news may mean
a wedding celebration for some...
...and mourning to death for others.
I am going to Leila Hanim's room.
Their guest has woken up with a good
appetite. I am taking some food to her.
Did you come to take him?
No...
...I came to take your head.
Justice always prevails here.
A killer who killed Aleppo's
most respected trader...
...and the guards of the palace
shall surely be punished.
Just like a bird,
you flew into the trap we set up for you.
We don't hunt birds, we feed them.
You became a game for the wolf....
...while trying to hunt the bird.
You!
Don't think that I forgot you!
Ertugrul.
Put this man in the dungeon for killing
the innocent witnesses who did nothing...
...but to tell the truth as well as
the guards of his highness the Ameer.
When I saw so many guards here...
...I was worried about the security
of the palace.
What do you say, Nasir?