episode 9 will start at : 12:30
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
I am coming from the Kayi tribe.
Ertugrul Bey gave us your name.
Ertugrul?
Ertugrul.
Why did you bring us here?
Why are we not going
to the secret passage?
Do not panic, brother Bamsi.
This room was chosen
by our people on purpose.
It is not a room that is used frequently.
Shut up, woman!
She fainted.
With this woman, we can sneak through an
army of guards. Let us wear these clothes.
Let us take a carpet out on the way
out so that we will not attract attention.
Open the door!
-I am telling you, open at once!
-Are these your men?
Open the door! I am talking to you!
Open the door, then, brother Bamsi.
Obviously, this is
the last day of his life.
You are right, brother Dogan, he shouted
too much, he is giving me a headache.
We have to cut off the noise.
-I'm telling you!
-Great God!
Bamsi...
...we would harm our Bey like that.
We do whatever he told us to.
Bey...
...will you go into
Nasir's trap knowingly?
I do not want any objection
to my orders, Dogan.
You shall do what I say.
This is a big trap set up for not only
our tribe but for the whole Islamic world.
We have break their game.
Neither my life nor your lives
are important in a mission like this.
Bring the woman who will take us to
the snake's nest, whatever it costs.
Bey?
Nasir will put his most trusted guards
here in order to catch me.
This will make your entrance easier.
While Nasir
enjoys the euphoria of victory...
...you will take that woman out.
Stop.
Where are you taking these?
His highness the Ameer and Leila Sultan's
governess Ummulhayr Hanim ordered us...
...to change the carpets of
their living quarters.
They told us to give away
the old carpets to those in need.
Aleppo's poor people will pray for you.
Carry on.
Dogan and Bamsi came before us.
We came with Ertugrul but...
...my son Yigit and Turgut Alp...
...could not reach Aleppo.
They were captured by the Templars.
-The Templars...
-Aykiz...
I knew it. Turgut!
Turgut.
Turgut!
Don't tell me that those traitors
beat us again, Nasir.
No, your highness. We caught Ertugrul.
He was put into the dungeon for killing
the witnesses in Sahabettin's trial.
Do you think you can get
any information from Ertugrul?
There is no power that can stand against
the absolute and swift justice of Aleppo.
Ertugrul will see talking as
the only solution to save his own life.
Why are you so tense, your highness?
Traitors have suffered a great loss.
When we take Sahabettin in...
...this network of traitors
shall be completely disbanded.
For God's sake, while my uncle
roams freely in the city...
...how can I relax, Nasir?
You know how much the soldiers
are loyal to him.
I do not want a discord in the army.
Did you think that you can lie down
and rest in the dungeon?
-We will clean you to the bone!
-Even your dog will not get your scent.
Come on.
Brothers, the woman woke up.
Give it to me, Aykutluk Bey.
Let me take over.
What is in it?
What can it be, commander?
A carpet and some dust on it.
There might be a female tick. The kind
that sticks and sucks your blood.
Put the carpet down.
-Shall I put it down?
-You suckling veal...
...didn't our Bey tell us
to bring the woman in one piece?
-But the soldier said put it down.
-I said put it down!
Our Bey gave himself up for this woman.
-Bamsi, you take the carpet and go.
-How is that possible, brother?
Do what I say, Bamsi.
Great God then!
Have a good fight, brothers!
I entrust Aykiz to you, Gokce.
And I entrust both of you to first God,
and then to the bookseller.
I need to inform Suleyman Shah
immediately.
Do not worry.
They are our lodge's girls from now on.
Look, Gokce.
You are the only one with Aykiz.
If I see you stand strong like this,
I will not worry about you on the road.
We should go then.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS' CASTLE
When Master went after you in a hurry,
I don't know how I completed the sermon.
-Hold it straight.
-Okay.
How did you manage to escape from there?
While we were trying to save the wolf
from the trap, he saved us from there.
Tell your infidel stories
to that black priest there!
I don't care about the good tidings
of your father in the skies.
Thank God,
I know both my father and my God.
Pull.
-In the name of Jesus!
Arrow.
The Grandmaster is a clever man.
He will make Yigit a Templar knight...
...and use him against the Seljuk.
What about the young man in the dungeon,
Afsin Bey? What will they do to him?
I do not know what they will do to him...
...but I hope we get out of here
before we witness that.
Then, Yigit will not be affected so much.
-With God's permission, Bey.
-With God's permission.
Yigit!
Let brother Turgut go!
I said let him go!
Enough!
You carry the blood of
my father's murderers.
You deserve to die.
Be thankful that you are Yigit's friend.
Shahzade's friend is our friend.
Come on, Yigit.
If someone from us killed your father,
he must have deserved it.
Killing someone undeservedly
is not written in our book.
My father respected your religion.
He spent all his life in these lands
to understand the Muhammadans.
If he was someone
who respected our religion...
...search for his killers among people who
do not even respect their own religion.
Are you ready?
He will be ready soon, sir.
I am guessing that we are acquiring
a friend from the enemy side.
Please be rest assured, Hayme.
With God's permission, our tribe has never
been left without a homeland or future...
...and it shall never be.
A long life that was spent on trying
to survive, in front of the Mongols.
All the way from the Caspian Sea to here,
every homeland took a piece from me.
Just like tearing my liver out.
It tore out and took them.
My father...
...my brothers...
...my sisters.
Then...
...my son.
My Sungurtekin.
I don't even know whether
he is alive or not.
Trying to live on
without knowing whether
my brave son is alive or not...
As if these were not enough...
...now Ertugrul.
If anything happens to him...
Thank God, Wild Demir is back.
Come on, have a seat.
Welcome.
Thank you, Bey. Thank you but...
...the news are not that good.
Tell us then. Is Ertugrul alright?
Is my brave son alive, Wild Demir?
Wild Demir!
Is Ertugrul alive?
I saw him with my own eyes.
He lives.
But...
...he is in the dungeon.
-What?
What are you saying, Deli?
Do you hear what you are saying?
I wish I could beat my tongue
on the anvil but...
...this is the truth.
Rahman, go to the tribe
on the migration road immediately.
Tell Gundogdu...
...to take Kurdoglu and the other
Beys and come here in the quickest manner!
Now...
...tell everything
from the beginning, Wild Demir.
Whatever you saw, whatever you heard.
Did he talk?
Pity...
What a pity, Ertugrul.
I feel bad seeing a brave man like you
being tortured like this.
Atabeg Sahabettin, for the sake of whom
you suffered so much...
...fooled not only you but all of us.
But I see that
you are still under his spell.
Who could think that Sahabettin Tugrul
would collaborate with those infidels?
We were caught from
the least expected place.
We are thankful to God,
who forced him to make a mistake...
...and reveal how the Templars
nested in our palace.
I hope you open your eyes before it is
too late and see what kind of a man he is.
Are you going to open my eyes with
the stories you put El Aziz to sleep?
You do not act wisely, Ertugrul.
If you do not care for yourself,
at least care for your nomad tent.
In this stormy winter, they are torn apart
in the migration journey.
Yes, your tribe reached
the Aleppo borders.
Settling in a new homeland
will depend on two words...
...that will come out of El Aziz's mouth.
His highness Ameer's only wish is
to see the so called uncle of his...
...who collaborated with
the killers of his father, executed.
If you correct your mistake
and hand Sahabettin Tugrul over to us...
...I can weigh in on your behalf for
a decision on your new homeland.
A land won by betrayal would not
be a home but only hell to Kayis.
These fabrics are very nice.
We should order a couple of
new dresses for you with these.
We can also order one for Halime.
It would be a present.
It would cheer her up.
Look, Halime started to wake up.
Get well soon. How are you?
Do you have any pain?
I am better, thank you.
My name is Leila.
I am the Ameer of Aleppos's sister.
So you are a sultan.
Yes.
How did it happen?
We were ambushed on the way to Aleppo.
I do not remember the rest.
You are very lucky.
You were on the brink of death.
The arrow hit you right above the heart...
...and you are being treated
in the palace.
Moreover, you are in my room.
I wonder whose idea that was.
Thank you.
I am recovering thanks to you.
I will never forget your good deeds.
Did you come to our palace before?
No.
But I do not like palaces.
I don't believe that anyone
can really be happy behind stone walls.
I also did not believe that anyone
could be happy in this palace, too.
And I turned out to be right.
My uncle was the target of slanders.
He had to run away.
Now I do not even know where he is.
This is why I like loneliness.
Please do not take
her words personally, my girl.
She does not mean bad.
After her father and mother
were killed right before her eyes...
...she shut herself in this room.
I see that our patient has recovered.
I am glad.
Thanks to you, your highness.
I am grateful.
Actually, I am grateful to you
for dawning upon my gloomy castle's...
...soulless rooms like sunlight.
Leila.
I see that you are enchanted as usual.
I am in a good mood today,
my dear governess.
Nasir has caught the goat herder
who abducted Sahabettin.
Who was this brave man?
A troublesome nomad from the Kayis.
Kayi Bey's son Ertugrul.
Halime? Halime, my girl?
What happened?
Continue until he talks.
You will not even taste
the joy of rotting in Aleppo dungeons.
Bamsi? Dogan?
Bamsi?
Dogan?
Ertugrul Bey?
Aykiz? My Aykiz.
My Aykiz.
Aykiz. Aykiz.
Ustad, I congratulate you.
My vizier?
Thank God!
I thank God, for letting me see you alive.
My vizier...
...what am I doing here?
What do these men want from me?
Are they...
Are you...
...suspecting me?
Do you think that I betrayed you?
Now...
...my eyes are open wide enough
to see the truth.
If you even have
a doubt they I am a traitor...
...if you have the slightest doubt...
...kill me here at once without hesitation.
I don’t care about your life...
...or your death...
...as much as I care about
a knot in this Turkmen carpet.
Now, I am listening to you. Talk.
Hasn’t this Turkmen goat herder
talked yet?
Don’t let him die.
Let me have some fun
while you eat your lunch.
Do not die, alright?
Our fun is not finished yet.
It is my turn to have fun.
Just like the tick in the carpet found its
home, you found your home in this barrel...
...you Turkmen goat herder.
Tell me, Esma. Who else is a Templar
other than you in the palace?
What is the goal of
the Templars within the Aleppo palace?
I wish I die...
I wish that you kill me as
I can’t bear the pain of you doubting me.
Stop lying to me!
Tell me the truth.
Esma, why did you do this to me?
My vizier, I did not betray you.
I didn’t lie in the court,
when I testified against you either...
...I only told what I saw.
I beg you...
I beg you,
please don’t treat me like a traitor.
What did I do to deserve this?
Who are the other Templars in Aleppo?
How is your trade, Abu Hisam?
Abu Hisam. I yearn for the day I’ll get
rid of this name and these Muslim attires.
But the answer to your question
is positive, Nasir.
Good.
Anything that can be converted into money.
Mines, quarries, big fields...
...we will own them all.
Slowly, slowly.
While El Aziz dreams about
swimming in pools of gold...
...all the treasures of Aleppo will flow
into the cool cellars of our castle.
Until his highness the Ameer turns into
a beggar who begs from the Templars...
...we shall take everything he has.
Then, I shall give you the good news.
Ertugrul is in our hands.
You will give him to me.
You have to learn to be patient,
my precious friend.
After we use that goat herder as a bait
to pull Sahabettin into our trap...
...then Ertugrul will be yours.
Do we have permission, Bacis?
Please do not say that.
My children...
...how much you hurt inside
can be seen from the tears in your eyes.
Not knowing the fate of those whom you
wait is eating your heart out like a worm.
Your pain is big.
But big dreams require big sacrifices.
Who sees the dream, Efendi?
Will Ertugrul and Turgut be sacrificed?
Once upon a time, Abraham,
peace be upon him, wanted a son.
He prayed to God over and over again.
If he is blessed with a son,
he would sacrifice the boy for Him.
One day, a little drop from the eternal
power of God fell on Abraham’s prayer.
Ishmael was born.
Then, one day Abraham saw a dream.
In his dream he saw that
he was sacrificing Ishmael.
He told this dream to Ishmael.
A son is like an essence of the father.
Ishmael was a believer like his father.
He accepted.
He said, “do not feel despair, father.
Carry out your promise to our Great God.”
As his heart rose with compassion,
as his soul got ripped apart with pain...
...he put a knife on Ishmael’s throat
at a dark corner.
Just at that moment, Gabriel came down
with a sacrificial ram on his lap.
God is a witness to that you are one
who keeps his promises.
Take that knife from Ishmael’s throat
and sacrifice this.
Thank God.
It is like this, my children.
Those who dream big and keep their promise
need to be ready for big sacrifices.
Ertugrul and his companions
are passionate to see a good dream...
...for the Muslim world
who are living in a nightmare right now.
That is why they put their throats
to the knife like Ishmael.
Knife will not be hurt from them.
We hope that God,
most Gracious and most  Merciful...
...will not let those braves get hurt.
You scared us, Halime.
I am so sorry, governess.
I made you worry.
When an ache struck like that
all of a sudden...
Are you better now?
I am better, thank you.
Your father is here, outside.
Stop. Don’t try to get up.
Governess, let us invite him in.
And I shall take some fresh air.
Come in, Numan Efendi.
My girl.
Thank God I am well, father.
-Father.
-Tell me, my girl.
I am aware of what happened.
I know what happened to Ertugrul, father.
First Yigit, now Ertugrul.
How will we get out of this bog we are in?
My girl...
His highness the Ameer would like to
see Numan Efendi.
My girl.
Your highness, when the whole Muslim world
was in the dark...
...you rose up like the sun above Aleppo.
I am thankful to God for this.
You are a ray of hope for not only this
city but for everyone who is oppressed.
Don’t say that.
Yes, your highness.
Welcome.
Come in, come close, please.
You know how valuable
these prisoners are for us.
Titus!
Everything in this world will be over,
everything will be forgotten...
...everything will be forgiven...
...but I will not forgive you!
I will never forget
what you have done to us!
You lowlife dog!
I wanted to introduce you to two of
the most precious persons of Aleppo.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, Kurdoglu.
God bless, I saw you standing up
straight like this...
...I won’t care if I die now.
Thank you, God.
And you gave me the good news of
a grandchild, son.
You made me happy.
We are in a bind once again,
Suleyman Shah.
-Rahman told us.
-I understand.
What will we do, Bey?
What is on your mind?
We are on a hair thick
Sirat Bridge, Kurdoglu.
Without falling down to hell,
without giving or taking a life...
...we have to solve this.
Why did they imprison my brother?
It is a game of these Crusader infidels.
Templars have infiltrated everywhere.
Then we should go and
bring down the sky on top of them.
So many Alps have become martyrs
because of these infidels.
Our tribe got scattered.
We almost went to war with Karatoygar.
We won’t find peace until
we finish them all.
But Gundogdu, there tribe is on migration.
We are not ready for a war.
I told you that Aleppo would be our grave.
Do not worry, Kurdoglu.
Someone from our blood would come and...
...take our graves from here.
Now, listen to me closely.
Another valuable friend of mine
whom I want you to meet it...
Open the door!
Your highness Ameer.
What kind of an imprudence is this?
What do you think you are doing?
Nasir, I am hoping that you will give a
suitable punishment to this tactless man.
-Of course.
-We have received a critical information...
...about a topic Commander Nasir
has ordered to gather intelligence.
That is why I had to barge in.
I beg for your forgiveness.
Commander, as per your order, we looked
everywhere and we are now sure that...
...servant Esma has been kidnapped
from the palace.
I don’t understand.
Nasir?
If it comes to it...
...you shall break every door in Aleppo,
search everywhere and find Esma, Nasir.
I mean, right now.
Tomorrow we shall go to Aleppo. We will
either get our homeland from there...
...or we will die! There is no other way.
What about Ertugrul?
We do not know what he is accused of.
We shall learn and act accordingly.
Gundogdu, you shall go to
the moorland where we will settle.
Have the tribe settle there but be ready
for a war that might start anytime.
Wild Demir, you ready the weapons.
As you wish, Bey.
What will we do now, Nasir?
What if Eftelya talks?
You don’t know Eftelya, Titus.
She would never do anything to harm
the Templars, you can be rest assured.
You have still not learned that
you can never be sure about humans, Nasir.
We cannot risk it.
We should find Eftelya and bring her back,
whatever the cost.
Dead or alive.
We are almost sure that
she was abducted from the palace, right?
Did something happen in the palace
that caught your attention recently?
Think a bit harder.
No. Nothing.
We took Ertugrul and
put him in the dungeon.
The rest was ordinary palace chores.
What about before?
Stop.
Where are you taking these?
His highness the Ameer and Leila Sultan’s
governess Ummulhayr Hanim ordered us...
...to change the carpets of the Harem.
Guard!
Bring the governess to me!
Nasir is looking for Esma
everywhere in the palace.
He will be aware of her absence soon.
Ertugrul...
...they tortured him a bit in the dungeon.
-You...
-My brother, don’t!
We are not like them. We do not oppress.
We do not owe our enemies
anything but justice.
There is one more news.
Some people came to the lodge
from your tribe.
They said two young women and an old man.
They asked the bookseller about Ertugrul.
I am going.
Nasir...
...I told you to not to turn into
Karatoygar.
But you are drowned
in courage of ignorance.
I hope you can change
some things before it is too late.
I give you my respects, Commander Nasir.
What am I doing here, Commander?
Are you interrogating me?
How can I do such a thing,
Ummulhayr Hanim?
You are the mother of this palace.
How can you say that?
There is only one small issue
that caught my attention.
-I wanted to consult you about that.
-Do ask, I am listening.
Did you recently give an order to donate
the old carpets of the palace to the poor?
We continuously donate the old items in
the palace to the poor...
...but I have not given
such an order recently.
Moreover, you know me, Commander...
...I do the charity work by myself
without been seen.
Of course we know this, governess. You are
the soul of Aleppo carved from a jewel.
The protective wing of Aleppo’s poor.
I am sorry if I disturbed you.
Please.
You can go back to your quarters.
Guard!
Prepare your regiment immediately.
To a city where Ertugrul is in chains,
where even the Alps cannot escape...
...how could you send Gokce?
Selcan! Gokce volunteered to go.
Have you forgotten that
our women are as brave as our men?
Do not worry. Nothing will happen to them.
Would Wild Demir leave them and return
if they were in an unsecure place?
Mother Hayme, Gokce is my only companion.
If she is gone as well...
...how can I bear this pain?
Do not fear.
Selcan, look at me.
Nothing will happen to them.
Do you understand?
Do not fear.
My vizier, you can tell
anything to this brave.
He would even forget the message himself
after he delivers it.
There are a few men that I trust in the
palace. You will tell them where we are.
They will whisper our location to
Ertugrul and he can manage the rest.
Come on, braves. Let us load the woman.
Great God!
Stop! What are you doing?
We have to leave immediately. Wear
the guard’s uniform. We have to hurry.
Stop!
Where are you taking that?
What is inside it?
Put it down!
Great God!
Aykutluk.
My vizier, you go.
Vizier, you go, we will take care of him.
Go!
My vizier, please go.
Vizier, go! Come on!
This way.
Go inside here, Bey.
God damn!
Guards! Guards!
He shall not even stick
his nose out of the palace...
...or I will have all of you executed,
understand?
Go!
Halime?
Where is Leila Sultan, my girl?
I did not see her this morning, governess.
Where is she?
Girls!
Search the Harem immediately. Find Leila
Sultan wherever she is and inform me.
As you wish.
Governess, why did you get so anxious?
His highness loves his sister very much.
He wants to know every step she takes.
What am I going to do?
This is all I can do, Bey.
Go down this hall.
It will take you to Nasir’s room.
This is a very dangerous plan,
may God be on your side.
-As Aykutluk said, you are a brave man.
-Thank you.
You incompetent men. God damn you all!
Sir, we found two guards dead!
Get out!
Get out and find that man, get out!
Did I make you angry?
What do you want, Ertugrul?
Everyone in Aleppo to know who you are!
Then you have to kill me.
Because nothing can break
the seal of my tongue.
Why?
Are you going to poison yourself
and die like a foaming rabid dog?
I don’t think so, Nasir.
You are a coward dog.
You should see your own face. It is
as white as the shroud of the Sultan.
You still don’t see
how powerful the force against you is.
They will destroy you and
your reckless tribe to the last man.
I am not in the least scared
of you killing me.
I have seen the drooling bodies of your
dogs that were after me, so many times.
I even lost count.
I don’t think you are as devoted as
those dogs of yours, Nasir.
When it comes to killing you...
...one more or one less,
It makes no difference to me.
Even if one hair of mine is damaged...
...Shahzade’s daughter Halime,
for whom you went all into this trouble...
Do you think we are stupid, Ertugrul?
We know everything.
If something happens to me...
...Shahzade’s daughter Halime,
her brother who is our prisoner...
...and your Alp Turgut...
...may turn up dead.
I already took my precautions, Ertugrul.
I have so many men in this palace
who will take the life of Halime...
...where Titus’ arrow had failed.
I am not even counting
the ones in Kayi.
What happened, Ertugrul?
Did you abandon the idea of killing me?
Go on, kill me.
Why did you stop? Kill me, Ertugrul!
I will expose the people
who made you do this one by one.
Then...
...may God be my witness that I shall
kill you with my own hands, Nasir.
Guards!
Catch him!
Don't let him escape! Bring him to me!
I saw him, he is running away.
He went that way! Catch him!
Please...
...do not get up.
How is the sunlight of my palace?
I am better, thank you.
This is great.
I talked with the physician as well.
He says that you are better.
May God bless him.
He went into a lot of trouble to cure me.
Governess Ummulhayr was always by my side.
All thanks to you.
I was waiting impatiently
for you to get well.
I was waiting so that instead of talking
about health in this gloomy room...
...we can walk in the gardens of Aleppo.
And talk about nice topics.
Poetry for example.
Do you like poetry, Halime?
I would have liked to read you
some of the poems I wrote.
As I am recovered now,
I will need to leave the palace soon.
I would like to be with my loved ones
as soon as possible.
Moreover, I have been a burden on
Leila Sultan for some time.
Governess? Where is Leila?
You are safe here.
No one knows this hideout.
Who are you?
I am the niece of the man who you saved.
Vizier Sahabettin's.
So you are El Aziz's sister.
I saw how you risked your own life
to save my uncle from...
...the foolish decree of my brother.
I am not your enemy.
It is unclear who is
a friend or foe in Aleppo.
Only my uncle can save our city from
this state. That is why I am helping you.
My uncle's friend is my friend as well.
What if you are also a foe
who looks like a friend?
Spend the night here. I will get you
out of here when the palace calms down.
I don't think I have another choice.
All the exits are blocked, sir.
We will find him sooner or later.
Look in all holes, all cracks, understood?
No one shall know
that Ertugrul has escaped.
Especially his highness,
the Ameer El Aziz.
Get out!
I still see Ertugrul being taken
when I close my eyes, Aykiz.
We have to find a way and reach them.
My Turgut...
...if he is still alive...
...only Ertugrul can save him.
Dogan?
Shall we pray, Yigit?
I am going to ask you something.
That man Turgut...
...do you think he speaks the truth
about my father's death?
He never lies.
Alright.
Now repeat everything I do.
When you are going to pray,
go to your room and close the door.
Pray to our Father secretly.
Everything that is done secretly
shall be rewarded by our Father.
Do not pray with empty words,
like the infidels.
They only try to be heard with verbiage.
Do not be one of them.
Because our Father would know what we need
even before we say and bless it to us.
Pray like this:
Our Holy Father up in the sky.
Thou name shall always be sacred.
Amen.
Welcome.
Why do you say welcome
as if we have good news to give them.
Do not be agonized.
We know about the things that happened.
So you know.
We wouldn't have liked to
greet you with our heads down...
...but we faced many troubles.
-Turgut Alp is our flesh and blood.
-I said I know what happened.
We should talk about
what we need to do now.
Aleppo has gone out of control.
Vizier Sahabettin.
He is a fugitive.
We brought him here,
as the lodge was the most secure place.
He needs to return to his post
for all the problems to be solved.
How does this concern Turgut?
As I said, Baci.
Here, everything is a tangled mess.
But Ertugrul Bey has a idea
to put everything into order.
And for this idea, he sacrificed himself.
You must be hungry.
You have to regain your strength.
Thank you.
Please do not endanger yourself
for me anymore.
I want my uncle to return to the palace
where he belongs, as soon as possible.
That is all.
The guards are still running about.
Try to manage with this until the morning.
I will find a way to get you out of here.
My problem is not getting out of
the palace, it is Nasir.
He is the one who sold out
your uncle and us.
Do you understand?
In this cold weather, drink so that you
can warm up a bit, my son.
Thank you.
With this holy duty, you deserve a place
in the heaven kingdom of our Father.
You come and drink some as well, my son.
We have to show this sinner soul
that has collaborated with the devil...
...the path of our Messiah, Jesus Christ.
-Here you are, son.
-Thank you.
Share with the others,
they should warm up a bit as well.
May God protect you.
My brave, how are you?
Drink, drink up.
I will get you out of here as soon as
possible, try to bear it, alright?
Recite the patience invocation,
I promise that I will get you out of here.
Don't. I won't leave Yigit to them.
Yigit and you will go out of
this castle safe and sound, trust me.
With God's permission, in this castle...
...I will be a martyr.
If the road takes you...
...to my tribe...
...to Kayis...
...one day...
...find Aykiz...
...tell her that...
...Turgut...
...for even one second...
...did not forget you.
That I bore all the pain...
...by thinking her love at all times.
Find Aykiz...
...and...
...tell her that I love her very much.
Alright, Alfin Bey?
You will tell all these to Aykiz yourself.
I promise you, I will get you out of here.
Drink some more.
Recite patience.
Patience.
Dear God...
May God protect you, my sons.
Ertugrul did what he always does again.
Is it a lie?
Ertugrul Bey messes everything up...
...and you end up worrying for him.
What should I have done, Hatun?
Should I have said, nothing that happens
in the tribe concerns me?
All I am saying is that you are being
the Bey of the tribe at the moment and...
...that your father should know this.
Will you abide them turning a blind eye
to whatever he does once again?
Ertugrul should pay the price of
the damage he caused for these people.
The great Kayi tribe. We don't have
a home, we don't have land...
...we don't have plentiful food...
...instead of thinking about these,
you still think of evil, Hatun.
Is it a lie?
As if these were not enough...
...you stick your nose into things
that don't concern you even when pregnant.
What more can I say to you, Hatun?
What can I say?
The letter you have written to
the Pope and Emperor Frederic...
...is not an ordinary letter anymore,
Thomas.
I was just thinking what you might give...
...to see what I have written,
my dear friend Petruccio.
You have learned our power.
Out network of spies...
...our financial sources...
...and the opportunities
we can present for a new crusade.
Especially for you, my dear friend.
What if you fail at the crusade?
Would that be important after you became
the Pope, my dear friend Thomas?
Yigit, listen to me very well.
You have to be very careful, alright?
Did you understand what I said?
You have to get that key from Marcus
at all costs.
We will overcome and
solve everything, alright?
You are a strong man.
That is obvious.
But you came out stronger than we thought.
You did not collapse
after everything you went through.
Well done.
You are like a raging bull.
Like a bull challenging his toreador.
You are not very talkative...
...but I can find a topic
that might interest you.
Aykiz.
The name you blabber while being tortured.
Is she your lover?
I don't think you will talk to me.
Shame.
Then I am going.
What do you want from me?
Your father's killer?
My father.
In this state?
I cannot go into the dungeon...
...but I know that there is a prisoner
in there called Giovanni.
There is only...
...a Muslim man called Omer in there.
I want you to ask something to that man.
Whether she knows a girl called Isadora.
If you can give me a reply...
...I would do anything I can
for you to escape from here.
How will I give you the answer?
Shahzade Yigit will help us.
Vizier is trapped. Turgut is far away.
Ertugrul Bey is away in the dungeons.
Aykutluk became a martyr.
We are left all alone here.
-Where are they?
-They are here, sir.
Ertugrul?
I am waiting outside.
Vizier...
...I know how much
you tried to help Kayis...
...thanks to Dogan and Bamsi.
They also told us
the conspiracy against you.
If you find it suitable as well...
...you should be taken somewhere
where no one can reach you.
Let us take you to Kayi tribe.
Not only the Templars, even if
the 70 kings of the Roman cities...
...unite to attack us,
they cannot take you out from there.
Suleyman Shah, your offer
made me more than happy but...
...I am afraid to bring more disasters
to your already distressed tribe.
Let disaster come to a brave,
while he is being brave...
...it would be an honor.
Rahman...
...Ilyas Fakih...
...take our vizier to the tribe
without attracting attention.
Just like written
in the letter to the Jews...
...in a way to please God...
...with fear and respect...
...let us pray.
My holy brother, if you accept as well...
...participating in a sermon by a monk
like you, who has devoted his life...
...to the Messiah, would be
a great honor to all Templar knights.
By sitting in the shelter of the Creator,
the One who has the power...
...to do anything,
he takes refuge in His shadow.
He is my shelter, my fortress!
I say for God.
He is my God, I trust Him.
Because He protects you from the traps
of the hunters and all deadly diseases!
He takes you under His wings.
You take shelter under them.
His loyalty becomes
your shield and shelter.
Amen.
Do not forget...
...some non believers who reject
the Messiah Jesus Christ...
...have secretly infiltrated amongst us.
It has been written long ago that
they shall be tried!
Amen!
Nasir...
...hasn't Esma been found yet?
Your highness, most probably the Templars
who are collaborating with Sahabetttin...
...have kidnapped her as well.
Come with me, let us interrogate Ertugrul.
When I think that my brother is in their
hands, I am about to lose my mind, father.
Ertugrul?
Halime?
Leila, my girl,
what do you think you are doing?
How can you help this man?
How can you bring him to this room?
I had to.
They are looking for him everywhere.
This is the only place
where I can hide him.
That is what I was saying.
They are looking for this man everywhere.
And you brought him to your own room.
Did you ever think what would happen to us
if your brother finds out that he is here?
If my brother finds out that he is here,
I would commit suicide.
-Do you understand me?
-God, Great God.
I am Kayi tribe's Bey Suleyman Shah.
I came to talk to you.
As you took the trouble to come all
the way here, I am listening, Turkmens.
Free my son whom
you have imprisoned unjustly.
And rehabilitate the dignity of the Kayis
whom you slandered with plague claims.
What would happen
if we don't do what you say?
We would still settle
in the lands you had promised us before.
But if my son Ertugrul is not freed...
...while a tribe is being settled there,
a city would be burnt down here.
Aleppo would be wasted!
Alright, Suleyman Shah but what would
you do if I raise my army and come to you?
Whom do you trust to talk like this?
When you put us in the edge of
the Crusader countship...
...we said yes putting our trust in Him
and we trust Him again!
Do now forget, your highness Ameer...
...us Kayis believe in God,
we trust Him and take refuge in Him.
If your army is greater than Him, come.
We shall be waiting in our tribe.
Nasir...
...if Sahabettin is with them,
our job is very difficult.
Your highness, give me permission
to put them in their places.
I want to be informed about
every step Kayis take.
Alright?
I have a feeling that
we can find my uncle if we follow them.
The rear side of our Bey's marquee
shall always be protected strongly.
The tents of the Alps shall be
distributed in the outer rings.
We can make this flat area ahead
our training ground.
The people have started to put up
their tents. Shall we wait for our Bey?
We didn't come here
to scratch the soil, Alpargu.
We will of course set up our tents.
Make sure that your Alps are ready
at all times.
An infidel might come out
from behind those mountains...
...or an attack from our so called
religion brothers may come any minute.
That is why you should be alert
at all times.
Hatun...
...you are carrying two lives...
...put it down. We can carry them.
There is still a long time, Gundogdu.
I cannot sit around empty handed
while there is so much work to do.
-Peace be upon you, Gundogdu Bey.
-And peace be upon you.
God bless you all,
you have settled so quickly.
Thanks to God, Fakih. Thanks to God.
Aleppo vizier, Sahabettin Tugrul.
Welcome, we are happy to see you.
My brother Ertugrul
always spoke highly of you.
Thank you, I am grateful.
May your new homeland be a blessing.
Thank you.
Bey...
...and about the identity of
the woman at the back...
...we should ask the devil.
Please.
Shahzade, I will save Turgut from
the dungeon in the first chance I get.
You stay in the courtyard or the corridor
in order not to attract attention, okay?
We will have only one chance.
God willing, you should not need
to use this but you should...
...have it.
What will happen now, Titus?
Kayis came and settled
on the land without consent.
Who will save us from the fury of Ustad?
If you can get into El Aziz's mind and
make him do the things we want...
...I know a way that would make
Ustad more pleased than ever.
What is it, Titus? Tell me now.
The girl El Aziz is in love with...
If we can make her father
and El Aziz allies...
...our Ustad's big plan
would come to life.
Aleaddin Keykubat who will reject
this alliance can do anything.
The sons of Seljuk and Saladin Ayubi's
children will fight, right?
God, what a scene it would be.
You do not understand
the gravity of the situation.
The Templars' ears and eyes reach
inside the palace.
You being...
They might have whispered the Ameer
that you are a Seljuk Shahzade.
I am glad you came, Nasir.
-There are some things I want to ask you.
-Please do, your highness.
I hope it is not something bad.
Did you ever fall in love?
No, your highness.
I am only in love with my job.
You are very boring, Nasir.
As you have never been in love,
you wouldn't know what a lover should...
...give the loved one as a present.
I am drowning in my own problems
all alone.
There are some issues I need to inform
you about. Issues of vital importance.
How can you explain the interest
and affection they show you...
...of those who are scared of giving us
a land due to plague claims.
Ertugrul Bey, I understand your anxieties.
But one of my children is in an unknown...
...and the other...
I do not have a refuge for
my child other than a prayer.
If I do not do whatever
I can for the good of my daughter...
...I cannot find peace even in my grave.
Please, Ertugrul Bey, understand me.
Ameer of Aleppo, his highness El Aziz
would like to see Numan Efendi.
May it be a blessing, if God permits.
Let us go then.
-Our Shah is coming!
-Welcome, Shah.
-Welcome, Bey!
-Welcome, Suleyman Shah.
-Long live, Suleyman Shah.
-Long live, Bey!
Great God!
May you let our new land to be blessing.
Bless us with Your mercy and have us see
Ertugrul and Turgut back in our tribe.
May you make our sons and daughters happy.
-Amen!
Gundogdu...
...inform all the Beys.
-We shall have a meeting soon.
-As you wish, Bey.
Invite the Aleppo vizier to my marquee.
I need to talk with him.
Welcome, father.
Thank you, my girl.
-I have news from Ertugrul.
-Will he return to the tribe?
His job is hard.
After clearing the smear
that have been brought upon us...
...he will return, with God's permission.
Welcome, my girl.
The troubles have formed a line
in front of us, what will happen now, Bey?
Your eyes should be on the visitors
who came from Aleppo, Alpargu.
They are a blessing for us.
But first, we shall see what our Bey
will say in the headquarter meeting.
As you wish, Bey.
Welcome, Shahzade.
I think there is a misunderstanding.
Do not tire yourself out, Shahzade.
I know all about your story.
The Templars who are after you,
Sultan Aleaddin's wrath...
...I know that you are running away from
the assassins who are trying to kill you.
That is why I know that
you changed your identity as well.
Thanks to Nasir's intelligence network,
I also know that ...
...young Shahzade Yigit Alp
is a prisoner of the Templars.
My offer to you will be short and plain.
I am listening, your highness.
In this fight against the Templars...
...side with me.
Having a Seljuk Shahzade on my side...
...will open many doors.
And I will prevent
the young Shahzade Yigit...
...from growing up with the infidels.
My Aykiz...
...piece of my heart, look, if you try to
hold back your troubles inside...
...you will eat yourself out.
Instead of sitting down silently,
shout, cry, make a scene.
Don't make your old man sad.
From these Crusaders, we need
to take Turgut and Yigit back...
...as well as our revenge, father.
We have to make them live through ten,
1000 times more of what they did to us.
We will find a solution
when Ertugrul comes, my girl.
But I know how much you are hurting now.
You want to turn the whole world into ash.
But still...
...do not plant seeds of hatred
in your heart, my girl.
Despite all the evil in the world,
plant seeds of hope, my girl.
Plant them, so that victory can be...
...on the side of good and righteous.
And always believe in God's justice.
Of course those devils will
face a judgment day as well.
I cannot do it, father.
I am so angry that I cannot put out
the fire inside me.
Cry, my girl. Cry, my girl.
Cry.
-Talk to me!
-We looked everywhere.
We couldn't find him anywhere.
There is no sign of Esma or Ertugrul.
What about El Aziz?
Did you make sure he didn't learn?
Sir, we avoided giving direct answers
to his questions.
-But...
-But what?
Tell me, you fool!
Sir, the governess made a scene.
She shouted about that she had
something to tell to El Aziz.
The Ameer heard her voice and took her in.
You incompetent fools!
Your highness, El Aziz.
I don't know where to start.
You know me, my only worry is my children.
You and Leila.
But, I am very worried.
My governess...
...your state of mind worries me too.
You were like a mother to me.
Whatever that is worrying you,
please tell me directly.
-That young man who abducted our vizier.
-Ertugrul?
Yes, him.
I was so happy when Leila
started go out of her room.
But...
...the last time
she returned to her room...
...she came with that young man.
How can that be, my dear governess?
Guards!
Bring me Nasir immediately.
I am scared that something will happen
to my Leila because of that man.
Do not worry, governess.
I can take care of this.
We will learn what happened now.
Halime Sultan...
...you had said “my tongue only speaks
what is in my heart.”
What kind of a tongue is this?
While your heart
can't persuade your eyes...
...how can your tongue persuade me?
Neither my tongue nor my heart have
the strength to talk, Ertugrul Bey.
I don't know whether I should be torn
apart from what we have suffered or...
...how we made the ones who have extended
their friendship to us suffer.
Halime Sultan...
...it does not suit a Kinik girl like you
or a Kayi son like me to give up.
Close the door!
Open your eyes and
see what is happening around you.
Look at the state you have
put yourself and Aleppo in.
You are still not aware that you are
a toy in the hands of the Templars.
You are a traitor, Ertugrul.
A traitor who took advantage of my trust
and killed my soldiers.
I will not let you deceive me once again.
Come on! Hurry up!
Break the door!
Harder!
Get out of the way!
Hit with the battering ram.
Harder!