Episode 26 will start after 12:24 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You pander!
I will kill you.
What did you want from my wife?
Unfortunately, I got you without
your weapon.
I have never imagined like that.
It should not have been this easy,
Gundogdu.
Come on!
Gundogdu Bey! Give a holler!
I am here!
I will be back Gundogdu!
I will never give up until your kin is
nonexistent! Know it!
Gundogdu!
Have you forgiven me?
Before I die, tell me that you have
forgiven me. Forgive me.
Hatun.
Selcan.
For God's sake. God forbids.
How can it be? Open your eyes! Selcan!
Open your eyes for me! For God's sake.
For our baby.
Bey. Selcan Hatun.
Go, tell the healer. One of you,
go tell the healer, right now!
Come on, hurry up!
Hold on Selcan.
Hold on Hatun.
Hold on for me, hold on for our baby...
...hold on Selcan.
Hurry! Hurry!
She lost so much blood.
Hurry up for God's sake.
Leave Bey. We will take it from here.
Sister! Sister!
Gokce! My sister stop! Stop sister!
Let them, let them do their job.
Brother!
Brother! What happened?
While Titus was trying to kill me...
...Selcan shielded herself to protect me.
How is she now?
She is not good at all. She is not good
at all my brother.
Alps went after him.
On your happiest day...
God damn it!
My brother.
I promise you he will pay for the thing
he has done.
If God permits, my brother.
It is all my fault!
It all happened because of me!
I should not have talked to her like that.
Gokce do not say that. Pull yourself
together.
Selcan.
Send ten Alps towards Kurtbogazi.
Find the trace of that bastard!
Find him!
Abdurrahman.
As you wish, Bey.
My son. How are you?
How can I be Mother?
We have conquered the castle
but the victory is still far away.
Until that bastard Titus is dead,
this matter will not be settled Bey.
At first Dundar,
now my daughter-in-law Selcan.
That degenerate is blinded by revenge.
If given half the chance, he would
have killed Gundogdu in that very place.
He got him without a sword
by the nomad tents.
I wonder who's turn is it now?
How is Selcan?
Her condition is dire Bey.
Poor girl sacrificed herself for Gundogdu.
May God be pleased of her.
What have we been through Hayme?
As Selcan said once...
...everything started when Ertugrul
brought Halime.
Only with her presence...
...did we realize the purulence in
our nomad tent.
The lid blindfolded us was lift off
thanks to our daughter Halime.
If God permits, we will get rid of this
purulence Bey.
When our daughter Selcan recovers...
...the peace we are longing for will come
to our nomad group, if God permits.
After you safely return.
If God permits, Hanim. If God permits.
The proxy of our nomad group and the seal
of Seigniory is entrusted to you.
And the glory of our nomad group is
entrusted to you as well.
Do not worry, Bey.
As long as I have you, I will never worry.
It is time to take the road.
Let me help you Bey.
Bey.
We will have a grandchild.
Selcan is pregnant.
I increased the security precautions
in the nomad group.
However, if you do not have to,
do not go out of the nomad group.
Do not worry about us Ertugrul.
Your duty is heavy.
Come back honorably, that is enough.
The day you were shot by that traitor
still haunts me...
...you falling to my arms,
sacrificing yourself for me.
Everyone sacrifices their life for
their beloved, Ertugrul.
Selcan did the same thing.
After all the things she did to you,
you are still protecting Selcan.
We all know indeed, her heart is
still pure.
After all she broke bread with your
mother and father.
Titus will never give up Ertugrul.
He even tried to kill a little baby
to take the revenge of his brother Bisol.
He is blinded by it.
He got so out of hand that he even
harms women.
I am sure he will come after you.
I wish he would come and get
his destruction.
He will.
I have no doubt.
Do not feel sad for that our wedding day
brought such pain to us, Ertugrul.
Every day you came back home is
my wedding day.
I only want you to be careful, alright?
As long as you keep praying for my well
being, what is there to fret?
Godspeed.
May sun not burn your skin.
May rain not make you cold.
Nothing may get in your way.
May it be easy to come back
to your nomad group.
Stop, son.
That load will not fit into that
sack anymore.
Are we not going to take
the chest with us, Efendi?
Do I have your permission?
Come in.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
It is time to leave your nomad group, son.
Will I be able to see you again?
Surely one day our paths will cross.
From Andalusia to here...
...many place resided us.
Many opened their hearts to us.
However, none of them were as peaceful
as the Kayi nomad group.
May God grants you blessings.
Thank you.
We had received you in our hard times.
I witnessed your hard times.
However...
...as a seed sprouted to a new life...
...I witnessed the pain of a new
resurrection in the Islam world.
From now on, everything is in your
hands Ertugrul.
You should know that.
You become the ones who is entrusted
a mission...
...may God give power to you
and your nomad group.
May God let nothing to stand in your way.
Amen.
And may nothing stands in your way
as well.
You forgot to take the chest, Efendi.
As I have told you before son,
the deposit have found its owner now.
For the moment do not open it.
When the day comes, it will open for you.
May I ask what is it inside?
We could say that it is a little gift
which will help you when you feel the...
...draught or swelter while carrying out
the task that your fate bring upon you.
It is somewhat hard to open the chest.
It has always been hard to breach
the shell and reach to the jewel inside.
When the time comes...
...you will breach the shell and reach
the jewel inside.
Gokce Hatun...
...I trust Selcan in your hands.
Not only her but our baby, as well.
May nothing stand in your way,
Gundogdu Bey.
Be at ease.
Both Halime and Mother Hayme are here
with us.
If God permits, my sister will get better
until your return.
If God permits.
Safely.
Halime Sultan...
...welcome to our community.
You came with graces.
Thank you, Gundogdu Bey.
I am honored by your words.
Do not worry about Selcan Hatun.
May God let nothing stand in your way.
Amen. Safely.
How is your wife, brother?
We are going far.
If you wish so, you should not
leave her alone.
How can it be, brother?
While Oghuzs fighting to death
with Mongols...
...we should be united, we should
stand as one, like my father says.
No doubt, I too will come to show him
that I support him.
Is everything ready, Bamsi?
We, Bey, we are always ready.
-My brave boy.
-Brother.
I trust this land to you.
My grand grandfather Gokalp,
gave this ring to his son, Kizil Buga.
And Kizil Buga, gave this to my father
Kaya Alp.
And now I am trusting this to you.
I may never come back.
When the time comes, it is your duty
to give this to nomad group's Bey.
This, firstly is your duty, Bey.
May nothing stand in your way.
May God let nothing stand in your way.
I should not have spoken with you
that way, sister.
However wrong it may be...
...sinful it may be...
...I should not have act that way to you.
I should have respected you, sister.
Forgive me sister, please.
You are a part of me.
Look, we will be blessed with a newborn.
Sister you have to live.
For Gundogdu Bey, for your baby,
you have to live sister.
Do not give up sister, please.
Gokce.
It seems that Gundogdu has forgiven her,
as our Suleyman Shah.
Thank God.
From now on, everything will be
as good as the old days, Gokce.
From now on...
...we should not shadow our own happiness
which we earned by our bloody tears...
...by blaming neither ourselves,
nor others.
If God permits, my daughter Selcan will
get better as well.
If God permits.
Let us hope the pain in our nomad group
will come to an end, if God permits.
You do understand me, do you not
my daughter?
It is me, Titus.
I could not realize that it is you,
my Lord.
-Did you bring what I asked for?
-Yes, my Lord.
Is there any news?
Master Titus, Suleyman and his sons will
meet Oghuz Beys in...
...a caravansary by the Euphrates.
Oghuz Beys you say?
What is happening, Cornelius?
What are these Turks trying to do?
It is said that they are seeking
an alliance against Mongols, my Lord.
Damn them.
Is the ambassador of Seljuk coming,
as well?
Yes, my Lord. Aleaddin Keykubat
will send...
...Ata Bey Celaleddin Karatay himself.
This alliance is not solely
against the Mongols...
...but against the crusader army as well.
These Muslims.
If they learn to act as one for once, this
will be the end of all of us, Cornelius.
I cannot let that happen.
Suleyman and his offspring must never
reach the caravansary.
What do you want me to do, my Lord?
Go at once.
I will follow Ertugrul.
Gather the men.
Sun is about to set.
Let us spend the night here.
Have a look around.
As you wish, Bey.
We were in the roads for days, brother.
You kept your silence.
This saddens all of us.
However, father is the most worried.
Get yourself together.
Our duty has much importance.
You are right.
You are right brother...
...however I cannot stop myself
from thinking about Selcan.
And that heathen called Titus, as well.
Our maker will grant Selcan to you.
I believe that.
And Titus.
The one gives him to you will be me.
You will punish him for what he did to
both Dundar and your wife.
Trust me.
Father wishes to speak with us.
Let us go.
Be seated my sons.
It is safe here, Bey.
Since Titus has not attach us...
...he must be planning a trap for us
which we cannot escape.
You are right father.
He learned the cost of directly
attacking us.
He will set the trap near caravansary.
If God permits, we will reach caravansary
at sundown tomorrow.
If God permits, son. If God permits.
We are few in numbers.
Our duty is crucial.
We can surprise him by taking a road that
no one can anticipate.
This time he should be the one
falling our trap, father.
We need to finish this job without
any bloodshed.
But the most important thing is,
reaching caravansary in one piece.
Ointment is ready.
Eygis told me to put it on before
it loose its efficiency.
I will do it Halime. Put it there.
Mother.
Halime.
Wait daughter, I have things to say.
We would like to enlarge the rug house.
It seems that, from Damascus to Konya...
...everyone is asking for our rugs,
our textiles.
Praise be.
Even the merchants coming from Constantine
are asking for our goods.
We will send Wild Demir to Aleppo to
buy new handlooms.
This will cost us, Mother.
We will be using the loot that we obtained
from crusaders.
There is one more thing.
Both Suleyman Shah and me...
...want you to become
the head of the rug house.
So our wedding preparations should
continue as well, Mother.
Of course, it will continue daughter.
We should not be cut away from our
entertainment, right?
You are right. Of course.
If God permits, my daughter Selcan
also will get better.
I am saying that the peace will come to
our nomad group however...
...I do not know what is this
grayness I feel, Halime.
Simply, you are weary Mother.
Get some rest.
Wild Demir and I will prepare
for the rug house.
Do not worry, Mother.
Thank you, my dear daughter.
Thank you.
Let us put the ointment on her at once.
You both, go there.
And you, return to your spots.
Put two more men behind those bushes.
First act should be done by them.
After that, second archer unit will
attack to the Alps.
And finally cavalcade.
Yes, my Lord.
You all, return to your spots.
What happened?
There is no one here.
What do you wish us to do?
Get ready. We are going to caravansary.
Get ready. We are leaving.
Run Ertugrul.
Let us see how far you can go.
What if Banu Cicek fall for a brave man.
What can you do?
As a wild flower like that withering,
would bees leave it alone, brother?
Let us say bees become scared seeing that
Banu is so lively...
...what if her father gives his daughter
to a brave...
...ball of fire man then what can you do?
You know what.
What a foreboder man you are!
-What did I say?
-Damn the things you said.
Brother Turgut...
...this shy rooster do not stop
splitting hairs. He will do nothing.
If he is fallen for her, we need to nudge
this lazy brother a little.
You are a wicked man.
I wonder what will Titus do when he
realizes he cannot spot us.
Surely, he will follow us until we reach
to caravansary.
This will be the last trace
he will follow, father.
Live long, Suleyman Shah.
Live long, Ertugrul Bey.
Live long, Gundogdu Bey.
May your hands that collapsed the castle
of crusaders, will never bare hardship.
Suleyman.
Korkut.
Welcome to you all.
Thank you.
Welcome, Suleyman Bey.
The great Beys of Oghuz, thank you.
Praise be.
It seems that you overpowered
the crusaders with your brave sons.
They have to wait forever to be able to
gather their army back together again...
...to overpower us.
I am not saying this because
I am their uncle.
As long as you have these
brave sons of yours,...
...you can sweep over their armies
as well.
Thank you, Korkut. Thank you.
How is my sister Hayme?
She sent her regards.
Wishes you well, Korkut.
Korkut Bey is here as well.
It is time to talk then.
Should we ask for Banu Cicek for you?
Are you trying to drive me mad?
Make way.
Come, let us toy with him.
Do not. We have things to do.
We did not forget that...
...our son Ertugrul saved us from a major
disaster, Suleyman Bey.
Thank you.
Suleyman Shah is not here with us.
Because he collaborated with crusaders.
Lie!
This ignoble, casts aspersions on us.
The ones sow discord among Islam world...
...the ones who are trying to keep us
from pray in Jerusalem...
...now are trying to shatter Seljuk Empire
by set Oghuzs against one another.
This waste of a man who is trusted armies
by Selahaddin Ayyubi's descendants...
...is standing before you
as a crusader army dog.
May peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Suleyman Shah came with his sons Gundogdu
and Ertugrul, Ata Bey.
Thank God we heard about the conquest
that you have done with your sons...
...Suleyman Shah.
Our Sultan, Aleaddin Keykubat asked me
to bring his regards...
...as well as his greetings to you
and your sons.
Thank you, Ata Bey Karatay.
Give him my regards as well.
May he accept the gift that we brought him
for his marriage with Damascus queen.
Thank you, Suleyman Shah.
Without your efforts,
our Sultan's wedding...
...would not be taking place.
Our Sultan's love and respect will not
leave your side.
May God bless you.
Go ahead get seated, get some rest.
Let them bring ayran to us.
Let my nieces catch their breath.
Go ahead.
Ertugrul has come.
White bearded men will be receiving
Ertugrul this evening.
Hatuns.
I have things to say.
You are working for days without a break.
Some of you weaves cloths,
some of you weaves rugs.
Some of you stitches clothing for Alps,
some of you prepares armor.
However...
...even after we bought handlooms,
we did not make as much goods as intended.
I know you are weary.
But what will we do if we take
migration path up again?
What is more, the clothing and armor that
we made for Alps are not enough.
What I want to say Hatuns...
...until Suleyman Shah returns
to our nomad group...
...we have to reach the numbers
he gave us.
I am willing to teach my job to our
willing young women.
If we increase our numbers,
we will be able to make more goods.
Do you understand me, Hatuns?
-Understood, Halime.
-Understood.
Thank you Hatuns. May is be easy.
-Thank you.
It is clear that she will be the
Mother of our nomad group in the future.
She is already aching to be in her
mother in law's favor.
How is your back, father?
It is nothing compared to facing
a sore like Kurtoglu, son.
We pull through many sores.
Hearing that from Konya Palace to
Cairo Palace...
...everyone praising you,
brings me honor son.
Your abilities and...
...intelligence surpassed me tenfold.
Not at all, father.
It should surpass, son.
You are the only one among us
that has Bey vision and state vision.
Upon seeing your abilities...
...I realized this fact as well.
You showed us that our nomad group
will live on.
After I am gone...
...you will shoulder the burden of
our nomad group.
Father.
Your brother knows this as well, son.
He embraced it.
You should prepare yourself to this,
as well.
It is certain that we will return to our
nomad group with a new mission, son.
May God favor us.
Amen, father.
Then what happened Konur Alp?
Banu Cicek did not marry that man
as well Turgut.
Gosh.
Among many candidates, why does not she
pick one?
It is said that she has fallen
for someone.
Gosh.
I wonder who is that man?
Have you seen Ertugrul Bey?
Here he comes.
What did Dogan do?
He is tending the servants of caravansary,
Bey.
Like you said brother, do not be surprised
if there is a crusader among them.
Bamsi and I will take a look around
as well.
Let us see if that waste of a man
Titus came so far out here.
Be careful.
-As you wish, Bey.
Turgut.
I do not like this Afsin Bey, brother.
Especially when they do things in secret
with Bey, I became very irritated.
Irritated, brother.
Let us mind our business, brother.
Come with me.
You will go in alone.
Why are you not coming in, Afsin?
Our rank is not sufficient, Bey.
Go ahead.
May peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul.
Be seated.
You asked for me.
Yes, son.
We asked for you to see the face of the
one we have been hearing about.
To understand the mind of the one we
have seen before us.
I am listening.
You have been in and out of many wars...
...go through many hardships...
...meeting enemies, seeing the world.
Tell me, what is the state of the world.
World is in a crisis.
On one hand there is crusaders,
on the other Mongols...
...and then there is us, fighting a war
over Anatolia.
All in power knows that
dominating the Anatolia...
...means dominating the world.
Then, which one of you will succeed
in your opinion?
Crusaders came here with a great force.
When they departed they had the purpose of
taking hold of the Jerusalem.
However...
...every time they arrived here
they forgot their purpose and...
...went for the loot instead.
Mongols...
...they want to come to Anatolia...
...however they are like a hungry wolf
attacking the herd.
They go back once they are full.
Then us?
What do you say about us?
We first came to Anatolia under the
leadership of Tugrul and Cagri Bey's.
Then Sultan Alparslan...
...with battle of Manzikent,
opened the doors of Anatolia for us.
However...
...our unity is broken down.
If we can unite...
...and provide justice...
...Anatolia will be ours.
Son, if you wish these lands to be ours...
...you need to listen to me carefully.
And not even once, you will leave our
advices aside.
Even my weapon sheds rubies...
...as long as I am alive I will fight
for this purpose.
And I will wave the flag of justice once
more in Anatolia.
Gokce.
I brought you supper.
Gokce, have I done something to
break your heart?
My sister was always ambitious.
She committed many sins.
But she was right at one thing.
Ertugrul.
When Ertugrul saved you from crusaders and
brought you to our nomad tent...
...she told me that nothing will be
the same ever again.
She was right.
Maybe if you did not came
to this nomad tent...
...this would not happen to my sister,
Halime.
Are you still talking about Ertugrul,
Gokce?
I thought that you were done with this
matter after everything that happened.
I am done.
While suffering this pain...
...while ripping Ertugrul
out of my heart...
...I did not do this for your sake,
Halime.
I did it for Ertugrul.
For his happiness.
I hope that you will cherish him
the way he deserves.
I will take my leave then.
Mother.
O God, let Your Peace come upon
Muhammad and the family of Muhammad.
Mother, are you alright?
May God favor us daughter,
I had a dream, I am alright.
May God favor us.
Wait Mother, I will give you some water.
Take it Mother, drink.
I have been seeing the same dream
in the last couple of days.
A river, flows thick and fast.
However.
However what, Mother?
However, Suleyman...
Master Titus, there is no way to go in.
How about the kitchen?
Unfortunately we were not able to
poison the cauldrons.
They are pouring the food out and make it
once more in their own ways.
Korkut Bey brought women from his
nomad tent to prepare food.
Then, are we able to learn
what they are discussing inside?
Of course, my Lord.
Our inside man will come to inform you.
Are you talking about fighting against
Mongols, Karatay?
To protect the state of Aleaddin,
do you want to sacrifice us...
...while there is so few of us
left already?
The state of Sultan Aleaddin, opened
his arms to the fullest to embrace Oghuzs.
Bad blood in the past has been dealt with.
To what cost?
There is blood shed all over us.
What happens when Sultan Aleaddin
abdicate the throne?
Similar to old days,
who knows what the new Sultan...
...after acquiring the throne,
will do to us?
Hayat Bey is right.
Every hardship falls on us, nomads.
We will fight to our last breath.
However, no one stood beside us
in our hard times.
He is right.
What Hayat Bey said is right.
We are always the ones that left behind.
Beys...
...elders of my kin...
...I agree with you
from the bottom of my heart.
We were belittled for being nomads.
Both Ayyubis and Farisis acted this way.
We were pushed around.
However, Sultan Aleaddin is different.
Like Ata Bey said...
...he opened his arms to embrace
all of us.
Great Beys of my kin
whom I know their bravery well...
...there is no one among ourselves
who does not know how many Alps...
...fallen martyr fighting against
crusaders.
We learned many things in this war.
We would like to hear what you learned
from you, Ertugrul Bey.
Every problem starts from within.
I say...
...we should not be the mite that
gnaw to this almighty sycamore...
...which has been planted
by Alparslan himself.
If this almighty sycamore falls over,
we all will get buried by it.
Our voyage that started in Otuken, will
come to an end in this beautiful land.
Beys...
...against Mongol demons coming
in waves from east...
...and crusaders rise deviously
from west...
...our job is to unite as one
under the holy coat of Ahmet Yesevi.
If we cannot become united as one...
...we would be betraying both
our voyage from Otuken...
...and the heritage of Yesevi.
May almighty God...
...preserves us from
disobeying our prophet's legacy.
For that, great Beys of Oghuzs...
...I say it is time to unite as one.
Islam world is shattered.
The resurrection fire that we scorch...
...will spread to the world and a new Turk
seigniory will come to light.
Now...
...I say that we unite against Mongols...
...and close our ranks in Anatolia.
Do you agree to this unity Beys?
Suleyman Shah...
...history will write this things that
you have done one day.
We are throwing ourselves into
the fire again.
Up until today, this degenerate entrapped
us time and time again.
Now it is his turn to be entrapped.
God is the most favorable of the ones
that set traps.
Come on.
I know that we have no other choice
as well, father.
However, is it right to go against
Mongols, solely with swords at hand?
You talk about a unity.
What if the unity breaks down?
Then, what can we do all alone?
I feel your worries as well, son.
However Kayis destiny is already set.
Our way points towards Anatolia.
And there is no way back from it.
May God favor us.
Thank you, brother.
Bey.
Bey you were right.
Titus is here.
He came by the caravansary
with his knights.
We confirmed his location.
Finally.
Our paths came across.
Let us see if you are as brave as you are
going against women and children.
At least I am not as stupid as going
against the whole world as you do.
As long as you follow God's will,
no matter if you are alone Titus.
But a lost demon like you would not
be able to understand that.
I will collapse the order that you created
by treachery and betrayal, around you.
Me and my kin.
So do we.
We will not stop until you go back
the hell you came from.
We all came from God,
we will return to him.
But soon you will see the hell
you will go back to.
Come and send me there then.
Kill me Turk.
You are the destiny of my brother.
Victory will be God's.
We do not doubt that, praise God.
We have a long way ahead.
Thank you, brother.
We should not keep the ones missing us
waiting any longer.
Thank you.
Upon seeing you people will think that
you are not a new bride...
...but a mourning widower, Halime Sultan.
What is wrong?
Why are you so sad?
Gokce.
Tell me. What happened?
She still talks about Ertugrul.
How about her heart?
The wound of her heart poisons her tongue.
I do not know how long
this will go on, Aykiz.
She told Ertugrul that he is
as her brother however...
Her heart will get cold, do not worry.
While trying to put out the fire in her
heart, she went through a lot of pain.
Finally, Selcan.
There is no one that she can confide
in as well.
Do not give her a hard time.
It will all pass.
What if it does not happen
the way you think?
Then what can we do, Aykiz?
How can we face one another
in this nomad tent?
Good bye.
Thank you, Afsin.
After you set your nomad tent, I will come
as soon as possible, if God permits.
Afsin Bey.
I will tell you one thing.
Do tell.
Say the thing you have been keeping
to yourself and be at ease.
Father of lineage Yigit.
Did you kill him?
Bamsi.
I am sorry, Bey.
I could not get a hold of my tongue again.
We were always one of those who
had a duty, Bamsi.
May God help us in our new duty.
May God grant you to be the ones...
...not hurting their loved ones
but helping their lives prosper.
Good bye.
Father.
We can stay in caravansary, if you wish.
We can leave tomorrow.
I am alright, alright.
We have much to do in our nomad group.
It became our destiny to migrate again
before the end of summer.
It is said, Korkut Ata from Hayat tribe,
one man stands tall.
Korkut Ata says...
...in those times, when a boy does not
shed blood they would not name him.
And they would not give their ranks
to Beys.
-Gosh!
When the boys ride horses, wield swords,
shoot arrows...
...be brave as you are...
...then they would become subjected to
the training of becoming an Alp.
Do you think we do deserve such training,
as Suleyman Shah says, Wild Demir?
Of course my brave boy.
Did you not open the way to us
to go into the castle of crusaders?
Did you not stand against enemies
in Aleppo?
Did you not protect our ancestors' honor
by not being fooled by their threats?
Dundar...
...you, did you not save your father,
your family and your nomad group...
...by standing against the cowardly Titus?
If you did not, Kurtoglu would unite...
...with him and kill your father and
your brothers.
I did not do anything, Wild Demir.
Only...
Dundar.
The best quality of an Alp is humility.
As I see it, thank God you both have it.
Humility, honesty, hospitality,
generosity.
An Alp should not act arrogantly.
Should not think himself as superior.
Kara Polat should own his mind's sword.
Should act without pity.
One cannot become an Alp if he is fond
of riches.
Though he cannot be a man as well,
anyhow.
The one you call Alp should learn to tan
somebody's hide from his ancestors.
He should stand a man on his horse.
Children plays with mind's sword,
but man must own it.
He should protect other's order.
He should not know lies.
Shedding blood is not enough to become
an Alp.
Virtue and merit are the most important
things that made one an Alp, indeed.
And of course, a sword.
An Alps needs a sword as virtuous and
skillful as he is.
I am making these swords for you.
As I did for Suleyman Shah, Gundogdu
and Ertugrul.
Where did Suleyman Shah go, Wild Demir?
There is no way to run from the Mongols
that chase us for years, brave boy.
It is high time to make a unity and
stop this calamity.
We either win and live or we die.
There is no other way.
Is that the reason of them leaving?
Yes, son.
May God help them.
Amen.
Should we rest here for a while, Bey?
You take me for an old man.
How could that be, father?
You could take all of us down,
with God's help.
We said it for the horses.
Bey.
Let’s go cross the river first and
take a look around.
Hurry.
I am thankful to you, my God.
Thank you for giving us a heart to stop
and listen to all this beauty...
...you have created and to embrace them
with good sight.
Thank You for letting me
follow Your way for a lifetime...
...and permitting me to raise
my brave sons.
Thank You, for giving me a short and
pleasant life, like the sound...
...of this nightingale,
united with my sons' mother.
Father.
Father!
I trust our nomad group in your hands.
Protect our nomad group...
...from all the kinds of evil,
like you do for your wives...
...and for your children.
Obey the laws of our ancestor Oghuz...
...and the state of Seljuk
that came from it.
Be one and lively.
Bey?
Bey.
Bey!
Rest in peace, Bey.
I intend to say my prayers
for God's sake.
To pray for the Meyyit.
For a man...
What are your thoughts on the deceased?
He was a good person.
-Do you give your blessings?
-Yes, we do.
-Do you?
Brave sons of Kayi,
may God, Who turns night into day...
...day into sun, bare witness,
this is not a tale.
The story I will tell is the real story
of a blessed way and voyage...
...that will reach from Otuken mountains
to Anatolia...
...from Anatolia to many conquests
and conquerors.
This story is the story that made
our Bey, Suleyman Shah...
...amongst many other Beys.
Suleyman Shah is the one who
never turned his back on humility...
...bravery, chivalry...
...and God's justice,
the one who knew that...
...being united as one means to exist...
...the one who is the gem of
the Turkic history...
...to be told by our ancestors
until today...
...and from this day forth.
From Oghuz Khan to today,
from today to many Sultans...
...and many conquests, he is a victorious
Bey in our glorious history...
...who has been entrusted to carry on
yesterday's history to tomorrow’s.
He protected this trust with his own life.
He never let his nomad group go
hungry or be alone.
He never turned his back on God's justice.
He always knew his God
and his ancestor's laws.
He fought but never lost either
to his own self or to the enemy.
Neither the betrayals that came from
the ones who are close to him nor...
...other hardships were able to
turn him away from his ways.
Neither the cruelty of a tyrant, nor the
power of the heathen could stop him.
For him, Kayi was entrusted to him
by his children.
He carried that trust to this day,
as a Bey, as a Shah...
...as Suleyman Shah, so that you could be
conquerors so that...
...there will be no cruelty or
tyrants left, with God's permission.
Now that trust is yours.
It is a debt. It is our burden.
May God bestow his graces upon him.
And may God put you in the way
of many conquests, if God permits.
Do not forget my children,
you are his descendants.
Never forget that
My Shah went to heaven.
Father? Where is my father?
Where is my father, brother?
You have to be strong.
Your father would’ve also wished for that.
Let him, let him feel the pain of his
closest friend, Aykiz.
Is it true?
Ertugrul.
My father died in peace.
Any other way would not suit him,
anyhow.
May he rest in peace.
May God give you longevity.
Before he died...
...he asked us to go to Anatolia.
A hard and painful life starts
once more, Halime.
It is okay.
Wherever you are
is my home, after all.
And where my nomad group goes is
my homeland as well.
May God keep you beside me.
If God gives us a son,
we should name him Suleyman.
For that blessed man's sacred memory.
Bey.
Your father tells me that
he died in peace.
You are right, Wild Demir.
He died in peace.
God's and his loved ones' names
on his tongue, in peace.
Where are we going to migrate, Bey?
We will go to the path that Alparslan
cleared, Wild Demir.
We can go to your father's grave and
say our prayers for him...
...before the winter comes, can we not?
Be seated.
In the 99 names of almighty God,
who creates with his word...
...and blesses our hearts with faith.
In the name of the God.
My Beys, my brave men,
supremes of my nomad group...
...welcome, you bring grace to us.
-Thank you.
Our Bey, Suleyman Shah, assigned me
as a substitute before he died.
Now, we will determine
our nomad group's future...
...without Suleyman Shah.
We are relieved to hear that...
...Suleyman Shah assigned you as
a substitute, Mother Hayme.
Otherwise, we would now
be dealing with...
...the Bey issue and be stumbling.
Thank you, Wild Demir. Thank you.
In the last discussion that we had
with Oghuz Beys, it was said that...
...the Mongols were harassing Anatolia.
Small Mongol units started running raids
in Anatolia lands.
It is high time to stop this
flock of cruelty.
What can we do when there are a thousand
Mongol for every Kayi, Mother Hayme?
Not only us Kayis...
...all the Oghuz nomad groups know that
this alliance is the last resort.
For that, all the Oghuz nomad groups
will gather in Anatolia.
If we do not stand up as one, and stand
tall...
...if we keep bad blood between us...
...we can only be the prey for those
jackal Mongols. Prey!
That said,
it is still good to be cautious.
As you know, we endured many hardships
and sufferings coming to Aleppo.
As we are free from the crusaders...
...why would we set off on
another journey, once again?
Son.
Suleyman Shah made an effort
to create this alliance.
On one hand, there are crusaders
and on the other, there are Mongols.
A new world order is
being set as a shameless...
...ruthless and bloody order as it is.
In this order, we need to be together,
either with the scared dogs...
...or with the Alps who are standing tall.
I say, in this mortal life,
let us go against the world!
Even if we know that only one of us
will stand in the end...
...let us fight these tyrants.
And I say...
...it is high time to seek revenge
on the Mongols.
They killed our children,
our mothers, our sisters.
If we do not stand against them...
...this world will not find peace.
You are right, Wild Demir.
Now, what do you say to
going back to the Anatolia lands...
...that we came from, Beys?
I do not wish to set off.
However, headquarters
has reached a verdict...
...and surely I must concur.
Thank you.
Hit the drums.
It is time for us to set off on a journey.
It is time to stop those Mongol bandits!
May God help us all.
Amen!
Kayis set on the road
for the resurrection of Anatolia.
As they set forth, history would change.
As they set forth, cruelty would end
and justice would prevail.