Episode 18 will start after 12:14 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
This is it, sons.
You do not have permission
for the rest of the way.
I will not be back for a while.
Wait here until I am back.
You will not go out of this circle...
-...until I come back.
-Yes, master.
As to you, son...
When I come back,
what lies in your heart will be revealed.
You will not go
out of this circle as well.
Do not worry. I will not.
Alright. May God help you.
Where does Ibn al-Arabi go?
Who knows...
When will the sheikh be back?
What is known, then?
One's place, sir. One's place.
My sheikh told you not to go
out of this circle.
And told you that what lies in your heart
would be revealed.
Sit down and wait.
Peace be upon you.
The community of peaceful people.
May community be beneficial,
your prayers accepted...
...and your hearts joyful.
Welcome. Your brought joy to us.
You were out of our sight,
but you were not out of our hearts.
Thank you, Brother Salih.
Thank God for bringing us together.
Everything is for a reason.
God creates everything for a reason.
Even if we do not know the reason,
we accept our fate.
When I look at the Islamic world, I feel
like we are at times just before Doomsday.
The Islamic ummah
is the ummah just before Doomsday.
Our prophet is the last.
And we are the ummah of the afternoon.
However, only God knows
the exact time of Doomsday.
Our duty is to plant a sapling
if we have one in our hands.
It is God who expands and contracts time.
KAYİ TENT
Gokce...
Ertugrul, press it tight.
We have to stop the blood.
Ertugrul...
You...
Are you alright?
We will both be alright, Gokce.
Do not worry.
Call the midwifes in.
Alright.
Gokce...
The day our Prophet
conquered Mecca...
...he broke down all the idols
in Kaaba.
How a holy day it was.
Do you think it is easier
to break down the idols inside us...
...than to break down the ones
in Kaaba, Bey?
You are right, Hayme.
The ones who worship idols of arrogance
are all over my tent, even my marquee.
Who are you talking about? Kurdoglu?
It is not only him.
He also poisons my Gundogdu.
I can see that.
You turned out to be right
one more time.
And I made a mistake one more time
by not listening to you.
My son Gundogdu will understand
everything sooner or later.
My blood brother
cannot accept me being the bey.
My decisions are not approved
by our people.
What is the point for me
to be on the seat as a bey?
And I cannot overcome
my own illness, either.
What if they get their foot on the door
when you are not in the marquee?
What if they create obstacles
for the tent with unexpected problems?
I will do what is necessary
until the idols of arrogance are broken.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in.
Alpargu...
...entered Akcakoca's tent
to kill Ertugrul Bey.
Tell me, Adiote. I am listening.
When will this Selcan Hatun matter
come to an end?
When will we be even?
I will tell you when that time comes.
Now, tell me.
Tell me, woman! Can you not talk?
Why did Mother Hayme send men
to his brother Korkut's tent?
What is she up to with her brother?
It is a girl matter.
Girl matter?
What gives?
Who is she trying to find a girl to?
Speak!
To Gundogdu Bey.
Ertugrul...
Let us go and
let the midwives do their work.
Get this bastard out of here.
Wait.
Talk, you low-down bastard! Talk!
Were you the traitor in the tent?
I said talk!
Were you the traitor in the tent,
or was it Kurdoglu?
Talk!
Tell me!
Talk, man!
Talk!
He is dead, Ertugrul.
Take him out.
Ertugrul, son!
Sit down.
How is Gokce?
She almost gave her life to save mine.
The reason that I live is her.
The Islamic world is
going through a big test.
Tests are all around us.
Islam was born as a light,
and it enlightened the world.
But now the Islamic world is on fire.
Our predecessors carried Islam
to Andalucian, India and Sindh.
However, the successors
are busy with ambushing each other.
The magnificent tree
that has taken root in Medina...
...is now being pruned.
Its branches are being broken.
Everything will be alright
when Mahdi comes.
Only what God wants will happen.
We will not sadden.
We will not wait. We will not stop.
We will refuge to God
like in the first days of Islam...
...and we will always strive.
We will make effort
in order for this light to spread.
Has our prophet not ordered us...
...to plant the sapling in our hands
even if it is Doomsday?
Tell us, Sheikh Muhyiddin...
...what is the reason for you
to come here from Andalucia?
Which sapling
did you come here for to plant?
When God wanted me
to come here from Andalucia...
...I noticed this was
a different kind of travel.
I noticed that I would not come back.
I was leaving Andalucia for good.
I refuged to God and asked...
God, I know there is a reason
for everything you create.
What is your reason
for sending me in foreign lands?
God inspired within my heart...
"The reason for this travel...
...is a pearl drop
waiting to me picked out of deep sea.
You will bring him up.
You will train him.
And he will train others.
He will be the
leader of the holy generation...
...that will bring Islam to humanity."
What did you do, man?
God, forgive him.
What are you whispering for?
I said what is going on?
Sister Gokce...
In Akcakoca's tent...
-They say she is seriously wounded.
-What are you talking about?
Alpargu stabbed her.
Bring some water!
Move aside!
Kurdoglu is behind this, father.
-Ertugrul...
-Halime knows it from the beginning.
She is suspicious of him...
...since the day their tent have been
attacked by Kara Toygar.
Just like her late father.
Just like Shahzade Yigit.
I did not say anything to anybody
besides Ertugrul Bey.
Alpargu was one of the
closest beys to him.
It is impossible for him to do such a
thing without Kurdoglu knowing it.
If he is the traitor,
it will be revealed soon.
How?
Gundogdu set up a track.
If you are right,
Kurdoglu will fall into that trap.
I hope you are right.
At last you did this to my sister, too.
It is all because of you, Ertugrul.
The troubles you caused
come back and hit us.
Shame on you!
Selcan!
Alpargu was the one
who tried to kill Gokce.
Direct your hatred to the right person
if you have to.
How could they do this to you, my dear?
Did they stamp on the fresh spring flower
with their boots on?
Did they rip the mare's flesh
before she even sucked milk?
My dear sister, you be well,
and let your sister be buried.
We were all your children.
Until that ominous girl showed up.
Mother, get us out of this trouble
until it is too late.
Or Ertugrul will be the reason
of the disaster that will destroy us.
His name was told to me.
He is such a brave man that
he will bring glory to the Islamic world.
He will turn defeat to victory.
The Islamic tree that was pruned
will turn green again.
The flag of Islam
will extend to Konstantiniyye...
...as our Prophet told us.
Then, it will spread to the whole world
from there.
Muslim, Christian, Jew...
Everybody will be under its shade.
They will drink the water from
Islam's source of life under that tree.
And I was wondering what the reason for
Sheikh Muhyiddin to come here was.
Tell us about that brave man.
So that our prayers will be with him.
So that the help of the elders
will be with him.
What will the person's qualities
that will carry the holy relic...
...that will bring victory to Islam be?
First of all, the person who will carry
the relic will be clever.
However, he will not deem cleverness
as cunningness.
He will look with the light of foresight.
He will distinguish the good and the bad
in a dark night.
He will be merciful.
However, he will not limit mercy
with having pity.
He will be fair.
Hazrat Omar said...
..."Possession and power
is based on justice."
He will know that justice
that does not give God his share...
...is persecution itself.
He will be very brave.
He will have courage.
But he will know that
the strongest courage...
...is holding yourself back
under the situation of anger and lust.
A person who cannot control his hand,
mouth and lust cannot be a ruler.
He will be forgiving.
His fight will be for God.
He will have possessions,
but he will not lay claims on them.
He will see the elders of the people
he rules as his father...
...and the young ones
as his brothers and sisters...
...and the little ones as his children.
He who wants to be the leader of this
ummah should have these qualities.
The community of the peaceful men...
...the ummah waits for
somebody like this.
The troubles we are going through
points out to him.
It is as if we are in the time of dawn.
As if we hear the morning breeze.
Dawn, that is, the closest time
to morning is our time now.
"Give the power to the competent ones.
Give everything back to the ones
who own them."
Of course, our prayers
will be with this brave man.
So, who is this brave man?
Ertugrul, from the Kayi Tribe.
And with God's permission, a big army
that consists of his descendants.
Help!
-Do not worry.
-Help!
Just a man who does not
know his place.
Help!
Would you allow us?
Are you alright, Ertugrul Bey?
I am alright, Wild Demir.
And Gokce?
She is seriously wounded.
Was the traitor Alpargu, Bey?
We will know soon, Wild Demir.
I know it is not the time...
...but... our guest, Bey.
Isadora. She wants to say
some important things.
Who are you, my girl?
I am coming from the Templars' castle.
My name is Isadora Manzini.
I am Grandmaster
Petruchio Manzini's niece.
There are things
I would like to tell Ertugrul Bey.
-Isadora?
-Yigit!
It is so good to see you again.
You cannot lay a hand on him
before Gundogdu Bey comes.
Let us make this murderer pay, Hamza.
This bastard stabbed Ertugrul Bey.
There is the blood of
so many Alps in this hands.
Enough!
I will cut whoever comes close up.
Gundogdu Bey left him to me!
Do you not understand?
Hamza!
What is going on here?
Alps want reprisal, Bey.
Reprisal is their right.
But first, it is Ertugrul's right.
Do not forget, Turgut is Ertugrul's alp.
The first person who can
spill his blood is Ertugrul.
Sultan Alaeddin will never forget
what you have done.
As I said, he wants to see
you and Ertugrul Bey in Malatya.
My brother will accept your invitation
when he gets well.
-I would also like to come.
-Of course.
My Alps will escort you to Damascus.
I hope we can meet again,
Gundogdu Bey.
-Give me your blessing.
-You, too, Ersagun Bey.
Hamza, we will take him to tent ourselves.
-Yes, Bey.
-Good. Get that bastard prepared.
Son, you confused us
with your Templar masters.
You cannot go over the line
that is set for you.
You cannot pass it.
It seems like the people that trained you
have not taught you this.
These pains will be with you
until you arrive the Kayi Tent.
Suffer, so that you can understand
the people you made suffer.
Is there not another remedy?
My father said he will be in very serious
pain if he does not take his pills.
And then, unfortunately...
There is another remedy for sure.
I am very sorry.
Is my Turgut going to die?
We will pray all
for him to die without suffering.
Did you come here
to tell us Turgut will die?
No.
I came for my father's death wish.
His Sheikh Ibn al-Arabi
wanted him to help the Kayis in his dream.
That is why I am here.
And if you would like to
bring that ominous castle down...
...I will tell you how to do it.
I cannot take my father
out of there by myself.
But if you attack, there will be
an opportunity for my father.
Tell me, would you recognize that traitor
that came to your castle?
I know he came there twice
to talk to my uncle.
Once I was in the room.
I saw him, but not clearly. I did not
raise my head and look into his eyes.
You cannot imagine how many traitors
come to that castle from these lands.
I wish I could kill that bastard.
It was granted to Sister Gokce.
I hope she will not get sick.
If she had not entered Akcakoca's tent,
Ertugrul Bey would also be...
Do you really believe
this loser is a traitor?
Yes?
No.
I mean, yes, but...
...not by himself.
He is Suleyman Shah's friend
from childhood.
His blood brother.
So, Suleyman Shah cannot believe it.
But we all know from which tent
trouble spreads out.
Come with me, my girl.
Was this the traitor?
He is very similar.
I wish I could remember.
You...
Sister Isadora...
This lady
helped us to break out of the castle.
We would be dead if it was not for her.
Where are you going?
I was going to thump some medicine.
Be quick.
Yes, Selcan Hatun.
Those ominous people...
...put my sweet sister
in this situation.
God damn you all.
Back to work!
My beautiful Gokce.
If anything happens to you...
Gokce Hatun will live, Selcan Hatun.
How do you know?
She is a strong girl.
He will overcome this, too, but...
But what?
The wound is on her groin.
She will not be having a baby anymore.
Look at me!
If anybody hears this,
I will strip your skin with my own hands.
-Do you understand?
-I did. Please let go of me.
Come here tomorrow.
I will give you gold in amount that
you have not seen in your life.
How is Gokce?
She is very well, mother.
She will get well, with God's permission.
I will not let her die
before she gets married.
My revenge will be so harsh.
I will make you pay
for what you made me suffer.
You, your husband...
...and his offsprings.
Uncle Kurdogdu is not around.
If he is the traitor,
whom I think he is...
...he must be
looking for a place to hide.
Bey, you will get mad at me again...
...but what if this woman
is the Templars' new trick?
What if she came for new trouble?
I vouch for her.
She protected
me and the young Shahzade.
And who is going to vouch for you?
Bamsi...
Anybody wants ayran soup?
Forget the soup.
Let us check the horses.
We just checked them.
Then check again, moron!
Do not worry, they will not kick you.
Bey...
Gokce...
She was so young
when she came to our marquee.
She would cry all day in her swaddle.
Her mother died
while she was giving birth to her.
Even though Selcan was
7 years old when she came...
...she was like a
mother and sister to her.
Two girls had come amongst three boys.
Our order was messed up completely.
If my mother could cope with three boys,
it is because of Selcan.
She did not complain even once.
She helped my mother,
and she was like a mother to Gokce.
That is why she is mad at you.
She actually hates you.
It is because of me.
Do not worry.
I can cope with Selcan's anger.
What about Gokce's sorrow?
Can you cope with it?
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS' CASTLE
Sultan Alaeddin must have noticed
that we have sneaked as far as Konya.
Otherwise he would not change his way
and want help from the Kayis.
He does not trust
even the soldiers of the Ayyubid emeers.
Gundogdu escorted the train
because Ertugrul was wounded.
He is as dangerous as Ertugrul.
We need Gundogdu.
If he goes after his ambition,
he will serve us a lot.
When we get rid of
Suleyman Shah and Ertugrul...
...we will leave him
to his uncle's compassionate hands.
Yes, sir.
Bur sir, what about Isadora
and the Cardinal?
I have very nice plans for both of them.
I do not doubt, sir.
You will set off to Damascus
tomorrow with Eftelya.
If we cannot prevent this marriage...
...everything our cult has been
striving for will be under risk.
Do you understand me?
Are you alright, sir?
It feels like the lust of death
is wrapping around my body.
Is it possible to save yourself from it?
Would you like me to call in a healer?
Sleep... Some sleep.
You Teuton half-breed bastard!
I hope you not wake up.
Good.
Even the Grandmaster
could not praise the Templars more.
You deserved to be the Pope
exceedingly, Thomas.
If you can reach these passages
and open the closed tunnels...
...you will reach the dungeon.
I drew this
according to what my father told me.
There may be a margin of error.
Are all the passages closed?
I know two of them are open.
But neither my father
nor I know where they are.
What do you think, Wild Demir?
Is it possible?
Bey...
...it could take months
to open these passages.
But it is not impossible.
However, there is something
I am scared of.
Think about it.
If there is a traitor in this tent...
...and if he informs them...
...we will fall into trap with hundreds of
Alp trying to pass those passages.
And nobody will survive.
Will you not rescue my father?
I think Wild Demir should check
all the tunnels, anyway.
If you are right about
what you just said...
...we will bring that castle
down on them.
Be patient, my girl.
We cannot proceed
before we catch the traitor.
Bey...
I say we confront my uncle
and Isadora if you permit.
Let us see what Kurdoglu does
when he sees Isadora.
This is all because of you.
It is not because of me.
-It is because of our common enemies.
-This is not the first time!
Your father lost his life
in the cause of fighting Suleyman.
This is nothing.
The game is just starting.
That girl who came
to the tent, Isadora.
She is coming from the castle.
She might recognize me.
Suleyman may call me into the marquee
any moment to confront us.
If this happens,
it will not be good for any of us.
What are we going to do?
First, we must get rid of that Isadora.
What if she recognizes you?
Talk!
What did they give to you?
Did they give gold? Seat?
My name is Judas.
They will cause your breed extinct.
Which are you from?
Get him out.
Sit down.
Tell me. What happened.
Did anybody from the Templars
or my uncle come?
No, Bey.
Neither the Crusaders, nor Kurdoglu.
Nobody came.
Then my uncle is not a traitor.
If he was, they would certainly come
to ambush Alaeddin's train.
Your uncle is innocent.
Hopefully, he will be one of your biggest
supporters on the way to be the bey.
Everybody knows
how much Kurdoglu loves and respects you.
Be at ease, Bey.
Thank you, Hamza.
What would I do
if anything happened to you?
My dear sister.
The faithful friend of her sister.
What would I say to my father?
How could I say
"I could not protect her."
Father?
Forgive me, father.
I could not protect my sister
from Suleyman's offspring.
Please forgive me.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in.
Suleyman Shah
invites you to his marquee, Bey.
Go. I am coming.
I was with Gokce.
Thankfully, she is alright.
She will wake up soon.
Shall I prepare you
something to eat?
Thank you.
There is a matter waiting to be solved.
You better wait inside.
As you wish, Bey.
Let me check Dundar, then.
Here I am, Bey.
Have a seat, Kurdoglu.
I think your guest mixed me up
with somebody.
I am sorry.
No problem.
Everybody is similar to somebody.
What is it, Deli? I have not seen you
with a weapon for so long.
Wherever a craftsman
girds on his weapon...
...that place is uncanny
from then on, Kurdoglu.
For a tent to be out of being uncanny...
...everybody should be
as outspoken as Ertugrul.
Outspoken, such that he would
come to my tent in the night time...
...and blame me of being a traitor.
Is this true, Ertugrul?
It is, father.
I did what my uncle deserves.
I did not resent, Bey.
This shows how good his heart is.
But I will make him pay...
...when his thoughts
turn out to be delusions.
Am I right, Ertugrul?
It is your duty to teach a person...
...who says bad words
to his elders his place.
However, even if
one of those bad words are accurate...
...then everybody is obliged to do
what is necessary.
Alright.
They said you wanted to see me, Bey.
This lady mistakenly
crossed the border and got lost.
It is best to be cautious, Bey.
You know everybody who comes
to the tent brings new troubles.
If this is it, I will do
what is necessary.
Thank you, Kurdoglu.
Alright.
Excuse me.
What do you think?
Was it him?
I wish I could remember.
It will be very dangerous for you
to return to the castle, then.
If the traitor is still here,
your end will be like your sister's.
Oh, Ertugrul.
If you were in your brother's place...
After all that torture and medicines,
he both forgot his name and his real self.
The only thing he did not forget
was you, Aykiz.
No human could resist
those tortures.
They turned him on a wheel
naked in cold weather.
They did all kinds of tortures.
But he did not stop saying your name
even a single moment.
May God bless you, Isadora.
Sister...
Is sister Gokce alright?
She is, Bey.
She will wake up tomorrow.
Thank you.
You have always been
my little sister, Gokce.
How did we end up like this?
How are we going to overcome this
without saddening you?
How?
Forgive me for yelling at you,
Ertugrul Bey.
Gokce is the sister of both of us.
I understand you.
We are hurt.
But nobody is hurt
as much as her, Ertugrul Bey.
Even the dagger that cut her flesh
did not hurt her as much as you.
Gokce...
You know there is something
regarding the two of us.
My father wants to see you
as his daughter-in-law.
But my heart beats for someone else.
You are my sister
whom I grew up with.
There is nothing beyond this for me.
I just wanted you to know that.
I know, Ertugrul Bey.
Your heart only says "Halime Sultan".
One who waits for the loved one
is bound to be saddened.
I can only accept this saddening now.
I will not come to you
unless you tell me to.
I will wait for you until I die
if necessary.
Do not worry.
This matter is between you
and your father from now on.
Keep in mind that I accepted my fate.
Sometimes you look at the Moon.
You reach out to it.
You want to hold it between your hands.
As if you would hold it tight.
Next thing you know,
it moves away from you.
You try again.
You take another step.
Then again.
Again.
No good even if you try
until you reach the end of your rope.
You are like the Moon
who enlightens my night, Halime Sultan.
Whenever I reach out to you...
...whenever I hold you...
...earth shook and both worlds
tangled into each other.
My friends became my enemies,
and my enemies became my friends.
The ones I love the most
rubbed salt in my wound.
Especially, my father
He wanted me to marry Gokce
as part of his will.
I have nothing other than you.
Everything other than you
means nothing to me.
I may be the one
who enlightens your night...
...but I receive my light from you.
You know where I am
when you want to reach out to me.
I always wait for you there.
Be at ease.
Do not ever be in despair
while you love me.
The taste of love is as much as
the effort made to reach it.
How could one know
love that does not crack their skin...
...if they have not burned
in the wind of the steppe.
Let our wounds bleed first.
So that we will be satisfied
with the water.
Let us be hungry,
so that we could enjoy the meal.
Let us miss each other,
so that we could appreciate rejoining.
Thank God for the gazelle
that took me to you...
...and thank God for sending it to me.
The Cardinal must still be sound asleep.
He wrote your goals
one by one to the Pope...
...with the excitement of
being the new Pope.
Especially his words to
Emperor Friedrich were like a poem.
He praises you.
Good.
Well done, Eftelya.
Alright. Have a safe trip.
I am waiting for good news
from Damascus.
Even if what Thomas said are true...
...we do not have strength
to bear with such a defeat...
...after Aleppo.
We will not allow
the Seljuk-Ayyubid alliance, sir.
Sultan Alaeddin will never
marry the queen.
Go, then.
May God help you.
Titus...
You did not like
me sleeping with Thomas, did you?
Everything is for Jerusalem.
Right, Eftelya?
Everything is for the holy Crusade
to succeed, Titus.
Somebody is coming!
Sir, we captured Ibn al-Arabi, but...
Damn it! Kayis again?
No, sir. Claudius.
Thomas' man Claudius?
Yes, sir.
What are you up to, Thomas?
What?
That is all for my daily report, sir.
I still think that we can have
great gains in Jerusalem...
...by choosing the peace path.
All parties are weak and disunited.
Nobody wants war
when Mongols are on their borders.
Last of all, I will declare a few points
that will determine my thoughts...
...after the Council of the Templars.
Cardinal Thomas.
You left bed early, Ertugrul Bey.
I thought, let me hurt my pain
instead of it hurting me.
I am setting off for Ahlat.
Who knows when we will
see each other again.
I came to have your blessing.
You served a lot to my tent, Afsin Bey.
And to Halime Sultan and her family.
Thank you.
However, your wrong deeds
saddened me a lot.
When we went for Turgut,
the black priest...
Cardinal Thomas.
Him.
Told me something.
What did he say?
I hope it is not something evil.
That you killed Shahzade Numan.
I did not have a duty
to kill the shahzade.
If I did, I would kill him
without batting an eye.
The continuity of the state
is above all.
What kind of duty is this?
Who gives this duty?
We, Oghuz' are still
like the children of the steppe.
We love to death,
and chase our enemies to death.
That is, we do everything to death.
Without thinking about
our front or back.
We do not even refrain from
endangering this order...
...or our state.
Since we do not see anything
both with love and hatred...
...we need somebody
to remind us what we have.
The states we have established
are not ownerless.
The duty is given by the people
who remind us what we have.
They are more than welcome to us.
You had so many things to tell,
Afsin Bey.
This is the least of things to tell.
Duty is given to us when words fail.
May our blood and lives
be sacrificed for this.
Who knows
when we will see each other again.
I told you
what I have not told anybody.
It is out of trust.
Give me your blessing.
It is yours.
Goodbye, Afsin Bey.
Goodbye.
Ertugrul eggs his mother and father
on against me and his brother.
Last night they came over me
by just listening to him.
They will bring this up
at the headquarters today.
What is their trouble, Bey?
They think I cooperate
with the Crusaders.
Their intention is clear, Bey.
They want to finish you.
But we will not let this happen
as long as we live.
Thank you.
Give us your blessing, Afsin Bey.
We owe you so much.
It is yours, Halime Sultan.
Do not leave my shahzade alone
and without a prayer.
Visit him everytime you go to Aleppo.
You give me your blessing, too.
It is yours.
I would like to know
if you find my father's murderer.
The state does not accept the one who
tries to come to the throne with greed!
What are you going to do with him,
Shahzade?
He is my father's murderer.
I will kill him wherever I see him.
They keep track of every step
and every breath we take.
Sometimes they cross our path,
sometimes they wait to use us.
They could not have done this...
...unless they had traitors
in the tent for them to rely on.
They could not have
attacked the shahzades' tents.
They could not have killed
our Alps who were going to Aleppo.
They could not infect us with plaque...
...and provoke the Aleppo emeer
against us.
The traitor has been revealed, Ertugrul.
What are you still up to?
He must still be suspicious. He is saying
there are more than one traitors.
If Alpagu's corpse in front of the marquee
dis not satisfy you...
...tell us, Ertugrul,
how many more corpses are required?
Right.
Kutlu is right.
What do you want, Ertugrul?
When will this tent have peace?
You are all so numb that you see neither
the front nor the back of things.
Wild Demir, make the anger
within Ertugrul go away first.
This anger leads all of us
to uncanny roads.
It is time for somebody
to stop Ertugrul.
Tell us, Ertugrul.
Who else are you suspicious of?
Kurdoglu!
-What?
-It is impossible.
I am suspicious of Kurdoglu.
I see that my niece carried the poison
on his tongue right into the marquee.
Does my niece want my head,
or my pride?
Or is there something else
that he wants?
If Beys also see fit...
...I want him
to be suspended from his duties...
...hand his weapon to our Bey...
...and be kept in this tent
in open arrest...
...until his innocence is proven.
Do you have any single thing
to prove what you are saying?
You do not.
How dare you come in front of us
and say these words?
The night that
the Shahzades' tent was attacked...
...it was Kurdoglu who sent me
away from that tent.
When we were going to Aleppo...
...it was Kurdoglu who sent Alps
after us and caused their deaths.
When I was lying sick in bed...
...someone came into my marquee
and tried to kill me.
There are people who saw Kurdoglu
walking around my marquee that night.
I have their names.
Even though Gundogdu
kept this assassination a secret...
...Hayme saw that
the felt of my marquee has been cut.
And she followed up on that.
Bey, do you know
what you are talking about?
I am also suspicious of my blood brother.
I am not only suspicious,
I also know it.
I also know that you poisoned my son
Gundogdu with your thoughts.
Enough, Suleyman!
Talk decently.
I will not talk you like that
just because we selected you as the Bey!
I have my eyes
on neither seat nor position.
I prefer grassing my cattle
and living my life...
...if otherwise
there will be duality in the tent.
But if my innocence
is proved one day...
...Ertugrul will pay for these
words he said!
Bey...
My uncle is innocent.
Uncle, you can put the dagger
my father has given you back.
I vouch for you.
Me and my father
set up a trap for my uncle.
And he came out of it honorably.
From now on,
whoever talks bad about him...
...will find me against himself.
My brother Ertugrul included.
Leave the delusion inside you...
...and bring your Alp who stabbed you
from your back to account.
Turgut ambushed a Seljuk train
together with the Templars.
And Titus was their leader.
Ertugrul, you are looking for the traitor
in the wrong place.
The traitor is among your Alps.
Brother...
Do not say anything to me.
Say what you want to say
to Turgut.
He is in the marquee square.
Thank you, niece.
You saved your uncle
from an ominous defamation.
Is it not right, Bey?
Are you the one
who tried to kill my son?
Are you Turgut
whom I cherished as if he was my son?
Turgut...
Or are you an ominous jinn?
What are you?
My Turgut...
Ertugrul Bey, demons
have settled into his flesh.
Turgut inside him has long gone.
Allow me since I bring him back.
I will fight the demon inside him
until I die.
Do not kill him.
You were my brother.
And you will always be, Turgut Alp.
Untie him.
My Alp will not have a punishment.
He will be kept in a cage as precaution
until he gets well.
How is she?
She will get well with God's permission.
But I do not know if the wound
that Ertugrul made will heal.
She did not hesitate
to sacrifice herself for your brother.
But Ertugrul did not come to her
even once and say "Get well soon".
He is unfaithful.
He did not take after you.
How are you doing?
I do not know
how I can bear so much pain.
First, my baby. Then my Gokce.
It is you who helps me survive.
You are an important bey
for the Seljuk Sultan.
The people of the tent
see you as our future.
I will not leave you alone
in this rough path.
Now, you have Kurdoglu behind you.
Your uncle, who proved his innocence.
He will always support you.
It will be okay, Turgut.
It will all pass.
I will not let you die.
Turgut...
Your mother kicked me out of the
rug shop because I lost my baby.
Everything I did
was in that rug shop.
She took away everything
that connects me to life.
She gave it to Gokce on purpose,
to breed bad blood between us.
You do not know what you are talking
because of your pain.
Mother Hayme
would not do such things.
For God's sake, pull yourself together.
Excuse me.
Gundogdu...
You still do not respect
what I say, do you?
You are right, she was like your mother
even though she did not breastfeed you.
She fed and brought you up.
She did not let you feel
the lack of your mother.
But nothing is as it seems.
You dried up both yourself and me
with your delusions, woman.
Delusions?
So you do not respect me
as much as that woman.
It is too late.
I will go away.
Selcan!
Yes, I will.
I am a woman who cannot even
carry your baby.
I will go away
when my sister gets well.
Let me go.
I am begging you, Gundogdu.
There is nothing more.
There is neither peace nor happiness
in this tent anymore.
Selcan! Pull yourself together!
I just wanted you to have peace.
You are both my peace and my woman.
Then why does your mother
look for a woman for you...
...in her elder brother Korkut's tent?
I do not understand.
I was not going to say...
...but you forced me to.
Just forget it.
So, just like that.
He warded off all the suspicions.
The death of so many Alps,
so many instigations.
It is all on that Alpargu bastard now.
Enough, Hayme. Enough.
Kurdoglu came out of Gundogdu's
trick blamelessly.
The traitor was Alpargu. It is over.
Kurdoglu is innocent.
Everybody witnessed that.
This matter is closed. Finished.
What do they want from you, then?
To withdraw. Do you not see?
To withdraw.
Our people are after welfare,
not traditions.
Kurdoglu sees their problem
more than me.
He sees it and wants me to withdraw.
And he will replace Gundogdu with me.
This is the truth.
Even though you do not want to hear
that I got older...
...and our people do not say anything
out of respect, this is the truth.
May I come in, father?
Come in.
I have some things to say
to both of you, if you permit.
Father...
...you will break up my family
unless you marry Gokce and Ertugrul.
Do not do what my mother
has been trying to do for so long.
Gundogdu!
Do you hear what you are saying?
What kind of words are these?
Mother...
...I know you have been looking for a
woman for me in my uncle's tent.
We are already in pain.
For God's sake,
do not increase our pain.
Bring Selcan back to the rug shop.
I do not want my family to be broken
because of the bad blood between you.
I do not want anything else from you.
Excuse me.
What did you do, Hayme?
Greetings, Halime Sultan.
Greetings, Ertugrul Bey.
You wanted to be daughter of the tent...
...instead of living in palaces
and being Halime Sultan.
Every place I am in with you
is my palace.
I am only the sultan of your heart,
Ertugrul Bey.
And the Oghuz Tent is our home.
You wish to be
my father's daughter, but...
...you must take the chance of
going away with me when the time comes.
I would go
to the far end of the world with you.
And I would not ask why.
But I know why you are leaving your tent.
That is why I am worried, anyway.
If I disregard my father's legacy,
my Bey's order...
...I cannot stay in this tent
and look at his face anymore.
Will you disregard it?
I can only leave this tent
with my loved one.
I wish I taught you about
women's tricks...
...like I taught how to use weapons.
You were caught unprepared.
Do not say that, uncle.
On one side is my mother,
and on the other, my wife.
These are all games of throne, Gundogdu.
Games to make you tired and whelmed.
And Hayme is behind all of them.
It is so clear.
I had told you. Selcan Hatun
had told you, as well.
He is panicked because
his ruling power is about to finish.
These are all temporary.
Ertugrul also cannot see these games.
He has his mother behind him.
It is her who oppresses him this much.
Do not worry.
When you enter the marquee
and be the bey...
...everything will be passed.
And we will be with each other again.
The elders in the tent
will also adapt to their new lives.
By the way, I have good news for you.
Tatos Harput
just sent the money for the flock.
Uncle... these are...
These freckles of gold
are all your success.
You cannot be a bey just by girding on
your weapon and defeating the infidels.
You will feed your people first...
...so that they will fight for you
when you want them to.
Neither an Alp's mother
nor wife will say anything to you.
Now, do what is necessary
on the path to be the bey...
...and give a feast.
Let the people know their future bey
who will live in the marquee from now on.
My heart aches, Aktolgali.
But I know that it is that ache
that will lead me to the victory.
Neither Kara Toygar nor the Templars.
None of them was a victory.
They mean nothing unless
I finish the instigation within my tent.
A wind that is even incapable of
hurting a spring branch...
...will destroy my tent.
The war just started, Aktolgali.
God help us.
Well done.
Women...
You heard what happened to Gokce.
From now on,
Selcan Hatun will run the rug shop.
Her words are my words.
Good luck. Everybody back to work.
I hope you will not interfere with
my work and family from now on.
I brought you up
since you were seven years old.
I was by your side at all times
like a mother.
When did you become that?
Your mother was my dearest friend.
How could you be born
from such a woman?
How could somebody like you
be brought up in my marquee?
Shame on you.
If everybody knows their place...
...you will be my mother,
and I will be your daughter.
It is that easy.
Sons talk instead of the elders.
Girls give orders instead of mothers.
God help us all.
Women!
We will weave so many rugs this year
that the tent has never seen.
I will have four new weaving benches made.
Our rugs will be in all benches...
...from Aleppo to Damascus,
from Konya to Antioch.
Understood?
Understood!
We will see who is stronger, Mother Hayme.
Umur...
22 cattle, 3 camels and 67 goats.
-Is it right?
-It is.
63 coins.
-Enjoy it.
-God bless you, Bey.
May God keep you among us.
Thank you. Enjoy it.
Yagiz...
33 cattle, 7 camels and 123 goats.
Is it right?
It is.
103 coins.
-Enjoy it.
-Thank you, Bey.
They have said you were different,
but I have not believed back then.
Thank you.
Gundogdu's day is today.
But the Alps are not happy about this.
They will shut up when we go to war.
-God bless you, Bey.
-You, too. Enjoy it.
-Thank you, Bey!
-God bless you, Bey!
Thank you. God bless you, too.
I know what the troubles
you were putting up with for so long.
These hard times are over now.
All of you had your shares.
With God's permission,
we will earn more from now on.
-Yes, Bey.
Tomorrow night, I will give a feast
at the marquee square...
...to beys, flock owners and shepherds.
You are all invited!
-Thank you, Bey!
-Thank you!
Thank you. God bless you, too.
What is Gundogdu up to, Ertugrul?
Your elder brother
is playing a dangerous game.
It is your duty to wake him up
as his brother.
Your father is stuck
between the people he loves and his duty.
Even my father is stuck
between the anvil and the hammer...
...this will only make him
tougher and stronger, Wild Demir.
Surely, there is something he knows.
The moment my father takes a step,
I will follow him running.
Gundogdu has sold the flock.
They say that our people earned money in
amount that they have never seen before.
Gundogdu will give a feast
tomorrow night...
...to the beys, shepherds
and flock owners.
He is doing this without letting me know.
He invited me by sending Abdullah to me.
Our people are very happy.
He sold the flock for a very high price.
I do not know how those weak cattle
cost that much money.
Selcan told me
not to come to the rug shop anymore.
They do not want us
because we got older, woman.
I told you that it was time for me
to withdraw for a reason.
Kurdoglu would want to
nominate Gundogdu and destroy you.
Who knows what he will do next.
But it would not surprise me
if he spends Gundogdu like he did to you.
It is our duty to do what is necessary.
I will look after Sister Isadora
until the border. Do not worry.
Good luck.
I am grateful to you, Isadora.
I will never forget this.
God save you.
Goodbye.
Please be careful.
It is possible that
we still have a traitor in our tent.
Your life may be in danger.
As Turks say,
let us hope for the best.
I leave Halime Sultan
and Shahzade Yigit to you.
Thank you.
May God protect you.
Alright.
I will take care of him.
I will not let him die.
Ertugrul Bey, will you come with me?
There is something
I would like to show you.
Turgut...
Do not do that.
Do not surrender to the poison inside you.
I am begging you.
Alright.
No! Look at me.
Look at me. Alright. Please.
Turgut!
Get up.
Please, do not do that.
It is okay.
Alright. It is okay.
Do you remember when you told me
that you loved me?
Do you?
I will tell you everything.
You will know who you are, Turgut.
I will tell you everything
from the very beginning.
I will give you back
everything that they made your forget.
Alright. It is okay.
It is okay.
Ibn al-Arabi allowed only the two of us
to know the existence of this chest.
Did he say anything else?
He told us not to open it ever.
He will take it back from us
when he gets back.
Isadora said that his father
talked about Arabi's relic.
I do not know if there is a relation.
I just wanted you to know.
Welcome, Bey.
-God is Haqq!
-God is Hayy!
The time is now, Wild Demir.
I am with you until my last breath, Bey.
-God is Haqq!
-God is Hayy!
God is Haqq!
Isadora!
My angel!
I got so worried about you!
Are you alright? What happened?
I got lost, uncle.
At last, a villager helped me.
I am very tired.
I will tell you everything
after I get some rest.
Go, honey. Rest will do you good.
By the way...
...there is something you should know.
What is it?
Mario...
They found him dead the other day.
He hung himself.
Everything will change
after the feast tomorrow night.
Everybody will see
that we are not ordinary shepherds.
We will revive this seigniory
with trophy raids on the Orthodoxes.
This gold you see is just the beginning.
Now, our Gundogdu Bey waits for you.
Ertugrul Bey would get hold of him
if he was not his elder brother.
Who are you to give a feast
when there are beys to do that?
You...
I would say, "Gundogdu,
do you know what you are doing?"
And what about that jackal, Kurdoglu?
All kinds of instigation is his doing.
I have half a mind to
grab his collar and...
God forgive me. What am I saying?
So, are you not going to the feast?
They will eat sheep and camel,
and you will not go?
I would not go there
even if I died from my pain.
My brother!
Both of you are going to that feast.
As I always say...
...we left the meal to them,
but the hunt will be ours.
Understood?
Understood, Bey.
Congratulations, Bey.
Everybody knows that
you are different now.
You are the chief pillar of this tent
after your father.
And you will be the one who keeps
this tent up after your father.
May God keep you among us.
The feast you are going to give
tomorrow night...
...will seal you as the future bey.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Karabudak. Come in.
We came here to wish you good luck, Bey.
We want you to know that
we are always with you.
Thank you, Kutlu. Thank you, Karabudak.
We are going on a path with you.
But it does not end in Aleppo.
It ends in the tomb.
We would like to see you as the new bey
of the Kayis when the time comes.
If God permits.
We would like to kiss your hand
if you permit.
Father, this is the best day of my life.