Episode 22 will start after 12:21 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Talk.
What do you want from me?
I can see the hatred in your eyes.
But I know that you are clever enough...
...to understand that I do everything
for the nomad tent's future.
With that bastard named
Grandmaster Petruchio.
With that murderer named Titus.
And with that bastard named Black Toygar.
Did you ally with them for this?
This is not a personal matter.
I hate them as much as you do.
I am sure they hate me, too.
But I bear with them.
For what?
Only for the future of Kayis.
If your future is in the hands of the
Templars who guide the Crusaders...
...it is better for the Kayis to perish.
However, both Ertugrul and I
know very well that this is not the case.
He will reveal all your games
one by one.
He will make you regret
for what you did.
Suleyman Shah will take the crown back.
It is too late, Halime Sultan!
Suleyman Shah, his family,
and the ones who are with them...
...are not alive anymore.
You are lying.
Unfortunately, this was necessary.
But you can be at ease.
Turgut Alp must have done this
in a painless and fast way.
As to Ertugrul...
...Ertugrul and his Alps
Dogan and Bamsi...
...are in the hands of those
bastard Templars.
You are lying!
Listen to me carefully, Halime Sultan!
You do not have anybody left in your life.
Except your brother.
If you want to take your brother,
go far away and start a new life...
...I am ready to give you
this opportunity.
What do you want?
Arabi's ark.
Ibn al-Arabi allowed
only the two of us...
...to know where this ark is.
He told us not to open it ever.
He will take it back when he comes back.
Listen, Halime Sultan...
...if you tell me where the ark is...
...you can start a new life
with your brother.
This is my first and last offer to you.
What is he doing here?
It is impossible for him
to do it and come back this fast.
Guard, let the Bey know.
Tell them Turgut Alp is here.
Yes, Bey.
I do not know anything
about Arabi's ark.
Lying does not befit
a beautiful sultan like you.
Why do you think
I know where the ark is?
Why would he give it to me
if it is important like that?
He gave it to Ertugrul, not to you.
But since Ertugrul was wounded,
Arabi handed the ark to you.
I will give you something
before I leave.
You will give it to Ertugrul
if he recovers before I come back.
Do not ever look inside it.
I will definitely protect it
at the risk of my life.
I got you watched everywhere.
I know every step you took
after Ertugrul recovered.
Now that you know
every step we took...
...you must know where I hid the ark.
Both you and your brother will die
if you do not talk!
-Bey?
-What is it?
Turgut Alp is back.
His hands were covered with blood.
Tell him to wait in the marquee.
I will go there.
Do you believe me now?
You do not have
anyone left in your life.
Think carefully.
This is you and your brother's
last chance.
Did you do it?
I did. They are all dead.
Tell me what happened.
I want to know everything.
They found an opportunity
to untie themselves.
They struggled to escape.
However...
-Turgut!
-No!
None of them could escape.
Good.
What about my Alps?
They are all dead.
Both Alps and the Templars'
that the Grandmaster sent for precaution.
They are dead.
Well, well, Suleyman Shah.
Your time is over.
Do not tell anybody anything
about the Templars.
Of course, Bey.
Ayhan, did you hear something?
No, why did you ask?
You go, I will catch up with you.
Ayhan, do not get yourself into trouble.
Ertugrul Bey!
-Ayhan Alp.
-Thank God you are alive.
That bastard sent Suleyman Shah to exile.
I know.
-I have a request from you.
-Whatever you ask, Bey.
I can give my life
for you and Suleyman Shah.
Thank you.
You will go to Kurdoglu.
You will say "If you want Ertugrul...
...he will come and surrender to you.
However...
...he has one condition.
He wants a headquarters meeting.
He wants to face you
in front of the beys."
After that, if he still wants
and if he still has enough power...
...he will take my head.
Bey, what are you saying?
He overthrew my father
with betrayal in his marquee.
And I will take the throne back
in the same marquee by God's will.
This is my plan.
I want you to make Halime talk.
Do whatever is necessary.
Find out where the ark is.
Yes, Bey.
Go to Halime Sultan like this.
So that she will see how serious you are.
We are ready, Bey.
We can set off.
Bring the Alps' corpses, Kutlu.
Let us organize a funeral
worthy of their heroism.
Let us read Quran and shed tears.
Let us grieve for them.
Let our people see how right I was
to send Suleyman and his sons.
Let them admire me.
The pain of our lost Alps
will unite our nomad tent even more.
What shall I do with them?
Suleyman Shah and his family,
Wild Demir and his daughter...
...feed wolves and birds with them.
So that their rotten flesh
would be good for something.
Turgut... Let us go.
How could you let this persecution happen?
How could you do this?
They killed all of them.
Yes. They all died
trying to rescue themselves.
What did they do to our tent?
Bey, they did not even have any swords.
It was clear that it was going to be
like that. Look at our tent now.
Everybody! Do not stay here!
I said do not stay here!
Do you not have any other thing to do?
Go away!
It was clear that
Kurdoglu would not let them live.
-He knew he would lose the throne.
-He did it because he was scared.
-It is a shame.
-He killed the women.
And poor Dundar.
Do not talk here like this.
Somebody may hear.
Here he comes.
Bey, they are coming!
This is his head stooge, Kutlu.
Here we start.
You know what to do, Ayhan.
Do not worry, Bey.
Hide a sword under my seat in the meeting.
-This is what I want from you.
-I understand, Bey.
I will take care of it.
-May God help you.
-You too, Bey.
Turgut Alp will take care of you
until you say where the ark is.
So that you can find out
how Suleyman and his family passed away.
God will punish you all.
You...
You were Ertugrul Bey's closest friend.
You were his Alp.
You were his brother.
How could you do this?
How could you kill those people?
I can kill you too, Halime Sultan.
Tell me where the ark is.
I would not tell you
even if I knew I would die.
If Ertugrul died...
...I do not have a reason
to live on anyway.
To kill me would be the best gift
you could give me.
If you want your brother to live...
...do not make me wait.
They will let
neither me nor my brother live.
Yigit will live my father's fate
even though he lives.
It would be better for him to die.
You will not hear even a word from me.
Turgut Alp, have fun.
Finish this before sunrise.
Bey...
What do you want, Ayhan?
Ertugrul has something to say to you.
What are you talking about?
Where did this come from?
Where did he see him?
Bey, we were patrolling with the Alps.
He showed up suddenly.
This is impossible.
Do you hear what you say?
Bey, he was very angry.
He put a knife on my throat.
Talk! Talk, man!
What does he want? Halime?
No, Bey. He wants to confront you
in the headquarters.
I am scared of neither you nor Kurdoglu.
Get out.
But, Bey...
Get out!
I am not a traitor.
I did not betray my ancestor Oghuz.
The blood that spilled on my hands
were for the future of Kayis.
It was to be stronger, bigger.
It was to have a land and to be powerful.
May I come in, Bey?
Come in.
You ordered me, Bey?
You will go
to the Templars' castle secretly.
You will tell them Ertugrul lives.
-Yes, Bey.
-Come on, be quick!
Wait.
Get Ayhan Alp followed.
He clearly has a trouble.
I need to know every step he takes.
These ominous infidels
could not just beat that son of Suleyman.
But I will give him such a death...
May I come in, Bey?
Come in, Karabudak.
They beys and the people are anxious.
The Alps are bothered.
They go around saying
"How could we let such a thing happen?".
They need to be eased, Bey.
Otherwise, there will be
even more blood spilled.
Be at ease, Karabudak.
I know very well what I am doing.
Send news to the beys.
I want them to come to my marquee
in the afternoon.
Yes, Bey.
What do you want, Ayhan Alp?
Do you want to die?
Bey, I brought you
greetings from Ertugrul Bey.
Where are these damn corpses?
Suleyman Shah?
What? You were not
expecting us, were you?
Come on!
What are you waiting for? Kill them!
-What are you waiting for? Come on!
-Do not bellow like an ox!
Come and take our lives.
Come here.
Come and learn by bitter experience.
Forgive...
Forgive me, Suleyman Bey.
It would be an insult to mercy
if I forgive you.
Feed birds and wolves with his corpse.
So that everybody sees what happens
to the ones who try to destroy Kayi.
It is meaningless for me to live
when my Yigit has died.
Kill me.
I brought you greetings
from Ertugrul Bey.
Everybody is alright.
Do not worry.
We will all be saved.
Turgut...
How is this going to happen?
Let us be patient, sister.
Ertugrul will save both us and the tent.
1 DAY AGO
We will camp here.
-Turgut!
-No! Father!
-Turgut, do not do that!
-Father!
Turgut!
Turgut, do not do that!
Turgut, no!
-Father!
-Turgut!
At least, do not kill the women.
It would be a shame. A sin.
-Father!
-Turgut!
-No!
Turgut!
Wild Demir!
Father! Gundogdu!
Brother...
My little brother!
Father, where is Halime?
Kurdoglu is holding her, son.
Turgut...
Turgut?
Are you alright?
Father, Turgut is...
-Turgut.
-Turgut!
What is going on?
-Turgut, son!
-What is going on?
-Turgut!
-Bring some water.
Turgut!
I have to go to the tent immediately.
Be patient. Let us talk about it first.
There must be another way.
Gundogdu is right.
We must act reasonably.
If we want to overcome this plague...
...we cannot show weakness.
You must control your anger.
How is he?
He is in so much pain.
Kurdoglu brought him the drug
in the cage that Templars gave him.
He did not drink it.
He struggled with himself.
If I ever catch you...
Oh, if I ever catch you...
Turgut.
Ertugrul Bey.
Do not get up. You are not well.
We have to save the tent.
I will not live any longer.
At least, I would like to do
my last duty until I die.
God, help my Turgut.
Give him strength.
Aykiz.
If you die, you will be my pride.
I will not have a man anymore.
I will die with your memories.
However...
...I am begging you,
do not talk about dying.
Neither to me nor to yourself.
We will not let that ominous drug
to take over you.
We will fight to death.
The two of us, together.
Do you understand me?
I promise...
...I will not surrender.
THE DAY OF THE MEETING
This matter will be closed today
by God's will.
Thank God.
You have to be patient, Halime Sultan.
Turgut, this is very dangerous.
Ertugrul is alone, and you are still ill.
We do not have any other choice.
Ertugrul Bey sent you his greetings.
Do not worry,
we will do whatever we can.
Thank you.
May God help us.
Turgut!
Turgut...
Alright.
I am alright.
Come on, let us go.
We do not have
any other choice, father.
Kurdoglu must think we are dead.
This will increase
our possibility to succeed.
If he finds out that we are alive...
...he will let neither Ertugrul
nor Turgut live.
My brother is right, father.
We have to do this
before Kurdoglu finds out about the truth.
We must convince him
to accept my participation to the meeting.
What if he does not?
Then, we will not have
any other choice...
...than going to all the Oghuz tents...
...and look for brave men
willing to fight.
None of us would accept
so much blood to be spilled.
The beys would get themselves
out from this darkness...
...when Turgut tells what he went through
in the castle and reveals Kurdoglu.
As my brother said...
...none of us would accept
more blood to be spilled.
I am also worried about Turgut's illness.
Ertugrul, watch out for
both him and yourself.
Alright, brother.
Bey, Ertugrul walking around the tent
is not a good sign.
Everybody is anxious.
Nobody can know how this will end.
Suleyman and his family died.
Are you afraid of Ertugrul
who is left by himself with only two Alps?
We started this journey
for the sake of our tent's peace.
We overcame so many challenges.
And now you started getting scared of that
Ertugrul who does not know his place?
Is this your notion of being a bey?
Is this your notion of being a man?
Is there anybody who has something to say
without getting ashamed?
I asked a question!
No, Bey.
Ertugrul wants to come to the meeting.
May him come, then.
And learn his lesson.
I will say all his lies one by one
to his face...
...and kill him with my own hands.
What are you talking about?
They all escaped?
Yes, sir. Ertugrul saved his family
with Turgut.
All our knights are dead.
Get out of my face!
Stupid.
I told you to kill him
when you caught him.
God damn old man.
Uncle, what are you doing?
I know you are a traitor
just like your father.
I will kill you
like your sister and father.
Take this bitch!
God damn you. Suffer forever.
-Sir, are you alright?
-Get out! Get out!
Take her!
We must tell the situation
to the Grandsmaster.
The Cardinal's man Claudius
attacked us.
He saved Ertugrul and his Alps.
Do not worry. I let him know.
He is about to come.
Take the corpse away.
Are you alright, sir?
I am, Titus.
Just a small wound.
That is all.
One of Kurdoglu's men is here.
He confirmed what the knight said.
Ertugrul is alive.
He will go to the meeting
and confront Kurdoglu.
No. Suleyman's rule is over.
We must catch Ertugrul.
What about Turgut?
He is obviously with Ertugrul.
How can this be possible?
The drug...
The drug is powerful, but...
...this is the power of faith, Titus.
This is the power of faith.
He will clearly die in a lot of pain
because he did not take the drug.
But he can serve us the last time
before he dies.
He can give us Ertugrul's head.
Ertugrul wants to overthrow Kurdoglu...
...with Turgut's testimony.
He wants to take the throne back
in front of the beys.
Let us see who overthrows whom.
-Did you bury the corpses?
-Yes, sir.
Good.
What about Arabi?
He thinks I converted to Islam
and became his disciple.
What about his ark?
I found out that it is in the nomad tent.
I saved Ertugrul and his Alps
from the Grandmaster's knights...
...in order to be able to take the ark.
Moreover, I know
the Grandmaster knows this.
My dear friend Petruchio...
...so you hide information from me.
That is all, sir.
You are the best knight I have ever known.
May God protect you, son.
God will punish you so bad...
...that you will pay the price
of the sins you committed.
Turk!
You will send a message
to Kurdoglu.
Tell him that
we want Halime Sultan and Turgut.
Tell Kurdoglu that all his family escaped.
And that the two of them is behind this.
Be quick. You must arrive
before their meeting.
Go now.
Jesus Christ...
...help them in their fight
against the persecutors.
Make Ertugrul gain a victory.
Enlighten their way
with your divine justice.
God, forgive my sins.
Isadora?
Isadora!
My beautiful niece
paid the price of her betrayal.
Murderer!
She was your blood.
She was from bad blood.
And she died.
You have been given a last chance
to live, Shahzade.
You will go to Konstantiniyye
with Cardinal Thomas.
Otherwise, you will die like Isadora.
Think thoroughly.
I would rather die instead of serving you.
We will see...
...how much longer
you will talk like that.
Be very careful.
The war begins now.
Yes, Bey.
Thank God you are alive.
You made me so happy.
We are all ready to die for you.
Did Kurdoglu accept
confronting Ertugrul in the meeting?
He did, Bey.
I will go there.
He promised that
he will be fair to you in the meeting.
I am sure he will do
as much as he can for the sake of justice.
None of us wanted this happen, Bey.
We are all ready to give our heads
for the sake of justice.
Thank you.
We do not doubt about it.
You proved this
by coming here, anyway.
May God protect our tent.
-Amen.
Amen.
Come here, Halime Sultan.
Sit down.
May their hands break.
That bastard Turgut
did so many bad things to you.
First he beat you,
then he sent me to take care of you.
Ugly face.
No, I am alright.
It is all because of Selcan Hatun.
Hold on there, Eydis.
What are you going to say?
Whatever. She is dead now
with all her sins.
It would not be appropriate for me
to talk ill about her.
Say it, Eydis!
Say what you have to say.
She was such an ominous woman.
When Alpargu stabbed
late Gokce Hatun on her groin...
...she wanted to get her married with
Ertugrul Bey...
...even though she knew
she was not going to have a baby.
She gave me gold money
to prevent me talk.
And I took them with these
ominous hands of mine.
And that baby matter...
What about the baby?
I was suspicious of her pregnancy
in spite of being an infertile woman.
And she whipped Aykiz
because she lost her baby.
Anyway. God forgive her sins.
Let me go if you are alright.
There will not be peace
in a place like this...
...where there are such sins...
...and pathetic people like me
who do bad things for money.
God forgive our sins.
You cannot trust Kurdoglu's promise.
We talked about this, father.
He thinks all of you are dead.
I have to do this alone.
Ayhan talked to the beys
who are close to us.
And with the Alps.
Do not worry.
I will not be alone in the tent.
Turgut will be waiting for me
in the marquee.
If anything happens to me...
...take care of Halime.
Give me your blessings.
You have it.
May God protect you.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Thank you so much.
You sent help with Omer.
Thank you, son.
Where are you going?
To the tent.
I am going to take what we deserve.
Stay on God's path,
and he will be with you.
The victory belongs to God
even though our blood may be spilled.
Hopefully.
Excuse us.
Turgut!
Did Halime Sultan talk?
Not yet.
But she will.
Listen to me carefully, Turgut.
I have a good idea to make her talk.
You will take a walk with her.
Go.
Yes, Bey.
Ertugrul warned me a lot.
Also, you.
All the things you said about Kurdoglu
turned out to be right.
It was a big mistake for me
not to listen to him back then.
He said he did not want justice
to be hurt.
He was right.
May the justice not be hurt.
We can accept to be hurt.
May God protect us from the shame...
...of forcing our children
live in a place where there is no justice.
Everything will be alright.
It is Friday today.
God does justice to innocent people.
May God keep you always with me.
My girl...
Do you need anything, father?
Thank you.
How is Gundogdu doing?
He is trying to get rid of the
poison inside him.
He will be alright in a few days.
Selcan became a good daughter suddenly.
What do you say?
She was disciplined by the situation
of first her sister, then her man.
I hope you are right.
Do you think he will recover?
God knows.
Let us pray.
God, forgive me.
You have to deserve to be forgiven first.
How can I deserve that?
My daughter...
...if you want to deserve
to be forgiven...
...you need to cleanse your heart first.
The heart is our valuable asset.
Our Prophet told us that
God says...
..."The heavens and the earth
cannot contain Me...
...but the heart of a true believer can."
Therefore, this heart of ours...
...is the biggest treasure of human.
My daughter...
...if you wish to be forgiven...
...be like Hazrat Khadija.
Hazrat Khadija challenged
all the non-believers...
...with our Prophet
when the spread of Islam began.
She wanted to be the ointment
when his heart was broken.
She spent her money
to spread her husband's cause.
She believed him when others did not.
She supported him
while everybody was avoiding him.
And God granted our Prophet
children from her.
Therefore,
let Hazrat Khadija be your guide.
What is going on, Turgut?
Where are we going?
This is not good at all, Halime Sultan.
Something is wrong.
What is going on?
Where did we come here?
We will go to the tent,
and you will go to the castle.
Turgut!
God, help my son.
Help him, so that
the persecution will be over.
-Amen.
God granted him a conquest for sure.
Our Prophet set off to Taif...
...in order to find
a peaceful land for the believers...
...when the persecutions of the
non-believers in Macca increased.
Taif did not see the grace even though
there were high hopes about them.
Our Prophet did not lose hope
when all doors were shut on his face.
He struggles on
to make his cause be heard...
...and to be able to make
even one person a believer.
However, the people of Taif
threw stones at him. They persecuted.
Our Prophet went outside Taif, wounded.
Angel Jibreel showed up.
He said they would destroy Taif
if our Prophet wanted.
However, our Prophet
who was sent as a mercy to all creation...
...said "No, I do not want them
to be destroyed.
I wish God brings up people
from their generation...
...who will serve and pray
only to God, and not to others."
The people of Taif
became Muslims years after that.
Mercy prevailed over persecution.
Hopefully, mercy will prevail
over persecution again.
Our Bey is coming!
Our tent will be happy!
Welcome, Bey!
May God keep you always with us!
Ertugrul Bey, welcome!
May God help you, Bey!
Welcome, Bey!
Ertugrul is here, Bey.
So he comes.
Welcome, Bey.
May God keep you always with us.
May God help you.
Today is the day
to pay the price, Ertugrul.
You are right, Karabudak.
Today is the day to pay the price.
Everybody will pay the price
in the Judgment Day.
Thankfully, we have no doubt about it.
However...
...it would break my heart
for you and Kurdoglu...
...to wait until the Judgment Day
to pay your price.
Our condolences, Ertugrul Bey.
Our condolences.
May God give you patience.
Our condolences, Bey.
I heard you wanted to
confront me, Ertugrul.
As your loyal dog Karabudak said...
...today is the day to pay the price.
I will disregard
your father's holy memory...
...and I will smash you here!
Know your place!
Ertugrul...
Nobody recognizes you
neither in this marquee...
...nor in this meeting...
...or in any forage where oxen grass.
I just accepted you in my marquee
out of respect to your father.
If you cross the line...
...you should know that
I will impale you in the tent square!
Your loss and pain is big.
However, if you have even a little respect
left for the people of this tent...
...do not provoke disturbance.
It was decided that
your family would be exiled.
They were going to be sent
to your uncle Korkut's tent.
However, your father and brother
chose to go against this decision.
May them rest in peace.
Amen.
Now, say what you want to say.
And then, obey the decision
that will be given here.
Are you planning to kill me
on the way...
...by way of the Templars
that you have been allying with...
...and with the Alps that you bought,
like you did to my family?
What is going on?
That is enough, Bey.
This tactless man
has crossed the line way over.
Now that Kurdoglu Bey
invited him here...
...let him talk, Karabudak.
Now that this is the place
where God's justice will be done...
...I say let us allow
Ertugrul Bey to say what he has to say.
He is right!
He is right.
Thank you.
The price for blaming a bey
in his marquee like this is very high.
You will not get out of here alive
if you go on like this.
You are not the bey of this tent,
Kurdoglu.
You are a disgrace
to the people of Oghuz and Kayis.
My words reflect the truth.
I have two witnesses to prove them.
I would like you Beys to allow these
witnesses enter the marquee.
Let them come, Bey!
Alright, then.
However, I am sure
you also noticed that...
...there are three beys missing here.
They apologized from you.
What is going on?
Brother!
Halime Sultan, are you alright?
I am.
I am so glad to see you three
like this again.
Turgut!
Brother Turgut!
-Brother, are you alright?
-I am.
I need to go to the tent.
Come on, brother.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
I see that things went crazy
while I was away.
Tell me, then. What did your witnesses
witness against me?
That you allied with Black Toygar
and got the train raided.
That you got fifteen of our Alps martyred.
That you allied with the Templars and
brought all kinds of troubles in the tent.
Enough is enough, Bey!
How much longer are we...
That you went to the castle
a lot of times...
...and committed crimes
with their Grandmaster Mancini.
Well, well, well.
Look how strong witnesses
my niece Ertugrul has.
I do.
They saw and heard in person
that you are a traitor, Kurdoglu.
They will also witness that...
...you bought men in the tent
with the gold you took from Mancini.
They will tell who the bastards
you bought are one by one.
Who is your witness?
It is Turgut Alp.
Do you think I do not know that
you and Turgut Alp killed my Alps...
...who were taking your family to exile?
Ertugrul Bey would never do that.
Oh, Ertugrul.
It seems like you underestimated Kurdoglu.
They tried to set up a trap for me.
They won Halime Sultan over.
They are trying to ruin my reputation
with all kinds of slanders.
But they do not know that
I will be the one who ruins them.
There will not be an exile anymore.
I will kill you all, Ertugrul.
I will not let any of you live.
I will kill your family even if they go
to the other side of the world!
Alps! Catch him!
I will kill you here
unless you confess everything.
Talk, Kurdoglu!
My beys, they are all lies!
They are all slander!
Do not be scared, my Beys!
They are all lies!
Kurdoglu, the truth came,
and the lies went away.
-Turgut Alp.
-Yes, Bey.
Send a message to Suleyman Shah
and tell him that he can come.
-He can come to his marquee.
-Yes, Bey.
I hope this holy marquee
does not have a shame like this anymore.
Father...
...the fire is lit.
Ertugrul succeeded.
Let us go, then.
Hayme, you will catch up with us.
As you wish, Bey.
Abdurrahman, get the horses ready!
Yes, Bey!
I swear by the name of God
Who creates everything with one word
And fills our hearts with faith
I swear by my weapon, my flag
In this path to war
May my ancestor Hizir be my companion
And Hazrat Ali my guide
May Zulfiqar be my weapon
And Duldul my horse
May the dawn be ours
And the victory be God's
-Welcome, Bey!
-Welcome!
Welcome, Bey!
May God keep you always with us.
Mercy...
There is no mercy for traitors, Kurdoglu.