episode 7 will start at : 12:10
Kurdoglu.
Tell me? Whose dog are you?
Where is my brother?
Where is the Shahzade?
Talk!
It won’t be so easy this time!
ALEPPO
You have not even blinked an eye
the whole night.
I have caused great distress
with the news I gave you.
You are not the source of my troubles,
just the opposite...
...we learned who the traitor was
thanks to you.
I worked for our vizier for years,
he is a very good man, he was...
-...on the right path for years but...
-But the important thing is...
...not to be on the righteous path but
not to stray for even for a second.
Alright, Vizier Sahabettin
had served our state well for years...
...but this does not mean that we shall
turn a blind eye on the things he did.
Because of the things I shared, I feel
responsible for the fate of your uncle.
Sahabettin Tugrul’s fate shall be
whatever he deserves.
I had personally said that
whomever collaborates with the Templars...
...and becomes a traitor shall be
hanged at the city walls.
Hamza...
...are the Alps ready for
the security of the migration route?
They are ready, Bey.
Ilyas Fakih...
...did you talk with the families of
the people who have to stay behind...
...because of this plague?
-I did, Bey.
I tried to comfort them but it is hard.
May God never test anyone
with their children.
If He does, may He grant them
the patience to overcome the pain.
Amen.
Akcakoca...
...would this plague spread outside
the confinement?
Bey, these things cannot be known
by looking from the outside...
...but it seems that this plague
is not spreading outside.
If you see it fit as well...
...there is nothing else holding us back
from the journey.
I see it fit, me may go.
Then...
...for our loved ones in the graves
and for our babies in their cots...
...as an Oguz tribe,
we shall walk to our new homeland.
The tribe is in enough turmoil as it is,
why do you summon me here?
I know...
...Kurdoglu did not manage to kill
Suleyman Shah.
Do not feel sorrow, Selcan. It is soon.
You shall revenge the death of
your father Alpsungur.
Suleyman Shah’s death
will be from your hands.
But first there is another evil
you need to solve.
-What evil is that?
-Plague!
The whole tribe shall be infected soon.
You have to save yourself
and your son from this evil.
The ill are isolated. The animals
are burnt! What are you saying?
It is not over yet.
This evil shall take many more lives.
This evil does not have a remedy.
There is nothing else but confinement.
I do have a cure.
You should drink this every day.
It will protect you, your husband
and most importantly...
...your son from this evil.
What happened?
What were you doing here, Kurdoglu?
I rode my horse without rest
for the safety of our Bey.
Thank God, I made it in time.
My blood brother, my life brother.
Was it an intuition, Kurdoglu?
How did you know that something
like this might happen to our Bey?
Mother Hayme, this dog called
Bozok came to me a few days ago...
...asking me about the
death of his father.
He heard Gundogdu accusing me
in the headquarters.
He saw me as the killer of his father.
He stuck a knife at my throat.
I still pitied him thinking that he is in
deep sorrow, he was a boy of this tribe...
...and forgave this impudence.
But when Gundogdu mentioned that
the Bey’s tent was cut with a knife...
...God forbid,
implied that he was attacked...
...I thought about how some people might
have whispered something in his ear.
Then I could not stay back, so I got on
my horse and rode until it was exhausted.
What happened to my tribe in two days?
Traitors have embarked, Alps have
separated and everything has fallen apart.
Thank you, despite everything, Kurdoglu.
What if you were late?
God has spared our Bey’s life to us ,
Wild Demir. The rest is not important.
Well?
What will you do now?
Will you come with us to Aleppo?
No, I have to return. I cannot leave
the tribe alone in a migration journey.
You are with our Shah, Wild Demir.
I know he is in good hands.
Thank you.
See you in Aleppo.
This is Turgut’s axe!
And this is Shahzade’s necklace.
What are they doing here, Bey?
Sit down.
I will tell you everything.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS TEMPLARS CASTLE
Yigit...
...do not let yourself down.
Patience is bitter but its fruit is sweet.
Alright, my lion?
I am fine, Turgut Aga.
I am only a bit tired.
Well done, my boy.
Why did you chain the Shahzade?
Untie him quick.
My Shahzade, your cap.
Have some water.
These crass savages have been tactless.
Having a Shahzade like you...
...breath the same air
with a shepherd is shameful.
Would you like me to wash your face,
Shahzade?
I am Cardinal Thomas.
I come from the Papacy.
I am always ready to assist you.
I could not sleep all night because of
how these miserable people treated you.
I have arranged a special room for you.
I would like to serve the best I can
to host you in a manner deserving of...
...the royal blood you carry.
What about Turgut Aga?
Do not worry about him.
They will take good care of him.
Shall we go, Shahzade? Please.
But...
...we have another big trouble
awaiting us.
It is obvious that the things I told
Sahabettin has not been heard by El Aziz.
Today El Aziz,
tore off the agreement saying that...
...there is plague in our tribe.
This means that the caravans
don’t have a home to migrate to.
Aleppo! Aleppo! May the ground split
and take you in, Aleppo!
This is not the time to cry and frown.
I understand that Sahabettin fell victim
to a plot of the Templars.
Otherwise he would not have left me
alone in that palace no matter what.
What do you propose, Ertugrul Bey?
What is on your mind?
We have to learn
what happened to Sahabettin.
The vizier is the only person
who can help us reach Yigit and Turgut...
...as well as solve
this issue of our homeland.
We cannot leave him to the mercy of
the Crusader infidels.
Where are we going?
We are going to watch a ceremony where
youngsters like you turn to real heroes.
Father...
...Son...
...and The Holy Ghost.
Father...
...Son...
...and The Holy Ghost.
Have they become Alps now?
They have become invincible warriors,
more powerful and braver than the Alps.
My governess...
...I am really worried about my uncle.
Can he be in some sort of trouble?
You are not hiding anything
from me, are you?
My beautiful girl,
when did I ever hide anything from you?
Do not worry. I sent the maids.
We will get good news from
our vizier soon, if God permits.
If God permits, governess.
Look, whatever the news,
you shall tell me the truth. Promise me.
Leila, do not worry.
I told you that I would.
Promise me, governess.
God give me patience. Alright. I promise.
Do not be sad, Esma.
We set out a trap but could not succeed.
I did not realize that the infidels were
within us and they held my nephew...
...in their hands.
Who do you suspect, Efendi?
I did not consider him at first but...
...Nasir.
Do not be scared. Do not be afraid.
My brave Esma. There is no one
I can trust in the palace apart from you.
What can I do for you, Efendi?
Just order.
You need to find someone
and bring him here for me.
His name is Ertugrul.
My uncle.
Did she bring the news?
Calm down, Leila. You will get ill.
I am calm, governess. You promised me.
You shall tell me straight up.
Is my uncle well?
Vizier Sahabettin has been arrested.
He is to be tried.
Who did this and why?
Leila, calm down.
Your brother.
Your uncle was arrested on
the orders of your brother Ameer El Aziz.
Leila, Leila.
You need to be calm. Come and sit here.
Come on, my girl.
Calm down. You need to be calm.
Brother. I have to see my brother.
Governess, I have to save my uncle.
Do I understand you correctly?
This man called you smooth faced...
...and you got angry.
Yes, your highness.
But you cannot grow a beard.
Why do you get angry?
Anyway, you tell me.
-Your highness, this smooth face came...
-That is not appropriate.
In my presence, in the presence of
Ameer of Aleppo, El Aziz...
...you shall both watch your manners.
Now talk.
Efendi, this man came and...
...plucked my beard, Efendi.
Is that all?
-Nasir.
-Yes, your highness?
Throw both of them to the dungeon.
They shall stay in the dungeon
until the smooth face grows a beard.
When the smooth face grows a beard,
the man whose beard was plucked...
...shall pluck the beard of smooth face
to exercise the right to eye for an eye.
And this problem shall be solved.
-Let me go, your highness!
-Let me go! I beg you, let me go!
-Please spare us.
-Let me go! Let me go!
Nasir? Are these real?
Or did you arrange
this visit day to entertain me?
Please know that I have no contribution
at all, your highness.
Your subjects came to take refuge
in your justice.
My dear Nasir...
...why didn’t you tell me that
these state issues are so boring.
Your highness.
Leila Sultan.
I do not understand.
What happened to Leila Sultan?
She is not well. They wait for you.
I have just seen Sahabettin.
He suspects you.
Peace be upon you.
My dear Afsin Bey.
When they said that they saw you in the
streets of Aleppo, I did not believe them.
So the youngsters realized that
I was following them.
You raised them well.
But I am surprised. Is there anyone
left in the youngsters who know me?
Please.
Your fame precedes you, Afsin Bey.
And the ones who don’t know,
we tell what a valiant man you are.
Do not say that.
But we talked about you, we tell
the youngsters that you are a martyr.
But you are as alive as us.
We were just creating a myth.
Is there any news about
the wise man in Ahlat, Aykutluk.
It has been a while since
I have to Ahlat and talk with them.
But the news we received is not nice.
They say that the path taken
by the Seljuk dynasty is not right.
Taking Sultan Aladdin from the Konya
palace and burning down the rest...
...would not be a sin, they say.
I do not know what will happen.
When a cloud covers the crescent,
they say the night is dark, Aykutluk.
But everything depends on a wind.
The crescent shall shine again,
you can be rest assured about that.
Anyway, I want something else from you.
Listen closely.
Inform all your ears and eyes
in the streets of Aleppo.
We need to learn
the fate of Vizier Sahabettin.
Thank you.
Leila? My sister?
Brother, where is our uncle?
The starry night of Aleppo, Leila.
Why do you worry, my dear sister?
He did not visit me for days.
He never neglected me before.
Are the things I heard true?
My Leila.
The ache of my heart.
Why do you make a fuss over my uncle?
He must be drowned in state work.
He would visit you in a few days.
Tell me the truth, brother!
Are the things I heard true?
Is my uncle in prison?
When a slight breeze passes,
you tremble like a dry leaf.
Your innocent heart cannot bear
the ugliness of the world.
You would be bedridden
like a wilting rose.
My precious sister...
...do not think about our uncle.
-Brother. Is it true?
Our uncle Sahabettin...
...engaged in things not befitting to him.
Unfortunately,
what you heard is true, my sister.
I do not believe that.
How can you believe such a thing?
Our uncle would never attempt a bad thing.
You are mistaken, my innocent sister.
Our precious uncle...
...our wise vizier...
...collaborated with the killers
of our father, the Templar Knights.
Leila, Leila.
Leila.
Leila! Leila!
I told your request to our people,
Afsin Bey. We will hear something soon.
Shall we drink some sherbet
and rest until then?
Ertugrul?
Tell me, my Sultan.
Do not worry about me.
I shall be fine.
I know.
But I burn inside as I see you in pain.
You risked your own life to save me.
What if something happened to you?
But it did not. I am fine.
When I opened my heart to you that day...
...you denied it. You are ready to
sacrifice yourself but...
...you refrain from
telling me what is in your heart.
When a girl knows that
she cannot attain her worldly love...
...she yearns to reach the Godly love.
Ertugrul you always told me the truth.
I beg you not to hide
the truth from me now.
I know it is not a good sign
that they are so delayed.
Is there any news about Yigit and Turgut,
Ertugrul?
-Yes.
-Tell me the truth, Ertugrul.
Did something happen to my brother?
The Templars...
...took them as prisoners.
Don’t.
Yigit must be devastated. Ertugrul...
Ertugrul, I beg you, save Yigit.
I promise you, Halime.
I will bring your brother back to you.
Hatun.
You shall be a bit uncomfortable but...
...when we think about the long time
you shall be spending with us...
...it is best for everyone
that your paws are under control.
-Where did you take the boy?
-Don’t you worry about him.
You can be rest assured that
we will look after him very well.
He is an innocent boy.
What do you want from him?
Do whatever you want to do to me!
Why do you think that we treat him badly?
Cardinal Thomas who came here
is looking after him personally.
You should have seen them while
they were watching the knights.
In the eyes of the small Shahzade,
there was a sparkle that is befitting...
...of the poor warriors of Jesus.
Welcome, my princess.
Where is Elanora?
Why didn’t my sister come out to greet me?
Ma’am, Ustad is waiting for you.
He shall inform you about
this matter as well.
Isadora!
My dear niece.
You are here at last.
I missed you very much, dear uncle.
But my sweet sister is still
nowhere to be seen.
Didn’t she miss me?
But she was urging me to come as soon as
possible in the letter she wrote to me.
Where is Elanora, uncle?
-Governess?
-I am here, Leila.
Close the curtains, governess.
There is too much light inside.
My dear girl...
...if you could get up and walk a bit,
if you could eat something...
...you would regain your strength.
You did not eat anything the whole day.
I am really worried about you, Leila.
Close the curtains, governess.
Is there any news, Afsin Bey?
What is his situation?
The news is not very good, Ertugrul Bey.
Sahabettin Tugrul is arrested.
He is in Aleppo dungeons.
What is the reason?
What is he accused with?
The accusation is not known, Ertugrul Bey.
But yesterday Chief of Guard Nasir
and Melik El Aziz were seen...
...taking something out.
There was a maid from
the palace with them as well.
It might be something to do
with the vizier.
Are you better now, Isadora?
How did it happen, uncle?
How did my beautiful sister die?
You know that...
...Elanora never accepted
his father’s death.
And this thought had started
to affect her health.
Maybe she mentioned this to you
in her letters.
Mad girl.
She had a wild idea that
your father was in the dungeon.
She insisted to go there and started
to create ridiculous excuses to go there.
And she did not want understand
how dangerous the dungeon was for her.
I forbade her to go there.
But...
...a day when I was not in the castle...
Did she go down the dungeon?
One of the ferocious convicts...
...in the hope of that he might escape...
...killed our innocent Elanora.
-Is that convict still alive?
-No.
He was executed,
just like the guards who let her go in.
Elanora’s death was avenged
in a suitable manner.
She is very tame, Efendi.
But she knows her job well.
One of the most beautiful girls
we have, Efendi.
-How is this one?
-She can stay.
This one is a genuine pearl.
Words are not enough
to describe her beauty.
She is intelligent, skillful, educated.
She has a beautiful voice as well.
She can sing, recite poems
and dances beautifully.
Those who watch her dance are enchanted.
You can arrange the rest.
You know how this axe is made, right?
Yes.
I know well.
A heap of steel becomes an axe
blow by blow, beaten up endlessly.
Well...
...do you know how miners makes the metal
and how leather man makes leather?
If this piece of leather on you
didn’t get beaten blow by blow...
...it would have become
a piece of garbage.
If it wasn’t fired, the metal in your
sword would still be a rock somewhere.
What about you, Ertugrul?
What would happen if you were not tested?
Do you know that?
The problem is not only me being tested.
My friends,
my battle comrades, my family...
...my tribe who trusted me.
The vizier who wanted to help me.
They are all in great difficulties
because of me.
The pain caused by this
is burning my soul.
Existence is a school, son.
Everyone is a student.
And God is the only Teacher.
He manifests His Titles and test us.
But distress or blessing,
mercy or trouble is always from Him.
Everyone lives their own exam.
You need to be one of the people who pass
the exam and submit yourself to Him.
Then you would be the greatest warrior
and the greatest hero.
Is sitting around like this
a test as well?
God likes submission, son, not imprudence.
If a brother is in a bad situation...
...submission is to look for a way
to get him out, without forgetting God.
Come on, get up.
Test of a valiant is not easy.
And a valiant should not stop.
Her room.
-If you don’t want to stay here...
-On the contrary, I want to stay here.
You are very tired.
Rest well tonight, Isadora.
Good night, my girl.
Good night.
Bey...
...I am the private maid of
Vizier Sahabettin Tugrul.
My name is Esma, he sent me here.
How do I know that Sahabettin sent you?
He told me to say “a man’s word is said
directly to a man’s face” and that...
...you would know, Bey.
He wants to talk face to face with you.
All state matters are left to you,
your highness.
And I thought that you have
a right to enjoy life a bit.
I hope that I was not tactless.
How will you take me in?
There is a secret passage that goes
to the dungeons. My vizier told me.
We will slip through there
without anyone realizing.
Do not let yourself go, son.
Be strong.
They will test your will to the limits.
What more can they do to me?
I do not care about myself...
...I wonder what they are doing
to that innocent boy.
They might have even killed him.
Look, young man...
...if your body is in this dungeon...
...the thing that awaits you
is much more than death itself.
If you know what will happen
to us so well...
...you must know those infidels well.
Because I know them so well,
I am in this dungeon for 17 years.
How did you bear this for so long?
With love.
The one who lights up the darkness
inside you even if your eyes are closed.
Do not stop thinking for even one second.
-Are you a hunter.
-I am the hunted this time.
The new home will be a new and joyous life
for all of us. Especially for us.
-Does Aleppo have everything?
-It has everything.
When we reach there, it will be complete.
We will go and we will wed.
This is my promise to you.
Aykiz?
Let me see?
It is a deep wound.
Thank you.
Aykiz...
...I was presumptuous.
I broke your heart.
But believe me, it was not my intention.
When you talked like that
about Ertugrul...
Aykiz, there is nothing
in my hand except my dreams and hopes.
The only thing that
make me go forward is hope.
If I did not have that, I would die right
here, right now from disappointment.
You cannot sooth your pain
by hurting others, Gokce.
But do not despair so much.
My problem is not you.
I thought that as we near Aleppo
I would be relieved...
...I would be joyous with
seeing Turgut again.
But a shadow is cast over my heart.
It is as if I am getting further away from
my sweetheart, instead of nearing him.
Memories pass in front my eyes.
Don’t tire yourself out
over nothing, Aykiz.
Over all the hardships and
sorrows we go through...
...your love is like a flower
that heralds the spring.
Ertugrul’s love made you a poet.
May God bless us all.
I only want to meet Turgut safe and sound,
that is enough for me.
Come on.
I am hungry like the wolf, Hatun.
Can’t you hurry up a bit?
I am coming, Bey.
I made the food you like.
It has been a while since we ate alone.
-May it be healthy, Gundogdu.
-Thank you, Hatun.
May it be healthy.
Hatun, I don’t have time for anything
because of the tribe’s issues.
You are right, Gundogdu.
You are like Bey of the tribe right now.
It is not easy to carry this load.
May God give you strength.
-Come on, Bismillah. Eat up.
-Bismillah.
Do we have permission, Gundogdu?
Gundogdu.
What do you want?
Control yourself, Gundogdu.
Don’t do anything you might regret.
You stay away from this, Selcan Hatun.
There are things you don’t know.
Yes...
...these are the things
that happened, Bey.
But as you have opened your eyes,
nothing is important anymore...
...they will all pass away,
if God permits.
Now, even if all hell breaks loose,
we can put it out with our hearts, Bey.
When we stand together in prayer line,
what trouble can hurt us?
You have always been with me, Wild Demir.
Anytime I had a problem,
you were on my side.
You are closer than a brother for me.
When you talk about brotherhood, Bey...
...you, I, Kurdoglu...
...Alpsungur.
We were brothers. Yes, we were.
Look, we are still like that. But...
Friendship get valuable with age, Bey.
Old friends like you and I.
Did you see Kurdoglu? He could not hit
a bear in front of him in the old times.
As he gets older, his eyes started
seeing better than a hawk, God bless.
This man is someone who I call Emmi
and our Shah calls blood brother.
But what did he do?
He tried to kill our Shah.
The matter is not like you think,
Gundogdu.
-First you have to listen to me.
-What will you tell me? What?
How you panicked when I told you
that you secretly went into the tent?
Or how you went to finish off the job
in the middle of the night? Which one?
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
I went to save Suleyman Shah from
the fury of the rabid son of Baybora.
I saved our Bey at the last second.
Moreover it was you who warned me
by telling me the tear in the tent.
It was Bozok who went
into the Marquee that night.
I went after him so that he cannot
complete the job he left unfinished.
And...
...I just came to congratulate you.
Mother Hayme told me.
I wanted to congratulate our new nephew.
The group talked nothing else but this.
Did Suleyman Shah,
our father heard it as well?
What did he say?
He was the most happy one.
Suleyman Shah was overjoyed with...
...the news of a grandson.
Anyway...
...I said what I came to say.
I should not bother you anymore.
Everything happened as you expected,
Ertugrul Bey.
Yes, it did.
They become a hunt while being a hunter,
with God’s permission.
But the situation is more complex
than we thought.
If Sahabettin’s most trusted maid
whom he sent for me is a traitor...
...the vizier is stuck in the trap.
If a lion is trapped,
even the jackals start to growl.
We have to save him whatever the cost.
I will be gone for a while, Ertugrul Bey.
Is this the right time, Afsin Bey.
Will you be leaving us alone
in this fight?
Ertugrul Bey, I know that you wonder
who I am, how far I can reach and...
...where my roots are. I will answer
all your questions and more in time.
But now, we have to pass through a bridge
that is thinner than a hair and...
...sharper than a sword. I ask for
one thing and that is for you to trust me.
We fought side by side, Afsin Bey. We have
a code of battle friendship between us.
I believe in you.
Tomorrow you should go to the Turkmen
carpet man in the market, Ertugrul Bey.
His name is Aykutluk.
He will help you in every way he can.
And I will enter through
the gates of hell for Turgut and Yigit.
Thank you.
Where did those men come from?
How could you not see them, Eftelya?
He didn’t have time to inform anyone.
He must have suspected
beforehand and came prepared.
But how could you not notice
those two goat herders while walking?
Do you have an explanation for this?
I could not see, Commander Titus,
that is why I escaped in the last minute.
Just like you failing against
Ertugrul every single time...
...I failed to notice his warriors.
You should understand me very well in this
manner as you are much more experienced.
Stop! What are you doing?
We are all like apostles
fighting for God’s lamb.
If we don’t trust each other, Jerusalem
can only be a distant dream for us!
Moreover, when Sahabettin
is killed tomorrow...
...Ertugrul will only be like a sewer rat
walking around the streets of Aleppo.
Then, how you take revenge shall be
up to your personal taste.
You caused all this!
When will you stop being a stubborn brat?
You don’t care for anyone.
Not your father, nor your tribe!
Look at the state of this tribe!
It is cracking up!
Winter is coming and we don’t even
know where to go! Open your eyes!
Open your eyes!
How will this tribe stand strong,
Ertugrul? How?
You are lying, Ertugrul.
The eagle is in the cage.
Now it is the wolf’s turn.
Be the sultan of my heart,
the mother of my children...
...and my companion till the end.
When I could not even become
the sultan of the palace I was born in...
...I cannot be the sultan of your heart.
Great God, Who has created
the world and the skies, I turn to you.
My aim is to set on a new road.
You are the Owner of
the road and destination.
May You bless us at the end of this road.
My wish is not to be the owner of
a throne, a crown or property.
The thing in my heart,
on this road I set off with Your name...
...is to glorify Your name.
My only aim in swinging my sword is to...
...make my weapon a tool of Your justice.
If my heart or mind strays from this...
...lead me to the right path with
crooked swords, Dear God.
On this road I set off to glorify
Your name don’t let my heart...
...stray to worldly desires. Don’t let
my mind be deceived by the devil.
Don’t let me bow down, Dear God. Let me
and my progeny serve you in Your cause...
...and be martyrs on this road, Great God.
Hamza.
Yes, Bey?
Take this and load it to the camel.
Look, Gundogdu.
Little feet will be wearing these.
With time our son will grow and
be a valiant man, just like his father.
Your heart and mine is beating
right here now.
Everything we have, all our hopes,
our happiness is here now.
He will be our life, our blood,
continuity of our progeny.
You will see that
all troubles will be left behind.
The new homeland will be
a new world for us.
If God permits, Hatun, if God permits.
Let us complete
this migration journey first.
Come on, I have some business to
attend to, you should get ready as well.
Father?
We ran away for so long...
...we faced so many troubles...
...we went through so much...
But at the end,
we could not protect Yigit.
There is nothing we can do
except pray, father.
Look at the state I am in.
I cannot even get up.
We will find a way in the end, Halime.
God will surely open up a blessed path
in front of us in time.
Ertugrul Bey promised me.
He will not let Yigit and Turgut Alp
be captive in enemy hands.
He will not, right, father?
Your wound is very serious. I beg you,
don’t distress yourself so much.
There is a Turkmen carpet man
around here with the name of Aykutluk.
Do you know his place?
Wake up! Wake up!
Wake up!
Be patient, my girl, Leila, be patient.
Do not throw yourself
into those dark wells once again.
May God help you.
-Didn’t she eat?
-No.
Today will be a difficult day
for all of us.
We do not know how it will end.
No news about our vizier
shall reach Leila, do you understand me?
As you wish. We will of course be careful.
But, how can something like this be?
How can our great vizier,
Sahabettin Tugrul...
...whom no one can suspect his honesty
and righteousness be tried?
You are right. We don’t know with
what kind of a slander he was imprisoned.
The only thing we can do for him
is to pray God. You may leave.
God! God! God!
Welcome, Ertugrul.
Our mad ones have been heralding that
you were coming from many streets away.
Are all those madmen, beggars and
drunkards your comrades?
When mayors are being bought
and sold in the market...
...we work with madmen
in this life or death market.
We need to rescue
the vizier from the dungeon.
It is very difficult to organize it
before a week, my brave.
We need to contact the guards in
the dungeon, arrange their schedule.
Moreover he will be tried today.
In the Muslim world the balance of justice
is not that crooked yet.
We should not lose hope from God.
We should wait for the outcome.
What if it is crooked?
What will we do then?
If betrayal damages the justice,
our crooked swords shall put...
...the strayed ones
on the right path again.
But, Nasir...
...this is dangerous.
Judge Efendi, you were not thinking
of the danger...
...while you were putting
pouches of gold under your belt.
You were saying the vizier is as good as
dead. Why do you tremble like a leaf now?
And...
...think well, Judge Efendi...
...after the issue of the
vizier is handled...
...his highness Melik will need
consultants like you beside him.
Can you really do this, Nasir?
Of course.
You are very important for me,
your judgeship.
It is not easy to find a man
that can be bought so easily in Aleppo.
On behalf of Emirate  of Aleppo,
Melik El Aziz.
In the name of God Who is
The Just, The Avenger...
...The Prevailer and The Most Gracious...
...we shall commence the trial of  Emirate
of Aleppo Vizier, Sahabettin Tugrul.
The accusations are murder,
disobedience of an order...
...abusing the trust given to him
and betrayal to the City of Aleppo...
...as well as to the Muslim world.
I am one of the private guards of
Sahabettin Tugrul...
...he ordered me to obtain
a fast acting lethal poison.
I did as I was ordered.
I saw the people who tried to kill the
Kayi envoy with the vizier in the market.
The vizier was giving something to them
in a pouch. I am sure that it was gold.
I am a trader, the vizier forced me...
...he used me as a decoy in his business
dealings with the Antioch Countship.
Sahabettin Tugrul, you have heard
the accusations, what do you say?
I reject all the accusations.
The accusers
are false witnesses who are bought.
This is a platform of justice and reality.
With permission from God, these eyes
can tell between the truth and lies...
...just like they are black or white.
You do not need to worry.
Call in the last witness.
God send you to us, Ummulhayr Abla.
We were going to send a message to you.
-We have a problem.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-Welcome, Abla. What happened?
You talked about an important matter.
I do not know whether you heard about
what happened to our vizier.
Sahabettin Tugrul is
an honest person inside and outside.
He is a valuable statesman
Great God has bestowed upon us.
Everyone knows that he had been doing
his duties in a competent manner.
He is going through a difficult test...
...may Great God be on his side.
-Amen.
Leila has learned about her uncle.
She is devastated since she learned that
it was her brother who arrested him.
I worry that she may fall ill once again
and turn her back on life.
Poor girl, she was recovering
quite well recently, wasn’t she?
Yes. She had recovered with
the support of our vizier but...
How can we of help, Abla?
I...
...if it is possible...
...she may be refreshed with
a conversation with our Sheikh Efendi.
I thought that she should be refreshed
with his light before she turns...
...herself back to darkness.
-You thought well.
I shall inform our sheikh
and tell you his decision.
May God bless you.
I heard that you have a problem as well.
We have visitors in our lodge.
They are also going
through difficult tests.
A young girl like Leila is wounded.
The doctor did all he could but...
...the wound is getting worse.
The cure is with God.
If the palace physician checks her,
maybe he can find a remedy.
Of course, I will immediately
tell him to visit you tomorrow.
The girl’s condition
is an emergency, Abla.
Do you swear on the Great Holy Quran
that you shall not be lying in court?
I do, Efendi.
Tell everything as you
told me before, my girl...
...and do not be afraid of anyone.
What happened in that room that day?
The vizier and I went into
the room the killer was in, Efendi.
Was there anyone else who knew that room?
What did you see when you went in?
The man...
...was lying down.
He started to tremble.
Foam started coming out of his mouth,
he was poisoned.
He died...
...in the arms of my vizier.
You may leave, my girl.
We heard what we need to hear.
The verdict is decided upon...
The physician has completed
his examination.
You were wise to inform us. The wound
is infected, her condition is not well.
-I did a small surgery.
-May God bless you.
But we cannot do much here.
She needs to be looked after in the palace
and treated with special medicine.
We can take her to the palace. If her
condition requires it, we shall abide.
Physician, can you tell us what to do
so that we can treat her here?
I do not want to part with her
while she is in this condition.
Her situation is critical,
she may not come out of this alive...
...we did whatever can be done here,
we shall do the same in the palace.
But only God knows
what the outcome will be.
You can be rest assured, Efendi.
Your daughter is entrusted in me.
I will personally tend to her.
Ummulhayl Hanim is my sister.
She will look after your daughter well...
...in the palace and she was also
the governess of El Aziz and his sister.
Sultan Aziz is like her son.
If God permits, there'll be no problem...
...you can be rest assured.
Thank God, you are better, right?
Thank God, Hayme.
We have more meals to eat,
more days to see.
Yes, if God permits, we shall have
our grandchild in our arms soon.
It was time anyway.
This is the only joyous news I heard.
We used to yearn for
a grandchild for years.
Gundogdu and Selcan will make us
live through that joy.
May God give them the chance
to see their own grandchildren.
If God permits. If God permits, Bey.
The Emirate of Aleppo can be seen.
Put down the banner, bring the tribe flag!
Rahman! Bring my horse!
We need to enter
our new homeland on a horse.
Here you are, Bey.
Thank you, God.
You did not leave our tribe without a Bey.
What is the situation?
Bey, the front door is guarded
very heavily. There is another door...
...at the back for provisions,
we may be able to enter from there but...
...I don't know whether
we would be able to get out.
People who heard that
the vizier is being tried have gathered.
The guards are having
a hard time containing them.
They are convinced that
Sahabettin Tugrul is tried unjustly.
If we can somehow take the vizier out
we can run away in that turmoil.
-That is all I can say, Bey.
-Do not listen to him, Bey.
We don't know where the dungeons are.
It is very hard without help from inside.
If you ask me, we would be caught
before we even reach Sahabettin.
What news do you have, Bey?
I will tell you. First we should go
to the lodge and see how Halime is.
Yigit.
Ertugrul.
Poor Girl.
Please do not worry, Numan Efendi.
When we reach the palace
Halime will be much better.
Hear ye, hear ye!
It had been decreed that
our highness Giyaseddin El Aziz's...
...vizier Sahabettin Tugrul has been
collaborating with the infidels...
...and the verdict is
that he is to be executed.
-Sahabettin is our father!
-He would never do such a thing!
Bey, let me go and kill them.
To set an example.
The execution shall take place today
during the afternoon prayer time.
Master...
...our fellow Muslim brother
Sahabettin Tugrul is been subjected to...
...various slanders and is being tried.
Our hearts ache deeply for him.
What do you suggest we do?
He Who saved Jonas from
the stomach of the fish...
...Hiob from the worms
eating his wounds...
...Joseph from the well...
...Moses from the Nile...
...and The Last Prophet from the cave...
...would save our brother as well
if He wishes to.
We shall take refuge in Him.
God, Who turned the fire Abraham fell
into a rose garden...
...would turn the dungeon where
Sahabettin Tugrul is, into a womb.
Those who wait tyranny, murder and
betrayal to emerge from there...
...would be bewildered when
a resurrection emerges.
Do not worry, Turkmen.
When I finish with you,
you will not remember any pain...
...from the things I did to you.
Hello, young man.
-Who are you?
-Yigit.
What are you doing here, Yigit?
-I was not doing anything bad.
-Were you looking for someone?
Would you like me to help you?
Yes.
Then tell me, who are you looking for?
-My Turgut Agabey.
-Who is this Turgut Agabey.
He is a very powerful warrior.
He is very tall, he has very strong arms.
So he is very powerful.
Do you like Turgut Agabey very much?
Yes, I do. He is a very good man.
Come.
I am not comfortable
leaving you behind like this, Hatun.
I don't want to.
It is God's will, Bey. God forbid,
what if something happens to the tribe...
...during the migration,
what would they do without Akcakoca?
Come on, let us go in.
Everyone thinks that this is
the wisest decision, Bey.
You gave the best decision like a Bey.
May God help them.
Amen.
Are you two ready for the journey?
We are, Bey.
We are.
Come on, then.
-In the name of God.
May God be with you, Hatun.
May you have a clear road.
Halt!
Who are you?
I am from the Bozok branch of Oguz,
Bey of Kayi tribe, Suleyman Shah.
We are going to the homeland Aleppo Ameer
Giyaseddin El Aziz gave to our tribe.
We are here on the order of El Aziz.
You are not to enter the city...
...and we shall escort you until
you leave the Aleppo territory.
-Let him go, he is not a traitor!
-Let him go!
Lay Halime down there.
-Murderers!
-Let him go!
-You are the real murderers!
-Traitors!
-You cannot do this!
-You murderers!
-Traitors!
-Murderers!
Vizier, do you have a last word?
Do not remember me as a traitor!
Whatever I did,
I did for the future of our people.
Quran is my guide and God is my witness!
My head is up!
My cause is God!
If I need to die for this cause...
...whether in sleep...
...or with an axe!