Episode 14 will start after 12:10 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Glad to see you again, Shahzade.
Thank God.
Thank you, Afsin bey.
Yigit, I have some things
to talk about with Afsin Bey.
Aren't you going to Halime Sultan's
wedding, my Shahzade?
I will be there shortly, Afsin Bey.
I would rather...
...die a thousand times than be your wife.
Halime?
Halime? Halime?
I am listening to you, my Shahzade.
I have allied with El Aziz
as a Seljuk Shahzade.
From now on, I am going
to struggle to get my share...
....on the Seljuk State.
If you do,
the Seljuk State would fall apart.
The blood of brothers killing each other
would dirty the swords, my Shahzade.
I have been living with the fear of
losing my children for years, Afsin.
Now it is their turn to fear.
My decision is clear.
It is your decision, Shahzade.
I would like to have you
on my side as well, Afsin.
Let us make
the Seljuk State rise again, together.
If you work with me, I will endow you
with anything you want from the state.
You have also been running away
like a deranged man for years.
I would be grateful, my Shahzade.
Is there anything you want from me?
I want you to deliver
a message to all the Turkish tribes.
I will provide a fortune
to win their hearts.
How are we going to find
that “fortune”, my Shahzade?
El Aziz will provide
all the support he can.
You shall take action now.
I will send you a message.
You can find me in the Turkmen carpet shop
in the Aleppo souk, my Shahzade.
May you live long!
You, the courageous
Beys of the Oghuz tribe!
Are you going to rely on the words of this
villain or El Aziz the Ameer of Aleppo?
This is all I have to say,
noble Beys of the Oghuz Tribe!
The ones, who
infiltrated our nomad group, who are...
...willing to transmit
the plague to our people...
...and cause a fit among the
Islam world...
...and are willing to prevent us
from praying in Jerusalem...
...are now trying to subvert
the Seljuk State...
...by setting the Oghuzs
against each other.
This is such betrayal that it is beyond
comprehension for a man of honor.
The most evident example of it
is standing right before you.
This human piece of garbage...
...to whom Salah ad-Din Yusuf ibn Ayyub's
grandsons commended their armies...
...is standing right before you
as the Crusaders' bastard.
The ones who believe
Ertugrul are mistaken and misguided.
Those who resort to him
will pay a heavy price.
Hey you the son of a bastard!
Are we supposed to believe
the son of Suleyman Shah...
...or someone as evil
and nondescript as you?
Why should we believe the things you say
with that inauspicious face of yours?
I see that you have set a trap for me,
together with your uncle Korkut.
From now on...
...the Kizil Kekelis
are the enemies of the Ayyubids!
Those who betray
the Ameer of Aleppo El Aziz...
...shall not leave here alive!
Move!
If he is the leader of the soldiers
who you trust the most...
...you'd better replace them
with donkeys, Nasir!
Brother!
I cannot let her do this to me!
Your Highness, stop, for God's sake!
Don't do anything that you
will regret later!
What are you doing here, Halime?
You were supposed
to go to the hunting lodge.
This matter is finished, father.
There is no wedding!
What are you saying, Halime?
If you are going to carry
on with that treachery...
...you will not be able
to abuse me, father.
Halime, what have you done?
Shame on you!
You promised me!
I have fulfilled every request you made.
I have given you a dowry
no woman would ever receive.
For what?
For a little hope!
For the hope that Halime Sultan might...
...love me one day, if she pleased.
But what did she do?
She humiliated me in front of everybody!
She degraded me!
She trashed the Salah ad-Din
Yusuf ibn Ayyub's lineage!
For what?
For that goat shepherd named Ertugrul!
-Brother!
-Leyla, shush!
Shahzade, you will clean off
the shame you’ve covered my face with...
...or you all will pay the price for it.
KAYI NOMAD TENTS
Take two of the best Alps with you.
You will hit the road, armed with weapons.
Aye, Bey!
You will watch the Templars' castle.
You will inform me about...
...who gets in and out, even
about the birds that fly over it!
There is no stopping from now on!
Since they have waged a war against us,
we will loom over them like a dark shadow!
Aye, Bey!
Nobody will know about your mission
except you and the other two Alps.
Pick the most close-mouthed ones.
We saw a castle similar
to this one while we were in Alamut.
But we did not have the chance to get in.
We are meant to enter this one!
You can get in, but I am not sure
if you will be able to get out alive.
Let's hope for the best, Knight!
You can speak our language
very well, where are you from, Knight?
I am Saxon and also my mother is Breton.
Ah, good!
There is no cross tattoo on him!
Neither a cross nor a crescent, brother!
Who the hell are you?
Did you take his ring out?
Yes, Bey.
-There was poison in it, like you said.
-But he has no tattoo on his head, Bey.
If he is not a Crusader...
...he must be someone else's stooge.
Untie him.
So we are alone together, Nasir.
I will not allow you to kill yourself.
What do you want to know?
Nothing.
I already know what I should know.
Then what do you want from me?
I will take you to the nomad tent.
Just think.
An army with one
commander captured by the Kayis...
...and another one
taking shelter in the Kayis.
Do you think they would be
able to go to war?
You bastard!
Dogan, Bamsi.
Get him ready!
Turgut.
Move, Turk, this way!
Sir, I have brought your guest.
Welcome Kurdoglu!
I am glad to be here.
You must be the Master.
God bless, everybody
can speak our language here.
We had a conversation
with your knight during our trip...
...even though he is not
as friendly as you are.
Speaking the enemy's language
is the greatest weapon, Kurdoglu.
Are we still enemies?
We know how to embrace
everyone who collaborates with us.
Even the Muslims?
The shadow of the cross
upon which Jesus was crucified...
...keeps us all cool in the fire
of our tormented lives, Kurdoglu.
Who we are does not matter.
What matters the most is that our
interests are aligned, don't you think so?
Smart people have always
set my mind at ease.
I had a very nice meal prepared for you.
Since I know how your fine tastes are...
...I could say that I had it
prepared especially for you.
Titus overpraised your cuisine,
and especially your hospitality.
Thank you.
After you!
Wow!
This must be what it’s like
to be a great and wealthy person, huh?
Every herd needs a shepherd, of course!
Our herd cannot even
prepare a simple meal, Bey!
They only know how to herd animals.
Anything and everything
is about snarling at other men.
This time they have gone too far.
Aleaddin on one side...
the Ayyubids on the other side,
the Crusaders on the other.
It is all about two
impractical evils doing stupid things.
Suleyman Shah and his son, Ertugrul.
If somebody doesn’t
put them through the wringer...
...too many heads will roll, Kurdoglu.
Mostly from your nomad group.
-Isadora.
-Uncle.
I took your Aristotle book.
Excuse me.
She is a beautiful girl, isn't she?
We can only say:
“May God grant her a happy marriage.”
Mario?
Good day, madam.
How much longer are you
going to run away from me?
Come to see me tomorrow morning.
Eftelya?
Titus.
This...
This is impossible!
I saw your burnt body myself.
Titus, you are underestimating me.
That body you saw was not mine.
Wear it!
I know that El Aziz and Halime's
wedding plan went down the drain.
So the Seljuk and the Ayyubid
war is just a dream now.
Are you holding my arms, that you once
held with love, with anger now?
I am not responsible for what
happened. Come to your senses!
I am sorry, Eftelya.
I did not mean to make you angry.
There is only one person responsible
for the things that have happened.
And that is Ertugrul!
Ertugrul and Halime
are madly in love with each other.
There can be two reasons
for a man's failure, Titus.
The first is his uncontrollable
ambition, and the other is love.
You still have a chance.
If you can manage to abuse
the weak sides of those foolish lovers...
...you will be able get what you want.
Go to the castle.
Lie low for some time.
We will find a way to get you
into the palace when this is all over.
What about Nasir?
Huh, Nasir!
He is busy with provoking the Turkmens...
...into starting a riot
against Sultan Aleaddin.
What are you going to do?
This marriage will be solemnized.
And Ertugrul will die.
That is my job.
I would have liked to serve you some wine.
I am growing the grapes in my own
vineyard with my own fair hands.
But I thought it would not be
appropriate because of your religion.
Thank you.
As I said earlier, I would have liked to
help your nomad group very much...
...but I do not want to take El Aziz's
armies on without a cause.
The only thing we all wish for
is just a little peace, isn't it?
Aren't you going to help at all?
I cannot help because the interests of
the Crusaders' world do not permit that.
But we are both smart enough to get the
best out of this situation in the end...
...don't you think so, Kurdoglu?
How can that be?
If you kill Suleyman Shah
and supersede....
...you will not only get our support...
but also the support of the
Crusaders' Principality of Antioch...
...which is under our control,
the support of El Aziz's palace...
...the support of everyone!
I am not talking about
just moral support.
The fertile grasslands...
The loot you will receive
by raiding the orthodox infidels.
You shall not be pushed for money.
I would like you to find
new allies in your nomad group.
Persuade them into being bewitched
by the gold and captivate them.
A small gift for you.
Any questions, Kurdoglu?
The knight I saw in the courtyard.
Isn't he Ertugrul's Alp, Turgut?
We are calling him Judas now.
When the right time comes and
he goes back to your nomad tent...
...he will be your closest helper.
And also my messenger.
Judas.
I am going to head out
for Konya immediately.
I am going to tell Sultan Aleaddin
what has happened.
Ertugrul, we shall not waste
our time here any longer.
It is best to hit the road
as soon as possible.
Keep an eye on him.
Do not let him kill himself like Eftelya.
Don’t worry, Bey.
What if this pander quibbles
and tells his soldiers that it’s a lie...
...when you take him to the nomad tent?
As long as Nasir and Sahabettin
are in the nomad tent...
...he would not have the courage
to sic his men on us, uncle.
Will you hold him hostage?
El Aziz will have to listen to us.
El Aziz is such an inept man that...
...he knows very well he cannot
rule the country without them.
May God help us all!
Amen.
The entire palace is imprisoned by your
sorrow, Your Highness The Ameer.
I’ve been badly betrayed, Ebu Hisham.
Halime...
...the woman I love...
...humiliated me in front of everyone...
...and abandoned the wedding.
I do not know what to say,
Your Highness The Ameer.
And you were so excited about it.
You were going to go
to the hunting lodge...
...and spend the sweetest
and happiest days of your life there.
I cannot explain how sorry I am.
So you say, Ebu Hisham,
I was destined to be unhappy!
I wouldn't like to bore you on
a sad day like this, but perhaps...
...if I told you something that
I have just learned, it might help.
I am listening...
If you take Halime Sultan
and head out for the hunting lodge...
...I know that someone
will come after you.
Ertugrul.
How do you know that?
Because of the secret visit...
...that your sister and your nanny
made to my beloved merchant friend...
...Your Highness The Ameer.
Talk frankly, Ebu Hisham!
Leyla and your nanny...
...are meeting with
Ertugrul in Ephraim's shop.
Ertugrul learns everything that is going
on in the palace from them.
No.
It is a lie, isn't it?
Soldiers, come with me!
Tell Commander Gunhan
not to wait any longer!
I do not want to hear the name Kayi
any longer.
Kill anyone who resists without pity.
Are you still here? Hurry!
I loved you as if you were my mother.
You became Leyla's wet nurse.
Your milk was so poisonous...
...that you poisoned my sister as well.
El Aziz, what kind of words
are those, son?
The tricks you pulled behind my back
with my stupid sister...
...your meeting with Ertugrul
in Ephraim's shop...
I already know everything, nanny.
-Brother!
-Brother?
You will never ever get out
of this room, Leyla!
And speaking of you, nanny...
Guards!
Take this woman...
...and take her to the dungeon.
She will not get out of there
till she dies.
No!
El Aziz, son, why are you doing
these to us?
Take that woman.
Brother, don't do it.
Don't, please! Brother, don't do it.
Don't do it.
Brother! Please!
Brother?
I do not want to see your face again.
Neither yours nor hers.
You both are dead for me.
Get ready.
We are leaving, Halime Sultan.
Where?
As we have decided earlier,
to the hunting lodge.
I am not going anywhere with you,
Your Highness The Ameer.
You will.
If you want to see your father
and brother again, you will.
Odalisques!
Help Halime Sultan to get ready.
We are leaving tomorrow.
Ertugrul Bey sent me.
You should have said that before, son.
I had an awful fright.
All right, Master Ephraim.
Forgive me if I have scared you.
Oh love!
It is love, son, I understand.
Love conquers all.
Leyla Sultan sent this note.
Shall we take Ertugrul's Alp, sir?
No, he will bring Ertugrul to us.
Nothing will be the way
it used to be, father.
With God's permission, everything
will be very good, daughter.
Look, nawruz has arrived,
spring is everywhere.
Our hopes will blossom, like life.
Hopelessness does not suit us, daughter.
By taking refuge in God,
it is our religious duty, our worship
to start every day with
the rising sun like a spring bud.
Dear Aykiz, my pale daughter.
My pure daughter.
If God permits, your destiny
shall be as beautiful as your face.
Permission to come in, Master Demir?
Come in.
I came to see how she is.
If you need anything...
With God's permission,
my daughter is fine.
Her wounds will heal soon.
But she is tired now.
She shall rest, eh?
I am sorry for everything, Master Demir.
I would not want this to happen.
I know, daughter. Your heart
is as pure as your face.
God will call anyone who has sins
to account, I know that as well.
There you go.
Bey.
If you say anything
I will cut your tongue
into pieces with my sword, Nasir.
Walk!
-Peace be upon you, father.
-Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, lions.
Thank God you are here.
How are things? Tell me.
The plot thickens in Aleppo, father.
El Aziz the Ameer of Aleppo is willing
to drag Halime Sultan's father
Shahzade Numan into a war against
Sultan Aleaddin
by marrying Halime Sultan.
If this happens, the Seljuk State
which is our only hope
would fall into the claws
of the grim reaper.
We need to shield the Seljuk.
We have spoilt their games
for now, father.
-El Aziz will not be able to attack us.
-Why not?
Nasir; El Aziz's commander and
the Templars' man at the same time.
We have captured and brought him here.
You made me happy. You made me proud.
May God bless you in both worlds.
Your unity and peace
shall not be destroyed.
You shall be honored with
Halil Ibrahim's abundance.
If we can manage to take
Halime Sultan from him...
...we would put the Seljuk at ease.
Bey.
Where is my mother?
Where is my brother Dundar?
Your brother Dundar...
...is fighting with the grim reaper
inside.
Mother?
My lions!
My lions are back.
Thanks be to God!
You came.
-How is he?
-Akcakoca said
"Where there is life there is hope!"
But even if he recovers,
his mental skills...
Who has done it?
We do not know, son.
When that merchant came to buy
our goods, what happened was...
Ebu Hisham!
The real name of the man who
you know as Ebu Hisham is Titus.
A Templar Knight who has been chasing
me since I killed his brother Bisol.
What happened is all my fault.
Give me your blessings.
It is the volition of God, son.
The volition of God.
Our chivalrous brother will recover,
if God permits.
Son...
...there is still a hope for Dundar.
But...
...we have another great anguish.
What is it, mother?
-Selcan.
-What happened to Selcan?
Bride Selcan lost her baby.
-Son!
-Gundogdu!
Selcan?
I could not be the wife
to give you a child.
I disappointed you, hurt your pride.
Come on, you do not say it.
God is the giver and the taker.
Come on, just tell me,
how did this happen?
While we were practicing for the war
we have gone to because of your brother...
...Wild Demir's Aykiz caused me
to have a miscarriage.
I told you that Aleppo would do us
no good, Gundogdu.
Talk frankly, woman.
Did Aykiz cause you to miscarry?
She attacked me regardless
of my pregnancy.
I found myself tumbling down without
realizing what had happened.
She caused me to lose my baby.
So I will burn their home down then.
I beg you, do not do anything, Gundogdu!
It will pass, daughter. It will.
These bad days will pass,
these grieves will pass.
Do not forget that, God Almighty
is the most merciful.
And God Almighty is testing
our patience and resignation.
And that shows that
he has not given up on us.
May God protect us from the ones who
makes mischief and casts aspersions.
Permission to come in, Wild Demir?
Go ahead, Gundogdu.
Aykiz!
The murderer of my unborn baby!
What was your problem
with that innocent baby?
We all were blind to your faults
just because you were in pain
we ignored your foolish acts. But sooner
or later, you will pay the price for it.
Manners, Bey's son, manners!
You want to take a life?
An eye for an eye?
Go ahead, kill me!
But don't you ever forget that
your serpent-eyed wife...
...has cast aspersions on my daughter.
What aspersions, Wild Demir?
What aspersions?
Your daughter has no limits,
without measure.
And what is more, she ruined my family!
Sooner or later, she will pay
the price for it!
Since you have been out to gather
information about the army
I shall tell you the things
you should know.
The army that El Aziz has sent
to the nomad tent
consists of 3600 horsemen.
And together with the pedestrians
and the support forces
the number is around 7000.
And with your 2000 Alps, the difference
is beyond comparison.
How do you know that?
Do you think El Aziz's army would do
anything without my knowledge?
What are you doing here? You traitor!
Who is this man, Kurdoglu?
He is one of Suleyman Shah's Alps.
There were two Turks there,
now they do not exist.
Did Suleyman Shah have you chased?
I do not think so.
He must have sent him to watch the castle.
It is better he did not return
to the nomad tent.
No doubt.
How could you do this
to our Bey, Kurdoglu?
Hell with your Bey!
Whatever I have done, I have done it
for my nomad group.
Turgut!
Welcome Claudius.
His Holiness The Cardinal
is expecting you.
You have received the news I sent.
That is good.
I was worried sick, Bey.
Where have you been?
Stash these gold away, Alpargo.
Now the time has come.
Your father told me not to come
but I could not help myself.
It is not your mistake, Gokce.
My father must have said it
to prevent you from coming into
conflict with your sister.
What happened that day, Aykiz?
We started to rake over the old coals,
I do not know how.
She mentioned your father.
My father. Suleyman Shah.
Is what they are telling true?
When my father died,
was Suleyman Shah with him?
He was.
And also my father had gone into
combat to protect Suleyman Shah.
That is how I heard.
My father never talks about it.
If my father had gone against...
...the nomad group, the headquarters
and the Beys...
...what had been done must be
what ought to be done.
May God forgive his sins.
You are a good girl, Gokce.
May God unite you with your loved ones.
You too, Aykiz.
I hope to see you in your bridal gown
in your wedding with Turgut.
I will come back again.
What are you saying, Kurdoglu?
How many days do you think
we can withstand
if El Aziz's army attacks us tomorrow?
For three days, we won't let them into
the emplacements we have prepared.
On the fourth day...
...they would pass over the emplacements
and the ambuscades.
On the fifth day...
...our children would be
at their commander's mercy.
Even a single Alp's chance to stay alive
is not within the bounds of possibility.
I would like to discuss the decision
you have made with you
in the headquarters.
What do we have to discuss?
Am I supposed to discuss cutting my son
Ertugrul's and Atabey Sahabettin's
heads off and proffering with
my own hands, with my Beys?
There is no harm in discussion, Bey.
Are not the headquarters
an Oghuz tradition?
Are not the traditions the reasons
of our current situation?
The headquarters is the embodiment
of the Oghuz tradition.
Of course there is a price
to pay for our current situation.
-And that price has to be paid.
-Enough!
What an impertinence!
I am talking to you as an old friend...
...a blood brother, Suleyman,
not the way as I would talk to my Bey.
This matter is not about
me or you, Suleyman.
It is about the future of our nomad group.
Thousands of lives.
I would like to discuss this matter
with you in the headquarters.
If you gather the headquarters
after the friday prayer
we will discuss it.
Now if you excuse me,
I would like to get some rest.
Welcome, Ertugrul Bey.
You wait for me inside, son.
There is a matter
I would like to talk with you.
I heard what you talked.
What would you say
about this matter, wife?
You have always looked for
the enemy outside, Bey.
The enemy was among us.
But you never wanted to see it.
I claimed a headquarters after
the friday prayer tomorrow.
The payback time with Suleyman
has already arrived.
What will we do with so many gold?
We will buy the nomad group's future,
Alpargo. The nomad group's future.
I want to talk about my testament
with you.
You know that...
...I do not own anything other than
my weapons and three or five animals.
We have not condescended
to anything on this world...
...we have not gone after it, thank God.
I didn't mean that.
However we have too much on
our shoulders than we can achive.
El Aziz's army may attack us anytime.
And whether we will survive or not
tomorrow is uncertain.
It is the ephemeral world,
the mortal world.
As your father, I would like to bequeath
one of the millstones around my neck.
Like I have bequeathed one of them
to your brother.
I am talking about Gokce, son.
I know about Halime Sultan also.
Do not think I am ignoring
the fire within your heart.
I also know every sacrifice you have made
for our nomad group.
That Ertugrul I sent to Aleppo
is not before me.
That Ertugrul has gone and
the hero that will save the nomad group's
future has come instead of him.
I also know this very well.
Father...
The reason why I am not speaking about it
on these hard times is that.
If we can get rid of these troubles
and breathe easy...
...you will marry Gokce, Ertugrul.
Gokce is no longer your sister,
she is your wife.
If I die...
...I bequeath Gokce to you.
Oh God, make my dreams come true.
Put your dagger back in its sheath, uncle.
Your time has not come yet.
But, it is about to...
...do not worry.
What time is that, nephew?
Till things are exposed...
...till you are unable to find
a place to hide...
...you are safe till your sins
shine your shadow.
Till that time you can cower behind
my father's friendly shadow easily.
But...
...I have my eyes on you, you should know.
If you think I would let you dig a pit
for us, then you are mistaken, uncle.
Do not think you took becoming
the Bey for granted
just because you have managed to bring
El Aziz's commander to the nomad tent.
Tomorrow is another day.
Of course someone will know
about the things you have done
and call to account.
And you know that in our tradition
it has no importance what or who
you are to become the Bey.
Even if you marry the Shahzade's daughter
and bring her to the nomad tent
this does not make way
to the marquee for you.
You should know that I am not inclined
to become the Bey, Kurdoglu.
There are so many men who would not
drag the nomad group
into endless adventures and
let them go astray, Ertugrul.
They would not opt for the adventurers
like you, even if you wanted them to.
Especially when there are
decent Bey candidates like Gundogdu
in the nomad group.
And you, Kurdoglu?
Are you planning to become the Bey
by falling into the arms of that infidel
who introduces himself as Ebu Hisham?
I know there are so many people
that respect the men who stab people
in the back like yourself.
But my brother is not one of them.
Do not ever think that I do not know
what you are planning...
...with your uncanny friends
just like you.
I know what you have been doing
since the day you went to Aleppo.
However...
...I do not have the proof for them.
My life is yours the very day
you find that proof, Ertugrul.
But if you cannot,
I will make you pay for these defamations.
Delusions and baseless defamations
all the time.
I do not know if I should get mad at you.
Whether I should beat you up
like I did when you were a little boy.
What am I going to do with you, Ertugrul?
Nothing, Uncle. Nothing.
But I know very well
what I am going to do with you.
You will see it when the day comes, Uncle.
My son...
One of my brothers is in his deathbed...
...and my other brother is
God knows where.
One of my brothers is in sorrow
for losing his child.
And I am wounded.
The troubles of this pavilion
never come to an end, Mother.
You have such an indestructible sorrow.
They would talk bad about us
if we got over these troubles.
If we cry on the inside,
but laugh on the outside...
...the evil eyes wouldn't leave us alone.
One who gets in the Lord's pavilion once,
seeks salvation in death.
What can we do?
This is our destiny, son.
What about my destiny?
My heart goes towards its loved one
who is from the Kinik tribe...
...like a galloping rider on his horse.
However, our father, our lord...
...sees fit the hazel eyed girl
from the Kayi tribe.
The horse that lies in my heart
has only one saddle, mother.
When the lord speaks,
when the father speaks...
...the young one should only obey.
When you become a lord, your heart
should be as big as your pavilion.
If the horse that lies in your heart
has a saddle...
...you should sit on it yourself,
not your woman.
If what your heart says,
and what your brain says...
...really love you...
...they will certainly
come to you together.
What are you saying, mother?
You were the one who said...
..."Should the place where you lean on
wear off and come apart?
Even a wild animal is hairy.
One should only have one spouse."
Ertugrul Bey, can I come in?
I had Ilyas Fakih read this, my Lord.
What does it say?
El Aziz.
He is taking Halime Sultan
to the hunting lodge.
However, they have not gotten married yet.
El Aziz is taking her there by force.
My Lord...
Dogan, what is it, son?
Mother Hayme...
...Ertugrul Bey...
...has gone.
Gone where?
To bring Halime Sultan back.
My Lord...
Please let us come with you.
It is not ready, my Lord.
It has not been fixed yet.
It will do the job, Bamsi.
I will go alone.
The war is at the door.
The tent should not be left alone.
My Lord...
Thank you, brother.
What the hell are we going to do now?
My Shah...
I was wondering if you need anything.
No, my girl.
Have a good night, my girl.
I just wanted to say good night,
Hayme Anne.
You too, my girl.
You were going to ask Ertugrul,
weren't you?
Come on, let's have a seat.
Ertugrul went to bring Halime back.
I am leaving, Dogan.
Where are you going? Our Lord said this
was for him to do and told us to sit here.
No, brother.
My butt hurts after all that sitting down.
I will tell him you urged me to do it.
So, you would sell me out just like that.
You are like a well-fed suckling veal.
I would sell you in the market.
Get out of the way, infidels!
We are going to bring Halime Baci back.
You love him, don't you?
Yes, mother.
I have been loving him
since my childhood.
Your sister Selcan
has brought this up first.
And I have told it to Suleyman Shah.
I know, mother.
So, tell me,
what if this had never been brought up?
Then it would never be brought up again.
I would live on with my untold love.
Who knows, maybe I would have
gotten married with another man.
I would have another life.
What about now?
Is another man possible now, mother?
If you really love Ertugrul...
...would you do anything for him?
I would, mother.
So...
...you could afford forgetting him,
wouldn't you?
Mario?
What was the thing
you wanted to talk me about?
Mario, say something.
Forgive me, my girl.
I committed a very big sin.
I cannot carry this burden anymore.
That is enough. Just tell me.
Your father is alive, my girl.
It all started when
Ibn al Arabi lured him away.
When he abandoned our religion
and became a Muslim.
Cardinal, his majesty,
please tell me...
...when my hands
are all covered with blood like this...
...will our Father Almighty
accept me to his kingdom?
I lost Jesus' words and mercy
in my heart.
I am afraid.
Isn't the blood on your hands for watering
the flowers in God's kingdom, Claudius?
The blood which turns
God's kingdom into heaven.
The blood which
spells the death of infidels.
I cannot forget
the screams of the innocent women...
...and children I have killed, Cardinal.
I cannot sleep at nights.
Whenever I close my eyes,
I wake up with those screams.
Nightmares...
Pangs of conscience that never stop.
I am begging you, set me free.
Allow me to go to a chapel
and live as a monk for life.
Yes, I have promised you,
have I not?
I was going to set you free.
However, I have one more request
from you, Claudius.
I will do whatever you ask, sir.
I found where Ibn al Arabi is.
I want you to kill him
and take the relic in his ark.
Your biggest enemy while doing this
will be Ustad Fetitus.
Be careful, only the two of us know this.
This will be our secret.
Yes, Cardinal, Your Majesty.
God forgive your sins, my child.
They will eventually be punished.
Please God Almighty, punish them now.
Hear our prayers, God.
Hear them.
Sir...
...Nasir has slaughtered
all our dervishes brutally.
Does a Muslim man
persecute another Muslim man?
We curse him day and night,
and that is all we can do.
A Muslim man
never persecutes another Muslim man.
He never attempts against life unjustly.
However, we will not let persecution
plant seeds of hate in our hearts.
We will protect ourselves
from being persecutors.
When a tribe requested somebody...
...to tell them about Islam...
...our Prophet, very lovingly...
Peace be upon him.
...sent 70 young men to that town
to tell them about Islam.
While Medina was waiting for good news...
...they received the worst news.
Lightnings stroke
from the skies down to the city.
Each household was in fire.
Those 70 men that our Prophet sent...
...were martyred in an ambush
that took place in Bir Maona.
Our Prophet was very saddened after that.
Anas Ibn Malik says that...
...our Prophet had never been
more saddened in any other incident.
He cursed those cruel infidels
after the morning prayer for a while.
What happened after that?
After that,
this verse from the Quran was disclosed:
"And We have revealed you
only as grace to the worlds !"
Our Prophet stopped cursing them
after this verse.
He did not even curse the infidels.
We will not curse any Muslim,
even if they are sinners and tyrants.
We will not fill our hearts
with grudge and hatred.
We will be cautious.
We will prevent persecution
with our full strength.
However, we will not let persecution
to turn us into persecutors.
We will not let the devil
settle into our hearts.
Sir, you always say
everything happens for a reason.
What is the reason of all this?
What is the reason for an innocent person
getting killed?
My son, yes,
everything happens for a reason.
The reason for a person
being martyred under persecution...
...is for him to not die as a persecutor.
To be persecuted and weakened
is not a shame for a Muslim.
The only two things that devastate
a man in both worlds...
...are persecution and betrayal.
Thank God for protecting our brothers
from being persecutors.
Thank God.
The state is under duress
as long as Numan lives, Afsin.
What are we going to do now?
You had to kill both Numan and Yigit.
You were weak.
Listen, Afsin.
I know what you feel about Shahzades.
But we do not have any choice.
If we do, tell me
and we will act accordingly.
When the fire of power glows once...
...the only way to put it out...
...is the spilling blood in streams.
May God forgive their sins.
We have been travelling
through all those places.
For what, gentlemen?
For our sons and our daughters
to be happy.
For our goats and sheep to strengthen.
We have been having trouble
for such a long time...
...instead of finding peace.
But, for what?
For what?
Our Lord's children
are bringing trouble after trouble...
...instead of reuniting our tent.
We saved ourselves
from Kara Toygar and came to this land.
And now we are besieged by enemies
from all sides.
We bring the fire into the tent instead of
evading the trouble, Suleyman Shah.
Gentlemen...
The higher people of my tent.
I see that you are tired of
our struggle to death.
And you are scared of the enemy.
What was our pact with each other...
...before leaving the
great mountains of Otukan?
We were not going to give up...
...even if the enemy
came for us like a dragon!
Wasn't this our pact?
But I see that you gave up!
I see that you are scared!
How can I trust you
in a battle after this?
How can I give you weapons
and send you to battle?
What kind of state is this?
My Lord...
We forgot neither the promise we gave
in Otukan nor how to fight.
However, you and your children...
...forgot the nobleness of this beylic.
You fool!
And your friends.
A child is a father's essence.
A lion from a lion,
and a jackal from a jackal.
Know your place!
Just know  your place!
My Lord, there is a messenger.
Let him in.
Suleyman...
The time has come.
El Aziz has decided
to destroy your tent.
As a Oghuz Turk, I came here
to warn you for the last time.
Turn Ertugrul and Sahabettin
over to us.
I would give you my life
even if you came to us like rain.
But I would never give you
even a baby goat from my tent.
Enough is enough, my Lord!
Enough.
You do the opposite of what we want.
You cannot throw the tent
into the fire for the jackals.
Kurdoglu!
I will take your head myself, Suleyman!
Commander!
Protect your own heads first.
What is this, Commander?
You should learn how to talk to
Suleyman Shah first.
If you talk without permission
in the Kayi tent...
...I will take your head first.
Now, go and tell El Aziz that...
...if he wants Sahabettin
and my brother Ertugrul...
...he should come and take them himself.
Now, take your men and go.
Or...
...I will hand this man's head
over to you.
Nobody in Aleppo would respect you, then.
Come on!
What are these, Shahzade?
You will deliver this gold...
...to all the Turkmen tents, Afsin Bey.
Just for them to understand
what they achieved...
...by being together with
Shahzade Numan.
What if they do not want
to be together with you, Shahzade?
They will, Afsin. They will.
This is our only way.
It is your duty to convince them
from now on.
Is this your final decision, Shahzade?
Yes, Afsin Bey.
Come here.
Traitor!
Shahzade Numan...
...the state will not forgive this.
The state hates the one
who obeys to others.
The state does not accept the one
who tries to ascend the throne with greed!
The state gave this task
to Sultan Alaaddin. And he is the sultan!
God...
Ertugrul, my father
is forcing me to marry El Aziz.
If you take me from El Aziz' hands...
...his rage will destroy
the whole Kayi tent.
But I will not marry him
no matter what it takes.
I will wait for you
until you come and rescue me.
If I do not, you should know that
the angel of death has taken my soul.
Then you should know that
I am also dead.
What did I do to deserve this?
I only loved you in the whole world.
I brought the whole world to you.
I gave your father his dignity back.
Didn't I rescue your brother from the
Templars and bring him back to you?
I gave you my live, I gave you my love,
I gave you everything I had.
And what about you?
What did you do, Halime Sultan?
You walked over me
as if I was a snake.
I never gave you hope.
I never said a word
to give solace to you.
At least, do not lie
to the man you walked over.
You said you would marry me
if I brought your brother to you.
It was the Templars who kidnapped him
who brought him back.
And they brought you into a fire which
would threaten the whole Islamic world.
Come on, Halime Sultan.
I have not read these kinds of devilish
games even in "1001 Arabian Nights".
Do you know what the biggest trick
of the Devil is?
He tricks the ones
who he chooses as servants.
And what is this trick, Halime Sultan?
He makes his servants see themselves as
angels when they look into the mirror.
Innocent, wronged, good-hearted.
Whereas they are
the biggest servants of the devil.
They are so arrogant that
they see the hellfire as a cool oasis.
Since you have the courage
to mock my feelings...
Never.
This is not mocking.
It is just that somebody
must teach people like you their place...
...because you are all
wronged and good-hearted.
Unfortunately, you do not have
a single friend to tell you the truth...
...in your big palace.
This marriage is going to happen
sooner or later.
It is certain now that
it will not be a marriage based on love.
I am sure I will benefit much
from this political marriage.
And Ertugrul...
What about Ertugrul?
You will see it soon, Halime Sultan.