RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Turgut!
The boy is dead.
Yigit Alp!
Let them go or I will kill you all.
Do you think we are stupid?
Get out of our way.
I thought I made myself clear. You either
let them go or I will kill you all.
I won’t. Get out of the way or
I will kill the girl.
This is my last warning! Let them go!
Yigit Alp. Yigit Alp!
Who are you?
Afsin.
And I am Deli.
Look at the scholar.
He fights well.
He may be a scholar but he is on fire!
My brother...
...how is your wound?
The tip is broken inside.
We should take it out immediately.
We cannot do it here. We should leave.
Others might come as well.
The arrow stops the blood.
We will cut it somewhere else.
This is all Karatoygar’s doing.
Let’s go.
KARATOYGAR INN.
You messed it all up!
First your knights...
...then my soldiers.
He killed them all like mosquitoes.
You and I made a very big mistake
by underestimating Ertugrul.
From now on never...
...never try to command me.
I will settle this issue my own way.
Not on my territory, Titus.
If Sultan Aladdin hears about it,
our plan would be ruined.
You said that you would settle this issue
and I obliged. But you messed up.
You let Ertugrul escape!
I will settle it my own way!
My door is always open for you, Titus.
But...
...I am saying it again,
if you go on a headhunt in my territory...
...you will lose your own heads.
What about in Aleppo?
What did you think? We have more skillful
servants than you in all the Muslim world.
And know this, Karatoygar...
...if you were not Ustad-i Azam’s dog,
I would have killed you long ago.
Look at the great Gundogdu.
Yes, you see, Selcan Hatun...
...they tame Gundogdu like this,
so you know.
You don’t get angry, you don’t build up
a rage, what is wrong with you, Gundogdu?
I am only waiting for
the right time, Hatun.
Thank God. Thank you as well.
May it be healthy.
What is on your mind?
Will you refrain from tell me as well?
Hatun, I was wronged when I was right.
Look, I also got punished for it as well.
I cannot digest this, Hatun.
When the time comes...
...the whole tribe will see
who Gundogdu is.
Don’t let your fury cloud
your judgment, please.
Selcan, winter is around the corner.
It is knocking on our door.
Karatoygar made his first move.
Won’t they say that Kayi could not even
protect their guests?
Won’t they? If it wasn’t for the trader’s
man, the guests would have been kidnapped.
-Do you know what this means?
-What does it mean, Gundogdu?
It means this tribe is not led.
It does not have a Bey, it has no one.
What will happen then?
If I am keeping quiet, if I am not tearing
everything apart, there is a reason.
Now I have to be patient.
Now let me work.
I told you to increase the security.
What did you do? Nothing.
Because of your incompetence,
the men of that dog infiltrated our camp.
My honor and the tribe’s honor
was violated.
-I took all measures for maximum security.
-Then how could they get in?
How?
They could not have done it
without help from inside, Bey.
What does this mean?
Is something like this possible, Kurdoglu?
There is no one in our tribe
who would stoop so low, Bey.
Your head of guard
is struggling to save himself.
He is so belittled that
he can’t even hear his own words.
You are not my head of guard anymore.
Gather all the guards on duty yesterday...
...and wait for my decision
on your punishment.
As you wish, Bey.
If Karatoygar has the nerve to raid
my tribe to kidnap our guests...
...I don’t know
what he would dare tomorrow.
Bey, give me permission to go
and talk with him once again.
What did you achieve last time?
He made a fool of you.
You still ask to go and talk with him.
He learned his lesson, Bey.
All the men he sent was killed.
Now, I can talk in a language
he can understand.
I know the language he would understand.
Load the bodies to horses
and send back to him.
From now on, we will talk the way
he would understand.
Bey, what can we do against
the great Seljuk army?
Don’t talk like the army is here,
Kurdoglu. It would take days for...
...Karatoygar to mobilize the army
in Erzincan and bring it here.
Anyhow, if Karatoygar didn’t have a hidden
agenda, he would have acted long ago.
He is violating the agreement I did
with the Sultan and acting on his own.
Actually, as a commander he has enough
experience to know that I would crush...
...his few hundred soldiers.
Then what?
The rest is up to Ertugrul’s success.
One way or another,
whatever our customs say shall prevail.
What will happen now, Akcakoca?
This will take away the pus of the wound.
It will enable him to recover quickly.
-Take this.
-If God permits. How is he?
This was not welcome before
he recovered fully but...
...there is no need to be afraid.
Do not worry.
The healing process will be delayed
for a few days, that’s all.
When you feel better, you should get up,
walk around a bit outside...
...it would do you good, alright?
Do not neglect to smear this ointment
on the wound three times a day.
-Thank you very much, Akcakoca.
-Alright, may God be on your side.
Thank you, Akcakoca.
Please do not try to get up.
I just came to wish you a speedy recovery.
Take these and feed your father well
so that he can get well quickly.
-I owe you not one, but three lives.
-There is no debt.
If you could grant me your name,
I would know the man I am thankful to.
Come close, young boy.
-What is this?
-This necklace belongs to your family.
To the Seljuk dynasty.
-Dogan, Bamsi, help him down.
-At once, Bey.
Come on, let us go.
My arm.
My arm is bleeding.
Dogan, Bamsi, fetch some wood.
Drink this.
He lost a lot of blood.
-Come on, brother, raise your head.
-Raise your head.
Ertugrul.
-What happened, son?
-We were attacked.
Didn’t I warn you to be careful and
say that the air is hazy around here.
Dervish, bring the saddlebag.
We need to stop the bleeding immediately.
Part of the arrow is inside,
we need to take it out first.
We can manage, with God’s help.
Who are they?
Be strong, my friend.
In the name of God. Come on.
-Hopefully he will live.
-Bamsi, don’t open your foreboding mouth.
Do not worry.
Fate protects a person from death.
I served under your little brother
Melik Rukneddin.
And my name is Semseddin Afsin Bey.
Your brother died in my arms.
The necklace belonged to him.
-You are Afsin Bey.
-That is correct, Shahzade.
I heard your name before.
You were a good commander.
-Thank you.
-But, how do I know that you are him?
That this is not a play
staged by Sultan Aladdin?
Afsin Bey,
why did you risk your life for us?
Your brother was my Shahzade.
But more importantly...
...your attitude toward Sultan Aladdin.
You did not engage in a power struggle.
You stayed loyal to the state.
You refrained from making moves
that would overshadow his successes.
You didn’t cast a shadow over Seljuk’s
bright days with an ambition of power.
That is why you deserve
the utmost respect, sir.
With your permission, I would like to
help you escape from Karatoygar.
How? It is obvious that someone
helped Karatoygar to get in.
Otherwise, they could not have
entered the camp so easily.
I don’t know who but
I know what he will do next.
Halime?
Than God. My God give you inner peace.
-Thank you, my girl.
-Please, sit.
I should not bother you, sir.
You should rest.
With your permission,
I will take Halime from you for a while.
Mother Hayme is worried about you,
she would like to ask her how you are.
Of course. The permission is yours.
Why did Mother Hayme
want to see me, Aykiz?
I really don’t know either.
But you don’t need to be cautious, Halime.
They are being punished
because of us, right?
They deserved the punishment they get.
Bey’s honor is our honor as well.
Come on now.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS.
TEMPLARS CASTLE.
The Muslims we killed
stirred up emotions as expected.
The whole Muslim world is in rage.
They will start attacking
the Christians soon.
Europe cannot sit back then.
Ustad-i Azam,
what will we do when they attack us?
We have limited number of
knights and soldiers.
We will attack them as well.
I forged up such an army, which no army
will be able to stand against.
From Palestine to Basra,
from Baghdad to Aleppo...
...everywhere will be covered
by the stench of burnt bodies.
The visitors you had been expecting
have arrived, sir.
Good.
Come now.
Let me show you my invincible army.
Son of a Bey should be like this.
Hamza.
I am paying the price of
being presumptuous, uncle. That is all.
-Good for you, my nephew.
-The ambush last night...
It was obvious that Karatoygar
would not back down.
Did you know about
the ambush beforehand, uncle?
Thank God we have a Bey’s son whom,
for his father, even suspects his uncle.
Moreover, he questions him while
looking into his eyes.
Our Bey has the same suspicions.
Our guests must be more precious
than we thought.
Come to my tent in the evening,
we will talk there.
We need to get rid of this problem before
trouble surrounds us from all sides.
May it be easy on you, Mother Hayme.
Do we have permission?
You do, my girl, you do. Come in.
Come and sit, my beautiful girls.
I am sorry for what happened.
Thank God no one was killed.
Thank God, Mother Hayme.
My father’s wound was uncalled for...
...while he was recovering
but thank God he was spared.
But why are these devil mongers
imposing you?
My father is a trader, when he was
transporting goods in the Mediterranean...
...we fell captive to the Crusaders.
They wanted to sell us to Karatoygar.
When you are dwelled in so much trouble,
don’t you have anyone to turn to?
Which tribe do you belong to?
-We are from Kinik tribe.
-So you are from Kinik tribe?
You carry the blood of the Bey
who founded the Seljuk state, is that so?
Well, which clan from the
Kinik tribe do you belong to?
-Do we have permission, Mother Hayme?
-Yes, you do. Come, my girl.
-Did you bring the drapes?
-I did, Mother.
The colors are faded.
What did you lack in material?
There is not enough grass due to famine.
We had to water down the dye.
We are doing all we can,
but this is the best we could do.
Did you try the leaves and
roots of dyer’s woad?
Our trader girl knows so much.
She learned so many things
as she traveled the seas and mountains...
...but she forgets that grass
don’t grow during famine.
If there was some, we would have used it.
Selcan is right, my girl.
We need to find another solution.
We don’t have much time left. We have
to go and sell these in the market...
...before we migrate but we don’t have
a single proper drape to sell.
Selcan, do your best.
You may leave.
Do not meddle in things
that does not concern you.
You are the dearest subjects
who will be going to God’s heaven.
You will find peace
in the compassionate embrace of Jesus.
You tasted death while alive...
...and now you will taste the peace of
redemption from all sins while you die.
Mario!
Rachel, my dear girl, you will find
the peace you seek in God’s heaven.
You know how much I trust your
intelligence and thus I gave you...
...the most difficult task.
Your task will be the Kayi Tribe.
Two knights of mine will accompany you.
My whole life was in unbearable pain, sir.
But my death will be...
...with the love of Jesus and honor.
My innocent lambs,
may you have a clear journey.
We did not understand your plan, sir.
Black death, my dear knight.
This small but powerful army
will spread the damnation of devil...
...all over the Muslim world.
Wait, stop there.
Do not worry. There is a way.
Come and sit here.
Look, my girl. Years ago one old woman
in the palace did something...
...to make the colors more vibrant.
The whole palace was surprised.
Even my late grandfather who was
the Sultan at the time was intrigued.
Everyone was against the poor woman. But
the colors on the drape were magnificent.
What did she do, father, tell me.
That is all. We set on the road from
Andalusia years ago and never looked back.
What made you leave your home, dervish?
A dream.
I am pursuing the divine call that made me
travel everywhere in the world for years.
-Is there a clan called Andalusia?
-Didn’t you ever hear of Andalusia?
-Never, brother.
-Really?
-Am I lying to you?
-Sometimes I wonder why you carry a head.
-Doesn’t it get too heavy?
-Leave me alone.
What about you, son?
Why are you going to Aleppo?
I was sent to Ameer El Aziz
as an ambassador.
-But we still couldn’t reach.
-You will, if God permits.
While his highness the Prophet and
his highness Abu Bakr was migrating...
...they took refuge in a cave.
The heretics were after them.
They found the tracks
that go inside the cave.
The companion of our Prophet, Abu Bakr
was anxious. Our Prophet said to him:
“Don’t you worry, Abu Bakr,
God is with us.”
There, a small spider weaved them
the most protective armor of all time.
So the real question is whether we made
God a companion to our road or not.
If we did, all doors would open,
all roads would finish.
If we did not,
our companion would be the devil.
-Peace be upon you.
-The devil!
-Shut your mouth.
-And peace be upon you!
And peace be upon you
We saw the fire and came.
Do we have permission?
Please join us at our humble dinner.
If Karatoygar attacked our camp so easily,
he must have a spy inside.
No one in Kayi Tribe would dare
to be a spy for Karatoygar.
What did you talk with Karatoygar?
I asked for some time,
to convince Suleyman Shah.
He attacked before the time was up.
We cannot even protect the people
who take refuge in us.
Old age made Suleyman Shah very weak.
The unity and solidarity
of the tribe is at risk, Gundogdu.
If we don’t act,
the great Kayi tribe will fall apart.
He is my father but the future
of the tribe is more important.
What do you have in mind?
I will wait for Ertugrul
to return from Aleppo.
If he comes back empty handed,
I will act immediately.
What about your father?
My father is my life and blood but
I would act accordingly to Oguz customs.
Oguz customs tell so much to those
who know how to listen.
We are on the road for days without food.
We were devastated.
But I thank God that
he put you on our way.
We can never know from where
the fortune would smile at us.
True. We can never know from where
the trouble will come either.
What is the matter?
Did something bad happen?
While our caravan was on the road,
the crusaders, those Templars attacked us.
They seize every opportunity
and attack everywhere.
Last time we met a regiment of crusaders.
We killed them all!
You did well.
Those crusaders, where did they get the
courage to wander in the Muslim territory?
I heard that those heretics
are preparing for a new crusade.
They mobilized the whole Christian world
to invade Jerusalem.
I heard that they killed all the important
rulers in the Muslim states one by one...
...and left their bodies in town squares.
So we will have a festival.
We will need to prepare a warm welcome.
You jest, Bey. How will this be?
Muslims only draw swords at each other.
-They kill each other.
-Don’t you worry.
God would bear a big warrior and
unite the whole world under his flag.
And his progeny would conquer
Constantinople, take Jerusalem...
...and serve Mecca and Medina.
If God permits, we shall fight under
the flag of that warrior.
If God permits.
I hope you are right, if God permits.
I hope He sends that warrior soon
so that we can find peace, if God permits.
I would like to know these valuable God
followers who shared their food with us.
I am...
...Ibn Arabi from Andalusia.
Ertugrul from Kayi Tribe.
I brought you molasses, father.
-Thank you, my girl.
-May it be health.
Well? Tell us now, Gundogdu.
What do you want to do and
require Oguz customs?
If I was a Bey and someone
attacked my tribe...
...I would think about the punishment
I would give to the soldiers on guard.
What would you have done, Kurdoglu?
I say, Bey, the punishment given by
Suleyman Shah is well deserved.
Son, one day you may be Bey.
Look for the answer to this question then.
Now, do not busy your mind
on unnecessary business.
Just think about how you can do
your own task the best you can.
-What task is this?
-Starting from tomorrow...
...you shall be collecting
the goods to be sold in the caravan.
The caravan shall set on
the road in three days.
Bey, why doesn’t the trader
take the goods?
Karatoygar has bad intensions.
He might raid the caravan.
That is why we can’t give
the goods to the trader.
Gundogdu will do this task with his Alps.
As you wish, father.
You invited me to your table,
shared your food...
...I shall never forget this kindness.
-May it be health.
I would like permission to leave.
I need to be on my way.
The roads would be dangerous at night.
We can go together at sunrise.
Thank you but I have not seen
my family for months.
I would not want to make
them worry anymore.
I have a carpet shop in the Aleppo market.
I would like to host you there.
If we have time, we may visit.
Please be aware, son.
The crusaders may attack any moment.
-They will not be seen around here today.
-You should still be careful.
They can masquerade and pose as anything.
Thank you.
-How are you, Turgut?
-I am better. Much better.
I regained consciousness.
Where are we?
When we had the chance,
why didn’t we slain them here?
We have warriors who killed
15 soldiers of ours.
God accepted my prayers in the end.
He made me meet my enemy.
We will prepare a nice welcome ceremony
for them in Aleppo.
Hear ye, hear ye,
please let it be known...
...the caravan will set on the road
in two days!
Orders from Suleyman Shah!
Dear Akcakoca, do you know what
I thought when this crier shouted caravan?
If you had listened to what I said,
your caravan would be...
...from here to China.
-Don’t start again, Wild Demir, don’t.
Look, Akcakoca, you don’t need to
get upset. All I said was that...
...instead of dealing with these ointments
for wounds, pains, poisons and such...
...you should have done an ointment for
women, put them in fancy bottles...
...with bright colors, women would smear
them on their faces and when they...
...found themselves beautiful,
you would have been bathing in coins.
Go back to your work! Dear God!
What is happening, my girl? The cows
cannot make dung fast enough for you.
For the love of God, father!
We are all stressed out as it is.
I understand, no one likes to joke around.
Alright?
Put a bit more.
Is this much dung enough, Halime?
Yes, I hope it is enough.
Everyone is very tense. They say no good
will come out of drapes bathed in dung.
They think all their efforts
will go down in vain.
Look, Aykiz. Why do you think the drapes
they brought to Mother Hayme were faded?
Because the drapes were gray.
First of all, we need to whiten
the drapes we will dye later.
These pieces of dung will make
our drapes as white as snow.
Then you can dye any pattern you like.
Believe me, Aykiz, they will be very nice.
As long as it solves the problem.
But if we mess up, we will be in trouble.
We will be the talk of the tribe.
This one is done, Aykiz.
Dry them in the sun for some time.
May it be easy, Hatuns.
What is happening?
What are you working on?
We bathe the drapes in dung.
You bathe the drapes in dung?
I was not expecting this.
Where did this come from, Aykiz?
Halime Baci got permission
from Mother Hayme.
What punishment is this? The drapes were
the only place where dirt was not smeared.
What are you doing, Gokce? She invaded the
weavery as well, why didn’t you stop her?
What could I do, sister? Do I have a say
after Mother Hayme accepted?
Don’t you worry about it. When they mess
up this job, they will pay its price.
Why would an outsider whore pay the price?
If these goods don’t make it
to the caravan in time, we pay the price.
Sister, why are you making
a big deal out of her?
As you overrate this girl,
she starts to get more confident.
Do you know why I am making
a big deal out of her, Gokce?
Because I have a very naive sister,
that is why.
The man my sister loves,
is tangled in her web.
My sister may not see, but I do.
My sister may not hear, but I do.
The way Ertugrul looks
at this girl is not normal.
Remember my words when
you start crying after him.
I have one rose in three branches
I have sweet made of milk, my dervish
Help me, Abdul Qadir
I have a problem
Master.
I can smell your grandfather,
our Master Gilani on you, Halabi.
Thank you. Welcome, master.
We came from a long way with our guests.
Suleyman Shah’s son Ertugrul
from Kayi tribe.
They have a mission,
they will go to the palace.
Then they are in luck, master.
Today is the visiting day of the palace.
If they can see the Emir, today is the day
otherwise they have to wait one month.
The One Who Blesses, son.
Dear God, I never thought that I would use
dung to bleach the cloths one day, Halime.
You should see them after they get
snowy white. It will be worth the effort.
Then we will see the faces of those
who talk from our backs.
Well?
We can also bath your dowry drapes
in dung as well.
Of course we can.
As long as they return safe and sound.
-Is your dowry ready?
-Of course it is.
They have been laying inside
the chest for a long time.
Turgut Alp couldn’t get down
from his horse yet.
Why Turgut Alp, why?
Yes, Aykiz, it is not easy to be
the wife of an Alp.
I have been waiting for
Ertugrul Bey for years.
If it weren’t for the trader’s man
and Wild  Demir...
...my reputation would have been ruined.
Do you think Karatoygar
will continue with these violations?
We now know Numan’s worth
in the eye of Karatoygar.
He is more precious than we thought.
Karatoygar would do anything
to get him back.
What will you do?
Until Ertugrul comes with good news,
we will stay here and be ready for war.
You know the guest’s daughter, Halime?
You should see her. She works endlessly
to make the dye brighter on the drapes.
Do you think she would succeed?
They make the best money in the market.
If God permits, Bey, if God permits.
If God permits, we will migrate to Aleppo,
we can think Ertugrul’s wedding and...
Anyhow, may God let him return from Aleppo
with good news first, then we will see.
Who do you have in mind?
Gokce.
I am surprised that you find her suitable
while knowing her sister.
Gokce is different. She is a good girl.
Maybe this way, she can control
her sister’s endless ambitions.
You would not talk like this
if Gokce did not want to wed.
Well? What about Ertugrul?
Does he have the heart?
If God permits, we will see about that.
Sister, you made a fool out of me! A fool!
What are you saying, Gokce?
Because of you, I faced off with Halime
and told her that I waited for Ertugrul.
What more do you want?
You were too late to act anyway.
Sister, I guess you didn’t understand.
I said everyone heard me. Aykiz as well.
Now everyone will tease me. They will say
that I am dreaming standing up.
-This is your fault.
-Gokce!
Look at me. Do not care
even if the whole world hears it.
You will win over Ertugrul
just like I did with Gundogdu.
And you will fight with
nails, teeth and all.
With your sweet talk and your beauty,
you will win over that son of a bastard.
You will crush anyone on your path.
Just like I became Gundogdu’s wife,
you will become Ertugrul’s wife.
We have not settled the score with
Suleyman Shah yet.
Each day the killer of our father sits
in the marquee, is a shame on us...
...a wound in our heart.
I don’t have any blood left in my veins.
Do you understand? Sitting in the marquee
is our well deserved right and...
...we will get our right.
What is it you want?
Did you swallow your tongue, talk!
A man’s word is said directly
to a man’s face, Bey.
Alright.
My eyes and ears are with you. Talk now.
I came as an ambassador of
Suleyman Shah of Kayi tribe.
I am his son, my name is Ertugrul.
Well?
What do you want, son of a Bey?
I came to claim land from you.
You want land?
What will you give us in exchange?
Apart from the goats that will damage
our crops and the stench over our city?
Did the city make you forget
your roots, Bey?
How did you know that
I was Turkmen as well?
The ring on your thumb. It is obvious
that it is not a mere ornament.
It gives you away, your thumb is damaged
due to shooting arrows to infidels.
If you give us a land, in exchange
2000 Alps will be on your side...
...anytime you have trouble.
-2000 Alps?
Even the guards in my palace
is more than this.
May you have a good journey, son of a Bey.
Next.
-Bey.
-Next.
Bey.
Come on.
Your guards, count them as three less.
Congratulations.
It was the best spectacle I have watched.
Isn’t that so, Nasir? You clap as well.
Your highness Ameer.
I would like to get to know
this Turkmen warrior better.
We shall listen to the myths, stories
and sagas of the nomads from him...
...during dinner tonight, what do you say,
my dear uncle?
I would be honored, your highness.
He sent the bodies of my men.
He thinks he can intimidate me.
Pray that he did not run over
your soldiers.
What are you saying?
Is your Bey opposing the Seljuk state?
Stop speaking nonsense, Karatoygar.
And don’t try to use Seljuk state
as an excuse.
Sultan Aladdin is not aware
of the things you do here.
I am sure of that.
I understand that these prisoners will
open other doors for you in the state.
You should focus your intelligence
on your own tasks.
What does this intelligence say
about your incompetence, Kurdoglu?
You should see the incompetence of
your own men first.
They cannot even throw an ambush.
That is enough, Kurdoglu.
If you don’t bring Numan to me...
...you cannot become the Bey you wish.
I would make the sky fall on you.
You and Suleyman Shah
would be crushed below it.
If you can be patient,
we can both take what we want.
But if you trample over me,
we would both lose.
I am prepared to fight
the whole world for Numan.
Don’t you ever forget this.
Won’t you still tell me
who those prisoners are?
Don’t think about who they are,
think about who I am.
This is more important for you, Kurdoglu.
What will we do now?
I will give you Numan and
Suleyman Shah as well.
You will come to collect them
like a ripe date on a branch.
Now, listen to me closely.
When the caravan is ambushed,
Suleyman Shah cannot sit in his tent.
He will come after you.
14 carpets.
Two dozens of wooden spoon.
72 pieces of kerchief.
God bless. God bless.
Your daughter and bride worked very well.
Dear Teyze, you should tie them well so
that we don’t have a problem on the road.
We wrapped them all up, Bey.
We wrapped them very well with my husband.
We don’t have a lot but I beg you...
...protect the caravan well.
Our livestock died of starvation.
All we have is entrusted in you.
I know, Emmi, I know. Don’t you worry.
Trust God first, then us with your goods.
I chose the best Alps I have for this job.
Do not worry about it.
Do not worry, people!
-Alright?
-Yes, Bey. Alright.
Gundogdu...
...with the money I get from these knives,
I will wed my daughter, let it be known.
You cannot save yourself
from Aykiz’s wrath.
Turgut’s as well.
We don’t know the distress they are
in Aleppo, may God be with them.
With you too.
Next.
Don’t come closer.
I would crush you like a millstone.
Please don't do this!
Anytime water touches my skin,
trouble finds me.
-You would go down with me as well.
-Bamsi, there is a feast in the palace.
Decide whether you will eat with us
or in the stable.
Please don’t.
I won’t give you my blessing if you die.
Bamsi, you have no way out.
You have to bathe. Give in.
I will not! I will die but
not submit to this. I will not!
-You skunk! You asked for this!
-Dear God!
-Please don’t do this. Dear God!
-Quiet!
Do not play around.
We will be late to the palace.
You heard our Bey, do not play around.
Bey? Why are you so thoughtful?
Being invited to
Ameer’s palace is a big thing for us.
They did not give us a land
or a promise, Ilyas.
-We will see what God has planned for us.
-Amen, Bey.
This job shall be finished tonight.
Will the men you send
be able to finish the job?
You do your part, Nasir.
Which one of you hid my weapons?
What are you saying?
Didn’t we go inside together?
-But they are not here, look.
-What do you mean?
-Mine are not here either.
-They stole mine as well.
I told you! Anytime I bathe,
some trouble happens! You saw it as well!
We were careless trying to bathe you!
That’s enough! Shut up!
How will we tell this to our Bey?
What will you tell me, Turgut?
-I am asking you, Turgut.
-Bey, they stole our weapons.
What?
Please, sit.
Please come to the table, Alps.
-Did you lose a man in the fight?
-No, your highness.
So, you were ambushed in my territory.
Is that so?
We will send soldiers and not let them
nest there, right, uncle?
-Of course, your highness.
-Fine. Alright.
They were punished severe enough.
They are all dead.
I know how the famine is affecting
you nomads. Sultan Aladdin is being...
...over tolerant with you. It is known
how your herds destroy villages and towns.
The struggle between
the Oguz Tribes is another problem.
Everyone is after their herd, after food.
Famine hit the tribes hard. But a few
vigilant people cannot be an example.
I am bored. Play something more lively.
Mongols from one side,
crusaders on the other.
I am not even counting
Khwarazmshahs and the Seljuks.
We need an ally to run to this fire with
a bucket of water, not a bellow.
When the factions inside the Muslim world
is demolishing everything...
...this is what we need.
Is this not so, your highness?
It is, uncle. We need to put out the fire.
Our swords would not go back to their
sheaths, our horses don’t back down.
We also need an ally with a bucket of
water to put out the fire in our home.
How will we make a deal with you, Turkmen?
We would like a fertile winter quarter
for our tribe.
A quarter.
First you ask a quarter.
Then that would turn into a moorland.
Then you would demand a whole territory.
True, we would.
If I gave you Aleppo...
...would you be satisfied?
Instead of offending an Ameer
who opened his land for us...
...we would let all the herds
we have starve.
-But I have reservations, Ertugrul.
-I am here to clear them up.
We thank you for the presents
Kayi ambassadors brought for us.
If you accept,
we also have some presents for you.
These are our weapons.
Now tell me, Ertugrul. How can we trust
the promises of warriors who cannot...
...even hold on to their weapons
during peace?
Why are you there, Nasir?
We are having fun here, come beside me.
Now you can go. Go and rest.
You came from a long way.
I will consult with my commanders
tomorrow and give you my decision.
I herewith swear that from now on,
a hand that cannot claim his sword...
...shall not hold any other weapon.
I wish our weapons had been
struck by lightning...
...so that our Ertugrul Bey
would not have been humiliated like this.
I wonder what Ertugrul Bey feels
right now. He must be in rage.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you,
with God’s Grace and Mercy.
With peace in our world and beyond,
we commemorate one of your followers...
...who was full of love,
his highness Abdul Qadir Gilani.
Great God...
...You never make a subject
carry a load too heavy for him.
You put the load of the whole tribe
on my shoulders.
Grant me a way to carry this load.
You took Jonah out from a hole and made
him Sultan of Egypt. Please grant me...
...an opportunity so that I can climb up
from this bottomless pit I have fallen.
Wake up, my son.
Dear God, we thank you.
What did you do, did you kill him?
Don’t kill him!
-Why did you kill him?
-What is happening here?
We learned many things from you,
your highness.
In your cities, we have to guard
our weapons and our lives as well.
Who is this man, Nasir?
A Templar.
What did you talk about during dinner?
What does he want from El Aziz?
Kayis.
They wanted a quarter to stay in winter.
Kayis must get what they want.
What do you mean? I don’t understand.
The territory they get, make it near
the border with the Crusader Countship.
This is an opportunity to kill
not only Ertugrul but all their blood.
Kayis may spend the winter in the skirts
of the Amanos Mountains...
...somewhere very remote,
near the border of Antioch Countship.
This will be the last winter
of their lives.
Titus, are you aware of
what you are saying?
This is a dangerous game.
Do as I tell you, Nasir.
Follow them everywhere.
You will report every move he makes,
every breath he takes back to me.
Take these pigeons.
You became the hero of the tribe all of
a sudden, you don’t even talk to me now.
Suleyman Shah is not giving
his goods for us to sell.
We came to the tribe for nothing.
Come on, help me prepare the caravan.
-I am not coming.
-I will not have this attitude, Afsin.
I took you with me while
you were starving.
I gave you food and water, made you a man!
Now you cannot turn against me.
You owe me.
-May you heal soon.
-Thank you, Bey.
It is not very common...
...for someone to be such a good trader
and swordsman at the same time.
I heard that last night you fought well
in this wounded state.
The helper of the trader is
also just like you.
If I were a good trader, I would not have
been left out with children and no money.
When we come to sword, what we know about
swordsmanship is playing with children...
...that is all. If God permits, the burden
we imposed on you should finish soon.
This is our only consolation,
Numan Effendi.
Our only consolation.
So you say I owe you.
Look at me, you dirty old man!
I worked for you like a dog for years...
...and I paid my debt to you! Now get out
of my face before I rip your head off.
Get lost!
One is a trader...
...the other one is a caravan worker.
But they are first class swordsmen.
You found each other well.
I don’t know why but I don’t wonder about
who Karatoygar’s man inside the tribe is.
What are you doing?
-Selcan.
-Stop! Don’t!
This is a sin! You cannot precede over
what God permits for you!
If we had a baby,
everything would be different.
My Hatun.
We will have a baby one day.
We should not lose hope from God.
Your mother...
...is about to crown Halime
the first chance she gets.
Selcan...
...don’t talk anymore!
You are not aware of
the things going on around you.
You don’t know the respect
she showed her at the weaving area.
She shows her the respect
she refrains from me.
She treats me as if I am not
his son’s wife but a mere servant.
Why?
Because I did not give her a grandson yet.
She hates me.
Selcan.
You are accusing my mother without reason.
She would not stoop so low.
I know what goes through her mind.
Look, woman, I cannot listen to
your whining right before the caravan...
...alright? For the love of God.
-You don’t understand, do you?
I am saying that Halime will set her foot
in our tribe but you don’t care less.
God give me patience, patience.
Gundogdu came out of his rage
very quickly, thank God.
He deserved to lead the caravan.
Just like he deserved to carry wood.
If God permits, he will manage
to beat his arrogance as well.
If God permits, Hayme. If God permits.
He organized the caravan very quickly.
That is not easy at all.
He works day and night,
fighting tooth and nail.
May God let him succeed.
-Sometimes...
-Sometimes what?
-Nothing.
-Hayme, what is on your mind?
I don’t know, Bey.
I get anxious about many things.
Don’t you worry.
They will both return safe and sound.
If God permits. If God permits.
Halime, come on,
let us go and eat something.
-Aykiz, I will come after I finish this.
-Alright, I will be waiting.
-Sister, what did you do?
-This is not the time to question me.
-What did you throw inside the cauldron?
-I am trying to save you from that girl.
Sister, what you did is not right.
Moreover, the problem is not Halime here,
it is the caravan.
Gokce, why are you so empty headed?
Haven’t you still grasped the problem?
That girl is the biggest disaster
who came to our tribe.
When will you understand this?
When Ertugrul weds her?
Do we have permission, Bey?
Bey, we put you in a difficult situation.
We want you to forgive us.
If you make a mistake like this again,
you would not find the opportunity...
...to come before me
and ask for forgiveness.
Bey, his highness Ameer
would like to see you.
Come, brave boy of the steppes, come.
I owe you an apology for
the things that happened last night.
Whoever is behind this attempt, my uncle
will find and punish them accordingly.
-Uncle.
-We decided to...
...give you the territory you requested,
son of a Bey.
If you want the truth,
Nasir persuaded us to do so.
Do you know this place?
West of the Asi River.
-I heard that the land was fertile.
-It is fertile in enemies as well.
It is at the border of the people
who came to kill you last night.
So we can sleep side by side
with the devil.
Is it worth to take this risk
for your herds?
Enemy enables us to be alert
and spry all the time. It keeps us alive.
Awesome, awesome, awesome. I love
these braves from the steppes, uncle.
So you want to test your fate in the face
of the scorpion needle. Is that so?
If you are so willing to sleep
side by side with the devil...
...all we can say is good luck to you.
We are impressed by
your courage once again.
When we have friends like you behind us...
...we would never refrain from
facing the enemy upfront.
Are you stilling thinking about
what Gokce said, Halime?
No. Why would her words concern me?
-It is between Ertugrul and Gokce.
-So you don’t care?
I know that you are eating yourself inside
out the last two days, am I blind, Halime?
-Aykiz, please, let us focus on our work.
-Alright but...
...please don’t take that mad girl
Gokce seriously. She is in an illusion.
Maybe Mother Hayme and Gokce already...
Aykiz?
For it to take this color,
pheasant’s eye seeds must be added.
Halime, who would do this?
Anyhow, there is a solution
for everything.
Caravan is about to leave,
how will we make it in time?
We will, Aykiz. There is no other way.
We will make it in time.
We are leaving.
Let us go and see our tribe’s
new territory.
-Ertugrul Bey?
-So El Aziz...
Let us not make our new land wait for us.
I don’t want Gundogdu, my father in law
or Mother Hayme to know that I came here.
Don’t worry. No one will know.
Especially that man, Suleyman Shah,
will never know!
As you asked,
I brought a wisp of Gundogdu’s hair.
You are the daughter of a big Bey, Selcan.
You don’t deserve these things.
The impudence of the woman who is supposed
to be your mother in law. Your husband...
...looking at you like a dried up twig.
-Enough!
Do not be ashamed of the pains you lived
through. You shall get all you deserve.
The spirit army shall fill
your stomach with the seeds of your man.
You will have a son.
And the fate of Kayi tribe will change.
Hamza, we will leave early in the morning.
Check the weapons of the Alps...
...make sure they have plenty of arrows.
-As you wish, Bey.
-May it be easy.
-Thank you, uncle.
I thought about it and...
...I don’t think it is a good idea for you
to be going with the caravan, Gundogdu.
Why is that?
We don’t know what that Karatoygar dog
may be up to.
Even if you take the best Alps with you,
this is very dangerous.
You are son of a Bey. Ertugrul is not here
either and your father is ill.
It would be best if you find
a way to stay in the tribe.
Uncle, would it suit a son of a Bey
to drowse around in the tribe?
Look around you. All these people have
trusted their goods and labor with me.
Of course, it should be
my duty to take them.
If that dog Karatoygar makes a move, we
shall do all what we can, if God permits.
Do not worry about it.
We made everything ready, Mother Hayme.
Gokce finished the carpets.
May your hands be blessed. If God permits,
they will find their worth in the market.
And I wove this for you, Mother Hayme.
My pure girl, clean girl.
You are one of a kind.
When did you find the time
during all this hassle?
She has not slept for days, Mother Hayme.
God bless.
Halime, what will we do?
Why did they become like this, Halime?
I am guessing that we did not use
enough dung, Mother Hayme.
We shall try again.
You did all you could do.
It would never be ready by the morning.
No! We will work all night if needed to
make them ready, Mother Hayme.
Do not worry.
One last hope? Alright.
May it be easy on you.
Welcome, son of a Bey.
I wanted a blessing from Ibn Arabi
before we set on the road.
Sheikh Efendi already left,
don’t you know?
-To where?
-God knows.
-Won’t I see him again?
-Only God knows.
-I need to find him.
-How can you find, if you have not lost?
How can you lose, if you have not found?
This was the stupidest thing
you could have done, Titus.
You did not manage to revenge your brother
and made Kayis a bigger problem for us.
Sir, I did the right thing.
You did the right thing, is that so?
-I did not expect such stupidity from you.
-Sir.
I don’t understand whom you are afraid of.
Of Ertugrul or the person beside him...
...Ibn Arabi?
How dare you say that I am frightened?
Listen to me closely, Titus.
We will never let the Turks
come to our borders, never!
If your desire for revenge precedes
your duty one more time...
...I would bury you beside
your brother with my own hands.
Great God, you make everything possible.
This must be heaven.
But hell is right around the corner.
Yes, beyond this territory is the
Antioch Crusaders Countship.
Secret fort of the Templars
must be somewhere around here.
Devil is everywhere, Turgut.
In our tribe, in Aleppo. Everywhere.
We will have a lot of fun, a lot!
God bless, Bey. You can find water
under every stone you turn.
I never saw such fertile land in my life.
It will grow the babies, fatten the sheep.
It will give life to the tribe.
How did they let such
a nice land to be uninhabited?
Because it is right next to hell, Turgut.
Yes, Bey.
Why did these Templars want to kill you?
I am guessing that they want to
revenge the knights we killed.
Bey, so we can say that they will not let
us find peace here as well.
Forget the heretics...
...think about your wedding with Aykiz.
As soon as the tribe settles here,
our first job will be to wed you.
God willing, Bey.
Aykiz is a dear. If she was someone else,
she would have wed another man long ago.
Bey...
...maybe we can have a double wedding.
Our flags shall be our tents. We shall
ride our horses to borderless plains.
Our weapons shall be our lovers
and our armies shall be strong.
Our crest shall fly over seven climates
as the flag of justice.
We shall carry our divine message
beyond the mountains and seas.
You came walking to your own death.
You have been breathing down
on our necks since Aleppo.
Tell me! Who holds your leash?
He has already gone to hell.
These are messenger pigeons, Bey.
Then, let us send them to their owner.
Dear God, thank you.
The long awaited has come.
What are you blabbering on again?
Didn’t you come to me because of the
heaviness that fell upon you, Petroccio?
I don’t believe in any of the prophecies
than heretic from Andalusia, Ibn Arabi...
...has thrown our way,
my dear brother Giovanni.
Don’t call me Giovanni.
My name is Omer.
You know very well that everything
my sheikh Ibn Arabi has said came true.
The starbursts herald
the long awaited braves.
Will these herd of shepherds running away
from the Mongols rule the whole world?
They will unite the whole Muslim world
as a fist.
And that fist will throw a punch,
demolishing your cursed order.
Did you take enough water, Gundogdu?
You won’t find water while passing
the Enger Mountain.
We did, Bey. We didn’t want to take too
much as it would be heavy for the animals.
-Good. Is there anything left behind?
-There is. Aykiz and Halime.
Let me run and check them.
They are coming.
We apologize for being late.
-Are they finished?
-All of them, Mother Hayme.
How did they turn out?
Are they worth taking to the market?
Show me one to see.
How is it, Hanim, is it good?
I have never seen such vibrant colors
in my life.
Good. Load these drapes as well.
The caravan may leave.
Come.
The caravan left the village, sir.
Suleyman Shah’s son Gundogdu is leading.
Come closer. Come to me.
The flood has passed and sand is left.
Thank God, we did not need to bow
our heads in shame in front of our men.
You worked very hard. After cleaning up,
you may all go and rest.
Come on now. Selcan, come with me.
There is an issue
I wanted to talk with you for a long time.
I am listening, mother.
My girl, after your mother and
father died, you and your sister Gokce...
...were entrusted with us. I tried not to
discriminate you from my own children.
May our lives be sacrificed for you,
Mother Hayme.
Did we commit a crime without knowing?
Did we break your heart?
No, nothing like that. The thing I want
to say is completely different.
Gokce has grown, she got very beautiful.
She became a very proper girl.
We need to wed her soon.
You are right, mother. I was also thinking
the same thing for a long time.
Well...
...who are we going to wed her with?
If you give consent as well, Ertugrul
and Gokce should grow old together.
Please, Mother Hayme, who am I to have
a say in something like this?
Don’t say that.
You raised her since she was very little.
I wanted to ask you first.
You can inquire and see her reaction.
I will go immediately, Mother Hayme.
I am going right now.
The pigeon wing’s final destination
is the wolf’s mouth.
Suleyman Shah’s son, Ertugrul.
Attack!
We expected a big welcome
with drums and all.
-This is strange.
-Everyone must have finished their job.
The caravan must be on its way as well.
Everyone is probably resting.
You carry on. I will visit my father.
Stop!