Episode 3 will start at 12:34
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Deal with the loot!
Come on!
Shame. Shame on you!
You did not deserve any of this, Gundogdu.
I told your father.
I said, “if you don’t give the prisoners
I will make the sky fall on you.”
Now he can make a decision.
Will he choose his customs or his own son?
Catch him!
Stop him! Stop him!
The whole tribe is starving.
Famine is everywhere.
We could not even go on a foray. Why?
Because our Bey has a boil problem.
The whole tribe complains
about your old age.
I told you that I would succeed and
make you proud. I have, father.
My prayers are answered.
Thank God they have.
We have a winter territory now
but our job will not be easy.
Kayi does not seek things that are easy,
son. With God’s help...
...we can overcome any obstacle.
-With God’s help, we can.
Welcome, my brave son.
You came with this good news...
...may God make you happy
in this world and next.
May your clan grow, may your progeny grow.
Mother, my life.
I would die for you, mother.
May God let you lead us till the end.
May God protect you.
Now you can go and rest.
You will attend the headquarters. You will
personally announce the good news...
...from Aleppo to all Beys of Kayi.
Then we can talk about
the problems in detail. Altogether.
If you have permission,
I have a small job before I go to my tent.
I would like to address that first.
God, I am very grateful.
Just when all our hopes had died,
you made Ertugrul appear before us.
You made him strong against the tyrants.
Now ordain him to return safely
with good news.
Ertugrul?
Aykiz told me that you were here.
-Did I scare you?
-I was not scared but...
...surprised. You came so quickly.
I had told you that I would not rest
and return as soon as possible.
You did.
I kept my promise.
Did you bring good news from Aleppo?
Is there a new home to go to?
Yes.
Thank God.
The tribe will find some peace at the end.
Everyone was waiting for your return.
Especially Aykiz.
Especially Aykiz?
I mean...
...your mother and father. The babies
who were getting cold in the highlands.
Everyone.
All of us.
I never parted from it.
It gave me strength in every obstacle
I faced.
Anytime I felt in distraught,
it reminded me that you are with me.
I brought this from Aleppo for you.
For me?
This is so beautiful, Ertugrul Bey.
I wanted you to see the beauty that I do.
Everything is like a dream.
But like all dreams, this will end.
What happened, Halime?
What is it that bothers you?
Karatoygar.
He raided the tribe to kidnap us.
He will not rest until he catches us,
Ertugrul.
You can be rest assured.
I promise you that I will never leave you.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
Today is the anniversary
of my father’s death.
It has been eight years.
I wish he had a grave,
where I could weep and pray.
You should not pray for your father’s
death, you should pray that he lives.
No one has ever seen
your father’s dead body until now.
Maybe he is still alive.
Maybe the hope of seeing his daughter
once again is keeping him alive.
When did he come and
meet with that ominous girl?
May it be easy, Hatuns.
Ertugrul Bey ran off to see that girl
as soon as he arrived, mother.
Where did they go?
How can they walk side by side like this?
Don’t think of malice
before you have your facts right, Selcan.
No one would benefit from it.
Ertugrul came and kissed our hands first.
We have to deal with this guest problem
as soon as possible, mother.
My father in law does not know
or see these things.
This girl has bad intentions
against our family.
Let your hands work instead of
your tongues. There is a lot to do.
What did Suleyman Shah say, Bey?
Ertugrul returned from Aleppo.
He got a territory from El Aziz.
Ertugrul turned out to be
more capable than we thought.
Do you think Kurdoglu Bey’s
bag of tricks have run out?
Of course we have a plan as well.
Wild  Demir,
the heretic’s sword is bigger than yours.
Dogan, where did you find
this donkey stick?
From the Crusaders we killed.
Infidels don’t know
the first thing about a sword.
A weapon should be like this.
It should be curved like aleph.
It should be comfortable on the wrist.
It should be a head to steel.
Karatoygar’s men raided Halime’s tent,
Wild Demir. Is this true?
It is true, Ertugrul. The dog did
his thing but he was defeated.
I entrusted that tent’s honor with you.
How can they come and
raid the tent right under our noses?
You are right, Ertugrul. Whatever you say.
A negligence on my part.
You can punish me.
I deserve what I will get.
I still have to thank you, Master Demir.
Their life were saved thanks to you.
No, not only me. There was Afsin as well.
The man of the trader
who came to the tribe.
But please know this, Ertugrul,
even a bad thing may be a good deed.
If those rabid dogs didn’t come
to the tribe to attack Halime’s family...
...that night they were going to run away.
What if the dogs attacked them somewhere
else outside the tribe?
We would not have been aware of it.
Halime’s family...
...were going to run away?
Did Afsin kill all those dogs by himself?
Look at the helper of a trader.
Halime...
...Ertugrul Bey asked for you
the minute he came.
You should have seen
how fast he went after you.
Turgut and I are going to meet in a while.
My heart always skips
a beat when he is away.
Thank God, they returned safe and sound.
And with good news as well.
Patience is a virtue, Aykiz.
Our wedding will be soon.
My hands have gone cold from excitement.
Did Ertugrul Bey buy this?
It is so nice.
So he was thinking about
you even over there.
So what if he thinks, Aykiz?
Why do you talk like this, dear Halime?
It is obvious that
you are not in the mood.
Did something happen and hurt you?
I had to run away for my all life
so that we don’t get hurt.
This is the first time I am hurting
because I have to leave.
I do not know from whom
or why you are running away.
If you want the truth, I don’t care.
But I know one thing, Halime...
...you are not alone anymore.
Ertugrul Bey would not let you go
or let something happen to you.
Elanora...
...you are in sorrow.
Your sorrow even made my pigeons uneasy.
I am in the lands where my father died.
I want to pray by his grave for once.
Knight Giovanni was the wisest and
the bravest knight I had ever seen.
You were the last person to see
my father before the Turks killed him.
They blinded me with hot iron rod
and left me to my fate.
Before I was blinded for good,
the last thing I saw was your father.
What if my father did not die?
I buried your father in a grave
I dug with my hands...
...while blood was seeping from my eyes.
You are saying you buried
my father when you were blind.
What if the person who you thought you
buried was not my father but someone else?
How can I not recognize
the master I worked for years?
I need to go.
With your permission, my girl.
Farewell, Elanora.
I am going to a mission and
I cannot return until it is completed.
I wanted to bid you farewell.
I will pray for your return.
Titus.
I want you to send this letter
to my sister Isadora.
She has suspicions about
the death of her father, sir.
She is trying to find a contradiction
in my statements by asking questions.
I want to be informed about
every step Elanora takes, Mario.
Gokce.
Mother Hayme wanted to ask you whether
your heart is with Ertugrul or not.
You should come to your senses. Don’t hide
in the corners and eat yourself up.
When I saw them together like that...
So she inquired my feelings?
This mission is over. You will not hide.
You should be seen by Ertugrul
in every occasion.
Sister, Ertugrul’s heart is with Halime.
You see and know this as well.
His mother might have inquired me
but I know...
...the son will not want to marry me.
My beautiful Baci, my naive Baci.
Who is asking Ertugrul?
If Suleyman Shah tells him to marry you...
...how can he object?
-He cannot, can he?
-Of course not.
When a wedding decision comes out of
Suleyman Shah’s mouth, it is final.
Have you ever seen Ertugrul oppose
his father up to this day?
Your wedding is soon, Gokce.
Do not eat up yourself.
When Gundogdu returns home,
we can engage you and Ertugrul.
Do we have permission, Yenge?
Come in, Bey.
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
I wanted to see how you are.
I hope you are well, if God permits.
We are better now that we see you,
Ertugrul Bey.
-You got us a territory from Aleppo.
-We did, thank God.
When my brother returns
with the caravan, we can migrate.
-Let him return safe and sound.
-He will, if God permits.
Yes but, Bey...
...the whole tribe wants a new territory.
Winter is at our door.
What can we do apart from migrating to
Aleppo? Do you know another way out?
Do you know how many Turkmen tribes
serve in the Mongol army, Alpargu?
-No, I do not.
-But I do.
Instead of conceding to Ertugrul's mind
and being stuffed into a snake hole...
...we can turn back and
make a deal with the Mongol commanders.
Why should Kayis be the guard dogs of
Aleppo putting forward their chests...
...as shields to Templar’s swords?
Or shall we do what scores of tribes...
...are doing and foray
the Rome territory from end to end?
But Bey, did not the Mongols
shed our blood tens of times?
This time will be different!
We have to risk making a deal with even
the devil for the future of our tribe.
Do not forget...
...we do everything for our tribe.
Now go and talk with
that simpleton called Baybora.
And don’t let the gimmicks of yesterday’s
child affect you.
Today I will keep quiet and
you will talk in the headquarters.
While Ertugrul talks about his sweet
victory, you should shake him up a bit.
This way we can also see
the reactions of the clan Beys.
Let us see how many will join in
your opposing views.
Stop!
Karatoygar wants him alive.
Take him away.
We will be a burden to you, Ilyas Fakih.
You will have to put up with us
until the tribe migrates.
Don’t make a big deal out of it.
We will just sleep quietly in a corner.
You are always welcome, brothers.
Turgut, what will Ertugrul Bey
talk to me about?
I see that you made yourself at home.
Do not test Ilyas Fakih’s patience.
Try to be tidy.
-Do you know what happened back here?
-Yes, Bey. Turgut told me everything.
It is obvious that Karatoygar
has a man inside.
He gave them the courage to raid
the tribe while we were away.
We need someone who will not
attract attention.
Just the job for us, Bey.
Will you do this job with
that body and bandit face of yours?
Is there someone our Bey suspects?
Yes. Afsin.
Trader’s man.
He stayed in the tribe
after saving Halime’s family.
I want to know who he is.
Of course, Bey. Do not worry about it.
I will breath down his neck.
I came for permission, sir.
Time for the mission.
I will finalize the job that I left
incomplete. I will do it silently.
Nurture the feeling of revenge inside you
like a newborn baby.
But never let it precede your mission.
Stop the Turks from settling at
our borders.
In the 99 names of our Great God,
Who creates with only saying “let be”...
...Who fills our hearts with belief.
In the name of God.
In the name of God,
most Merciful and most Graceful.
You may speak, Ertugrul.
Our new land is like the ones described
in the legends of our forefathers.
Very secure as described. Surrounded by
mountains on all four sides.
The people of the region even named
the place as Wind Stopper.
Then, if you even squeeze a stone,
water would drip.
It is such a fertile land.
A heaven on earth where our ponies can
freely roam and our herds can fatten...
...after the harsh winter.
-May God bless you.
-Thank you, bless you.
All problems are not solved
with getting the land.
Our new territory is fertile
but it is also fertile in enemies too.
It is at the border of
the Crusader Countship.
While our children and herds grow,
the ploys around us will grow as well.
If that is so, why do you talk about
our legends and confuse our minds?
Yes, Alpargu is right.
-He is right.
-He tells the truth.
We want a home, not a grave.
What makes land a home
is the grave, Baybora.
We should have graves so that
the land can be our territory...
...and our territory be our homeland.
-Wild Demir speaks the truth.
-Yes, he is right.
-I think so too.
You are wrong, Alpargu Bey.
Did you think the sagas of
our forefathers are fables?
They are not for making the babies sleep,
they are for awaking the grownups.
From them we learned how to cultivate
the fertile lands as well as...
...how to melt the surrounding
iron mountains.
What do you say, Kurdoglu?
Ertugrul is right, Bey.
The presence of an enemy gives us
the chance to be veterans and martyrs...
...praise to God. It would strengthen our
tribe. We can collect booty from around.
Is there anyone who objects?
As everyone agrees...
...let the migration preparations start.
KARATOYGAR INN
Come close, Gundogdu.
I can see the rage in your eyes.
Is that rage towards me or your father?
I do not like to lie about my feelings.
There is really no need for all these,
Gundogdu.
God forbid, if something happens
to your old father in the near future...
...wouldn’t it be better for you to lead
the Kayi tribe in the future?
If I were to become a Bey one day...
...I would skin you alive and
feed you to the dogs.
Interesting.
When I came to the tribe, I thought
the growling Ertugrul was the brave one.
But it is the other dog
who didn’t show his teeth then.
Bring him in!
Hamza.
I will give your father one last chance,
Gundogdu.
I will send your Alp,
Hamza to your father.
I will gently propose that he should
bring the prisoners alone tomorrow.
If he rejects my offer...
...first you, then the whole Kayi tribe
shall be slain by our swords.
I will do everything
a good intentioned commander would do.
This is all I can do.
Do you understand me?
Take them away to the prison!
Eyebrows should be like bows...
...and eyelashes like arrows.
You should look at your man in such a way
that you should hit him in the heart.
His eyes will not see any other woman.
Don’t put too much.
I don’t want to look like I am wounded.
Do not worry. You will be very beautiful.
Just like a Bey’s wife.
With your lush hair and apple cheeks...
...you will glide like a swan
the whole night.
Everyone will be looking at you.
But Ertugrul the most.
-Will he really look at me?
-Of course he will.
That is not all,
he will be hit directly from his heart.
The whole world will know.
Children...
...once upon a time...
...long before we migrated here from
the lands of our forefathers...
...there was a dragon which would
slay our people, rip apart our herds...
...and kill our horses.
The people were shivering in fright and
asking “is there a valiant Alp...
...who can save us from this monster?”
Our forefather Oguz cried out,
“yes, there is! There is!”
Of course he wasn’t like me.
Much taller and larger.
He took his bow, arrows, spear
and sword to set on the road.
You know your task.
Watch your manners, greet Ertugrul.
Bey, may God bless you. We won’t be killed
by the cold, thanks to you.
May your Alps always be behind you,
may you form a tribe with your daughter...
...make an army with your son,
may God bless you, always be our leader.
Amen.
Look at our tall Alp.
He is locked in again.
Oguz faced the dragon and said,
“look at me...
...I would hit you so hard
with this sword...
...your biggest part that is left
would be your ears.”
The Alps shall play sword and shields
in the honor of our new land.
Let our traditions live on!
Suleyman Shah protected you, as it is
a custom. Our custom is like this.
What about your customs? Does it include
seducing the son of a Bey...
...where you are a guest?
What are you saying?
I said what I had said
and you understood me well.
Stay away from Ertugrul.
Halime.
You are like an arrow which left the bow.
Do you intend to run away again?
So you heard the things that happened.
Yes, we tried to run away...
...but unfortunately we could not.
-Nobody wants you to go.
Guests are sacred for us.
This is our custom.
Ertugrul Bey.
We carry the dark clouds on top of us.
We should go, so that the dark clouds
above your tribe can disperse.
So you would have been long gone
before I came back from Aleppo.
Never to be seen again.
I was going to be hurt,
my heart was going to shatter but...
...they will never give up their pursue,
Ertugrul.
Who are they, Halime?
What do they want from you?
It is best if you don’t know
who we are, Ertugrul.
Bey, we caught a leper.
-Kill her, don’t let her live!
-Who are you, woman?
We caught her while she was pouring
something in the food cauldrons, Bey.
Do you want to die?
What did you put in the cauldrons? Talk!
The Templar Knights
send their regards to you, Ertugrul.
Put the cauldrons and
this woman in a pit and burn them all.
What do these Templars want from you?
You just told us this morning that they...
...tried to kill you in Aleppo, now they
try to spread their venom in our tribe.
Everything started with you saving
our guests from their hands.
What is this about?
The problem is deeper
than it seems, father.
I don’t think that
it only concerns Halime’s famiy.
The real reason they attack us must be
because we will be right at their border.
You don’t want to blame them but
our guests have a secret.
And this secret is very dangerous.
Of course they are our guests, we shall
treat them like visitors from God...
...but don’t think further, Ertugrul.
Father.
Ertugrul, son...
...you can’t have a tribe’s girl
from outside. Don’t you ever forget this.
Moreover, we would like to wed you with
our girl Gokce, the first chance we get.
We talked with your Mother Hayme.
I found it suitable as well.
Anyhow...
...the evil of the day should be preferred
over the goodness of the night.
Come to the breakfast table,
we will talk then.
-What makes your night a torture, son?
-Mother, what does my father say?
Gokce Baci to be my wife.
Gokce is a daughter of a Bey.
She grew up in our hands.
We know her manners, her attitude,
her ancestors and all.
You know all these, mother but...
...do you know my heart?
Halime...
...is here today, gone tomorrow.
We do not know who they are.
They say that they are traders.
Your father does not object...
...but he knows that they are not traders.
They are guests sent by God, he says.
He does not dwell on what it may lead to.
If the promise to the forefathers
is the well being of the tribe...
...this means Gokce for you, no one else.
Mother, God took me to her with a gazelle.
How can I betray those beautiful eyes?
Those sweet words?
If, one day, I summon the courage
to ask her whether her heart is with me...
...and she says “my path is your path”...
...how can I tell her to go?
Are you asleep?
I would give anything
for my eyes to be shut for an instant.
I talked with Ertugrul.
The girl’s father is better. They would
leave before the tribe migrates.
Bey...
...I offered Gokce as a name to you.
But I am not in peace.
Ertugrul’s heart is with the other girl.
An Alp’s heart is always
with his tribe, Hayme.
He is young, he is hasty,
his heart may overflow with feelings.
When the tribe migrates and the tents
are set, those feelings would dry up.
Come on.
May God give you a peaceful sleep.
What a blessed morning this is.
You can be rest assured now.
Be happy that your dreams will come true.
Suleyman Bey told Ertugrul
that you two should be wed.
I don’t know. I have butterflies in me
flying around but at the same time...
...dark clouds don’t seem to go away.
Let out a big breath, get rid of
all the bad feelings inside you.
This job is done. When Gundogdu returns,
there is no turning back.
-Did not Ertugrul arrive yet?
-He did not, Bey. He must be in his tent.
-Sit.
-My girl Gokce...
...go and inform him.
He should come to breakfast.
Ertugrul Bey?
Come in, Gokce.
Suleyman Shah expects you at
the breakfast table, Bey.
Gokce Baci.
I am coming.
The agreement is done.
We will give El Aziz as many Alps
as he wants...
...and we'll pay the taxes. The territory
he has appointed for us is accepted.
Tomorrow morning leave early
in the morning, send him my regards.
Inform him that I shall pay him
a visit after we settle in our new land.
As you wish, father.
If God permits,
after we settle in our new land...
...we shall wed you and Gokce.
Well?
I want a grandson, Ertugrul.
Father?
With your permission...
Get up and drink some water.
-I need to see our Bey.
-Wait, let me inform him.
-Rahman, who is it at the door?
-Hamza arrived, Bey.
-He wants to see you.
-Let him in immediately.
I hope it will lead to a good deed.
Bey...
...Karatoygar...
Karatoygar ambushed the caravan.
-Karatoygar?
-What are you saying, Alp?
-Where is Gundogdu?
-Where are the other Alps?
They all died, Bey. All of them.
-Gundogdu Bey is imprisoned by Karatoygar.
-What do you mean by imprisoned?
How can you leave your Bey? How?
Why did they let you go? What does
this snake called Karatoygar want?
The guests Ertugrul Bey
brought to the tribe.
Karatoygar wants them.
If you don’t give them by tomorrow...
...he will kill Gundogdu Bey.
These are all your doings!
Everything is your fault!
You brought those cursed people here
and all hell broke loose!
Selcan!
Selcan, come. Come here, my girl.
Rahman, send some trusted men
to bring back our bodies.
Take Hamza to a tent without anyone
seeing him. Akcakoca should treat him.
I do not want anyone in the tribe to
learn what happened. And bring me Numan!
As you wish, Bey!
Ertugrul.
Where is your manners? How can you enter
without seeking permission?
-Halime.
-Suleyman Shah awaits you in his tent.
Hurry up.
-Halime.
-Be quick.
Numan Efendi, what happened?
Do not worry, Afsin. There is no problem.
Father?
Halime Baci, where are they taking
my Shahzade?
Suleyman Shah wanted to see him.
I knew it would end up like this.
I knew they would be trouble.
If something happens to Gundogdu...
...I would kill that girl and her family.
-Stop right there, girl, stop!
Wife of a Bey needs to be resilient.
Control yourself!
Here I am, Bey. You called for me.
Come this way.
A messenger arrived this morning.
He told us that our caravan was ambushed
and our Alps were killed.
Karatoygar, who did this,
has my son Gundogdu as a prisoner.
Bey...
...I don’t know what a test like this
is called. May God give you patience.
I did not call you here to say prayers or
share our sorrow. As I called you here...
...you probably realized what those
bandits who hold my son hostage want.
Now, I am going to ask you one question.
And I request a single answer from you.
Who are you?
On one side, my husband and on the other,
the people we don’t know anything about.
They killed so many Alps,
they took Gundogdu prisoner!
And I am telling you,
they are hiding something from us...
...but I will learn what that is
then they will pay for all of this!
Mountains hold the ground,
Beys hold the customs, my girl.
All the things you say is men’s job!
Because of their curse,
is there a man left in the tribe, mother?
Go after her,
don’t let her make the matters worse.
Bey, telling you this is my debt but...
...please know that...
...not sharing this with you is as much
about your safety as well as my own...
...and my family’s safety.
Bey, if I tell you who we are,
the disasters you will face...
...will be many times worse than now.
But...
...I owe you a life.
I am ready to sacrifice anything for you.
This includes my life
and my children’s as well.
I told you to give a single answer.
Only one!
I am...
...from the Great Seljuk Dynasty...
...Muzaffereddin Davut.
Muhiddin Mesut Shah’s son.
I am the grandson of
Sultan Izzeddin Kilicarslan.
I am a Seljuk Shahzade.
Halime!
Hear me well!
You will curse the day you came here.
For all the things you made this tribe
go through, you will be accounted for.
Do you understand me?
If it comes down to me...
...I would not hesitate to kill you all!
I will kill you!
Calm down, Hatun.
Why do you attack like a rabid dog?
Because of you, our caravan is raided,
our Alps are killed...
...that filth called Karatoygar
holds my husband hostage!
If one hair on his head is harmed,
if I have to live through that pain...
...you will see what
a rabid dog looks like then!
Sister. That is enough.
Let us go.
We will not go, Gokce. They will.
Dead or alive.
-They will go!
-Selcan!
Control yourself.
Take her out.
Whatever you heard from by bride
a while ago, don’t tell anyone about it.
Stay in the tent. Because none of us know
what will happen now.
Do we have permission, Halime Baci?
I heard it all.
This is not good at all.
What will we do, Afsin Bey?
The bride threatened to kill us
if something happens to her husband.
We will find a solution.
It seems that Suleyman Shah will not
announce the dead Alps.
If the news gets around, no one would know
what the people might do.
God forbid. We don’t want any harm
on our Shahzades or Gundogdu.
Karatoygar’s aim is obvious.
In exchange for Gundogdu...
...he will request our Shahzades.
Don’t go out from the tent.
I will do whatever is needed.
With your permission.
We have grown tired of running for years.
I ran away from those who...
...threatened my state with me.
From the Templars, the Mongols. I ran away
from all those who want an uprising.
I ran away from those who pursue me
for the survival of my state.
And I ran away from my state so that
my valiant son would not be harmed.
Bey...
...it has been years since
I have given up on my own life.
So this is the end,
it is time to put an end to all this.
Karatoygar wants an exchange, father.
But even if we give him what he wants...
...he would kill you.
His rage against you will not subside
after he gets the Shahzades.
He will kill you and my brother as well.
You are right, my son.
First...
...we have to find a way
to save Gundogdu from him.
Not only my brother.
I would not hand you over to him, father.
If I attack with my Alps,
he would kill Gundogdu immediately.
And with the blood that would be spilt,
the tribe cannot stand strong again.
We would fall apart.
First you have to convince him
to free my brother, father.
Then convince him to come out of his fort.
If he wants an exchange, we set the rules.
-Why would he free Gundogdu?
-He has to, father.
Why did the Templars
try to kill me in Aleppo?
Why did they send a leper woman
to poison the tribe?
Why were the Templars were taking
the Shahzades to Karatoygar?
They wanted Karatoygar to be appointed
to an important post in the palace...
...and for him to serve them
at the palace.
Karatoygar is after the Shahzades, father.
He would do everything to get them...
...we just need to know how to ask for it.
What if something goes wrong?
Then we all die, father.
But at least we would die holding a sword
in our hands and honor in our hearts.
Will they die?
Unfortunately it has to be that way.
They will all die, except Gundogdu.
Maybe a lucky Alp will live to bring
the bad news to Suleyman Shah.
I don’t believe it.
The reign of Suleyman Shah will be over.
What a big bad world. Incredible.
What if he insists on customs...
...and not hand over the prisoners?
What else can he do?
Will he accept the death of his own son?
What will we do if he rounds up
his Alps and attack Karatoygar?
I know Suleyman Shah very well,
he would put his own life at stake.
Karatoygar will kill both of them.
Then only Ertugrul will be left.
-And his death...
-You have gone too far, Bey. Too far.
No good would come out of this.
You dog! If you were so scared,
why did you team up with me?
For the good of the tribe, Bey.
-I didn’t expect it to be...
-What didn’t you expect? What?
If a few Alps need to be sacrificed
for the good of the tribe, let them be.
Isn’t it so? Tell me, isn’t it so?
You are right, Bey.
They can be sacrificed.
May God forgive all their sins.
We did what needed to be done.
If I didn’t convince Karatoygar
to ambush the caravan...
...he'd have run over us with his army.
Our progeny would have ended.
Now I we need to do is to sit back and
wait for the bad news to reach the tribe.
You go and wash your face,
you need to freshen up.
Watch out for this coward, Alpargu.
If his cowardice lets his tongue loose...
...don’t be afraid to rip it off.
Everything will be alright, you will see.
Suleyman Shah would not sacrifice his son.
He would not sacrifice him, right?
Of course not.
But he would not step back
from our customs either.
Sister...
...please do not over think
the situation and devastate yourself.
What if he does something crazy, like
trying to save Gundogdu from Karatoygar?
This is what I am worried about.
I will go and talk with Suleyman Shah.
First he will free Gundogdu.
Then I will take Karatoygar outside
his fort to the place we determined.
When we reach there, the rest will be
up to your courage and skill, son.
-An important matter is being discussed.
-Get out of my way.
-Our Bey’s orders.
-I told you to get out of my way.
We will ambush Karatoygar
at Kartal Tepesi.
Let us talk outside.
I promise that I will deliver my brother
Gundogdu to you safe and sound.
If something happens to Gundogdu...
...if you sacrifice your brother
for people you collected on the road...
...you shall never find
peace from me, Ertugrul.
Bey...
...as a father...
...I will request one last thing from you.
If you give permission,
I want to entrust my daughter to you.
Karatoygar is after my son and I.
They have no business with my daughter.
My daughter is the tribe’s girl
from now on.
She has no one to turn to
or anywhere to go.
Please be rest assured, Yenge.
Stop! What do you want?
I wanted to ask about a sergeant.
He used to be a sergeant in my legion.
-What is his name?
-Sari, they call him Sari Bolu.
Of course we know Sari Bolu.
But he is not a sergeant
but a captain now.
Is he in the base?
He went on a mission with Karatoygar.
If you have a message, tell it to us.
I do, warrior, I do.
Welcome, Titus.
Have a seat.
I read the letter Ustad-i Azam
sent with a pigeon.
He does not want Kayis
to migrate to Aleppo.
Yes.
He should not worry.
Kayis will not migrate to Aleppo...
...but to a place
I find suitable for them.
How?
Their future Bey thinks just like me.
He prefers to kneel in front of
the Mongols rather than...
...to be neighbors with the Crusaders.
Who is this man?
Kurdoglu.
Suleyman Shah’s blood brother.
An ambitious fool.
Someone who will do anything we say,
someone we can use as we wish.
What about Suleyman Shah?
Suleyman Shah...
...will come to my fort in the evening...
...and surrender.
Moreover, he will bring with him
the Shahzades...
...your knights let escape.
Afsin Bey!
I thought you were dead.
It had to be known like that, Bolu.
Our state is under a big threat.
I need your help.
Why is this ominous news late?
Bey, Suleyman Shah calls you to his tent.
Whatever happens,
Karatoygar should not get the Shahzades.
What if he succeeds in taking
the Shahzades to Sultan Aladdin?
He would be Aladdin’s favorite commander.
Templars would have Konya in their hands.
They would roam within the palace.
The consequences would be deadly, Sari.
This state was founded
with great difficulty.
We will not refrain from killing
the Shahzades if needed.
I am ready to do anything
you want from me, Bey.
Thank you, I know that, Sari, I know.
What a tyrant this Karatoygar is!
How could he dare to kill our warriors?
As if that is not enough...
...he captured Gundogdu as a prisoner?
-Yes.
Now, they expect me to deliver our guests.
That means that the death of
this rabid dog will be from us.
Let us go with our Alps and
make the sky fall on them.
No!
I will go alone.
I won’t let you go alone.
Did we become blood brothers for one to
stay behind and cry like women...
...while the other one
is going for a certain death, Bey?
The path I will be on
is full of unknowns, Kurdoglu.
How can I go on this road if
my blood brother is not staying behind...
...to protect and serve my tribe
in case something happens to me?
You shall be taking
my place until I return.
Put this on as well.
Do not feel cold on the road.
-Sister...
-Say it, my lion.
What if I can’t see you again?
What are you saying, Yigit?
We survived so many difficulties together.
We passed so many obstacles.
We will pass this one as well.
But this time we are separated.
You will not be with us.
-What if those men take us and...
-Do not worry your pure heart like this.
Look, this time we are not alone.
There are Beys of the tribe.
They will protect us, they care for us.
Always stay beside my father.
Do everything he says, alright?
And do not think about me.
I will sit here and wait for you.
There will be no sadness, do we agree?
Come on.
Now go...
...and say goodbye to your friends. Go on.
Father.
I am just talking so that
Yigit is not scared or gets sad but...
...my mind does not believe my own words.
How will it end?
My girl, it has been a very long time.
We went through many sorrows
by running away and getting captured.
This thing will finish once and for all,
if God permits.
Ertugrul has a plan.
I found it probable as well.
With God’s permission,
we shall go and come back in one piece.
This tribe paid a very big price for us.
We can never repay them for all they did.
Please let me.
Let me come with you as well.
Whatever happens, good or bad...
...we should be together at the end.
You pray for us, that is enough, my girl.
My precious and brave daughter with
a beautiful heart and a beautiful face.
Just like her mother, self sacrificing
and loyal. My beautiful daughter.
Do not worry.
Everything will be fine.
What happened? What do you want?
Come with us.
This boil is hurting
like a knife in my back.
My Bey...
...your pain is my pain.
But there is nothing I can do.
All I can do is to pray
for you and my sons.
We went through so many sorrows,
so many journeys, so many battles.
We had the privilege to grow old.
Thank God, we have seen these days, Hayme.
You are right, Bey.
We saw so many weddings, so many babies...
...so many springs.
We saw so many victories.
If God permits, we will continue
to see more.
I want your blessing.
These problems are not permanent
and our lives are not eternal, Bey.
You always walked on the righteous path.
You never bowed to tyrants.
Has anyone seen a person
on the righteous path getting lost?
If God permits,
I will see you and my sons’ return.
May God be with you.
My blessing is with you.
Thank you.
What is it? What do you want?
Where do you go,
where do you come from, Afsin Bey?
I want to hear what you are made of
from your mouth.
Dear God, please protect them, Dear God.
You called for me, mother.
I did. Come and sit down.
Yes, mother?
Ertugrul Bey?
Do we have permission?
Halime Sultan comes to our tent,
does she need a permission?
Ertugrul Bey...
...I lied to you.
Yes, you did.
Do you understand now, why we had to go?
Why the days we spent in this tribe are
only a dream that we would wake from?
You are happy here.
Despite a life you lived in a palace...
...you talk about a nomad life
like a dream, Halime.
Even if the whole world comes together...
...I will not let you become unhappy.
Do you understand me, my girl?
I did, mother.
Good.
You may go now.
Instead of reacting and
spewing out bitter words...
...recite God’s name, pray
and fill your heart with goodness...
...so that our fate be good as well.
The problem is not my happiness.
The problem is my father’s
and my brother’s life.
Do not worry.
I will not let anything happen
to your father or your brother.
I will bring them back to you
safe and sound.
You can be rest assured.
After all the things that have been
robbed and taken away from me...
...you are taking with you
all that is left.
My father, my brother.
I beg you to return with them.
Return and complete
the thing that is missing inside me.
If I do not return, know that...
...whatever I had missing inside me,
I found it in you.
Their intention is not good, Gokce...
...they will let my man die
in the name of customs.
Sister, Suleyman Shah
is a human being as well.
Would a human let his child be slain?
Get rid of these delusions from your mind.
You do not know who Suleyman Shah is.
He would even burn his tribe for customs.
I have to find a way, Gokce, I have to.
I will not let them sacrifice my man!
Dear God!
Ertugrul’s Alps have prepared
their horses and weapons, waiting to go.
I have things to say to you, Kurdoglu.
What happened, Selcan Hatun?
Gundogdu trusts you, he respects you.
You know that.
What about you, Selcan Hatun?
-I have always trusted your bravery.
-Thank you.
What happened to Gundogdu is not
acceptable. But do not worry...
...Suleyman Shah will bring him back.
-No he will not.
If you are brave, if you do not want
Suleyman Shah to throw...
...his tribe into fire,
if you respect Gundogdu a little bit...
If Suleyman Shah
does something like this...
...I would throw him into the fire myself.
Now I am listening to you, Selcan Hatun.
Suleyman Shah and Ertugrul...
...will ambush
Karatoygar at Kartal Tepesi.
-What are you saying, Selcan Hatun?
-I heard it with my own ears.
Suleyman Shah decided to be loyal
to his customs rather than his son!
Do not tell this to anyone, Selcan Hatun.
And you did not talk with me...
...we did not see each other.
Alright, Selcan Hatun?
What will happen to Gundogdu?
We will find a solution.
Go on, get out before anyone sees you.
Will we let them go, Bey?
We will, so that Karatoygar’s hunt
can be more fruitful, Alpargu.
I cleaned the tribe from all filth
without drawing a sword...
...or getting blood on my hands.
Come on, get on your horse.
You have things to say to Karatoygar.
I swear on the horses
that run endlessly...
I swear on the horseshoes that sparkle...
If I am scared to die for our tribe,
for our Bey, for our customs...
...may I be slain by my own steel sword,
like a crop in the field.
May the blue sky tear,
may the brave ground sink...
...may my name be erased
from all monuments.
May my forefather Oguz,
my blessed tribe sue me in the next life!
In this path I have taken,
may God be by my side...
...may Godsend Hıdr accompany me.
Come on, Titus. Relax a bit.
Today is our day.
We will both get what we want.
You were this comfortable
when Ertugrul was going to Aleppo as well.
You were this relaxed.
Then we know what happened.
Your soldiers’ incompetence.
Sir, Suleyman Shah.
Let us not make our visitors wait.
Let them in.
He came alone, sir.
Bring him here immediately.
Let us see whether you will eat what you
hope or what you find, Karatoygar.
You, what are you up to, Suleyman Shah?
Where are they?
You will get what you want
after you release my son.
Do you want to be killed?
Is my son’s and my life more valuable
or the Shahzades?