RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
1225 - KAYI TRIBE
-Great God!
-Only one God!
Even the iron could not stand
reciting of God and gave in.
Wait a bit!
Take a look at this one.
This is magnificent. I pity the enemy whom
this will be the Azrael of.
In the hands of a valiant like you...
...let it be the sound of the oppressed,
wrath to the tyrants, if God permits.
There’s no sword other than Zulfiqar and
no valiant other than His Holiness Ali.
I’m ready to sacrifice myself for God,
who gave you to us.
For the love of God, in the name of my
forefather Oguz, I’ll gird it with honor.
Bring your hands.
What is the matter?
Your tumblers are restless again.
We are going hunting.
They are getting ready.
Are there any animals left to hunt
in this famine?
You are right but...
...hunting keeps the Alps fit.
It is better if we find a way to keep
the tribe alive as well.
That can only be decided
on the headquarters tomorrow.
If we don’t migrate from this highland
before winter, we would be doomed.
But if you say that you know a solution,
tell us as well.
My brother Gundogdu knows
these matters better than me.
If you wish, talk to him.
With Gundogdu?
No, he never breaths a single word about.
Is this what you bought for 40 coins?
This is called a map.
What is it used for?
Look, we are here.
Right at where these mountains are.
This is Aleppo. This is Baghdad.
And this is Damascus.
And this is Konya,
where the Sultan’s palace is.
Let go of the palaces
of the sultans and khans and...
...tell us where the tribe should
migrate to, Gundogdu.
The elders are having a dumb moment.
Your father is quiet.
He just sits in his tent like
a worrier not a warrior.
Where is this place?
Everyone will learn tomorrow
at headquarters.
You found a place, right?
Please tell me, where is it?
Ertugrul!
Where are you going?
I am going hunting, brother.
This is not the time to go hunting.
We have headquarters tomorrow.
The headquarter is yours
and hunt is mine, brother.
Alright. But don’t go too far.
Go quickly, come back quickly.
What are you doing with that meat?
We are going hunting, did you forget?
We won’t let you starve during a hunt,
don’t you worry.
How can you call a valiant as valiant if
he starves while he is hunting, Turgut?
-This is just for the road.
-It is impossible to relieve your hunger.
Come on, Alps.
Your man is going.
AMANOS MOUNTAINS
TEMPLARS CASTLE
Guard duty is your pride!
Guard duty is your honor!
If you betray your pride and honor...
...your death will not come
from the enemy, but from me!
You have honored us, Ustad-i Azam.
That honor belongs to us.
-Elanora.
-Commander Titus.
I hope your journey was fine.
Is everything alright, Titus?
We are safer than ever, sir.
Your chambers are ready, sir.
Would you like to rest before lunch?
Elanora may rest. We have work to do.
-As you wish.
-With your permission.
What is the latest development
about the prisoners?
I gave that duty to my brother Bisol.
They will submit Numan and his family
to Karatoygar.
For the others, I waited for you.
Good.
Where are they taking us, father?
To our palace, son.
We will be free there, right?
Until eternity, son.
Until eternity.
So out fate was to return to Konya
like this.
To the palace we were born in and
grew up, to be killed by our uncle.
I will not let anything to happen
to you or your brother, my daughter.
This way Karatoygar will be
dependent on us more than ever.
It is very important for him to win
the favor of Sultan Aladdin.
Karatoygar becoming a high officer
in the Seljuk court will relieve us.
KARATOYGAR INN
-We did everything as you ordered, sir.
-Okay!
Head of guard!
Are the Turkmen tribes paying
their taxes?
We can’t control them, sir.
They are always on the move.
-Which one is the biggest tribe?
-Kayi tribe, sir.
They ran away from the Mongol invasion.
-Who is their leader?
-Suleyman Shah.
-How many tents?
-2000 tents. But they are well respected.
-Do they pay their taxes?
-They do, sir.
Good.
Then, they shall pay their taxes
earlier this year.
-But, sir...
-You heard what I said.
How will this state remain standing?
Inform all the tribes
in the region immediately.
Yes, sir.
Where are those templars?
Halt!
Let us rest a bit here.
Check the surroundings.
We need to weaken the Seljuks
before the crusade.
You should put more men
in the Seljuk court, Titus.
Please be rest assured that
we will possess the whole court.
There is a group in the Papacy,
who are reluctant about the crusade.
I am not surprised.
We need to make a plan that will mobilize
the whole Europe.
We need to do this.
The Christian world should unite
and act for Jerusalem.
For this, we need to provoke
the Muslims and make them attack us.
I have some very valuable prisoners.
We can start with them.
Calm down, son.
Yigit.
Commoner...
...you can go to hell.
-Take us to our destination quickly.
-So you are very keen to die.
I pity for your beautiful daughter
and your small Shahzade.
Don’t shed a tear for us.
If you had accepted to be allies with us,
you were to become the Seljuk sultan...
...and everything was going to be fine.
-You offered slavery for the Pope.
We offered you peace...
...and a new world order.
We wanted to live side by side.
But...
...the Muslim blood will always be shed.
There is no escape from this.
And we will shed your blood with
the Muslim allies we have.
You will not succeed.
We will see.
In the mean time...
...to all your men I had sent to hell...
...give them my regards.
-The area is safe, sir.
-Good.
Water the horses.
These too.
-Come on!
-Yeah!
Come on!
You two, go and sit somewhere else.
I brought you water. Take it.
Take it.
Come on.
They are not aware.
Key! Take the key.
Come on, my girl.
We are in luck.
The prisoners are running away!
-Quick, run!
-Get them!
-Father!
-Are you alright?
Quick, take your brother
and get out of here.
No!
-Father!
-Quick! Run away!
-No, we cannot leave you in this state.
Take your brother and
get the hell out of here!
Come on, father! Get up! Come on!
So you tried to run away!
You will pay for this.
Father!
Have some decency! Dear God!
Have some decency!
Great God!
-Father!
Father, stay with us, please!
Your first victim was a crusader.
-Stay with us.
-Be strong, father.
-Quick, bring some oak leaves.
-Okay.
If we are successful, all the borders
in the region will change.
We should not refrain from using
our order’s wealth to save Jerusalem.
We are ready to spend the whole treasury.
For young men, a new Jerusalem campaign
would be the shortest road to riches.
They will be enlisting by the thousands
to be a member of the crusade army.
The Catalans, the Venetians,
the Marseilleans...
...they will be pining for this carnival.
Well...
...what about the spoilt princes of
Europe, how will we trust them?
When the Muslims start to fight
with each other...
...our job will not be difficult, Titus.
What about the Seljuks, sir?
Anatolia.
They are on the peak of their power
with Sultan Aladdin.
When we make the Turks and the grandsons
of Saladin Ayyubi fall out on...
...each other we will reach our goal.
Jerusalem will be ours.
Father, please be strong.
We have to go immediately.
You can go.
We can look after ourselves.
It will get dark soon.
The jackals would have
already smelled the blood.
-We should go.
-Dogan, bring the horses.
It is easy to fend off a crusader brigade.
What about this?
Ertugrul is lost now.
-God always helps those who get lost.
-He is lost real bad now.
Come on.
-What can you do alone as a woman?
-I said we won’t go.
We owe you a life.
We will pay our debt one day.
Tell us your name.
Ertugrul from Kayi tribe.
As you wish.
May God be with you. I wish you good luck.
We should go with them.
Is your tribe far?
Even our money for bad days is finished,
Brother Afsin.
We can set shop here. If we see that
they are not interested, we can go on.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you. Welcome.
Welcome, Gazanfar Aga.
You bring joy to Kayi tribe.
Kurdoglu, my brother. You always
look very healthy, thanks to God.
Would these moorlands keep a man healthy,
for us to be healthy, Gazanfer?
No, don’t say that. You look very well.
Where is your caravan?
The caravan is near the black rock.
I came to get permission from Suleyman
Shah to set up a stall in the market.
How is business?
We thank God on what he gives.
I wanted to come to Kayi to supply
whatever they need before the journey.
Thank you, Gazanfer. I hope you meet
your expectations, if God permits.
Thank you.
If Suleyman Shah is available,
I would like to meet him.
Tell our Bey that Gazanfer Aga is here.
-How much is this?
-He is a mute, sir. Let me help you.
80 coins.
You look familiar to me.
This is my first time in your tribe, sir.
You probably took me for someone else.
Peace be upon you, Suleyman Shah.
And peace be upon you, trader. Welcome.
You bring joy to us. Come and sit.
Suleyman Bey, my eyes are so happy that
they had the chance to see you again.
Please accept my presents. I brought them
from Constantinople for you.
You did not have to bother.
-Kurdoglu, give these to those in need.
-As you wish, Bey.
Well?
Tell us now. What did those eyes see in
other parts of the world?
I wish I was deaf and not hear it.
I wish I was blind and not see it, Bey.
What happened?
Sultan Aladdin controlled Konya but...
...he worries that the fugitive Shahzades
may give him trouble.
The Latins ransacked Constantinople.
All Orthodox people left the city.
There is no order, no peace...
...and with the famine now,
everyone is desperate.
We heard that the leftovers from
the crusaders were getting restless.
It is obvious that they are up to
something once again.
Well...
...how are the common people?
They will be on the road again
to find something to eat.
The rumor is that the Pope is calling for
a new crusade to the European princes.
And we Muslims fight against each other.
Sowing discord between us,
fueling the disorder as much as possible.
From Anatolia to Basra,
everywhere is on fire.
This fire will hit us as well, Bey.
Please don’t say fire, it upsets me, Bey.
I came to seek for permission to sell
my goods in your tribe.
-You have our permission.
-Thank you.
Karatoygar has come to the region
to control the Turkmen tribes.
So difficult times await us.
And this girl is from Venetia.
Rosalina, she has noble blood.
A white skin, green eyes.
A rare find, commander.
And she is very cheap as well.
I am in urgent need of money.
This is a very good opportunity
for you and me.
What do you say to this, commander?
They kidnapped her from
the Greek Islands.
She screams beauty and freshness.
She is a wild one.
I personally trained her.
For a master with good taste.
What about that blond one?
I must say that you have good taste.
I bought her from the crusader discards.
They brought her in with a ship.
She is Serbian,
she knows how to treat a man.
Enough.
Come here.
You don’t need to be afraid of me.
I am your master now.
You chose the most expensive one,
commander. But she is worth it.
-Sir?
-What happened?
The crusaders. They were ambushed.
Didn’t you save them?
We were too late.
So you were late.
-Welcome.
-Come on, help them.
-Help them.
Akcakoca, we have a wounded man.
-Come on.
-Bamsi, take him in.
-What happened?
-Nothing to worry about.
-You are alright, yes?
-We all are, thank God.
Ertugrul...
...what happened, my brother?
They were attacked, brother.
I will tell you later.
-Look after them, Ramazan.
-As you wish, Bey.
Who are they, Gundogdu?
I don’t know. He will tell us later.
We will find out soon.
Sister, what is happening? Who are they?
We will find out soon. We will see.
The sword hit him right below the rib.
Fortunately the oak leaves stopped...
...the bleeding,
otherwise we would have lost him.
-Midwife, bring hot water.
-At once, Akcakoca.
The leg is bad as well.
But we should fix this wound first.
Akcakoca can take it from here.
Let us wait at the side.
-We cannot leave our father alone, sister.
-Don’t worry.
Your father is in good hands.
Thank you very much. You are God sent.
-We brought trouble to you.
-Don’t say that.
You had more breaths to take,
more bites to eat.
Where were the crusaders taking you?
I don’t know. They didn’t say.
I guess they were going to sell us in
the slave market. My father is a trader.
We were captured in the Mediterranean.
Your father must be a good trader.
Having so many crusaders taking you.
Yes.
We were rich.
But we don’t have anything left now.
Well...
...which tribe is this?
You are in Kayi tribe.
I am the son of
the tribe Bey, Suleyman Shah.
We owe you three lives.
-Do you want to be freed from slavery?
-Yes.
-Then, kill this man.
-No!
I will buy and then free you.
Commander, you are furious.
First calm down...
Shut your mouth.
Don’t let me kill you as well.
Sir, please spare me for my children.
You are good for nothing.
Do it!
-I can’t.
-I said do it!
I’m freeing you!
A slave that can kill someone
to be free...
...can kill her master one day as well.
Get ready, we are going!
Bey, dinner is ready. Come to the table.
Dundar, come on, come to the table, son.
I will come as soon as
I finish this, mother.
Always be like that, my boy.
Finish the job at hand first.
-Selcan?
-Yes, mother?
-Bring the molasses, my girl.
-Yes, mother.
Where is Gundogdu?
He went to check the shepherds,
he will come in a few minutes.
Put another plate on the table.
For Sungurtekin.
If he comes back one day, he should know
that his place is ready at the table.
Come on then. Why is Gundogdu late?
He will come, mother.
In the name of God.
Well, son? You returned with a big hunt.
Something like that, Bey.
What kind of luck is this, brother?
You are like a lightning pulling tree.
You attract all kinds of trouble
to yourself.
The innocents were under attack.
We did what we could do.
Who are they? Where do they come from?
They were captured by the crusaders.
The man is a trader.
The crusaders must be from
Antioch Countship.
Knights don’t freely transport captives
in the Seljuk territory.
Well?
What I mean is, the Seljuks must
know about these prisoners.
There were no Seljuk soldiers with them.
Sooner or later, the kind of trouble
you called will be revealed, Ertugrul.
What should have I done, brother?
Turn my back and leave?
Both of you stop talking.
Host them in a way worthy of our tribe.
We will see what the future holds.
It is over, father. You are saved.
You will be healed.
-Do we have permission?
-Come in, Bey.
How is he?
It is up to God from now on.
With your permission.
Come in, Aykiz.
Aykiz.
Turgut’s sweetheart.
I wanted to ask whether
you need anything or not.
Thank you.
-We have been a big burden on you.
-Don’t say that.
Bamsi Beyrek and Dogan are preparing their
tent for you, you can stay there tonight.
I...
...should stay with my father.
Rest a bit tonight. You look very tired.
Your father will need you more
when he wakes up tomorrow.
Don’t worry, I will stay with your father.
Bey, how did you let the boil get so big?
We carry so many problems
on our backs, Hayme.
Will we be afraid of one this small?
If you had crushed its head when it was
small, it would have been long gone.
The jackals used to live in the mountains,
now they are inside our tribe.
They wait for my slightest
mistake to attack.
I hide it so that they don’t know
about my weakness.
It is better to bite your lip
and sit with pain...
...rather than giving them
something to talk about.
At least, you should have told Akcakoca.
I did, woman, I did.
He is preparing an ointment to cure me.
We will put in on at night,
if God permits.
What happened?
Are you thinking about our guests?
I don’t know what kind of
a smoky candle this wick has lit.
-Did you wear it?
-Yes.
-How is it?
-It is beautiful, Aykiz.
Let me see.
Dear God. You look like a queen
from a palace, Halime.
You look so beautiful.
What happened? Did I say something wrong?
No. I just found it strange
for you to say that.
Wait, let us put the head piece as well.
Turgut Alp got this for me.
Dear God! Why did you give it to me then?
Because I knew that it would suit you.
Let me see?
I was right.
When is your wedding?
After we migrate from this moorland,
if God permits.
Isn’t it very hard to be
the wife of an Alp?
If his heart is beating for me,
who cares how hard it is?
The only thing I want is for him
to be back safe and sound.
As long as there is no death.
-Shall we braid your hair, if you want?
-Alright.
Do you have a man in your life?
After my mother died, the only thing
that was in my life was being a mother...
...to my brother Yigit and
be a companion to my father.
-Anyway, which man would want...
-Are you out of your mind?
Men would fight, they would turn
the world upside down for you.
When was the last time
you looked at yourself in a mirror?
Wait.
Isn't he the brother of
the infidel called Titus?
Yes, sir. Bisol.
Send these bodies to the Templars.
We will be dealing with Titus as well now.
You! You! Come here!
Load this one on a horse.
-Which tribe does this seal belong to?
-Kayi tribe, sir.
So they are Kayis.
If they are with Suleyman Shah,
our job is very difficult.
Could that shepherd head
resist the Seljuk?
-May you have a good morning, Ertugrul.
-You too.
I brought you some food.
You did not need to bother, Gokce Baci.
-How is our wounded guest?
-Fine. He should be up in a few days.
If God permits. May God give him health
and hope he does not bring any trouble.
I will be back in a while and
we can go to the weaving area.
Alright, Aykiz.
Is my father better, Ertugrul Bey?
Yes, much better.
You will see when you go in.
His fever has gone down. We can take him
to your tent tonight, if God permits.
Did you see the girl?
She already has Ertugrul
eating from her hands.
You can only see him
in your dreams from now on.
Did you sleep well?
It has been years since
I slept so peacefully.
In the forest you said Templars.
Yes.
Who are they?
An order that fights for Jerusalem.
They are very strong and ruthless.
Their only aim is to take revenge
on Jerusalem.
If they are so strong,
what did they want from you?
-Is this the Seljuk territory?
-Yes.
Do you have an issue
with the Seljuks, Halime?
Not at all. What issue can
the great Seljuks have with us?
Towel.
-What is wrong with you, my girl?
-Nothing, father. I didn’t see it.
But you can still say
what you want to say, right?
A thing cannot become reality just because
you want it very much. I learned this.
From whom?
We were going to get married with Turgut
after the migration, we yearned for it.
The winter is knocking at our door and
we still don’t know where we will go to.
I understand.
You are as impatient as your late mother.
Take a look around you. Can we survive
the winter on a mountain this high?
Why do you think we have headquarters?
Why do all the neighboring Beys come to...
...our Suleyman Shah’s marquee?
We will sit, we will talk and
we will solve this matter, if God permits.
Don’t you worry about it.
We should not be late.
My dear sweet girl, Aykiz.
They will be gathering for headquarters,
Kurdoglu. Nobody knows what to do.
We will get over this, with God’s help.
Kurdoglu, the mountain is silent,
the rivers don’t babble anymore...
...we have no rain.
We are stranded in this moorland.
If we don’t move quickly our herds
will perish, our babies will die.
Well? What is on your minds?
A horse neighs according to its owner,
Kurdoglu. Our warning is to you.
Weigh in on the decisions.
Suleyman Shah is weak.
He can’t even ride a horse now.
In other words, Kurdoglu...
...horse belongs to who rides it,
sword belongs to who gird it.
Mother?
I came to Akcakoca to get
some healing herbs.
He is out. Tell me what you want,
I will bring them to you, mother.
No, I will come and pick them up later.
Our guest.
Numan Bey’s daughter. Halime.
Welcome to our tribe, my girl.
How is your father, did he recover?
-Yes.
-I am glad. May God heal him.
Our tents are always open for you.
If you have a problem, do not hesitate...
...come and tell me immediately, alright?
-May God bless you, Hayme Hanim.
Not on the ground, not in the air...
...only in the hearts of
devoted believers...
...the One that creates,
makes all creation one...
...in the name of God,
most Merciful and most Graceful.
Between the blue skies and dark ground,
let our blood, our clan, our tribe...
...our homes, our sons, our daughters...
...be united, be free, be keen.
In the presence of our most just Bey,
may we bless our headquarters.
-Amen.
In the 99 names of our Great God,
Who creates with only saying “let be”...
...Who fills our hearts with belief.
In the name of God.
Thank you.
My beys, my warriors,
the leaders of my clans.
Welcome and be blessed.
-Thank you.
Thank God that before we set on the road
to sell our goods, a trader has come.
I say that we sell our goods
to this trader at prime value...
...and save from the travel expenses.
That would be fine
if our only problem was the goods.
We don’t have any pastures left
to graze our stock.
They cannot drink water, cannot give milk.
They are all starving to death.
We need to find a solution immediately.
I also see the despair. We sent messengers
to all beys in the region.
We asked for a territory
but famine is everywhere.
Moreover, Turkmen tribes running away
from the Mongol invasion are everywhere.
What shall we do, shall we draw our swords
against our brothers for a pasture?
Is God’s merciful treasure is closed, Bey?
We have been camping here for months.
We cannot find a solution.
When did Kayis became so desperate?
-Isn’t there anywhere for us to go?
-If we cannot find a solution...
...how can we sustain our tribe?
Since when have we forgotten God,
the Bringer of Prosperity.
Our souls are kneaded with patience.
Whatever he blesses us with,
we should be happy.
We learned what patience is by traveling
without a home, Wild Demir.
Our wish is that our descendants don’t
wonder about without a home as well...
...don’t tell us what patience is.
When did I ever leave you without clothes
or food, for you to worry so much?
Never, Bey. I did not mean like that.
Bey, you never let us go bare or hungry.
At the same time we never let you be...
...without soldiers or weapons.
Bey, we say that we should find
a new home and migrate from here.
-To where?
-Anywhere where our sheep can live.
Let us go back to our forefathers’ lands.
They say the Mongols are getting weaker.
Whoever says this is a liar! The Mongol
bandits are like hungry wolf packs.
Didn’t anyone think of a solution, Bey?
Aleppo.
I heard that  Ameer of Aleppo, El Aziz is
gathering an army against the crusaders.
What do you have in mind, my nephew?
I say that, we should send
an envoy to Ameer of Aleppo, El Aziz.
He should say, “you give us a home,
we shall give you soldiers with weapons.”
This way we can fight with the crusaders
to become veterans and at the same time...
...we could have a place we can call home.
Aleppo.
We should act at once, Bey.
Since when do we give a decision
before I say the last word?
I am sorry, Bey.
Do you accept Gundogdu’s suggestion, Agas?
-We accept.
-Yes.
I find it suitable as well.
May it be prosperous, if God permits.
-If God permits.
Who will go as the envoy, Bey?
Ertugrul!
Suleyman Shah, some tactless people in
your tribe has put a smear in our honor.
The honor of the Sultan who gave a home
to my tribe is my honor, Karatoygar.
What did we do to dishonor
Sultan Aladdin and his commander?
This axe came out of the man you killed.
-Did you forget the axe there?
-I did.
You ambushed an ambassador regiment
and slaughtered their knights.
As if that was not enough,
you kidnapped the three prisoners...
...the regiment was taking to the Sultan.
Give back those prisoners.
You talk like you don’t know
our customs, Karatoygar!
We do not hand over guests
who have come to our tribe.
Especially if they are wounded.
I came here as the representative
of the Seljuk Sultan.
You have to obey my orders as if they are
coming out of the Sultan’s mouth.
Or else, you know what would happen,
Suleyman Shah.
We live and die with our customs,
Karatoygar!
We know that the Sultan is ruling
the state but he would...
...put his forefather Oguz’s
customs first, then sit on his throne.
You cannot have a sultan from a man
who doesn’t know customs and tradition.
You cannot be a Bey or a man!
And we would not have anything to do
with someone who is not a man!
You should know this as
a commander of the Great Seljuk.
This was my last word.
You can go now.
We asked you nicely, Suleyman Shah.
You have two days.
If you don’t give them,
we know how to come and get them.
Don’t oppose the Seljuk.
You know what would happen otherwise.
-What is my father trying to do?
-He is too old to know what he is doing.
I told you that it would all be revealed
soon. This is only the beginning.
Stay here.
Seljuk Sultan Aladdin Kayqubad’s
first assistant.
Commander of Haremzshahs.
Right hand man of the Khalifa, Omar.
Now all the Muslim world shall
cry out revenge.
Then it will be the turn of the Papacy.
Bisol!
Who did this?
They ambushed the regiment
who was taking the prisoners.
I said who?
Kayis.
But we don’t know who.
Ertugrul!
You caused all this!
Don’t shout at me, brother.
When will you stop being a stubborn brat?
You don’t care for anyone.
Not your father, nor your tribe!
What would have you done?
Would you turn away and go?
The Gundogdu I know is not
that kind of a man.
The Gundogdu I know would not
step on justice or fairness.
Justice. Fairness.
What justice? What fairness?
Look at the state of this tribe!
It is cracking up!
Hunger is all around us! Winter is coming
and we don’t even know where to go!
The animals are starving to death.
Justice. Fairness. Open your eyes!
Open your eyes! Look around you!
Right in the middle of the headquarters!
Look at what you did when matters of
life or death were discussed.
How will this tribe stand strong,
Ertugrul? How?
Forgive me, father.
I could not protect him.
I could not.
The world is not left to anyone,
let alone us, Aktolgali.
What should a man live for,
in this world of lies?
What should he ride to?
What should he gird his sword for?
Why should he have a home?
Why do we have states, customs or homes?
The tyrant is going to make the sky fall
on us if we don’t give him the guests.
Wouldn’t the sky fall on us if we do?
If we don’t give them,
my father will be in trouble.
What should I do, Aktolgali?
For a world where we cannot
even command one breath...
...are we going to give up?
Are we going to submit to the tyrant?
Won’t our customs fall silent then?
Won’t our fire burn out then?
Right, Aktolgali?
Karatoygar is a big tyrant.
He would do everything in his power.
Aleppo was a good thought, Gundogdu.
You showed everyone your intelligence...
...as well as the next Bey
when the time comes.
We need to get rid of this Karatoygar
from our backs.
When my father says “customs”
he never backs down.
Ertugrul, look at the problems
you created for us.
We need to convince my father. If we
convince him, Ertugrul would back down.
You talk like you don’t know your father.
He would not give them even
if the sky fell down.
What will we do then?
Your father told me that he will
send me to Karatoygar as an envoy.
I will do anything that is required.
Ertugrul Bey.
Do you have time?
What happened? Is there a problem?
No. This is something else.
I am listening.
I heard that Karatoygar came.
He wanted us.
-Yes, he did.
-Don’t put your tribe in danger for us.
We can take care of ourselves.
My father is getting better.
We can leave within two days.
Even if all the world were against us,
we would not deliver you to those tyrants.
If you get in a fight with Karatoygar,
there would be consequences.
Don’t worry.
We Kayis know how to handle all hardships.
What’s up?
I cannot sleep, mother.
Sit down.
What do you dwell on now?
I fell into a fire, mother.
I fell right in the middle of it.
I would not mind if I got burnt alone,
but I threw the whole tribe into fire.
When you were at the point of falling,
did you know that it would come to this?
Whether you would be facing
those infidel bandits...
...or that said commander being allies
with the crusaders?
Could you have closed your eyes and
turned your back to the...
-...cries of that gazelle eyed beauty?
-How could I, mother?
You could not. You would not, my son.
You could not.
You couldn’t have known that it would
come to this when you went hunting...
...that you would be throwing
the whole tribe into fire with yourself.
You threw us in.
Yes, you did.
The fire can burn a dough
and turn it into ash...
...or it may cook the dough into bread.
It was He who took you to
that place you fell.
You don’t have the right to protest
His decision, nor does the tribe.
This is a test from the Great God.
In this test we can either turn to ash...
...or transform into bread. So don’t
listen to those whispers inside you...
...or to the presumptuous people
inside the tribe.
Become a soldier of our customs and stand
strong behind your father’s decisions.
May God never take you or
my father away from leading us.
May God protect you, my son.
Come on, take this water and
put it to your father’s side.
I brought you water, father.
Give me some.
I should have been there instead of you.
I will fight until the blood of
the ones who did this to you is dried up.
I will fight until the last one of
them is in a grave.
You will be revenged, my brother.
I promise you.
If God won’t be by my side on this path,
I will turn to devils.
I will bring hell upon the Turkmens.
I will be their wrath until the day I die.
I promise you.
Forgive me, father.
That was it, Ilyas Fakih.
I didn’t know how to interpret this dream.
But a lump of fire has been burning
inside me since last night.
There are two options, Bey.
First one is, hard times await us.
The second is...
...this may be a spiritual order on
who will be your successor.
Father?
-Are you fine? Do you have any pain?
-Do not worry.
I am awake now. I will be up in no time.
Thank God.
Get well soon.
If you need anything Yigit can inform us.
Ertugrul. Yigit told me everything.
You and the people who raised
you are valiant people.
You saved and protected us.
We did what our customs order us to do.
There is no debt for that.
The people in these lands have long
forgotten their customs.
We must be God’s loved subjects for
someone like you to be there for us.
Please don’t say that.
I should go. And you should rest.
Listen to me, Halime.
Find us some horses immediately.
Get prepared with your brother.
Don’t let anyone get suspicious.
What is happening, father?
What will we do?
We are going.
Halime, there is no other way.
If we stay for one more day,
we would endanger their lives as well.
I am going to the stable.
Right before the headquarters,
where is this coming from, Gundogdu?
I am going to look at
the new horse they brought.
And you can start preparing
for the Aleppo journey.
I can make everything ready but...
...is it confirmed that
you will be going to Aleppo?
Don’t say that.
I was the one who put forth
the idea at the headquarters.
It is my right to be the envoy.
-Of course but...
-Of course but what?
Why are you worked up
so early in the morning, Selcan?
I don’t know whether I should worry about
the fact that you will be going or...
...the disappointment you will feel
if your father does not choose you.
Of course he will send me.
Who else can he send?
Hatun, look, if you are feeling sad
that I will be going...
...during the time I go and come back,
you can greet me with two lives.
When you are dealing with the horses in
the stable and me preparing you...
...provisions for the journey, you'd be
waiting for a very long time, Gundogdu.
I can check the horses after
the headquarters then.
Bey, do we have permission?
Come in, Hamza, come in.
-What happened?
-Bey, Suleyman Shah wants to see you.
In the name of God. In the name of God.
In the name of God.
I have decided that...
...Ertugrul will go to Aleppo.
Gundogdu.
I have some things to discuss with you.
Stay here.
Ertugrul, you go and prepare yourself.
Tell Ilyas Fakih that
he will be coming with you.
Come on!
Come on! Quick!
Faster, Turgut, faster! Come on!
Come on!
-I won!
Don’t be ridiculous, I won!
I passed the line first!
-What are you saying?
-I was the first to pass the line!
Ask Aykiz!
Aykiz cannot be the referee.
She is your sweetheart.
How can you say this, Bamsi Beyrek?
When did I ever lie?
-I told you not to do that!
-What would you do if I do?
-Your brain is as big as a walnut.
-But I am a hard nut to crack!
Don’t be afraid! Come on then! Come on!
Stop right there! Stop!
What is wrong with Ertugrul?
Suleyman Shah called him to his tent.
-I wonder what the problem is.
-He is probably going gazelle hunting.
That gazelle deserved to be hunted.
Get ready. We are going to Aleppo.
Bamsi! We are going to Aleppo, Bamsi!
I was getting fat sitting all day!
Tell Ilyas Fakih as well,
he is coming with us.
I brought up the Aleppo idea.
I told you that El Aziz needed soldiers.
Why him and not me, father?
Because of this, son.
“I know. I can do. I said.”
When did arrogance grew inside you?
Am I the arrogant one?
The whole tribe is starving.
Famine is everywhere.
We could not even go on a foray.
Why?
-Because our Bey has a boil problem.
-Know your place!
Let it go, father. The whole tribe
complains about your old age.
-Brother?
-Get your hands off me!
Do you think it is your brother’s right
to be the ambassador?
Yes.
Why me and not my brother?
Because he started to worship
the flame of power. His soul is captured.
So I put out the flame.
Now, let us talk about
the flame within you.
Our guests will stay
with the tribe until you come back.
I am telling you this so that
you can focus on your mission.
Do not come back empty handed from Aleppo.
The future of Kayi is on your shoulders.
Your failure will mean
the calamity of all of us.
For the land El Aziz is going to give us,
we shall accept any price.
But not a single Oguz
is a sacrificial lamb.
Don’t you ever forget.
As much as you need a home near Aleppo...
...Ameer  of Aleppo needs Kayi’s Alps.
Do not ever bow your head down.
Show them that you are a real Oguz...
...who knows what he wants and
is ready to make a just deal.
May God help you.
I shall succeed in my duty
even if the cost is my life, father.
I shall be back to make you proud.
What happened?
Gundogdu!
-Gundogdu, stop! Stop!
-Leave me alone!
Friends, Alps!
Stop! Please!
Out! Get out!
Aren’t you going to talk?
Ambassador.
Ertugrul became the ambassador.
-I told you!
-Enough!
Take it! Drink.
Drink this.
This must be Mother Hayme’s doing.
I don’t care less. It does not matter.
I know what I am going to do.
No! Please do not act in fury.
Those who act with fury always lose.
Enough, woman!
For the love of God, enough!
Finish your business.
Be ready with your Alps.
When that tactless brother of yours
messes everything up...
...you will get what you deserve.
And do not forget.
Angels of death wait for
the big day in the Bey’s marquee.
The news got stuck in my throat, Turgut.
I cannot swallow it...
...nor can I spit it out.
You talk like this is the first time
we will be apart, Aykiz.
When did we ever be together, Turgut?
Is waiting for the road at your father’s
tent and waiting for your man...
...in your husband’s tent be the same?
It is not the sorrow of separation
that is stuck in my throat...
...it is not being able to come together.
Anytime we talk about getting married,
it gets delayed for some reason.
I promise.
There will be no delay this time.
I don’t know whether
Aleppo will be a success or not but...
...the first wedding in our new land
will be ours. I promise you.
The drummers will cry out “Aykiz and
Turgut are finally getting married.”
All the girls in the weaving area
will say, “the most beautiful girl...
...of the tribe is getting married,
from now on it be our turn.”
When you leave Wild  Demir’s tent,
even the Sultan’s daughters will...
...get jealous of your beauty.
I wanted to say how sorry I am.
I do not know the words...
...that can describe this pain.
-Only you can understand me, Elanora.
Your father’s killers were
Muslims as well.
May you have a good journey, Titus.
Be careful.
I will be back, Elanora. See you soon.
You have witnessed a good commander
transform into a real Templar knight.
Revenge.
That was the only thing lacking in Titus.
If there is no revenge, a hay soldier
and a knight are no different.
Bisol’s death became Titus’ miracle.
May God forgive Bisol’s sins.
Looking at the presents, I can say that
Suleyman Shah realized the mistake he did.
Our Bey likes the Seljuk,
he respects them.
But only I can solve this issue,
Karatoygar.
The time limit I have put down
expires in the morning, Kurdoglu.
Or else the Seljuk’s wrath will burn
the whole Kayi tribe.
-You would burn with us, Karatoygar.
-How dare you?
Don’t tell me that
the Sultan knows about this.
Your manpower is not enough
to take them from Kayi by force.
You need to raise a whole army.
I am aware that you have armies
that are strong enough to crush Kayi.
You can do that. But first,
the Sultan would have to be informed.
And this would not suit you.
It would not suit us either.
I shall come to the point. For you and
the tribe to win at the same time...
...you need to hear what I have to say.
If you aim to cooperate...
...tell me. Who did this?
Was it Suleyman Shah?
Suleyman Shah’s son Ertugrul.
Bamsi, Dogan.
The word is out about a journey.
When?
We shall set on the road to Aleppo
at the morning prayer.
Are you prepared?
The Alps are always ready for anything.
True. Everything seems easy
when you get used to it.
Sometimes it gets harder
May you have a good journey.
May the sun not burn you.
May you don’t get cold.
May your feet don’t touch a stone.
May you go like water...
...return to your tribe like water.
My horse shall fly me to
my destination and back to my tribe.
Your father and mother would be happy.
What about you?
Me?
I would be long gone.
You cannot go...
...before I come back.
Your father would not recover fully.
May you have a good journey, Ertugrul Bey.
All of us.
There is something I wonder.
Our involuntary guests...
...are they relatives of
Sultan Aladdin or something?
-That does not concern you!
-True. It does not concern me.
Come to the point. What is on your mind?
If you want to take what you want,
I shall have one small condition.
Ertugrul...
...whatever my late wife and Aykiz are...
...Halime and her family are the same
for me. Don’t you worry about them.
May God bless you, Wild  Demir.
May God bless you instead.
Trust makes a man grow.
You trusted me in this tribe,
you came to my door, you confided in me...
...that is why, may God bless you. Halime
and her family are my responsibility.
You can be rest assured.
Come on, may God be with you.
My son. My life.
My dear son...
...may your road
and fortune be always open.
The weight of Kayi is on your shoulders...
...never bow your head
nor give a promise you cannot keep.
May God give you a clear road.
You may be going and not coming back.
You may come back but not see me.
I will ride tirelessly to see you again.
May you have a clear road, Ertugrul.
While you were being punished for
rebelling against your father...
...the little Bey became the ambassador.
I knew you would come.
Welcome.
I don’t care about the prisoners,
Karatoygar.
They ran away in your territory.
We did our part.
Give me the name of the person
who killed my brother.
You are impatient to become a hangman.
Be careful, don’t let the noose of
the hangman get around you neck.
Don’t try to delegate
your own inaptitude to me.
The knights you brag about could not
deal with a few trifling Alps.
What do you want from me to give his name?
I will give you more than you want.
I will deliver him directly to you.
This is not an issue of business.
Do you understand me?
It is an assistance to a friend in pain.
We never let ourselves stay indebted
on any help we receive.
Alright.
Who?
Suleyman Shah’ son...
...Ertugrul.
Aykiz...
...can you look at these patterns as well?
I won’t be long.
When are you leaving?
When my father says so.
Do not try to stand strong.
People do not stay in a place
where they are not wanted.
If you have some sense of shame,
go at once.
It is customary.
You cannot say go to a guest.
That is why everyone keeps quiet.
And...
...will you paying your debt
to these people like this?
Is this what you deem proper for people
who gave you bread, their own tent...
...and dressed your wounds?
-I...
-You...
While you try to flirt around,
blood will be spilt in the tribe.
Blood. Go your own way.
Halime. Halime!
Selcan!
What did you tell the girl?
What she needed to hear.
Is it your duty to tell her
what she needs to hear?
I am thinking about
the future of the tribe.
That girl should have heard this long ago.
Such a shame.
Daugther of a Bey forgets our customs.
She talks on top of the words
of her forefathers.
Come to your senses, Selcan.
Otherwise, you might find yourself
under the stones you thought you crushed.
-What happened?
-Mind your own business!
Ertugrul has gone on a journey
with four Alps.
Eye for an eye. Devine justice.
-Where is he going?
-To Aleppo.
I shall take revenge with my own hands.
I can never let you do that, Titus.
Why?
These lands are my jurisdiction.
In my borders, only I can use force.
If it is heard that I made an alliance
with the crusaders to spill blood...
...our plan would fail.
This man killed my brother, Karatoygar.
I want you to bring him to me alive.
I shall take his life with my own hands.
Don’t you worry. I will present him to you
like a sacrificial ram.
Karatoygar is convinced, Bey.
He wanted us to look after them
until they get better.
Did you manage to learn who they are?
The pig’s son did not even utter
a single word about it.
If they made the great Seljuks stand up,
the issue must be serious.
Our part should be to benefit from this.
You asked for me, Bey.
If you don’t have anything else to say,
you must be very tired, go and rest.
Save me from this pest of a boil,
Akcakoca.
If God permits, Bey.
My death will be from this.
-Inform me of all developments.
-As you wish, Bey.
Everything is ready, father.
I have all the provisions ready,
we will be going tonight.
Don’t worry about your wound, I watched
Akcakoca very closely to see what he does.
Halime, calm down, my girl.
We will be running away from a place
we took refuge, as usual. That is all.
Is that all, father?
Is it only that for you?
I don’t know what goes through
your mind but...
...what makes this place
different for you?
Is there anything you are not telling me?
I am very tired, father.
I am tired of running away.
Let us start a new life.
Go some place where no one will find us.
Let us go beyond deserts and seas
but go from here, that is all I want.
Father?
What happened, son? What happened, Yigit?
We have a guest. He wants to come in.
Let him in.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Please.
Father, look. Wild  Demir made
a sword for you and my sister.
He is the best ironsmith in the region.
He makes the best swords.
Please don’t exaggerate, son.
Ours is only a pastime.
-These are yours.
-Thank you.
Don't mention it, my girl.
As Ertugrul Bey is not here,
I did not want you to be without weapons.
He would feel more comfortable.
I would do too.
Anyway, I am at my workshop
but my eye is on your tent.
If you need anything,
please do not hesitate.
What could happen in a big tribe?
Look, my girl.
Ertugrul Bey is like a son to me.
So I would never turn back his request.
This was not called for.
We will go this way.
Tell Ertugrul that horses should
rest a bit. They are exhausted.
His mind is with Halime.
He wants to return before they go.
If you have the courage, you tell him.
Bey.
Us being exhausted is not an issue
but the horses are very tired.
Bey, shall we rest a bit
beside the stream?
We can set camp down there.
We will set off before sunrise.
-Dogan, light a fire.
-As you wish, Bey.
Follow me quietly.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
What happened to the gazelle?
We found it like this. It was probably
wounded while running away from a hunter.
I think that hunter was me.
If you let this game get away,
you must be a bad hunter.
I guess so.
Look at that beautiful face. So you
managed to escape from this big valiant.
Well done to you.
In the name of God, may you recover soon.
Come on now. Go. Go on.
Where do you come from and
where do you go?
We come from nowhere, to go anywhere.
What about you?
We are going to Aleppo.
Then you should always be alert.
Don’t become a hunt for
wolves and vultures.
The air here is very hazy.
Don’t be lost in the haze.
Will you grant me your name?
Ibn Arabi from Andalusia.
The time has come.
-Horses?
-Horses are ready.
I hid the saddles under the hay.
We will saddle up and go immediately.
There is no guard at the stable.
-Will you be able to endure it, father?
-We have to do this.
May you have a good journey.
May the sun not burn you.
May you don’t get cold.
May your feet don’t touch a stone.
May you go like water...
...return to your tribe like water.
Bamsi, is he asleep?
No, he is thinking of Halime Baci.
-Keep your voice down!
-Don’t talk to me like that.
Enough! Be quiet!
Go to sleep. Be quiet.
You should relax, Titus.
Before the sunrise,
we shall both get what we want.
To look down on the enemy
is for the stupid, Karatoygar.
No one can escape from
a well planned ambush, Titus.
No one.
I will deal with Wild Demir.
You finish the job quietly.
Come on.