Episode 39 will start after 11:52 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Do we have permission, Gumustekin Bey?
Kaya, come in.
Is there any news about Tugtekin Bey?
There is not, Bey.
We scoured the earth for him
and looked everywhere...
...but could not find a trace
or his dead body.
I wanted to inform our Bey.
I shall inform our Bey.
You may leave, Kaya Alp.
What will you tell me?
Tell me, Kaya Alp.
Is there any news about my son?
Bey, we did not find Tugtekin Bey.
You could not find him
dead or alive, right?
Tell me, Kaya Alp.
Say it.
Is it befitting for my Alps to make
black earth his eternal bed...
...before he could marry his sweetheart?
Why did you return while
the earth takes in his young body...
...like rain water?
Does it suit you to abandon
my son's dead body...
...to the beaks of ravens
and to the teeth of hyenas?
Bey.
-Bey.
Move here.
Find him!
It is alright, Kaya Alp, you may leave.
Brother, where is he?
I do not want to see
the Kayi tribe anymore.
They must leave here.
They must.
After I recover from this damnation...
...if I see them here...
...I will kill them, all of them.
I want all of them to get out of here.
It is all my fault.
If I did not tell Tugtekin
where Ertugrul was...
...now...
It is not your fault, Gokce.
You did the right thing.
The judgment is on God's hands.
-We want the killer of our Bey!
-We want justice!
We want justice!
Mother!
Dodurga Alps are coming here.
They are all angry and
they have their swords.
Mother.
Korkut Bey is dying.
He cannot endure this pain.
Ertugrul did not only kill Tugtekin,
he killed Korkut Bey, too.
We want justice!
Take your swords.
If a need arises, defend yourself.
Quickly.
We want justice!
We want the killer of our Bey!
-What is this uproar, brother?
-Some people must be restless.
We want the killer of our Bey!
Father. Aunt.
Dodurga Alps are heading for
Mother Hayme's marquee.
What?
Is it those dogs' duty
to secure the justice?
Father, what we will do?
Gundogdu anticipated this and he
positioned Kayi Alps around the marquee.
Blood will be shed, father.
Everything will be ruined.
What shall we do, brother?
You cannot allow it.
We want justice!
Stop!
My brothers, stop!
My Alps! My brothers!
Do not break our brotherhood
by violating our mores.
It is time to rise up!
Unless the betrayers die...
...there is no peace for us in this tribe!
Keep out of our way, Artuk!
Fine words butter no parsnips!
It is time to punish! Move, Alps!
We want justice!
The dog which is soon to die.
We want the killer of our Bey!
We want justice!
You shall answer for it!
Mother Hayme, come here!
You shall answer for it, too.
Mother. Please, have you gone mad?
Mother. You shall not deal with
a few trifling Alps.
I shall go there and talk to them.
I have informed Alps,
they are all ready to combat.
We want justice!
Mother Hayme, come here.
We want the killer of our Bey!
Son.
My children. Do you not hear that?
They want my head.
They hold me responsible for
their Bey's death...
...as much as Ertugrul.
No more blood shall be shed. Move aside.
Mother. You cannot do such thing.
We cannot know what this crowd would do.
-We want justice!
-We want the killer of our Bey!
We want justice!
We want the killer of our Bey!
If blood will be shed, it shall be mine.
Not of any of my Alps. Move aside.
-Mother.
-Gundogdu!
-We want justice!
-We want the killer of our Bey!
My God!
My God, what have I done?
Will you make me pay for a betrayal...
...or are you after a betrayal?
Do you want justice?
Or do you want brother's blood
to soothe your pain?
How much blood will satisfy you?
Tell me.
It is obvious that you are
looking for Ertugrul...
...you think he is the killer.
If the blood of your Bey's mother
will satisfy you...
...and if none of our Alp's
blood will be shed, I am here!
My blood is halal for you.
Mother!
We came here to ask for justice.
We are after the reprisal which
mores promised, Mother Hayme.
Since one-armed Ertugrul came,
all kinds of calamity happened to us.
How many of our man are
killed because of him?
Kayi marquee has been
the home of betrayal.
That is true!
We want justice!
Treacherous dog!
We want the killer of our Bey!
We want justice!
That is enough! Enough!
Enough! Stop!
Pull yourselves together!
Will you add more pain into our pain?
Just because your Bey died
without a shroud...
...will you make gallant men
accompany him with a shroud?
How many will you kill from your brother
tribe to soothe your rage?
One? Ten or 100?
Will your hatred end then?
What is this iniquitousness?
What kind of a mores is this?
Tugtekin is my son.
He is the son of my Bey
who struggles in pain in his marquee.
I know well...
...that we and Tugtekin's brave Alps
will not turn his blood adrift.
But how can you justify
revolting against your Beys...
...without knowing anything or questioning?
Know your place or you will not
be any different...
...than the killer of Tugtekin
in our eyes.
Where is Ertugrul Bey?
I said, where is he?
He has gone to the tribe, Halime Sultan.
We could not stop him.
How did you leave him alone?
Halime, my girl, Ertugrul Bey
will do what is necessary.
Wild Demir, they are going to
execute him. Do you not know?
They would not let him live there.
That is a war, too, daughter.
Sometimes a man rides against
the army coming onto his horse...
...even if he is alone,
even if he is wounded.
Ertugrul Bey will do his duty.
We will, too.
He shall go to the tribe
and defend justice.
And we shall go to Konya.
We are going to bring about
the bequest of Ertokus.
You wanted to go to this war.
There is no turning back now.
If God permits, either victory
or martyrdom.
Come on now.
Pull yourself together.
We have a long road to Konya.
All shall put their sword down
and head for their tent.
I said put them down!
This is a headquarters' matter.
Go back!
These are empty words.
We want to take revenge of our Bey.
The doings of these traitors is enough.
Traitor!
Ertugrul.
-Traitor!
-The killer came.
-The killer!
-Traitor!
Traitor!
Killer!
Hell for all traitors!
Ertugrul!
You are a tyrant!
First, you killed my son...
...now my Alp.
Damn you!
Mother!
Mother.
-Take your positions!
-Mother!
-Mother.
-Take your positions!
-Mother!
Everyone, tread lightly!
Put your swords down!
Unsheathe your swords!
Korkut!
If something happens to my mother...
...you must know that I will pay you back.
Slowly, Bey.
Mother!
In God's name.
Mother.
You came to your tribe.
I saw you before I die.
Thank God.
I am here, mother. Do not worry about it.
I will not leave you alone after this.
Forgive me.
Mother.
-Mother.
-Mother, do not leave us alone.
Beys, allow me. Selcan Hatun, help me.
Bey, please. Ertugrul Bey, please, move.
My God, help us, please.
My God, pity on us.
My God, bless her to us.
My God pity on us.
Daughter Gokce, bring hot water.
Slowly.
Open it.
God, what have I done? What have I done?
I killed my sister.
Settle down, Bey.
While there is life, there is hope.
Do not lose hope immediately.
What happened? Could they not find my son?
Send more Alps.
They will leave no stone unturned.
Do not worry about it, Korkut Bey.
We are looking for Tugtekin everywhere.
I sent off 50 Alps to northern side.
We had finalized all preparations
to look for him at night.
It is all Ertugrul's fault.
He could not find peace.
I did not cherish my son
as much as I cherished him.
He killed our best Alp
in front of our eyes.
I shall kill him.
Bey.
You need to keep calm, Bey.
First, we need to find out
if Hayme is alive.
Otherwise everything will fall.
The arrow has left the bow.
Either we take Ertugrul in or
blood will be shed in streams.
Bey?
Bey.
Halime Sultan, do not worry about him.
Ertugrul Bey surely knows something.
Patience.
Do not worry.
We are going to go to take
Ertugrul Bey's custodial with the Alps.
What custodial?
Brother, we had many troubles
because of this custodial.
Someone shall tell me what is in this.
Do not worry, you will see
the custodial, too.
We shall take the road.
What will we do, my sheikh?
You will go to Konya right away.
Be quick.
Did you feel the smell of
Ertugrul's carrion?
I have brought you
Sadettin Kobek's greeting.
Does he want gold again?
Whenever he sends a greeting,
I pay ten thousand gold coins.
What kind of a greed is this?
Do not forget, Noyan.
If it were not for us,
you could have not even come to Erzurum.
-What does he want again?
-Nothing.
Ertugrul returned to tribe.
We found out that he killed Kocabash.
-We are going to make him answer for it.
-That is good.
We delivered you the wolf puppy in a cage.
If you cannot succeed this time...
...I will make you and your Sadettin Kobek
pay for it. You shall know it.
Kobek never forgets the kindness
and misdeed done to him.
We will see.
Kocabash.
My faithful dog.
So Ertugrul cut off your head.
My miserable dog.
Ulubilge, play.
Play so that our souls shall be washed
with the soul of mountains.
Play until the moon sees our light
and the sky shines.
Alps of Ertugrul.
When I see you always on duty like this...
...I remember Tariq Ibn Ziyad
who burned the ships.
-Do you know his story?
-We do.
If I say we do, it would be a lie.
If I say that we do not,
it would be a shame.
We heard of his name.
And that is all we know, my sheikh.
Tariq Ibn Ziyad. He was a lion-hearted,
valiant man of Islam.
He was the conqueror of Andalusia,
I was born there.
There were many brave men who conquered
the states and hometowns in history.
But his place is different.
The blue waters of Mediterranean did not
realize that a new epic will be written...
...when he took the road
to bring justice to Andalusia.
When he arrived the coast
of Andalusia with his troops...
...he confronted his troops.
He shouted out to them. Andalusia
would start a new golden age...
...under the favor of his speech.
What did this great warrior
say to bring this new age?
Soldiers who saw a lot of enemies
in front of them...
...wanted to turn back.
Then the great commander
burned down the ships.
The waters of Mediterranean
warmed with the fire of his ships.
They had no means to return
to their hometown.
So either Andalusia would be conquered
or all of them would become martyrs.
And the great commander
said to his troops...
..."the sea like an enemy is behind
and the enemy like the sea is before you.
Where can you run away?
You have no choice but to be
loyal and patient.
Either your swords will bring the enemy,
as vast as the sea, to their knees...
...or the sea will fill with your blood."
How brave he is.
Thank you.
If you burn the ships
for the sake of your cause...
...you will conquer Andalusia
and create the golden age.
If God permits, we will see those days.
These lands will live the spring
like Andalusia.
If you can manage to burn the ships,
these lands will live many golden ages.
If God permits.
My God, restore her health
for the sake of your name, Healer.
In God's name.
Ertugrul, what have you done?
What have you done?
While we are trying to save you from
the blame of Tugtekin's murder...
...how could you kill Kocabash
for all the world to see?
I did what was necessary, brother.
Shut up for God's sake, Ertugrul.
My mother is fighting for her life
because of you.
No, brother. I will not take your side
anymore. Go your own way.
How could you kill Kocabash
for all the world to see?
Brother, he was a betrayer.
If I did not kill him, peace could not be
sustained in the tribe.
Do we have peace in the tribe now?
Do we?
Look at my mother.
There will be a bloodbath.
We have not found
Tugtekin’s body yet.
Tugtekin is alive, brother.
Is he alive?
Where is he?
He is in safe hands.
God!
Was he not dead, brothers?
Thank you, God.
I never thought I would be so happy
to see this tactless person alive.
Neither did I, brother.
Dervish, how is he?
My sheikh, we should carry him
somewhere safer.
Efendi, how did you find him?
Tugtekin.
Thank God, your heart says
that you are still alive.
Hang on, brother.
When Khidr is your companion, son,
fortune is always on your side.
For the sake of your name, Healer.
For the sake of the miracles
you bestowed upon Prophet Jesus.
Bestow them upon this gallant man.
Revive him.
Tugtekin.
Alhamdulillah.
We should hide him somewhere.
Alps, we should carry him right away.
Ertugrul Bey's salvation depends on
this young man's survival.
Hurry.
Then we must help Tugtekin heal and
bring him to the tribe immediately.
If God permits, he will get better.
What will we do if he does not?
We should wait until our mother recovers.
Brother.
Our uncle does not want
the two tribes to stay together anymore.
Always be on guard.
I showed mercy to Ertugrul.
I believed in him.
I trusted him.
I valued him more than my son.
But what did he do?
He killed my son.
He killed Kocabash,
who I trained with my own hands.
This is not your fault, Bey.
It makes no difference.
It is over now.
Everything is over.
Korkut Bey, if you give in...
...a fight between the two tribes
will be inevitable.
We shall stand upright and
solve this matter with our minds.
I do not want any more bloodshed
until Ertugrul is punished...
...and the Kayis leave my tribe.
There is only one person’s
blood to be shed.
And that is Ertugrul's blood,
after the council meeting.
Go...
...and stop the fight
between the two tribes.
Talk to Gundogdu.
They will leave my tribe...
...after the council meeting, tomorrow.
Sow the wind and reap the whirlwind.
You shall be calm first.
After all, nothing will be concluded
before you give the final word.
What did I do to my sister...
...with my own hands?
If she dies...
...how will I live with this sin?
Do not worry, Bey.
I will take care of Hayme myself.
You need to rest.
You try to calm Kayis down
and I will soothe our Alps' rage.
If we cannot compose both tribes...
...your margrave position
will only be a dream, brother.
If we cannot solve this matter, Aytolun...
...we should not become Beys,
nor hold our swords.
Give us Ertugrul.
We want justice!
Give us Ertugrul!
Give us the killer.
We want justice!
They swarm like flies that wade in dirt.
Go and wade in the dirt
in your marquee.
Sister! Neither Aytolun Hatun
nor Korkut Bey...
...or Tugtekin are involved
in any of these things.
It was an accident.
If you do not believe that...
...how can we make
the two tribes believe it?
Do you want rivers of blood to flow
from the two tribes' Alps?
Do not fan the flame.
Sister, you changed sides quickly.
While the woman who raised you
is on the brink of death...
...you stand before me and defend
that whore and her husband.
You do not know what you are saying.
Your hatred makes you blind.
Gokce!
If you did not inform Tugtekin
of where Ertugrul was...
...none of this would have happened.
Now, shut up!
Is that true?
Did you eavesdrop and
tip that sweetheart of yours?
I just wanted justice to be served.
I wanted Ertugrul Bey to come
out of the council meeting honourably...
...and prove his innocence.
My only aim was to stop the two tribes
from falling out with each other.
Gokce, the two tribes are
falling out with each other now!
You ruined it all.
Do you think so, Ertugrul Bey?
Your wife has caused us
a lot of trouble.
Many of our Alps were martyred.
We have had many troubles
because of your wife.
What are you talking about?
You are as foolish as Tugtekin.
You found each other well!
Is there any justice left in all this
filth to be given to Ertugrul Bey?
Artuk Bey, how is my mother?
Let us pray for her to live.
But be ready for everything.
Know your place, Gokce!
I will kill you even
though you are my sister!
We want the killer.
We want justice.
Give us Ertugrul.
Inform them that I am here.
I wish to see Mother Hayme.
We want justice. Give him to us.
Aytolun Hatun is here.
She wishes to see Mother Hayme.
I will talk to her.
We want justice.
Do you finally have what you wanted?
We shall not bring more trouble when there
is already so many, Selcan Hatun.
I worry about Mother Hayme.
I wish to see her.
If I do not want you to,
you cannot see my mother.
What is your problem?
Who do you think you are?
I am...
I am the daughter of Suleyman Shah.
What about you, Aytolun? Which
barrel bottom did they scrape you from?
Watch your mouth, Selcan!
Do not say anything
you might regret later.
All your games are finished,
are they not?
Many things you did not expect
have happened.
And you stand aghast.
Now, you are thinking
of how to solve it, right?
But that does not cut any slack with me.
You do not know what you are saying.
But allow me to say that
you are a well-versed woman.
You trained her well.
Since she cut herself free from her leash
and tipped Ertugrul to you!
Sister, what are you saying?
Shut up!
Aytolun, I know more than you think.
I know that you ordered
the murder of that old woman.
That you got into my uncle's bed
like a serpent...
...even before my aunt, Duru, died.
-That is enough!
-It is not!
There is more, yet I am waiting
for the right time.
One of us, you or me...
...will leave this tribe
before the winter ends.
Then you should be careful, Hatun.
Your soul may leave your body
while you are leaving, too.
Why did you come back to the tribe, Bey?
Why did you put your life in danger?
If my life were more important
than our cause...
...none of this would have happened,
Artuk Bey.
We would have either
fallen prey to wolves or ravens...
...or become an appetizer
on a tyrant's table.
Bey, we know that you are innocent.
But how will all these angry people know?
There was one person who could testify
to your innocence but...
I came here so the two tribes
would not fall out with each other.
And about Tugtekin...
...my Alps are with him.
He is fighting for his life
in Geyikli's cave.
Ibn Arabi is taking care of him,
as well as Geyikli.
But Tugtekin needs you.
To tell the truth,
you came just in time, Bey.
We shall bring Tugtekin to the tribe
as soon as possible.
In order to make the Dodurga tribe
believe in your innocence,
Tugtekin shall not come to the tribe...
...before he recovers and tells about
Kocabash's betrayal.
I do not know how far the arms
of betrayal reach in the tribe.
That is why, Artuk Bey,
if my mother is alright...
...you should go to Tugtekin right away.
I did what I could do, Bey.
The rest is the will of God.
The whole incident is here.
But you need to extend the time until
the council meeting, as much as you can.
So I can do all I can.
May God help you, Bey.
We will live by our fate.
Neither more nor less.
But the fire of instigation
in the tribe must die out.
Thank you, Bey.
Talk.
Halime Sultan and Wild Demir,
mentors of Ertugrul...
...set off to Konya.
How did you learn this?
Tangut, what are you hiding from me?
One of our warriors who spies on
the tribe said that...
...he saw them leaving together.
How do you know that
they are going to Konya?
From the intelligence information
of Ertokus we were after.
-The ones Sungurtekin sent?
-Yes.
Ertugrul has them. I can feel it.
He will send him and
his wife to Sultan Aleaddin.
Go after them, right away.
The ones Sungurtekin sent.
If my predictions are true...
...all the information about
the Mongol army should be there.
Aleaddin should not read those papers.
First obtain the paper...
...then kill them both.
Wait!
Tell Shaman to prepare my most
valuable, most brave warriors...
...who are eager to die tonight.
I will keep my promise to Ertugrul.
Before his life...
...I will take everything in his heart,
everything he values...
...what he treasures most...
...his tribe, his honour...
...from his hands.
You heard Noyan.
Make all the preparations;
prepare all the men.
Artuk Bey.
They said you were leaving.
Where are you going when
the tribe is in such a condition?
I take care of the Beys of
both tribes, Aytolun Hatun.
My duty is hard.
I must look for God's cure in herbs
for their treatment.
That restorative...
Does our Bey still take it?
He does not.
We risked being without a child
so our Bey could live, Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Aytolun Hatun.
Living in a marquee comes with a price.
When the time comes,
that price shall be paid.
That is what we are paying, Artuk Bey.
Even though our bed is cold...
...our hearts can pay this price
so that our tribe's unity and amity...
...can always be strong.
Thank God we have astute Hatuns
and Beys like you in our tribe!
Thank you.
May God keep your path bright.
The water is ready, my sheikh.
Geyikli of Bayirbucak Turkmens.
Your shelter changed the fate of people.
You are brave like all
Bayirbucak Turkmens.
You are courageous.
May God bless you in both worlds.
May He render your fight everlasting.
Amen.
-May God bless you, my sheikh.
-Thank you.
In God's name.
Mother.
My children.
My dears.
Always...
...be together.
Take care of Ertugrul...
...and the tribe.
The seigniory is yours, son.
Mother.
That knife had to pierce me.
It had to go into my flesh.
No, brother. Rest assured.
None of us are guilty in this matter.
As my mother said...
...you shall be Bey, brother.
There is no time to lose.
Demand a council meeting
and take the seigniory.
I will stand behind you until I die.
With God's help.
I have no doubt of it, brother.
My mother knows what I think.
You are right. My mother is right, too.
It is time to request a council meeting
and take the seigniory.
But...
But?
But I fear you, brother.
I said I will stand by you
until I die, brother.
-Why do you fear me?
-Agreed. I have no doubt of that.
I know that you do not want to be Bey.
But when I make a wrong decision
by your standards, what will you do?
I remember the day you brought
Halime and his father to the tribe.
I remember how you acted against my dad
to not give them over to Karatoygar.
The matter of the Templars, too.
You acted against me, my mother,
the council and the tribe...
...not just my father.
You are a headstrong,
tactless person, Ertugrul.
But a tactless person who turns out
to be right, most of the time.
God knows that you drove us
to the cliff's edge many times.
You did but you also saved us
with your own hands. As you do now.
I am trying to say that if we
face each other one day...
...I am not the late Suleyman Shah,
I cannot put you in your place.
And you are not a child.
I cannot beat you.
Tell me, brother.
If I make a wrong decision one day...
...will you stand by me uprightly?
Good luck with your seigniory, brother.
Your brother would die for you.
There is no news from Hayme's marquee.
People are grumbling outside, waiting.
What will we do?
If there is no news,
it means that she is alive.
While she is alive,
we should get a move on.
How?
First, we will take Ertugrul,
who is the killer.
If Hayme Hatun dies...
...it means that Korkut Bey
is a killer, too.
We will talk about this later.
If we take Ertugrul...
...we can calm down
Sadettin Kobek's rage.
You need to persuade Gundogdu.
My favorite thing is bargaining, Aytolun.
You will help me.
If he dies...
...we need to find another way.
Then our Bey will be ruined.
-Artuk Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-How is he?
-He needs a healer.
In God's name.
He lost a lot of blood.
It is a miracle that he is still alive.
Do not give in, Bey, fight.
Fight so the tribe can stay united.
-Everyone has a different expertise.
-Right, my sheikh.
Beys, things are complicated
in the marquee.
Ertugrul killed Kocabash.
Allahuakhbar.
Finally, the traitor died.
But Korkut Bey stabbed Hayme Hatun.
What are you saying, Bey?
What?
How is Mother Hayme, Artuk Bey?
She needs prayers.
If we cannot save Tugtekin...
...the sky will fall on our tribe.
Then our Bey will crane
his neck to the rope.
The Kayi and the Dodurga tribes
will be destroyed.
What saves a man from
death is his fate.
Do not be sorry, brave ones.
Now, leave me alone with Tugtekin.
Efendi, if you stay, you can help me.
All right.
-If Tugtekin dies...
-Ertugrul Bey will die.
Bamsi is right.
I can never imagine that
Ertugrul Bey's fate...
...would depend on
this ambitious dog's fate.
I will not leave my Bey's fate
in anyone's hands, brother.
We will not. Sit down, Bamsi.
What will we do if we do not?
If the decision is his execution...
which it will be...
we will kidnap Ertugrul Bey
and go to the mountains.
While we fight the Mongols on one hand...
...we will not hesitate
to fight with the Seljuk...
...whom we would have died for,
on the other.
Do we have permission, Gundogdu Bey?
Come in, Dumrul.
Gumustekin Bey is here,
in front of the marquee.
He wants to talk to you.
Traitor!
Come out, Ertugrul!
We want justice!
Murderer!
Traitor!
We want Ertugrul!
Gundogdu Bey.
I know how brave you are.
More than that I know
what a cautious Bey you are.
Please be prudent.
Be prudent so that
the two brothers can control the tribe.
Now...
...give me Ertugrul for headquarters.
Gumustekin Bey.
You are a Bey who is one of us...
...and you know palace customs
and politics.
We put our trust in you.
However, I will not give my brother
to you anyway.
Neither my Alps nor people would believe
that justice will be served...
...as long as Ertugrul Bey stays
in her mother's marquee.
You are a clever man, Gundogdu Bey.
You must understand me.
You must know that I want to solve
this without any harm as you do.
However, as long as Ertugrul
does not surrender...
...it is not possible for me
to hold my Alps.
Do not let another fire begin.
My brother Ertugrul has returned
to tribe by himself...
...so headquarters would make
a decision about him.
Let him stay in his mother's
marquee until then.
A man who wants to run away would not
come back to the tribe.
As long as Ertugrul stays in that
marquee, I cannot handle my Alps.
They are so furious.
How will you handle so many Alps
when I give him to you...
...while you cannot handle them...
...even if Ertugrul was in
her mother's marquee, Bey?
No, Bey. Do not request this from me.
Can you not see?
They all have blood in their eyes.
I will talk about it with my Beys.
You also know that it is not a thing
between the two tribes.
We are talking about the Seljuk Empire.
If Sultan Aleaddin heard about this...
...he would have ridden here
to see Ertugrul quickly.
Everybody knows how you have a strong
liking for him because of his reputation.
It is the reason of what happens to us.
Things that Sultan Aleaddin did not know
are not capital city's matters.
That is why you talk with your Beys.
Of course, we could find a common ground
that would satisfy everyone.
As long as we do not involve
dirty intents.
Nobody can take my brother Ertugrul
from marquee...
...that was given by Suleyman Shah...
...before headquarters
make a decision about him.
I have nothing else to say, Bey.
My Alps!
Great warriors of Dodurga!
Our Bey, Korkut Bey does not want to
add more pain to his pain.
He wants everyone to trust justice...
...and obey the verdict
that mores will decide.
He says that there will be no blood,
no matter what.
Hold your sword in its sheath
and your rage inside of you.
If one acts otherwise, one must know...
...that I would put his head
in front of the Kayi marquee...
...and his body in front of Korkut Bey's
marquee, to make an example.
What does Gumustekin say, brother?
He wants you.
I say, I should surrender.
If I surrender, Dodurgas would calm down.
You are right. I am just taking measures.
Most of our Alps have either became
martyrs or betrayed us.
We should keep a handful of Alps
that are left, on alert.
Welcome, Karabek.
-Greetings, Gumustekin.
-What is it?
Sadettin Kobek wanted to make sure
that Ertugrul's head is being cut off.
He sent me because of that.
Let's go inside.
Our pain is great.
You and your brother is fighting...
...while you put your head in the lion's
mouth to solve this matter.
You must know that, Bey...
...outside of the tribe
is boiling just like inside.
The traitor is dead, Yenge.
Traitors die, however betrayal
stays alive inside of us.
While my almighty God deems Oghuzs
worthy of bravery and beauty...
...he keeps betrayal alive inside of us
so we see and know its worth.
It is not my uncle who made
my mother like this.
Even it was my uncle's hand
which threw you that cursed knife...
...hand who had him thrown...
...stays in her marquee and
making the way of betrayal.
Who are you talking about, Yenge?
Aytolun.
She imbues Tugtekin against you
and Gokce against me.
The love Tugtekin has for my sister
and weakness Gokce has for you.
She wants to use it against you.
Do you think I do not know, Bey?
I do know it.
Not only me but also Halime Sultan
and Gundogdu Bey know it as well.
Also my mother.
She knows but she still can't accept it.
I also know it, Yenge...
...but I do not know why she is doing it.
It is your job to find that out, Bey.
You should be careful about
her brother Gumustekin...
...and Gumustekin's daughter Goncagul.
If anything happens to me, you must know
that Aytolun is to blame.
Is it connected with the things
between you and my brother, Yenge?
He does not want me anymore.
Who knows?
Maybe he wants another woman.
Maybe he wants babies.
I cannot be mad at him, Bey.
I am a useless woman
who is as dry as a desert.
Yenge.
Thankfully our tribe will become
cheerful with your baby's cries soon.
You do not worry.
Wild Demir would protect
your escrow to the death.
If God permits, they shall go and
come back in a short time.
If God permits.
Come on, my girl.
Come on.
Listen, my girl. He survived the traps
that were set against our religion...
...and the ones like in the palace of
El Aziz and the castle of the Templars.
He will survive this one, too.
May you be at ease.
All this time I have learned from
Ertugrul Bey that I should not fear...
...the enemy that eye sees, Wild Demir.
I fear the poisoned air
that covers our tribe...
...which we eat, drink and stay in peace.
I seek refuge in God from enormity of
the djinns and people who are mistrustful.
My God, may you protect us from djinns...
...and enormity of those who whisper
evil things to people's ears.
Let's go. Duty awaits us.
Sure, my girl. Let's go.
In brief, what I want to say is...
...we will wait until headquarters
debauchery is finished.
That would be fine, if the miracle
we are waiting for happens until then.
What if not? What if there would be
so much blood, Bey?
We do not defend the head of our Alps,
who is my brother Ertugrul...
...but we defend the justice.
If we give up advocating for justice...
...we would not have anything left
to fight for.
-Alright.
Bey.
I have something to say if you allow me.
What is it, Goncagul Hatun?
-May it be easy.
-Thank you.
-You go. I will come soon.
-Okay.
You know since the beginning I had
no doubts that Ertugrul is innocent.
I have told you.
However there is one other thing
that I want you to know, Bey.
What is it?
My father thinks the same
but not because of his duty.
You and your brother's job...
...is to find a middle way to prevent the
two tribes shedding blood.
This will not be so easy.
This will be harder now.
What do you mean?
Sadettin Kobek has sent
his ambassador Karabek...
...to monitor Ertugrul situation
more closely.
He is a dangerous man like a snake, Bey.
You must know that verdict
has already been reached.
My father should not be stuck
between you and Kobek, Bey.
Do not put my father and yourself
in a tight spot, okay?
They would probably want to take
revenge...
...for Ertokus and his soldiers
who were all dead.
They will surely ask for
Ertugrul Bey's head, Bey.
Make my father's work easy
so justice would be served properly.
Thank you.
Dumrul.
What is the rush?
We all want Ertugrul to die.
However not tomorrow.
-Even tomorrow is too late.
-Why?
Tell me something that I can understand.
Do you not see
how his Alps are royal to him?
He is so powerful that he can make
his Alps attack Dodurga Alps...
...with one command. Even attack Konya.
That is exactly why.
One who has influence on these mountains
more than Sadettin Kobek...
...one's tongue is chopped off.
It is effective for everyone.
Even for you.
Gundogdu Bey is here and wants to see you.
It seems that coming here
was a wise decision on my part.
Tell him to come in.
Ertugrul will enter the cage tent.
Gumustekin Bey. You will take
Dodurga Alps down the valley.
And I will take Kayi Alps
down the stream.
There will only be guarding
Alps in the square.
They will be responsible for
the security of the two marquees...
...the tribe and the cage tent.
I thought you were more reasonable
than your brother, Gundogdu.
How dare you come here
and tell us what to do?
We are trying to take Ertugrul
to Sadettin Kobek's headquarters.
If you have doubts about our goodwill...
...and want to show us our place,
you need to come here with more men.
Who will be the guard for cage tent?
Alps from both tribes
will be on guard.
Kayi Alps will be around the tent...
...and Dodurga Alps will be around them.
Nobody will enter inside without
the permission from me and Ertugrul.
You must know that if anyone
enters or tries to enter...
...I would show no mercy.
Alright.
Headquarters will gather here,
Korkut Bey's marquee tomorrow morning.
Commander Karabek will also attend
on behalf of Sadettin Kobek...
...and the soldiers who have been killed.
Our state is most welcome.
We also rely on its justice.
However whether we will rely on
Sadettin Kobek or not...
...will become apparent after
tomorrow's headquarters.
May God not let anyone
choose the wrong path of justice.
Amen. I hope so.
This will end tomorrow.
Alps from both tribes will be on guard
in front of the cage tent.
Nobody will enter without
your and my permission.
If one enters,
he shall be killed right on the spot.
Thank you.
You take care of my mother
and our tribe, brother.
I promised mother...
...that I had to take our brother
Sungurtekin to her.
How will it be?
They will let you know...
...if anything happens to me.
Take him to his tribe.
He has been serving our state
in the nest of evil for long years.
Ertugrul Bey. Where are you going?
-It is time, Yenge.
-Bey, they would not let you alive.
While my brother is with me...
...I fear no one but God, Yenge.
-Give me your blessing, Yenge.
-You have my blessing.
Traitor!
Justice will be served!
Kill Ertugrul!
Murderer!
Traitor!
Justice will be served!
Kill him!
Protect him or this would be
the end of everything.
Kill him!
Traitor! Pay for it!
You will be punished!
Listen to me!
Ertugrul Bey has come to the tribe
with his own free will...
...in order to prove his innocence!
Now, with his own free will again,
he will go to the cage tent!
Whoever crosses the line
will taste my sword!
Bismillah.
Alps!
Halime Sultan and Wild Demir
passed from here.
There is an inn on this road.
They will stay there for the night.
Come on, let's go.
May you live long, Ertugrul Bey!
We will not let them touch you!
Murderer.
We have risked our lives for you.
We have fought like lions
behind you in every war.
And what have you done?
You have killed my brother.
We do not want an Alp like you.
-Murderer.
-Onur Alp.
Control your anger.
-Headquarters will punish him, not you.
-Dog does not eat dog.
We know that there
will not be a decree against him...
...in Beys headquarters.
-Do not talk nonsense.
I would cut your tongue. Alps. Take him.
May you live long, Ertugrul Bey!
If anything happens to my mother, I would
make the sky fall on them, brother.
If God permits, nothing will happen.
If God permits,
Tugtekin will come back to the tribe.
If God permits.
There is God so there is no problem,
Ertugrul Bey.
My God who saved me from such troubles...
...have mercy...
...so my mother will stay alive.
So my uncle's son Tugtekin will return
to his tribe alive.
Bey. Karabek is here.
He wants to see you.
Let him come in.
-We have met again, Ertugrul.
-You!
I want you to see the truth
and join us, Ertugrul.
Sadettin Kobek sends his regards.
He also appreciates your great services.
-However...
-However what?
Now he wants me...
...to take your head to palace.
He said to take revenge of
brave Ertokus and our soldiers.
If traitors were able to walk
from Sadettin Kobek's table...
...to Noyan's table then to my uncle's
marquee freely and grinningly...
...so it means that our swords
will not be rusted in their sheath.
Traitor?
You have said a suitable word
for a goatherd like you.
Traitor?
Everything is done for the best
interests of our state, Ertugrul.
And will you be able to hold a sword
with that cripple hand of yours?
Or do you think that your body will still
carry your head after headquarters?
So your death is here, too.
We will see whose death is
here in headquarters, Ertugrul.
Make it easy.
We all want to believe that
Ertugrul Bey is innocent, Gokce.
Korkut Bey also wants to believe
this even he is in a lot of pain.
He is praying for this.
He does not have a clear conscience
about it, Gokce.
You must know that these are good things.
If God allows, all of these will be
left behind. Listen to my words.
But do not punish yourself anymore.
My mother, my brothers...
...and my sister turns their back on me.
They do not want me because I sent
Tugtekin Bey after Ertugrul Bey.
I do not have anyone else except you.
A new world order is being built,
Gumustekin.
You would want to go to war
against infidels...
...and be a part of the expansion
of our state as margrave.
Byzantium border is
really convenient for a holy war.
You want this and we have
big respect for it.
Our mores and religion
also want this, Karabek.
However we would have such times...
...that you would even have to go to bed
with the devil to get what you want.
Who is the devil?
For Kayra Khan who is wandering
in the super kingdom!
-Fear!
-Kayra Khan!
For Erlik Khan and his sons and
daughters in the subkingdom.
-Khan!
-Erlik Khan!
For the love of Muunchih and Musmal!
Akkam and Karakam.
Totem. Oge.
Death!
Muunchih, Musmal.
For the blessed
generation of Chengiz Khan...
...my brave warriors who deal
with death with pleasure.
May you be a nightmare to Kayis.
May you descend over them like death.
For the love of Muunchih and Musmal
For the love of Tengri Ulgen
Be prepared like we may go to Konya
in any minute.
You do not think about me.
I accept death or life since
I am on same path with you.
I have seen such brave ones
but have not seen a person like you
who is carrying two lives and still
fighting with evil, Halime Sultan.
May God clear your path.
Do not talk if you want to stay alive.
Come with me.
We have everything that Sungurtekin
spent his life
in order to take these
from Mongols, Wild Demir.
Sultan Aleaddin will see both inside
and outside of the enemy with these.
I cannot live with this embarrassment
if anything happens to state
of my ancestor's Seljuk
and to the things that Ertugrul's brother
had captured from Mongols
after such torment.
Do you have anything in your mind,
Halime Sultan?
I do.
I need a paper.
And some ink. Right away.
Sadettin Kobek is certain about offender
and the verdict of the execution.
This will be over right after headquarters
tomorrow morning.
We will not waste any time. Right away.
We must stop Alps of two nomad groups
fighting each other.
He has killed my son!
We may have bloods of others like
my son on our roof!
Let us have!
If it is for justice, we all sacrifice
our blood for justice!
Where did you learn medicine?
In Samarkand.
You came from madrasa then?
I have learned both medicine
and rhetoric in the madrasas
that Great Khan Tugrul Bey opened.
How did you become nomad?
I have become nomad and hit the road
so I can help poor.
There are a lot of physicians in the city.
Nomad people need help.
I have hit the road from
region to region with them.
Lucky you.
Who is your master on medicine?
Ibn Sina is my master on medicine.
And Imam Maturidi on Rhetoric.
That Great Imam from Turkistan.
He has brought great things
to our knowledge.
Those who benefit from it do not see it.
And as long as Islam World
do not recognize him
they cannot get rid of troubles.
Alright.
If God permits one day
we have a conversation
and talk about Imam Maturidi.
If God permits. Sure. Sure.
His soul is leaving.
My God!