Episode 61 will start after 13:53 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
Mother?
What have you done, son?
How can you leave us?
Leaving your father's marquee, his
nomad tent...
How can you go?
I will take the blessed road bestowed
upon the Oghuz, mother.
Your father's marquee... How can it bear
this separation?
You should know that I beatify my
father's soul.
Neither I nor the gallants who
accompany me
have any hesitations or grief.
If this is what makes your heart grieve
do not forget that Suleyman Shah's son
Ertugrul is on right path.
When I brought Halime to
the nomad tent
and I told you that I had fallen
in love with her
you told me that I'd thrown the whole
marquee into fire.
And then I said...
..."You throw the marquee into fire.
Some fire burns loaf.
Some fire cooks loaf."
She showed you where to jump into fire.
It is neither your nor the tribe's
business to rebel on it.
I said this is a trial of God.
This is a trial like every love, Mother.
As you say, I will either become a burnt
loaf or a well-cooked one.
To be blessed by the oppressed and
continue on the right path,
me and my Alps take the chance of
burning, Mother.
Our wish is to cook on this right path,
if God lets me.
That's why I'll set off, Mother.
I'm here to ask for your blessing.
How will my heart bear this?
My life is yours, but how can I tell you
to go?
I gave you my blessing the day
you were born.
Surely it is all yours.
How do I grow old in your father's
marquee, apart from you?
Do not go, my son. Do not take
my heart and leave.
You can come with us, Mother.
That way Halime, Gunduz, and Dundar
will not be alone.
How can I leave Sungur...
...Gundogdu, and Sevcan alone?
I could never leave your father's
marquee.
I could not do this.
Do not ask this of me.
You should know that your heart will
always be with me, Mother.
Every step I take, every war I fight,
your heart will give me strength.
Whenever I am in difficulty, I will find
consolation in your heart.
You should know that, my heart and my
prayers will always be with you.
Give me your blessings, Mother.
I give you my blessing.
It is all yours, my son.
Praise be, brother.
Praise be.
-Peace be upon you, brothers.
-And peace be upon you.
We are ready to go with Ertugrul Bey,
Dogan Alp.
Thank you, brothers. May God be with
us.
Amen.
Our wives and our sisters are biding
farewell to the women in the workshop.
We will go after we get Mother Hayme's
blessings, brothers.
-We will meet in front of the marquee.
-Thank you!
Most of the Alps who promised to come
did not show up.
What shall we do? Did we not say that
if need be we will go alone?
Yes, we said that, but all of the labor
and effort, was it all in vain?
No, brother, nothing is in vain.
God will give the reward of our efforts.
The patience is a blessing and healing.
We did all we can do. Time is the time
to trust, brother.
Samsa and Kaya Alp brothers came to
say goodbye to us.
We did not come to say goodbye,
Bamsi Brother.
We are going with you, brothers.
Brothers, how can Dodurga people
come with us?
What does it matter if we keep the same
path?
Don't we all come from the same Oghuz
family?
Our decision is final, brother. We'll go
wherever Ertugrul Bey is going.
Long live brothers!
Praise be, brothers. No one can stand
against us anymore.
Praise be brothers.
Praise be.
Praise be, brothers.
Are you stupid enough to be tempted by
them and perish?
What good is this punishment against
the shroud?
What are you saying, brother?
Since Tugtekin Bey died, we have
no place in this nomad tent.
Ertugrul Bey is our Bey from now on.
You are talking through your hat.
Many weak armies managed to defeat
larger armies in the past.
All mouth and no trousers when it comes
to customs.
Can anyone leaving their nomad tent be
pardoned according to our customs?
-What are you saying? Know your place!
-Brother, stop!
Let me, smash his face.
You insist on going your way!
There is no brave men would go
freely from this nomad tent.
Brothers, come to your senses!
What are you doing?
Do not use your weapons!
Get out of here, do not cause us
any trouble.
You'll soon see what trouble is.
Hatuns, where are the other ladies?
Are they about to finish their tasks?
That's all of us, Halime Sultan.
Most of the women gave up.
Did they give up? Why have they
given up?
Their husbands became rich with the
gold Gundogdu Bey gave them.
Very few people are left, Halime Sultan.
We'll not give up on our dreams even if
there are a thousand people or just one.
You should know that those who
exchange their vows to gold
will never be triumph.
Now, we will walk tall from this nomad
tent and set off for our future.
You will fall prey to the enemies in the
field of the heretics.
I know and I see everything, but I
can't do anything.
I am really upset because I'm helpless.
I could not persuade Gundogdu Bey.
Neither Ertugrul Bey, nor you.
Don't be sad, Selcan.
Our hope will manage to overcome
the heretics and any other trouble.
I believe that we will succeed.
What good it is to be successful?
As long as we are separated from
each other's shadows
what would I do with peace, Halime?
Do not speak like that, Selcan.
Which distance can separate us from
each other?
Our paths are separated, but our hearts
will always be together.
I knitted this for Gunduz.
This way his feet won't be cold.
God be with you, sister.
My God keep you safe from any kind
of trouble.
It will be good for both nomad tents when
Ertugrul leaves. Finally we'll find peace.
It is true that when Ertugrul goes
we will get rid of a big trouble.
The hell with him!
However, I will not let any of the Alps
to go with him.
It is the Kayi tribe's matter, Bey. How
are you going to get involved?
Ameer Sadettin agrees with me.
More importantly, the tribe who cannot
control its Alps would lose face.
I will not let this happen.
How will you do it, Bey?
As you ordered, 10 of our Alps are ready
to go with Ertugrul Bey.
Do you understand how I will
intervene now?
Kaya and Samsa actually want to
join, Ertugrul Bey.
They were the only ones left from
Tugtekin.
We will settle their account soon
enough.
Start as soon as possible.
Alps must step into action right away.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
We shall clip Ertugrul's wings.
-Permission, Bey?
-Come in, Dogan Alp.
The immigration community is ready.
The late Tugtekin Bey's Alps Samsa
and Kaya will come with us.
After that 10 Dodurga Alps will join us.
But most of the Alps did not show up
to the training place
because of the gold Gundogdu Bey
gave them.
Then we need to be more cautious
on our way.
Are you expecting trouble from
Ameer Sadettin?
I'm sure he'll plan for an attack as soon
as he hears that we're on our way.
You are right, Bey.
We must be cautious until we get there.
As we come closer to the border of
Byzantium, not only Kobek,
but also our coward enemies will try
to attack us.
The Crusaders, and Byzantine soldiers...
Mercenaries from different tribes.
Bandits. We are weak in number.
Your presence and your wisdom will give
us strength, Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Bey.
We cannot use the way that we used
with the Alps before.
We will prefer a longer, but a safer way.
We will cross the Kose Mountains
and the Tecer Mountains
and then we'll cross Kizilirmak.
And we will reach the border across
from Enguri.
I won't be worrying about my men while
I'm fighting, thanks to you, Artuk Bey.
You should know that while dealing with
these enemies
I will entrust my marquee, my son
and Halime Sultan to you.
I will be worthy of the task, Bey.
I appointed Dogan Alp for the safety
of the power caravan.
Samsa, Bamsi Alp and Kaya will be
the vanguard pacify the road.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
We won't give way to the enemy.
With God's help.
Upon reaching our destination, we
should know how to train ourselves
just like our enemies.
We must establish good relations with
Muslims and non-Muslims for trade.
Therefore, we should know how to keep
our doors open to those
who can empower our mind with their
knowledge and our spirit with their art.
We need to build a new sewing
workshop.
Our seeds will not hold root if we are
short of any of these.
It might break in the gentlest of winds.
Keep that in mind.
When you are talking, I see
Oghuz Khan's, Bilge Khan's
and even Sultan Alparslan's fire
in your eyes.
May God keep you and the Kayis
become successful.
Amen.
Bey, I would like to come with you.
I have entrusted my mother to you,
Abdurrahman.
Yes, Bey, but I...
Do not leave my mother alone,
Abdurrahman.
I can die for, Mother Hayme if need be.
God speed.
-Give me your blessings, Bey.
-I give you my blessings.
The time has come, Wild Demir.
It's high time we rebel against cruelty.
We've came to this land with hope, Bey.
We wanted to find joy and liven, but
each day we went through different hell.
If I can't make them pay for what
they've done to us
I can no longer live as an honorable
man.
What are you thinking, Bey?
I spent half my life with the Mongols
for my state.
I had one consolation: To be able to
go back to our own marquee.
I wanted to go back to my mother
and my brothers.
I came back, but now a new kind of
separation looms our marquee.
We have lived for our tribe and
our honor.
We have fought, we have killed,
we have lost lives, too.
The survival of our state has always
been the most important thing.
But our love for our state never
disabled us.
Whatever I did, I did it for the sake
of our state, Ertugrul.
I did it for our tribe, not for
Ameer Sadettin.
You treated me the way Yusuf's brothers
treated Yusuf, brother.
You become a tool to Kobek's games.
You threw me into the well.
I have no words to say.
I no longer have hope in my heart.
Everyone will go their own way.
If I tell you not to go
I know that you will not listen to me
and go anyway.
However, I cannot let you go with my
men, as the head of the Alps.
Our fate together ends here, brother.
Give your blessing to me and to my Alps.
Do you not hear what I'm telling you,
Ertugrul?
I will not let you take my Alps and leave.
And I cannot let you take Dundar away
from Mother.
Do not confront me!
Disperse!
No one will leave their tents!
Akca Bey commands it. If someone
revolts, he or she will be punished.
Go back to your tents!
Go, go!
As you have said
I did not allow the community to gather
in front of marquee, Sungurtekin Bey.
Ertugrul should see that he is all alone.
My Alps should not go with him, either.
Not to worry, Sungurtekin Bey.
No one will feel the absence of
Gundogdu Bey.
-Get down from there.
-Down, get down! I said get down!
What are you doing Alps?
You are not permitted to leave.
Get back to your tents right now.
You cannot do this.
Akca Bey and Sungurtekin Bey's orders.
You are forbidden to leave.
Mother. Give me your blessing.
My blessing is with you my son.
I entrust you to each other.
I would do anything for your entrustment.
The ones who will go with
brother Ertugrul wish to see...
...you for the last time
and get your blessings.
For the last time.
Seeing you
and your brother, Halime Sultan...
...my Gunduz and many brave Alps,...
...for the last time.
How will my heart take this my son?
Mother, I am begging you. Do not do this.
We are not many, Bey. That scares me.
Do not count the braves
on the road, Dogan.
What matters is,
who we go on the road with.
The essence these brave men
whom we go on the road with...
...carry inside, will give us
strength, on our darkest and...
...hardest day. That is what matters.
Well Bey, with God's will,
we still have a long road...
...until Constantinople.
Artuk Bey! Artuk Bey! Artuk Bey.
We were standing by just outside
the tent with the cars and...
...horses, Artuk Bey.
But Dodurga Alps came...
...and stopped us from doing that.
Brave man, what do you
think you are doing?
Do not make this harder, Artuk.
This is our Bey's order.
Ertugrul Bey. This is a presumption.
Where do you...
...think you are going with
my Alps, without permission?
Akca Bey. You got your head Alp
with you and you speak to me...
...with tongue of Kobek called Ameer.
Know your place Ertugrul.
You already broke the rules...
...of two nomad groups and Beys.
Bey. We were Alps of Tugtekin Bey.
And now our bey is Ertugrul Bey.
Give us your blessings.
Alps. Wait.
Sungurtekin, Akca Bey.
What do you think you are doing?
Do you intend to set
Alps against each other?
Yes, for the sake of our
groups prestige, if necessary.
Ertugrul can go wherever he wants.
I have nothing to say.
However, no Alps from Kayi or
Dodurga will leave from here.
That is our word.
Alps are bonded with each other
by a connection stronger than...
...brotherhood. However, man
who did not get his share of...
...being an Alp, like you,
do not know this.
Do not interfere with my Alps.
You are creating duality
inside the nomad tent.
You are dissuading and
misleading these brave men.
It is uncertain how many Oghuz
has lost their ways since...
...I have paid my homage to
my brother and Ameer Sadettin.
You cannot disobey the law
of the nomad group, Ertugrul.
You cannot walk over the
rules that Alps and Beys...
...lay down at headquarters.
Sungurtekin.
What do you think you are doing?
I am on my duty of the Oghuz law, mother.
Alps! Draw away from Ertugrul Bey. Now!
This is your last warning.
Sungurtekin Bey is right.
Leaving is offensive to the Oghuz law.
-I am out!
-Me too.
-I am out as well.
For all the rotten Alps
leave the group,...
...now we are together.
Bring it on.
Sungurtekin. Akca Bey.
This is enough, stop!
Sungurtekin Bey!
Our men will not be alone.
If you want to take lives, take ours too.
Do you hear me Akca Bey?
Akca Bey. We are hurt too.
Do not increase our pain.
Call your Alps back.
Brave Alps of the Oghuz!
I would like to remember
that you are always merciful.
Now, shall your weapons hide
in their scabbard and may...
...your anger rest against your mercy.
They may rest, so that our nomad
tent may not suffer any more.
Ertugrul. Do not do this.
-You have to go through me first.
-Mother.
Mother Hayme, what are you doing?
I do not wish them to leave as well.
However, this cannot...
...happen with tyranny.
Give way to my heroes!
Are you still not satisfied?
Is the black soil still
hungry for our men's blood?
What do you wish to accomplish?
How many more graves...
...do you want? Enough. Enough!
Alps!
Put your weapons in their sheath.
Sungurtekin Bey. Do not forget
that you are the head of the Alps.
How could you defy my orders?
I will not let any blood
spill here today, Akca Bey.
Kayi Alps! To the drill field!
Where you go, you will find
much worse trouble than...
...yourselves. When that
happens, you will not find...
...a nomad tent that protects you.
Shame! Such a shame!
To yourselves and to your children.
May you get what you deserve.
You will get what you deserve.
My brave men and women...
...who will pursue Ertugrul Bey,
where you go, may God...
...always protect you.
May you not be in need of bad people.
Amen!
My blessings are always with you.
May God speed you.
Mother.
-My daughter.
-Give us your blessing.
It is yours.
My Gunduz.
May God let you be with your family.
May he give my days to you.
May you have the best of luck.
Ertugrul Bey. May the God
protect you from all kinds of...
...trouble and harm.
Know that you will always be
in my heart.
Thank you Selcan Hatun.
May you be happy with
my brother and your child.
Thank you Bey.
First Turgut and now you.
Give me your blessing Mother.
It is yours.
My brave Alps! My brave sisters!
It is time to show patience to...
...evilness, gratitude to felicity
and consent to the destiny.
You shall know that this is not
a separation but only a reunion.
We will wave our noble tribe flag
everywhere, from west to east.
May God help all people
of the Kayi and Oghuz.
-Amen.
Alps! Let us go on our way.
Ertugrul!
Give me your blessings my brother.
It is yours.
-God speed.
-May God protect you, brother.
Ertugrul will pay the price for
demoralizing the prince and...
...rising up against the state.
Now you must carry out the...
...duty that our prince gave you.
Out state has no more patience.
You will bring the heads of
both Ertugrul and the prince.
And not only him.
Kill everyone who pursue him.
My men are ready to obey
your orders, Ameer Almighty.
Then be on your way
and bring me the good news.
Do not have doubts, Emir your highness.
Ertugrul will not get away
this time, Emir your highness.
I will take my leave.
Seeing that you have got a death
wish, seeing that you leave...
...your nomad tent willingly,
you will see how wolves eat...
...the stray, Ertugrul. You will see.
Bogac, how did you survive?
Did something happen to my brothers?
What are you up to
again you Kobek Sadettin?
Ertugrul Bey thought us how to be an Alp.
Ertugrul Bey thought us that
being an Alp is not about just...
...the wrist but about the heart.
We should have gone with him.
We should not have left him alone.
You are right brother. But it is too late.
Alps!
It makes us all sad that a
brave Alp like Ertugrul left.
However you should know that
our nomad group is not...
...about individuals.
A Bey will come, a Bey will leave.
Now what we must do is to
train strong willed Beys...
...and brave Alps so we
can continue serving...
...our group and state.
What matters is our group.
Our state. Just like...
...how you brave Alps came
out to shoulder my father...
...Suleyman Shah's legacy,
it will keep going like that.
Now, everyone will get their act
together from this condition...
...and perform their duties.
If I see or hear someone not...
...performing their duties,
consequences will be severe.
Now, it is time to exercise.
Permission!
So, everything that I could not believe
about my sons were true.
Did you provide the
peace and unity of the nomad...
...group with these gold that
you took from Gundogdu Bey?
Did you violate Ertugrul Bey's
rights at the headquarters...
...with this gold?
Is this the law of Kayi?
Do you protect the law of our
ancestor Oghuz like this?
Are you not ashamed of being such people?
When someone hear about this
tomorrow, how will you...
...look at people's faces?
Two heads are better
than one, Mother Hayme.
Gundogdu Bey gave these
for the unity of our group.
Ertugrul Bey took our brave me from us.
-And our Suleyman Shah's orders.
-Shut up!
Who do you think you are?
How dare you say Suleiman Shah's name?
How do you condescend to tarnish his name?
You should know, that you would not
invade the position of Bey, Mother Hayme.
We are silent because
of our respect to you.
If you have a problem,
talk to your son who is our Bey.
And you say these without a shame?
Shame on you.
Inattentive men who has no way.
Shame on you. You should...
...know that you did not just
trample on our peace and unity...
...but our hope and our law
as well, when you work with...
...Gundogdu Bey. These gold
should not pass your throat.
May God strike you.
Curse on you, shame on you!
Any news from Ertugrul?
I sent a rider, Bey.
We are waiting for his return.
Bogac. What are you planning again?
What are you up to?
Bey, Ertugrul Bey has turned
towards the narrow gate...
...with his caravan.
Open your eyes. We will catch
Ertugrul when he is most...
...vulnerable and take his head.
I do now know what you are doing but...
...I will drown you in your own well.
Bey. The wheel is broken.
Bey. Horses are tired as well.
The children are also tired.
They carry so much.
Fine. We spend the night here.
Dogan, show the single Alps...
...where their guarding duties will be.
Married ones will guard their families.
As you wish Bey.
Nobody will blink an eye, Bamsi.
With the name of God.
So you will
migrate the Kayi group to the...
...place where Ameer Sadettin said,
in peace and unity.
Yes, mother. With God's help.
Do not have doubts.
And, after all this shame,
how will our nomad tent stay loyal...
...to its law and religion, son?
What are you saying mother?
I know all your shames. You and Gundogdu.
Mother.
My Dundar was right. Two lions
cannot roar in the same house.
So we see that this is son of Bey's fate.
Do not tarnish our...
...ancestries honor on your
way by listening to strangers.
We will lose the trust your
father's legacy to us...
...to the Alps, to the people.
What would we do without
me and my brother, mother?
Think about it.
Ameer Sadettin would kill my
brother and become trouble...
...to our nomad tent.
Then we would lose all, mother.
We are still on father's peace
and unity way. We always...
...followed the unity way
that our father showed us.
Now if we can travel in
peace to our new home...
...it is because of my brother's duty.
You still dare and talk
to me about Ameer Sadettin.
That dire man can go to hell!
Growing up, you have always
said God, my son. Why?
To buy Beys with gold and
tarnish our marquee's law?
Did you intend to bring peace
when you overpowered an...
...innocent prince? You tried
to bring peace with stranger...
...statements when your brother was here.
How could you give credit
to that man's words?
Do not be a stranger to your law
and your nomad group.
It is your father's legacy to you,
in your hands.
Do not lose it to other people's hands.
This is what I say. Enjoy your meal.
Shah Suleyman. You said that
if you can steal, instead...
...of a sword it is better to steal
a staff. You said instead of...
...the lawless dark, marquees
would fall, it is better.
You said instead of only the
bitter grass that horse do not...
...eat would not grow, it is better.
You said that if only the brackish
marine that you cannot drink...
...would not flow. You said
if only the coarse son who...
...cannot carry out his
ancestor's legacy was no more...
...it would be better. You said
instead of lies that was bought...
...with gold, it is
better for marquee to fall.
Whoever is in pain in the
marquee, only the Bey of the...
...marquee would know
the true pain, you said.
You said that times can change
and brothers may be enemies...
...to each other and only the
mothers would know the true...
...burden of the marquee, you
said. Whatever you said has...
...become an edict my Bey.
My sons are strangers to each other...
...and in this dark marquee,
your throne is a coffin for us.
Oh my Shah Suleyman. If it is
not written in fate, a servant...
...of God would not have troubles.
May God protect us...
...from the shear of being
lawless and stateless.
My God. You are all. You are kind.
Show me the right way.
Show me so I can go on the right way.
So on your way, I can gratify
my Shah Suleyman's soul, my God.
We will catch up with the time we lost.
However the halt
will discourage the people.
That is why we should get on our way soon.
Bey, you were going to take
Noyan and Bogac to the Sultan...
...and prove to him that all the
things that happen to us is a...
...game of Ameer Sadettin.
But I have nothing in my hands.
Death of Noyan and escape of
Bogac has put us in a difficult...
...situation Artuk Bey. We cannot give up.
Whatever we try and whatever we do,
Kobek will always...
...follow us. That is why,
we must be even more careful.
Alps, do not let your guards down.
Even in our marquee...
...they did not leave us in peace.
They will do whatever it takes
to create chaos in the caravan.
What is your order Bey?
The caravan belongs to the God
first, than it belongs to us.
If we must, for the sake of
the caravan, we will not sleep.
Visit the guard Alps frequently.
As you wish, Bey. They will not be alone.
Halime. Did you talk with the ladies?
Does the caravan need anything?
No, Bey. I have talked with every woman.
Nobody needs anything.
We have a lot of food.
Do not ignore the women and the
children. Our way is long and...
...difficult.
We will not let anyone suffer.
As you wish, Bey.
Bey.
Our Holy Book, Quran...
...is the way that shows our religion.
Flag...
...is the safest place where we raise
our descendants in its shade.
Swords are a door to
holy battle and conquer.
Leave and go.
How could I leave your marquee
and go, Bey?
Every inch of land in world is
our marquee if there is Quran on it.
Know that our sons will seal their fates.
They will not deviate from right way.
Their mistakes will illuminate
their paths.
They will walk tall and be honorable.
Do not feel offend.
Do not offend.
Be with Ertugrul where
you should be, Hayme.
Give these three trusts to their owner.
May God give you a clear path.
In the name of God.
God...
...thank you.
Thank you, God.
It is not possible to set out with this,
Ertugrul Bey. It is irreparable.
How could not you repair it in one day?
-How long does it take?
-It lasts till evening.
Dogan.
Bamsi.
Get ready as soon as possible.
Let us take Yigit with us
and go to Sultan.
There is no time to lose.
Ertugrul Bey, let me come with you.
Sister.
We do not know what will happen
on the road. You stay here.
What will happen when you go to Sultan?
What judgment he will give
about you, Yigit?
I do not know whether
they let you live or not
and whether I see you or not.
-Artuk Bey.
-Yes, Bey.
Command the Alps and
caravan is entrusted to you.
Yes, Bey, do not worry.
-We will catch you up.
-Alright, Bey.
Dogan, Bamsi, get ready
as soon as possible.
We shall set out. Halime Sultan
is coming with us, too.
Yigit.
Good bye, brother.
I believe in our Sultan's justice
as my brother does.
If god permits, he will believe
our innocence.
If god permits, Dundar Bey.
Good bye, brother.
Come on.
-Permission, Mother Hayme?
-Come in, Abdurrahman.
You summoned me, Mother Hayme.
Abdurrahman, prepare the horses.
We shall not leave Ertugrul alone.
Mother Hayme?
We will set out as soon as possible.
Be quick.
Yes, Mother Hayme.
Mother.
Mother, what are you saying?
My daughter.
It is my turn to set out.
Please, do not go, mother.
Selcan, my beautiful daughter.
I know where I must be.
Please, do not.
Please, do not. How could I say this
to Gundogdu Bey?
Please, do not leave us alone.
Selcan, my beautiful daughter.
I know you will take care of
my son and grandchild.
You will do your duty as a wife
and as a mother.
Gundogdu and Sungur
will find the right way
for their nomad tent's unity
and peace sooner or later.
I believe it.
Ertugrul and Dundar on the west of state
Gundogdu and Sungur on the east of state
they will carry Suleyman Shah's legacy.
Your children that are going to born...
...will be biggest supporters of them.
Mother.
Daughter. Give me your blessing.
Peace be upon you, brothers.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, brother.
Give me your blessing.
I go to Ertugrul Bey with Mother Hayme.
Staying here preys me on.
I want to come with you.
Me, too, brother. I cannot stay here.
-I want to come with you, too.
-We want to come too.
So, prepare then.
Tell other Alps who want to come.
We will set out as soon as possible.
Sungurtekin Bey!
Bey!
What happened, Selcan Hatun?
Why do you rush?
Mother Hayme will go after Ertugrul.
Where did that come from?
Please, stop them or mother will leave us.
In the name of God.
Mother.
Is Selcan saying true?
We traveled lots of cities.
Tabriz, Damascus, Aleppo
Bagdad and Urumqi.
We stood strong, we never beg for mercy.
In our darkest times, we stood still.
You will stand still, too.
Do not ever miss me.
Give me your blessing, son.
When Gundogdu comes, hug him tight for me.
From now on, do not leave each other.
No, mother. No.
I could not let you leave.
You cannot go and leave us,
our father's nomad tent behind.
We hold in high esteem for you.
You are really dear for us.
Do not, mother.
Do not do it to us.
Give me your blessing, son.
You will always be in my heart,
in my prays.
May God keeps you safe.
Alps!
What are you doing?
Enough!
I will not let anybody
leave this nomad tent.
We made up our minds, Bey.
We do not draw sword to our Bey.
We would die for Ertugrul Bey...
...or by your sword.
The decision is yours.
Let us go, son.
You know, we could not make it here.
Let us go.
-My daughter.
-Give me your blessing, mother.
You have it.
Mother.
Son.
My dear son.
I give my life for you.
Mother.
Dear mother.
Give me your blessing, mother.
You have it, son.
Now, our nomad tent and our marquee
are entrusted to you and your brother.
We will never tarnish your name
or my father's, mother.
I know, son.
I know.
My mother took our flag
and left, Selcan Hatun.
As I can see, she thinks honor of Kayi
should be in Ertugrul's hand.
Ertugrul came,
rose clouds of dust and left.
We will not dread, Selcan Hatun.
We will not.
We will lead Kayis as they deserve
with Gundogdu Brother.
On the back of our horses as our
ancestors thought us, we will be free.
Our marquee is so silent
our hearts are hurt
even our horses are serving others
and you are talking about being free, Bey.
They could not go far while there are
so many women and children in caravan.
Where are they?
We must catch Ertugrul up
as soon as possible.
Mother Hayme, I know a shortcut
over there to Gediklitas.
If you use that way,
we could catch them up.
Alright, then. Let us lose no time
and set out.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
To glorious Seljuk Sultan Aleaddin.
May God let you be ruler
and let you be only Sultan while
other emperies are worthless.
Sultan, our Prophet (phub) said
"Serving justice for one day
is better than 60 years of pray."
I tried to be fair on the mission
you gave.
I want you know that
Sultan's son Yigit took your side
by distrusting rebellious Oghuz Beys.
He put his life in danger
not to fall into trap.
My brother, Ertugrul Bey,
put his life in danger to save him.
I want you know that
they are not rebellious.
I believe you will act fair.
May God let you live long.
Son of Suleyman Shah, Sungurtekin Bey.
Take the fastest horses
and change your horses before
your they die and continue.
Bring this letter to Sultan Aleaddin
as soon as possible.
Yes, Bey.
Get down the horses.
What happened, Yigit?
You beam.
Today is my happiest day, Ertugrul Bey.
I have stood still whatever
Sultan's judgment will be.
And you were always with me.
You did not make my sister a Sultan
in palaces but a Sultan in your heart.
So, I will not grieve.
I want you know that.
Our Sultan will listen to us, Yigit.
When he learns the truth,
justice will be served.
Then, we will live in peace together,
if God permits.
If God permits.
Perhaps, our Sultan will exile me
or let me come with you.
I do not know.
Whatever is the result
I felt the love of family with you
that I have never felt.
I will always pray for you.
I want you know that.
Thank you, Yigit.
In the name of God.
This is end of the way, Ertugrul.
Are you the new bastard of Kobek?
Ertugrul.
You could not escape this time.
Do you think you will get away with
what you have done?
I will send you to hell as your owner.
Yigit.
Alps.
Attack.
Them traitor.
Yigit!
Ertugrul!
Ertugrul! Gunduz!
Bamsi!
Ertugrul!
Yigit!
Yigit, my brother!
-Let us go to Ertugrul Bey!
-Wait Bamsi.
We cannot leave Halime Sultan.
-Sister.
-I am listening, my dear.
I am cold. It is like
my blood is draining.
I am cold.
Take your hands off my son.
Your problem is with me.
Stay where you are.
If you move, your son dies.
Drop your sword.
I said drop your sword!
-Son!
-Mother!
Son!
-I could not leave you alone.
My dear Gunduz.
Bey.
Forgive me.
From now on, I will obey
every order you gave.
Welcome, brother.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, Bey.
Yigit!
God.
Please do not make me suffer this pain.
Please, spare my brother's life.
-Sister.
-Tell me.
Ertugrul Bey will take Gunduz.
Of course, he will and you will be fine.
Bey.
Ertugrul! Ertugrul!
Gunduz is here.
Yigit.
-Sister.
-Mother.
-Tell me.
-I told you.
I told you.
Today is my happiest day.
Ertugrul Bey.
Give me your blessing.
I bear witness,
God is the sole divinity...
...and I bear witness Mohammad is
his servant and his messenger.
My daughter, may God award him
with heaven.
May God bless him.
Yigit died honorably as a brave
Seljuk Sultan's son.
Yigit!
Bey, these are Seljuk soldiers.
Kobek.
Sungurtekin Bey, welcome, sit down.
Our nomad tent stared
migration preparations.
We have lot of things to do.
If you excuse me, I would love
to go back as soon as possible.
Duty comes first.
Gundogdu Bey went to Ahlat
as you ordered.
He will look for place
where we will migrate.
We will set out as soon as possible.
I want you know that.
Very good.
Our Sultan and I are quite pleased
that two honorable tribes of Oghuz
act together.
And Ertugrul, I sent a letter to Sultan
because of my duty.
I reported that my brother Ertugrul
and Sultan's son Yigit did not
get involved in rebellion.
Our Sultan will decide it.
-Alright. If you excuse me.
-Of course.
Sungurtekin Bey.
My duty in these lands is over.
I want to set out to Konya tomorrow.
As I always told you
you should be a margrave
for the safety of these lands.
Also, this is our Sultan's desire.
I obey Sultan's order,
your Ameer Almighty.
I want you know that I do everything
for my state till my last breath.
I have no doubt about it.
May God speed Dodurgas and Kayis.
Have a safe journey, Ameer Almighty.
El-Fatiha  for his spirit.
My brother.
You had a hard life.
You always run not to harm
your state, traditions and...
...not be toyed by your enemies...
...through your life.
You sacrificed your short life...
...your childhood, everything.
May God take you to heaven,
my dear brother.
Daughter.
He died for you and your baby.
May God bless him.
Come on.
Come on, daughter.
He was brave as his name Yigit.
We witnessed he would sacrifice
his life for his state.
Come on, Halime.
World is such a place
where you spend your life
and get nothing in return.
Do not sink into Adam's wine mystery.
Do not take your eyes off
the life rack that reaches sky.
Human beings do not know
sky reaching mystery.
Every tribe's secret truth
rises step by step.
Every journey's destination is different.
Journeys that are not aware of each other
and a state that has endless boundaries.
When the time is right
that state could be in your hands.
Almighty Ameer.
I told you not to disturb this council!
There is something outside
you need to see.
What?
Talk! What?
What is happening here?
Ameer Almighty, a mad man
left this and run away.
How? No!
Ertugrul!
I will find you wherever you are
even if you are at the back of beyond.
If I am an Ameer of this state
if I am glorious Sadettin Kobek
I will not stop until I level you
with the ground and
bury you sevenfold below the ground.
Daughter, I know losing your brother
hurts your heart.
God gives lives and takes them back.
Like birth, death is for human beings.
Yigit joined the choir invisible.
He lived bravely and fell martyr
bravely as his name.
No word could ease my pain, mother.
First my father, now my brother...
I am just one in this huge world, mother.
Do not ever say that.
God is the only One, my daughter.
Pull yourself together.
You are a Bey's wife now.
From now on, we will cry
and you will wipe our tears.
If we will fall and you will rise us.
Even if we are perished,
you will stand still.
You must be sharp,
so your Bey could walk tall.
Do you know what turns a man to a Bey?
It is neither his weapon nor his strength.
What makes him a Bey
is his Hatun who believes
and supports him.
Do not forget this, alright daughter?
Sadettin Kobek will cause trouble when
he finds out what happened to his men.
Be on the alert. We will be cautious.
Bey, I completed the mission you gave.
Thank you, Geyikli.
Bey, some people are coming.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Son, we are here as your fellow.
If God permits, you will
restore these land
with scientists and artisans who will be
on your side on your rightful course.
Your caravan reminded me first Muslims
who immigrated to Abyssinia
with guide of Cafer bin Ebu Talib
and Muslims who immigrated
from Mecca to Madina.
After hegira, Muslims founded
their state and got strong.
One day our Prophet ordered
his companions to prepare for umrah.
Muslims prepared and set out.
Polytheists who open doors to their
enemies on pilgrimage time
did not open the doors for Muslims.
Muslims had set out before
taking Mecca's permission.
As expected, when Muslims
were close to Mecca
they understood polytheists
laid an ambush on a place
which is called as Hudeybiye.
So, Muslims stopped over there.
They made agreements with envoys.
But the agreement was
as polytheists wanted.
So, our Prophet went back to Madina
without performing a umrah.
Our Prophet's companions told
this displeasure to our Prophet.
Our Prophet calmed them down
and told them to trust God.
After the agreement, he had
Sura of Fetih  as divine inspiration.
God expressed conquer of Mecca by saying
"Indeed, We have given you, Muhammad,
a clear conquest" to our Prophet.
So, Muslims would have not only umrah
but conquest of Mecca as well.
May God give conquests to this caravan.
Amen.
As he conquered your hearts, other hearts
may be conquered thanks to you.
Amen.
If God permits you will serve that
rightful course where you will immigrate
you will fight for all the world
living that rightful course.
Amen.
You will heal wounds
with divine inspiration.
Amen.
May God let you found state you dreamt of.
For believers, every Sura is a glory Sura.
With the strength we took
from our Holy Book
it is time to stand up to tyrannies
which reach the skies.
World labors resurrection.
Holy Birth is coming with the help of God.
If God permits.
In the name of God.
With the 99 names of God Almighty,
the one who creates us
and fills our hearts with faith,
who brings things into existence.
Honorable people of Kayi...
...courageous women, brave Alps.
A new life starts now.
New lands are waiting us.
There are many castles and hearts
waiting to be conquered.
On this harsh path
Ertugrul Bey will take this mission.
From now on
Bey of Suleyman Shah's nomad tent
and marquee is him.
From now on, we complain, he atones.
He leads, we follow.
We enjoy, he suffers.
His award
is working hard and pleasing us.
Ertugrul Bey.
Good luck being the Bey of Kayi.
May God let you be victorious
in both worlds, son.
Amen, mother.
God...
...give strength to Ertugrul Bey
to wave his flag.
Amen.
-Save him from tyrant's traps.
-Amen.
God, let this a handful of people
to be victorious
-who set their minds on your path.
-Amen.
Give us patience of Eyyub Almighty
who prayed for you on good and bad day.
Amen.
-Do not deprive us of your aid.
-Amen.
Confront us with right people
who are on right way.
Amen.
-Do not lessen your love in our hearts.
-Amen.
-Give us prophet manners.
-Open seals of our hearts.
-Amen.
-Open them so we could conquer hearts.
Good luck with your seigniory, son.
-Do not deviate from right way.
-Amen.
Honorable people of Kayi
who do not leave me alone.
In this holy path
we will show to world what could
a handful of men can do
by taking strength from our ancestors.
The ones who said we could not
and we would perish by non-Muslims
and the ones who stopped us
we will shame them with
the state we will found.
Sun will be our flag
and sky will be our tent.
We will tremble very ground
and pierce the blue sky.
We will take our swords as lovers
and have large armies.
We will be guardians of justice and mercy.
I swear on my sword
I will keep my shoulder to the wheel
and make my descendants
and nomad tent victorious.
May God help us.
God is greatest.
From now on, Artuk Bey is the Bey
when I am not around.
Know that his orders are my orders
and his words are my words.
Alps.
From now on
Turgut Alp is your chief Alp.
Wait hand and foot.
In the name of God.
Indeed, we have given you, O Muhammad,
a clear conquest.
That God may forgive for you what
preceded of your sin and what will follow
and complete His favor upon you
and guide you to a straight path.
And that God may aid you
with a mighty victory.
It is He who sent down tranquility
into the hearts of the believers
that they would increase in faith
along with their present faith.
And to God belong the soldiers
of the heavens and the earth
and ever is God Knowing and Wise.