Episode 35 will start after 12:19 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Thank God we united again.
So my dreams were not for nothing.
But you were about to see
third dream, son.
You are late.
I thought I would never see you again.
Thanks to the one who made it happen.
Thank you.
If God permits.
Come on. There are some people
waiting for us.
Who is waiting for us?
Those who will give you the package.
Do you know how did
mighty army of Genghis Khan...
...got this much stronger, Tangut?
I want to learn about it, Baycu Noyan.
By embracing Turks, too.
He has always said that
you must collaborate with Turks...
...if you want to take
breath fearlessly...
...on mountains, moorlands, uncanny
cities, back of the beyond of universe.
I once heard that your mother was Turk.
You heard it right.
Maybe I love Turks because of that.
You may call it is because of blood.
Who knows?
Until the great army of Ogeday
comes, Tangut...
...we will find fearless Turks
who love to die fighting.
But we will irrigate this land
with their blood...
...if someone from them tries to cheat.
What did Efrasiyab do?
He is in the heart of nomad group.
He will not let it go until they
kill them.
Nice.
My brothers!
I am glad that I share my food with you.
Please be seated.
Do our Alps need anything, Hamza?
They need tent and bed.
If one warrior, Hamza,...
...does not see
sky as tent and earth as bed...
...that person could not become an Alp.
Serve the food.
Serve the first food to Abdurrahman Alp.
He is our new brother.
May you live long, Efendi Noyan.
Here you go, enjoy your supper.
Tell us, Abdurrahman Alp.
What news do you have from
the nomad group?
Nomad group is like
a boiling cauldron, Bey.
Every person who does not join
the mighty one will be boiled...
...in that cauldron.
So how did you escape
from that cauldron?
I heard that they sentenced you to death.
How did a big nomad group
slip you through its fingers?
That man in the nomad group.
What was his name?
Tugtekin.
Yes, that feverish guy.
How did he slip you through his fingers?
Tell us so we know about your skills.
Mongols bandits broke our connection
with our father's land.
We are not able to do business
on our father's land.
Assets' value became thousand from one.
Mongols infidels will not stop.
They are feeding with blood.
There is nobody will stop
this Mongols cruel.
That is shame that mighty people
groveled to them.
If that Mongols is so mightly
how did you escape from them, Efrasiyab?
They seized your properties but
why did they spare your life?
I have escaped from Dodurga Alps...
...just like Ertugrul escaped from yours.
We, Kayi Alps, do not give up
till our last breath.
If Kayis have taught you this,
why did you leave them and come to Noyan?
Kayi people have forgotten their customs.
Sons of Beys are drawing swords
to each other...
...instead of listening problems
of the community.
If there is no union
there's no life and peace.
We share our purses...
...as we share our food.
You have earned this, Abdurrahman Alp.
This Noyan will play every trick on you.
Do not let that devil's sweet talk
or buy you off, Abdurrahman.
Yes, Bey.
Thank you, Noyan.
But I have not left my nomad group
for gold or reputation.
I am here because I want to be
in the future's world's state.
I hope that what you said is true,
Abdurrahman Alp.
Eat, Beys. Eat.
Eat until you choke.
Eat so you have the strength to crush
the insects which stand...
...against the world's state.
Eat. Eat.
What on earth is this, Tugtekin Bey?
Do you want us to die?
Ofcourse not. Not at all
I am only curious how a merchant like you
have escaped from such wild warriors?
Thanks to Ertugrul's Alps.
Me and your Alps would have already
been dead if it wasn't for them.
In brief, what matters is not how powerful
our enemy is, but what we do.
Efrasiyab, our women weave the best rugs,
fabrics, carpets with their own hands.
We have a sack full of goods.
And many animals too.
You go and check them all,
appraise them and after that
we will make a deal.
If God permits.
Okay, Bey. Give me an assistant.
I came all the way here putting my head in
the lion's mouth for a successful trade.
I pray to God for it will be
a profitable deal for both sides.
If God permits.
Alright then. You should set to work.
Kocabash will accompany you, Efrasiyab.
My sons. I hope we will get
what we expect.
We will be ruined this winter,
if we can not succeed it again this time.
Efrasiyab is a good merchant, Uncle.
That's what I have heard. I hope that
we will get what we want from him, Uncle.
It is your duty, Gundogdu.
Our nomad group will ease for a while
with those sacs we already have.
You must deal with this
without having any troubles.
With great pleasure, Bey.
With the help of God, I will provide
prosperity to our nomad group.
I hope so. I hope so.
Mongols have smashed the Islamic world.
Kayi nomad group is down at the heels.
You should talk about your dreams,
not your troubles, son.
Dream means hope.
I am speechless, and
my heart is in misery.
I know that.
They have invited you so you would
not be devistated any longer.
Who are they? Why do they invite me?
There surely must be a reason.
You should be patient, son.
Mother. What is going on?
You are lost in thoughts again.
A war breaks out inside of me
every single day, my son.
I am tired of the war
between Hayme the mother
and the leader of Seigniory.
That unscrupulous Hayme who can't even
hold a sword herself, sent Ertugrul...
...to exile. That is breaking me inside
more and more everyday.
There is no such thing, Mother.
Do not talk as if you do not know
Ertugrul. Do not you remember?
My brother tore down those Christians
who were serving the satan.
You relax.
You are right, my son. You are right
but he had his mighty dad then...
who was watching him out.
He had you.
He had his Alps.
He is all alone now.
What does he eat? What does he drink?
Where does he sleep?
Is it not too late to think about these?
My daughter, Gokce. Call Halime to dinner.
I have something to talk to you.
Alright, Mother.
Mother Hayme is calling you to dinner.
I am not hungry.
She has something to tell us, Halime.
What is it?
You will find out if you come.
I have seen my son Sungurtekin near the
Caspian Sea for the last time.
He reared his horse, waved me and
It was the last time I've ever seen him.
He has never lost the child in him
even while he was fighting against
Genghis Khan's army.
There was this hopeful look in his eyes,
and he never lost his smile
nor his hope in this cruel life.
So does my Ertugrul.
I have seen the hope and resolution in his
eyes, even when he was being exiled.
They have never given up just as
their father.
We will fight too.
We will remember this, as long as we see
those two empty plates on our table.
-In the name of Allah.
Come on, let's eat.
Today, Korkut Bey was here.
He talked to me about Gokce.
-I hope it is a good thing, Mother.
-It is a good thing, son.
He told me that they would come
tomorrow and ask for Gokce's hand
with the commandment of God.
What is it, Father?
It is a good thing, son.
I have talked to your Aunt Hayme today.
I told her that we would go and ask for
Gokce's hand for you, my son Tugtekin...
...under the commandment of God
tomorrow night.
It is really good news, Mother.
Only a man like Tugtekin
would suit my sister Gokce.
What do you think, Gokce?
Would you allow me to say a few words
as her sister?
Sure, my girl.
Now we know why that traitor was bothering
with my sister all this time.
Selcan, if you say one more word...
Gundogdu.
She is her sister.
Let her talk.
Let her say whatever she wants.
She already knows that she should agree
with me in the end.
Her Bey's marquee is not enough for her.
She wants to rule her step child's bed.
She took my husband first,
now my sister...
I do not even count Alps that she captured
and Ertugrul that she sent away
from the nomad group.
That woman would not be satisfied
even with Kayi's marquee.
Now she wants to twist my poor sister
around her finger.
That's enough.
Enough, sister, what the hell
are you talking about?
Selcan, how can you talk like that?
Have you lost your mind?
You must get those sick thoughts out of
your mind, sister.
Swallow your words, then come here
and talk to us.
I am not the only one that you are
humiliating this way.
You are also humiliating yourself
and our family.
Do I look like I care about humiliating
myself from now on, Gokce?
If I have the right to say
only one word as your sister
you should know that
I will not give my blessings to you
if you get married
to that arrogant bastard.
Selcan!
Enough already.
You keep harping on Aytolun
since we came here.
You have been denigrating
my big brother and niece all the time.
I did not say a word until now
but that is enough.
You started talking against my marquee.
You must know your place.
You pull yourself together or...
Or what, Mother?
Will you send me into exile like Ertugrul?
All truth is not always to be told, right?
Will I be banished just because...
...I am telling the truth?
All I have left are my words.
I call you mother, because you are
my mother.
You did a lot for me even if you did
not give birth to me.
Whatever you decision will be, I should
submit it.
But these are my thoughts, Mother.
Have a good night.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Mother.
We should not go there empty handed,
Aytolun Hatun.
Make a good preparation.
Ofcourse, Bey.
Especially for such a blessed night.
Isn't that so, Tugtekin?
You are right, Mother.
You did not say anything
about my decision, my son.
I will do whatever you approve, Father.
It is like the sun has risen on his
shadowed face, Bey. Don't you see it?
He cannot show his delight
due to his respect to you.
Isn't it right, Tugtekin?
That is correct, Mother.
Selcan probably had gone mad
when she heard about it.
What is that woman's problem with you?
She is a sorrowful woman whose babies died
one after another, Bey.
Poor woman. I feel pity for her
even if I get angry with her sometimes.
I feel pity for Gundogdu mostly.
He is wasting that poor man's life
too as he did to himself.
I hope that Gundogdu Bey would come to
his senses and find a decent woman...
...that suits himself and have a child
before he gets too old.
I can not allow this any longer, Mother.
I can not allow Selcan to consume both
my life and kin.
Son. Starting a family is tough,
but breaking it up is very easy.
You should not be the one to brake it up.
Do not make the angels in the sky cry.
No, Mother. Either I will kill her
or she will kill me.
This relationship will not end well.
I will not eat anything.
I do not feel like it.
I want you to know that I have loved you
since I was a child.
I have loved you ever since I could
remember, Ertugrul.
I will not let Halime or anyone else to
take this beautiful pain away from me.
I will wait for you until I die
if necessary.
What do you think you are doing, Gokce?
How can I endure seeing you
in the same marquee
with my wife and children?
How can I look at their faces?
How can I carry you like
a ruthless guilty conscience?
Ertugrul.
Why that woman?
Why is it not me, but her?
Why?
You, night people.
Thank God who created the night and
the day for us.
He is the one
who gives strength after weakness.
There are easiness and conquests
after every difficulty and grueling.
Who are the ones to conquer?
Brave ones. Alp ones.
Alperen ones.
Bravery is the state of power
and strength.
So how can one reach the state
of bravery?
By controlling his anger.
By respecting his elders.
By showing mercy to underdogs.
By rebelling against cruelty
and serving his people.
Muhammad commands that
who can be the servent of his people
is the Master of them.
The one who thinks of serving as the main
duty of a Master, is the real brave one.
That one is Alp. That one is Alperen.
Listen, night people.
It is time for the son of Suleyman Shah,
the brave of Alps, Ertugrul,
who has devoted himself to serve
for The Turkish islamic guild,
to put on his holy dress.
He is now a member of the Turkish
islamic guild.
He is the valiant of young men.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
La ilahe illallahu vallahu akbar.
Allahu akbar and lillahi'l-hamd.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
La ilahe illallahu vallahu akbar.
Allahu akbar and lillahi'l-hamd.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
La ilahe illallahu vallahu akbar.
Allahu akbar and lillahi'l-hamd.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
La ilahe illallahu vallahu akbar.
Allahu akbar and lillahi'l-hamd.
Allahu akbar. Allahu akbar.
La ilahe illallahu vallahu ekber.
Allahu akbar and lillahi'l-hamd.
Illallah.
Holly Lord who has eternal vitality
and aliveness.
Oh God though who makes existence exists
with his entity.
My God who owns everything.
We are being protected by you.
Please protect us.
Please offer this to us with the shield
of Your name, with verity
with protection, with order.
-Amen.
Let my desire not humiliate me on this
holly path.
I will always rebel against cruelty.
I will always use my weapon
according to the scales of justice.
I will always serve my people.
I will always fight for world's order.
Son, do not take off this shirt
in the great wars you will fight.
Do not forget. This is the exposed one.
What you really wear is in your heart.
May God not embarrass me for the sake of
my fight.
-Amen.
Gokce.
Yes, Mother?
We could not talk to you
throughly last night.
What do you think
about your uncle's offer?
Mother Hayme, as you would appreciate,
it is so sudden.
I do not know what to say while
Gundogdu and my sister are on bad terms.
Let us hope for the best.
And you are the one to make this
blessed decision.
However, I am curious about
Ertugrul's opinion on this matter.
I now want to prepare this place
for tonight's guests as worthy of you.
Excuse me.
Fine, girl. That will be good.
May it be easy.
Very well.
Did you also see cattles and sheeps?
Artuk Bey and I checked them all
one by one, Bey.
Our animals are fattened, Bey. They are
in good comdition.
-They do not have any sickness.
-That is wonderful!
Gundogdu?
I hope nothing is wrong.
Where is this man?
How could not I wake up?
Efrasiyab, I swear to God
you cannot find such good animals...
...in any Turkish nomad group.
They have plenty of meat.
They have plenty of wool.
-May it be easy, Gundogdu Bey.
-Thank you, Aytolun Hatun.
So, merchant?
I hope you will not be stingy
and leave us in the lurch.
I am generous, Hanim. Do not be afraid.
Even if you are a penny pincher,
our great Gundogdu Bey will probably
make you loosen your purse strings.
No, Aytolun Hatun. Wait.
We have not done a bargain yet.
He will check on the rugs.
He will check on the carpets.
Then we will start the bargain.
What is going on, Selcan?
I was worried when I could not see you,
Bey.
Why would you be worried, Selcan?
Here is a huge nomad group, what could
happen to me?
Everything bad that happened to us has
happened in this big nomad group, right?
That is why I get worried every time
I do not see you.
Excuse us, Bey.
Let us leave.
Tell us, Selcan Hatun.
What did this big nomad group do to you
other than welcoming you to
it's dinner table?
I should know this as The Hatun,
so I will fix our flaws.
Do you know what is
the greatest flaw, Aytolun?
Your desire to rule everything
as being The Hatun.
Shush! Selcan!
It is no problem. It is not important.
It seems that Selcan Hatun
is trying to be a mischief maker
which she could not succeed
in Kayi nomad group.
But this paradise cannot be
the playground of her demons.
Neither Bey nor I would allow it.
Loot at her!
Demons became angels
but we were unaware of that.
What were those demons doing
while you were breaking up families
and taking place in marquees?
Selcan!
Go back to your tent now!
I will really cause an accident.
Come on.
I will prepare your morning food, Bey.
You come and eat.
My apologies, Aytolun Hatun.
It is no problem, Gundogdu Bey.
Wonderful. You are really patient, Bey.
You were patient with this barren, wild,
impertinent woman for all these years.
I wanted to say thisfor so long
but kept my mouth shut.
There is no mor Ertugrul nor Sungurtekin.
Suleyman Shah's lineage is
about to become extinct.
If you wait for this devilish woman,
you will wait for a long time, Bey.
Kayi would break up.
You mark my words.
May it be easy.
You are devil. Devil!
You subverted the peace in nomad group.
I am at the end of my tether
because of you.
Are you talking to me, Gundogdu?
Do you not see the evil next to you
and find fault in me?
Shut the hell up!
God damn the day I have met you, woman.
God damn the day
I have taken you into my tent.
It is not bearable any more.
I do not want to see your face again.
Pack your things and get out of my tent.
Okay? Get out!
I will not go. I will not go.
I will not leave my home
to that devilish woman.
I will not give my home to her.
Woman!
Is there any home left, woman?
Is there any home left?
Is there any peace left?
Get out! Get out, I do not want to see
your face again. Get out of my tent.
-I will not go. I will not leave you.
-Go. Get out. Come on.
-No, I will not go.
-Get out.
You are not my woman anymore.
Get out!
Get out! Go! Go!
My God!
The circumstances in the nomad group is
really tough.
Do not give them the amount
they are asking for.
You are their last hope.
Aytolun is so tough.
Gundogdu is so smart.
Gundogdu has problems with his woman.
You should entrap them slowly.
We will take action as soon as we hear
from Noyan.
Let us see how the nomad tent
will survive the winter without any gold.
Good boy.
Come on.
Harder.
I would be scared if I were
your enemy, son.
Your sword turns into the angel of death
in your hands. Wonderful.
My brother mows infidels
like he mows grass.
Stop.
Turali.
When you hold your weapon,
you will not feel the difference
between your hand
and your weapon. Okay?
Hold it now.
I want an axe as well, Turgut Alp.
I will not fight without an axe.
Let us hope for that. Maybe some day.
You will ask it from the master,
not from me, son.
Brother. What will we do
about this traitor in the nomad group?
We will follow every trace.
The traitor will surely leave a trace.
Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
We owe you our lives. We want to have a
dinner and have fun with you sometime.
Dinner is fine but we are not
in the mood of fun, merchant.
You would be out of your spirits
if you commiserate.
We owe you our lives, brother.
Your sorrow is our sorrow from now on.
We know how to share your pain
as we share our bread.
Thank you, Kocabash. Thank you.
Thank you.
Excuse us. You know, we have a lot to do.
May it be easy.
We cannot win victory
even if we make the all nomad group
go down on their knees as long
as Ertugrul and his Alps do not give up.
I would not die in disappointment since I
saw this Kocabash mutt...
...turned into a sheep. They learned
to appreciate.
A fox cannot be your friend
as you cannot use a bear's peltry.
Once a whore, always a whore.
You should be careful.
Selcan?
My girl.
What happened?
Come here.
Come here, girl. Come here. Sit down.
Selcan.
What happened to you? Tell us.
It is over, Mother.
Everything is over.
We are at the point of no return.
What do you mean
everything is over, Selcan?
What do you mean by
the point of no return?
Gundogdu does not want me
neither in his bed
nor in his tent.
Bring water.
He does not want me in front of his eyes
or on the land he steps on.
I have no place to stay
in this nomad tent anymore.
Selcan.
My girl. Selcan.
You are not only a daughter-in-law to me,
but also a daughter.
Do not say that again.
There is a solution for everything
in this world except for death.
You can stay with Halime for a while.
You will be companions.
Sit and relax. Pull yourself together.
After that we will talk.
Okay, my girl?
-Selcan.
Aytolun and Gokce were
the final straw, right?
Elhamdulillah, thanks to the One
who feed us.
Thanks to God.
Excuse me, sir.
Your heart seems broken.
Why are you sad?
Nobody understands me.
They do not listen even
if I warn them for trouble.
They made me fell apart.
Son, your best friend during your
bravery journey is your loneliness.
Do not wait them to understand you.
Your mother, your wife,
your brother and your Alps.
None of them will understand you.
They will not see the horizon inside you.
Bravery is equal to make everyone
a partner to your dreams.
Bravery is telling your dream
to your people.
Do not ever feel hopelessness.
Because when you keep
the justice flag flying...
...72 nations must find a place
under its shadow.
There is always enemy.
Oghuz Tribes and Islam World
could not take a breath.
Son, you should be happy about it.
Because when they are no longer
enemy of yours
it means that your presence
is no longer valuable.
It means you have already lost
your high value.
Because they declare war against
your beliefs.
Thank you.
My heart is healed.
When will I see you again?
We will be together for a long time
after a short period of separation.
Do not show the belt
you dressed to anyone.
It could be affected by the evil eye.
Do not forget it.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
See you in a short while.
If God permits.
Tell me, Karabey.
What is this important issue?
Saadettin Kobek sends his regards.
Sultan Aladdin sent a spy
named Ertokus to that area.
He is collecting information
for the campaign he will launch
against you in spring.
So Sultan Aladdin still thinks that
he can get rid of us.
So he still wants to play with us.
Fine. Let it be.
Tangut. Hamza.
Give my respect to Saadettin Kobek
for this information.
Yes, sir.
Hamza, you will go for hunt.
A traitor named Ertokus.
He will not be dead.
I want him alive. Do you understand?
With great pleasure.
By the way,
take Abdurrahman Alp with you.
But if he betrays, you are responsible.
You do not worry, Noyan.
Son, do you have time?
Yes, mother.
Gumustekin sent his Alp. They will
stay there longer than expected.
He wanted you to send your Alps
to take Goncagul from caravansary.
You know, roads are too dangerous.
I will take my sister Goncagul, Mother.
You know, she is my brother's
dearest daughter. He loves her a lot.
Of course, Mother.
That is why I said I will take her.
We will be back till the end of the day.
You be back so we will ask Gokce for you.
Goncagul is at the age
of marriage, as well.
She should experience this excitement.
She may get married soon, too.
My daughter! My beautiful girl.
My sheep.
Do not say anything anymore to
marriage between Tugtekin and Gokce.
What can we do?
We just hope for the best.
Come on, my girl. Come on.
-Come on, Selcan.
-Come on.
Everything will be fine.
We will get through
these tough days together, Selcan.
I will suffer the pain one by one
for evil things I did to you...
...and Ertugrul Bey, my Gundogdu.
I know that.
What comes around goes around, Halime.
I will not escape just by burning in hell.
Halime.
I will shut my mouth.
Do you know why will I do that?
So my sister forgets about Ertugrul.
Do you think that I do not see
the torture she did to you?
I will shut my mouth...
...but we all will see the consequences
of this marriage by living it.
Bey, I should come with you.
You do not worry.
We will be back before night.
You keep an eye on
this merchant Efrasiyab.
Why, Bey? Did he do something wrong?
I only trust my weapon
while Noyan's breath
is just behind our neck, Kocabash.
You are right, Bey. You are right.
Gokce.
It seems that Aunt Hayme
have talked with you.
She has told me what Korkut Bey told, Bey.
That is why you are not
trying to look at me?
As you can imagine,
since things are like that.
I will go to take Goncagul.
If it is in our kismet,
we will come to your tent tonight.
I know that.
My way is not so long.
But you should know that my heart
is beating like hell, Gokce.
I would have wanted
what you are going to say.
I am afraid that I feel one-day long road
as one century, Gokce.
It is Mother Hayme and
Korkut Bey's decision, Bey.
You are right.
But what your heart thinks
is more important than their decision.
Let us hope best for us.
Yes, Halime Sultan?
Where is Ertugrul Bey?
I want to talk to him.
I know that he is in an awkward position
but I must talk to him.
Our Bey will absolutely find a way to see
you once he is back, Halime Sultan.
Do not you know that?
I know that but it is hard for him
to come back to nomad group.
His mother has exiled him.
You also know that.
I cannot wait without doing anything.
Tell me if you know where he is.
I will go there to see him.
It is not right for you
to leave nomad group
while Mongols are nearby, sister Halime.
And we do not know where he is,
right, brother?
Yes, we do not know it.
I will not give my blessing to you
if you know it but do not tell me.
I beg you do not talk
like that, Halime Sultan.
We are servants who have committed
our life and spirit to our Bey.
There is no difference between you
and our Bey, sister Halime.
We just do not know it.
Brother Turgut.
Mother Hayme, Halime Sultan.
I have not lied that much all my life.
I wish I knew what to do.
Let us go.
Goncagul Hatun.
Atabey Ertokus.
Come please. Give me company.
Why did you come here?
I am visiting my aunt Aytolun.
It must be an important matter
since your father has sent you alone.
Yes, it is an important matter.
He has sent me since he had
some work to do in Konya.
What about you?
How come did Sultan Aladdin let you go?
I know that he does not go anywhere
in palace without you.
Let us say it is an important duty.
Innkeeper.
-Yes, Bey?
-Set the table.
-Yes, efendi.
Sister Halime is following us, brother.
It is not a good sign.
Our Bey will be mad at us.
Only mad? He will kick our ass.
-So what will we do?
-Nothing to do.
We will say that she followed us.
So we will lie as if our Bey
would believe it.
If lovers are going to be united
then they can call us liers.
Those old times, Hamza.
Once we were looking for
Ertugrul Bey here.
Those times have passed.
We have given our lives for them.
But they stroke at our hearts.
They have fired us from our homes.
Now forget about Ertugrul
so we do our duty.
Keep your eyes open.
Learn who is Atabey Ertokus
and where to find him.
Is The Great Seljuk Empire sleeping
while Mongols are walking around?
Sultan Aladdin must know something.
It is really shame if our destiny is
in the hand of Sultan who is in palace.
Does Sultan leave palace and join war?
Do you learn these words
from your father, girl?
The one who looks at palace
sees the boiling cauldron
inside of it, Ertokus Bey.
So your eyes can see behind the walls?
I wish you could have seen
your father's passion.
Innkeeper, set the table quickly.
Noyan trusts in you a lot.
I also trust in him.
You will also notice
quintessence inside him soon.
Tell everyone to be ready.
Lunatic, get out.
I said get out.
What is going on?
No! No!
Leave me alone! I said leave me alone!
No!
Are you the dog of Sultan Aladdin?
Ask permission, damned!
-Take this woman. Tie them all.
-No! No!
Leave her alone! Leave her alone!
You will pay for it! Who are you? Who?
-Bey.
-Brother Turgut.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Greetings, brother.
Dogan.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Greetings.
Abdurrahman is in the nest of snake.
I hope he will be our eye in the back.
But we do not know
if he is alive or dead, Bey.
What if he could not have gain
Noyan's trust?
What if something happen?
There is only one way to find out.
Entering the snake's nest.
That's what I am going to do.
Then we must go right away, Bey.
Not now, brother Turgut.
We have to know every weak points
of him in order to attack Noyan.
We do not have our nomad group's
support anymore.
How about you guys?
Were you able to find the traitor?
Unfortunately, Bey.
We were suspicious about Kocabash
but we are the one
who have saved him from Mongols.
We cannot win this war
without knowing their every step
and retaliate numerously.
I have to find out Abdurrahman's
status in a short while.
In the meanwhile you must
find traitor in nomad group.
Halime?
Leave me alone! I said leave me alone!
Leave me alone!
-Leave her.
Leave me!
Whose puppies are you?
What is going on?
Do you know who are you attacking to?
Shut the hell up or I shed your blood.
Prepare the horses.
We met you unexpectedly.
Come here, you Dodurga's kid!
Come here.
Come here so we close
that unfinished business.
Attack!
Do not be afraid, Goncagul.
We will escape.
How did you come here, Halime?
I have followed Dogan and Turgut Alp.
So Halime Sultan followed you
and you did not notice, did you?
Excuse us, Bey.
You are pregnant.
Why did you come here, Halime?
I found you when we got married.
But there was separation
in our destiny again.
I could not put up with longing
for you so here I am.
Does that longing worth to get yourself
and our baby into danger?
I do not know how long I will put up
with this anymore, Ertugrul.
There are fires around us.
We have no nomad tent
that we can breath in peace.
Halime Sultan,
you will be brave mother of Kayi.
A Kayi woman who never gives up
who is steady as a rock
who never gives quarter.
I am exhausted, Ertugrul.
I only become peaceful
when I put my head to your shoulder.
You are not with me now.
I dread to bring my son to a world
which he will grow up as a fatherless.
I promise you and my child
that I will offer the world
I dream about only
after sculpting it with my weapon.
Children of our people will live
in peace on this lands forever.
They will see this lands
as their motherland.
You should go to nomad tent now.
Nobody should know that you met with me.
When will you be back, Ertugrul?
I do not want to get nomad group
any trouble because of me.
I will return in not long time.
But also not short time.
But I will return if God permits.
You believe in my promise, Halime Sultan.
-Are you okay?
-We owe you our lives.
Which tribe do you come from?
I'm Tugtekin who is son of Korkutoglu
from Dodurga Tribe.
Goncagul Hatun.
You deserve every peace on both worlds.
You have saved us from these cruel men.
-Who were they?
-Kayi's Alps.
They are traitors.
They are puppies of Noyan now.
And who are you?
I am Sultan Aladdin's equerry.
Atabey Ertokus.
The Atabey Ertokus?
Welcome, Bey.
Soldiers from Seljuk are taking a rest
in the valley. There are wounded ones.
Take care of them right away.
What is going on, Bey?
Hamza and Abdurrahman allied with Mongols
and tried to kill Atabey Ertokus Bey.
Come on. There are wounded ones.
Get a move on.
Yes, Bey.
Come on, let us go to my father's tent.
I want to see Mother Hayme first.
I want to share her sorrow.
As you wish.
Bogac, take Ertokus Bey
to Mother Hayme's tent.
Yes, Bey!
Come on.
Aunt.
-Are you fine, Gonca?
-I am fine.
Brother Tugtekin was there
just in time, aunt.
If he was a little bit late...
What did happen? Noyan's men?
Yes, father.
Korkut Bey.
Come, Gonca. Sit there.
Those muppets Hamza and Abdurrahman
were leading them.
Ertugrul's cunningness is burning us
alive even he is not here.
-What did they want?
-Ertokus Bey.
Ertokus?
Was he in that inn, too?
-Yes.
Son? You have saved his life, too?
Yes, father.
You should have invited him into tent.
He wanted to go Mother Hayme's tent first.
He went her tent even though
I have saved their lives.
He did not come to this tent,
to you, father.
Are you feeling fine, father?
I am fine. I am fine.
Come on.
Let us leave them alone
and fulfill our longing.
Come on. Let us go there.
Sit.
Tell me about news from Konya.
Saadettin Kobek did not let my father go.
He trusts him.
But if you are really curious
about Sultan's dethroning
it is just a matter of time, auntie.
You can be sure about it.
I hope so, my beautiful.
I hope they dethrones him
so my big brother gets what he wants.
How could not you and your big brother
get if you want it until now?
How are things in nomad tent, aunt?
Why did you call me so sudden?
Your Aunt Aytolun is about to impress
her seal to nomad tent.
I have no doubt about it.
I have found a decent husband
for you, Gonca.
What?
For me?
You are best, aunt.
I could not hold my laugh.
Do not lose your seriousness.
Who do you want to burn with my fire
and send to hell?
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu.
We want you to know that we feel
sorry about your lost
during Mongols attack, Mother Hayme.
Sultan Aladdin has ordered me
to give his condolences personally.
Thank you.
May God always keep Sultan Aladdin
as the head of our state.
However you suffered only one
affliction from Mongols.
You personally caused second affliction.
Discharging and exiling Ertugrul will be
second major affliction for Kayis.
I know that Ertugrul is great warrior
and a great commander.
Ertokus Bey.
We have done what it takes
for the alliance of two nomad groups.
And about my brother's exile.
He will come back to his nomad group
one day. This is a temporary decision.
Mother Hayme personally
made this decision.
I see.
I hope you are right, Gundogdu Bey.
However, I want to talk to Ertugrul Bey
about a really important matter.
Tell him that he must find me
if you see him.
Do you mind, sister Hayme?
Of course not, Korkut Bey.
There is no such thing between
Beys of two nomad groups
who is sharing a common fate.
-Welcome, Ertokus Bey.
-I am not welcomed, Korkut Bey.
What I heard made me upset
just as pains you have been through.
I hope you recant your fault
as soon as possible.
Which fault you are talking
about, Ertokus Bey?
Exile of Ertugrul.
What Ertugrul has said to you
is correct word by word.
Noyan was here to batter Alps before war.
And I am here to inspect
brave nomad groups.
I see that Noyan is causing troubles
to every nomad group.
And he is personally dealing
biggest two nomad groups.
You have the worst winter ahead of you.
Not only Erzurum's merciless cold
but also Noyan's ambushs and traps
will freeze your hearts.
I hope you leave this duty to the people
who know it best
so me and Sultan Aladdin do not
worry about here.
So you are saying to the person
who saved your life
that he is not good
at his job, Atabey Ertokus?
If I think you are not best at your job
I will just tell it.
However Ertugrul is a different person.
Only a person like Ertugrul
can overcome scumbag like Noyan.
Excuse me now.
I want to take a rest. We talk again.
-Ertokus Bey will be guest in my tent.
-Yes, Bey.
Excuse me.
Look at brave Alps of Kayi!
They came back as dogs to lick the hand
who throws them bone.
-Listen first, Noyan!
-Listen what? Listen what?
We thought you are Alps but
you have failed and came back.
You are nothing for me!
Nothing!
-Bey!
You were always talking about bravery!
But you could not capture a man!
You are dead to me anymore.
You are not different than a dead mouse.
Ertugrul Bey should know that
Ertokus wants to talk to him.
-He will know.
-How?
Ertugrul Bey supposed to go back
to Geyikli today.
Dogan's horse is quick.
It will not give any problem on road.
Dogan.
Dogan!
-Yes, Master Demir?
-I got something to say.
Thank you, Turgut Alp.
Thank you, Halime Sultan.
We should not pay it if spies of
great Mongols gave wrong information
to a great commander like Noyan.
What do you mean?
We have failed because Tugtekin knew that
you were going to send your men there.
That is not possible.
If that is not possible
what was he doing there?
If Tugtekin did not show up
we would have done it already, Bey.
If the intelligence you got from
your spies was not solid
then we are not the guilty one.
Now, kill us.
Kill us so you relax and we relax.
I do not know your spies
in Konya or nomad group.
And it is not my problem.
However I think you should be careful
before acting after you get
any intelligence from your spies.
Or Mongols could not pass the steep
mountains of Erzurum easily.
One day I will cut off your tongue
and have a feast with it.
Halime.
Do you have any news from Ertugrul?
No, I do not know where he is.
I am sure that he will be so happy, too.
When he hears about I am getting married.
Of course he will.
Which brother wouldn't be happy
to see his sister's marriage?
And you?
Will you also be happy
if my mother gives me to them?
I do not know if we see each other
after separation of nomad tents.
But I want to remember you
as a good person, Gokce.
Despite everything we have been through.
-Will you be able to do that?
-And you?
Will you be able to remember me
as a good person?
Where is Selcan?
She is sleeping, mother.
She said she does not feel well
and will not come tonight.
Fine. Make it quick, girls.
We have a lot to do.
Come on.
Ertugrul's reputation on
Sultan Alaeddin's eye is great.
For years we have been grazing our
animals, but he was in Aleppo for war.
He always led the war against Mongols.
So it is normal.
But seigniory you want to build
for years will become a dream
if Ertugrul does not lose his reputation.
Ertugrul will get the margrave
which you wanted
from Sultan Alaeddin for years.
You will solve these matters one by one.
Let us see our Tugtekin's marriage first.
Everything will be changed.
Tonight is the night.
Brothers, let me take a rest.
I will come and see you.
-Who was that commander?
-Atabey Ertokus.
What are you saying, Kocabash?
Noyan supposed to kill him?
Abdurrahman and Hamza
encountered Tugtekin.
God damn it. What will we do?
Noyan wanted to learn a secret
from Atabey Ertokus since long time.
I must find out that secret.
-How?
He will stay at Korkut Bey's tent tonight.
Tugtekin and others
will go to ask the girl.
So?
So he will be alone in tent.
And I will sneak into tent and finish it.
What is it, Dogan?
Ertokus Bey is there, Bey.
Abdurrahman and Hamza
raid Kervansaray to take him.
-And?
-He is at nomad tent now.
Nice.
It means Abdurrahman convinced Noyan.
We have sent a pigeon
into snake's nest, brother.
Ertokus Bey said Mother Hayme
that he wants to see you.
I guess it is important.
Wild Demir and Artuk Bey
wanted me to let you know.
Nobody should see that I talk to him.
You are correct but
how will it be happen, Bey?
He is going to leave with his soldiers
first thing in the morning.
-I will come to nomad tent tonight.
-What are you saying, Bey?
Listen to me carefully, Dogan.
Go to Ertokus Bey and say:
"Ertugrul Bey will meet you
near nomad group tonight."
Uncle.
Welcome. Glad to see you.
Greetings, Gundogdu.
-Welcome all.
-Greetings.
I have always heard your name
along with Ertugrul Bey, Bey.
In Konya, in Erzurum, in Malatya.
Is it possible for them not to hear
such brave guy like Gundogdu?
Not at all! Not at all!
Our bride is here.
-Welcome.
-Greetings.
Goncagul, this is Gokce.
Where is Selcan Hatun?
Selcan is sick. She is sleeping.
I did not want to wake her up.
-Get well soon.
-Thank you.
Come on, let us go inside. Come on.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Welcome.
-Greetings, sister Hayme.
Please.
My girl...
...sit down.
Come.
I want to take a walk, Alps.
I will walk alone.
Do not worry.
I am safe in friends' nomad group.
I must digest that I ate.
I heard that you are looking for me.
Ertugrul.
Ertugrul?
My brave brother.
Thanks to God I have seen you
while I am alive. That is enough for me.