Episode 60 will start after 12:36 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
You will be okay.
Help.
Help. Brother!
To nomad tent, quickly. Quick.
Raise him up, Alps.
What I wanted to say is Mother,
neither me...
...nor Sungurtekin or nomad group's
Beys have patience left.
Gundogdu...
...I told you there will be no
headquarters without Ertugrul!
Do you not hear my words?
Your words are not a remedy for our ill,
Mother.
I said it, erstwhile, I said we shall go
to Aleppo. You did not listen to me.
I said, let us not come to these lands.
You did not listen.
Neither my father nor Ertugrul
listened to me.
And what happened? I was proven right.
We have been through many disturbances,
we left many martyrs, it is enough.
You know Ertugrul's intention
from the beginning.
You know but you do not tell.
The more you keep silent
the more he goes out of line.
Mother...
...you are confusing being a substitute
for Bey and motherhood.
You have a weakness for Ertugrul.
And this weakness endangers
the continuity of the state.
Know your place, Gundogdu!
Mother...
...I have talked to Beys of the
nomad group.
They want headquarters.
Now it is time to give what you were
resigned to its owner.
Sungurtekin stands behind me, too.
I know...
...you have strove for us from the
beginning.
Yet, Ertugrul will not stop.
If there is anyone to tell him to stop,
that is me.
Did you walk over me and talk to Beys?
I am the safeguard for the nomad group to
not divide when Ertugrul returns, Mother.
And what about the brothers dividing?
Is the state dividing better
than brothers dividing?
It will break if it must.
So Sungurtekin thinks like you, too.
Both of my sons disobey me and
want to have headquarters.
Mother...
...do you not understand?
It is not about you, it is about Ertugrul.
If we do not stop him our nomad group
will divide.
Beys are awaiting me at my tent.
Do you have any last words?
Do you know what hell is, Gundogdu?
It has no branch or wood.
Each carry their own fire.
Then everyone shall see
and know your doings.
Suleyman Shah.
The day you have told about for long
has come and knocked on our door.
From now on, I have only one duty.
To keep my sons together.
To Wise Men, who found states
and destroy states...
...greetings from Artuk, on duty.
Many Beys', especially Akca Bey's leashes
are in Ameer Sadettin's hands now.
Unfortunately, Gundogdu Bey
and Sungurtekin Bey, too...
...esteem Ameer Sadettin's words.
Gundogdu Bey gathering
nomad group's Beys...
...in his tent shows he is taking action
with Sungurtekin Bey against Ertugrul.
Ertugrul Bey is scorching
in a violent fire.
Yet, I have complete faith...
...that he does not have the smallest
hesitation in keeping his promise to you.
And he will perform
this duty he took on...
...with resolution and determination
against many difficulties.
Beys, we must do what needs to be done.
It is time for all of us
to shoulder responsibility.
I will stand for the Bey position
Hayme Ana holds as a substitute...
...in the headquarters, tomorrow.
We have wanted to see you
in Bey position for long, Gundogdu Bey.
Thank you.
But it is not possible for me to do this
without your support.
We will raise our ruined unity,
order together.
Bey, you are right but there are not
a few who appeals to Ertugrul Bey.
Even though Ertugrul Bey has no claim
on being a Bey...
...he confuses people's minds,
Gundogdu Bey.
I know.
But you should know this...
...when I become Bey the first job
will be to cut these cracked voices.
Even if it is my brother who will
prevent us from having peace...
...it is my duty to stop it.
We will be one voice, one fist.
And with our state's support, we will
reach the peace we search for in Ahlat...
...shoulder to shoulder with Dodurgas,
if God permits.
What if Ertugrul Bey stands
for being the Bey of Kayi?
What will happen then?
Ertugrul Bey's craft is hunting,
headquarters is my job.
But if he lays claim as you said,
it is my part to tame him like jades.
Do not worry.
As long as we are one, Bey.
-Our vote is yours, Bey.
-Thank you.
-Let us be one, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
If I talk to Gundogdu Bey,
would he sell his horse to me?
He is counseling with his Beys
at the tent...
...he would not even listen to you, Bey.
I heard the Bey storm is brewing in Kayis.
He said he would not sell it, Bey.
You shall go on your way, search
for another horse for yourself. Go on.
Dogan!
What happened, Ertugrul?
What is Shahzade doing at the nomad group?
Brother.
Slowly, Bey, slowly.
Ertugrul, which cruel did this?
Slowly, Bey, slowly. Be careful.
Slowly, Bey.
Slowly.
How did it happen, Bey?
He fell on a sharp log.
-Hopefully, his lungs are not ruptured.
-Hopefully.
It pierced the flesh and
went all the way in.
Ertugrul, tell me, how did this happen?
Wait outside, Bey.
Ertugrul, have you lost your tongue?
Sungur did not fall on a log.
What happened to Sungur?
Tell me the truth.
Did you tell Sungur where the cave was,
brother?
How could you do it?
How could you tell where the cave was?
How could you send him to the cave
when you know what he will do to Yigit?
Answer me, first.
What happened to Sungur?
It happened when I tried to stop him
from killing Yigit.
What are you saying, Ertugrul?
Oh God!
It was not enough you thwarted
Ameer Sadettin's orders...
...and you shed your brother's blood?
O, woe to us!
Sungur attacked the cave with Alps
because of you.
I was going to prove the troubles
Noyan and Bogach brought to us...
...that they were working with Kopek!
It happened by accident when
I was trying to stop Sungur.
Ertugrul?
Gundogdu?
What happened to Sungurtekin?
Sungur is inside, struggling to stay alive
because of Ertugrul.
My God, you protect us!
What did you do, Ertugrul?
-Mother.
-He said it, Mother. Sungur said it.
He said, a brother's blood will be shed
in this nomad group because of Ertugrul...
...sooner or later.
It finally happened. Ertugrul shed his
brother's blood.
Is this true?
-Mother, listen.
-Is this true?
Shame on you!
You finally have your brother's blood
on your hands.
Shame on you.
Mother, what did you do?
How could you shoot him without...
...listening, Mother?
-Dundar, do not get involved.
Enough, that is enough...
...how can you say that
Ertugrul brother...
...intends to kill Sungurtekin?
-Dundar!
As if your slap was not enough...
...are you going to beat me up, brother?
-Enough, enough!
The seigniory fire is spreading, Mother...
...two brothers on one side
and brother Ertugrul on the other.
Go away Dundar, get out of here right now.
Sungurtekin, my son.
I will do whatever is needed,
do not worry, Mother Hayme.
Son.
Dogan Alp, Banu Cicek, prepare
a tent for Ertugrul Bey and us.
Do not worry about it, Halime Sultan.
Yigit, you will stay in Alps' tent.
Bamsi, do not leave my brother alone.
Your wish is my command, Halime Sultan.
The arrow has left the bow.
There is no hesitation, no retreat now.
We shall have no complaints.
No one should regret that...
...our task is to stand firmly
behind Ertugrul Bey until the end.
Our Bey always said that
whatever the conditions are...
...Alps shall never give up.
We shall not give up anymore, Bamsi.
We shall fight side by side
with Ertugrul Bey.
-We will, Halime Sultan.
-Go now.
Ak Tolgali.
I saw that, the one thing
that subverts a man the most...
...is neither the enemy
nor the burden on his shoulders...
...nor all his sufferings.
The thing that subverts a man the most...
...is the wound, stab in the back caused
by and the betrayal of their closest.
Not being understood ruins a brave.
Despite screaming all the facts,
no one hearing you...
...breaks the heart.
I saw it, now I know better.
They should know that we came to this
point by fighting all the obstacles...
...all the traps, all the bans
they have set for us.
And in the future that awaits us...
...we shall not back up from
a fight on the road we know is just.
In this cause,
which we are eager to die for...
...even if those who hold us back are from
our own blood, we shall not hesitate.
Whatever they do...
...whatever they try, shall be in vain.
A message came from the Supreme.
They will not be able to stop it.
Come, my brave.
Brother, I know that
my mother is making you sad.
My mother will soon realize
that it was an accident.
She is already very upset
after what she did to you.
Brother, know that from now on,
your way is my way.
Thank you, Dundar.
Thank you.
Gundogdu brother gathers
the headquarters, he is doing...
...everything possible to become a Bey.
My mother resisted, but in vain.
The seigniory fire has spread
all around the marquee.
What will we do now?
Are we going to wait without a reaction?
My brother thinks he can stop me,
if he is elected Bey.
He thinks that there will be no problem
left, if he is elected as Bey...
...but that is not the case.
Even if I stop, our enemies will not stop.
If our enemies stop, history will not.
If I keep quiet...
...and do not get involved in anything,
the reality will not change.
Even if I stop...
...the fate written
for us will surely manifest.
Whatever our brothers attempt, we shall...
...continue to fight in order to reach
our destination on the right path.
We only trust God while on the road.
We have no support other than Him.
Sungurtekin was right.
Ertugrul has his
brother's blood on his hands.
Why? Because of his stubbornness.
He drags us all into the abyss.
For God's sake, Bey.
You used to say that Sungur and
I disobeyed you. What happened?
You see the result.
If I had stopped them right at the start,
none of these would have ever happened.
Artuk Bey...
...what is the condition of my son?
-Fortunately, Ertugrul Bey made...
...the first intervention
and stopped the bleeding, Mother Hayme.
There is no vital danger. He is
going to recover soon, if God permits.
-Thank goodness!
-Brother's blood has been shed.
What use is it?
Do not throw wood to the flames, Bey.
It was an accident.
Was it an accident? Was it an accident
that Ertugrul objected to...
...Sultan's command?
Was it an accident also he revolt...
...against the Emir Saadettin?
My son.
My son, thank God!
Ertugrul.
-Do not wear yourself out, brother.
-You must stop Ertugrul.
You were right.
We now understand what happens...
...when you let Ertugrul go out of
control. Do not worry, I will stop him.
Will you take your brother's life?
How can you say that, Mother?
When did you see me go out off my way?
I will tell him that he does not have
a free hand in this tribe, that is all.
-Sungur, my son.
-Mother.
You rest.
Ertugrul and Sungurtekin fought
tooth and nail because of the Shahzade.
Sungurtekin was seriously wounded.
Then you deserve to be congratulated,
Ertugrul.
He saved me from Noyan and...
...he lost his reputation
in the eyes of his mother.
Now, he would take
Sungurtekin to the tribe.
He has drawn his sword against
his mother, as well as Gundogdu, now.
Will you go to the tribe and...
...kill Ertugrul, your highness?
-The state does not exist at all times...
...with the sword. Let us leave the
task of killing Ertugrul to his brothers.
When the time comes, Shahzade...
...and Ertugrul will come to me.
Bogac...
...tell me now...
...how did Ertugrul's Alps
find where Noyan is?
They followed us, your highness.
We could not do anything.
I cannot show tolerance
for foolishness, Bogac.
I would kill you right now...
...but thank God,
your favors are still fresh in my memory.
I hope you will do me many more favors.
You can go now.
-Peace be upon you, Artuk Bey.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
-How is my brother's health?
-Do not worry, Bey. He will heal...
...with the permission of God.
-I hope so, Artuk Bey. God bless you.
-Thank you.
Despite my mother's opposition,
my brothers have succeeded...
...in persuading the Beys
in the headquarters.
My brother Gundogdu will be
nominated for seignory to stop me.
What are you going to do?
I will join the headquarters
and be a candidate for the seigniory.
There is no return from our task.
Start working.
Do whatever we need to.
Everyone should do their own duty.
We will speak individually with
the Alps and the community.
-God bless us.
-Amen, Artuk Bey, amen.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Thank God.
Sungurtekin Bey's wound is not deep.
His liver was not torn.
If God allows, he will recover quickly.
-Thank God.
-God gives trouble and God gives the cure.
There is wisdom even in trouble
if you have faith.
Thank you, Bamsi brother.
Dervish brother. I did not see Turgut Alp.
-Is he not here?
-Yes, brother, where is Turgut?
Turgut Alp bid farewell to the people...
...and left the tribe.
When he came back to the tribe
I thought his anger had passed...
...but I see that it has not.
-My son.
-Mother.
-Water.
-Are you alright, son?
-Yes.
Thank God.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
You almost succeeded where
Noyan had failed, Ertugrul.
Noyan?
Ertugrul killed Noyan.
Thank God.
You have taken revenge of
my brother Tugtekin.
Ertugrul, I am not angry with you.
It happened.
Thank you, brother.
Take a lesson from this
and give up on your stubbornness.
Ertugrul, be with me tomorrow.
Let us get rid of these troubles
you have caused, united as one.
Did you not always say "the hunt is mine,
the headquarters is yours?"
It is time to keep your word.
We should come together
and have people say...
...Suleiman Shah's sons solve
their problems, united as one.
Both the hunt and the headquarters
will be mine.
I want you to know that I will be
a candidate for seigniory tomorrow.
With your permission, Mother.
Ertugrul, are you aware of
what you are saying?
How dare you be a candidate
for seigniory in your brother presence?
You are not hearing
your own words, brother.
As if all the trouble
you bestowed upon us is not enough...
...will you be causing discord
in the headquarters?
The enemy's biggest trick
is friendship, brother.
You are too blind to see
the discord caused by Kopek.
I will not entrust
my father's marquee on you.
What kind of a man are you, Ertugrul?
You still talk about Kopek.
Then, tomorrow you shall be
a candidate for the headquarters...
...and learn your lesson.
And know this, I will not let you destroy
the tribe my father entrusted to us.
I shall not entrust my father's will to...
...the Kopek's sedition.
This is my last word.
The arrow has left the bow.
Let us see how you will stop it without
tearing up your father's entrustment.
Ertugrul will do everything
to stop you, brother.
Do not worry, brother.
You are with me tomorrow.
Have a nice rest.
Do not worry, brother.
Turgut brother.
When I asked for Banu Cicek's hand...
...he ridiculed me and gave this weapon.
He said that he would make
a bigger weapon for me for the wedding.
Is that so, Turgut brother,
they will not see our wedding.
If God permits, brother, we will do your
wedding with Banu Cicek sister...
...when we overcome these hostilities.
And maybe Turgut can come as well.
Do not think negative.
God willing, brother.
First, we must wait
for these tough days to pass.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
When we set off on this road, did we swear
that we shall not get tired,...
...be defeated, that we shall reach
our destination whatever the cost?
Yes, we did, Bey. We did, Bey.
Now, the time has come.
I nominate myself to the Kayi seigniory.
Brothers, did I not say that
good news would come up.
This is a good news, thanks God.
Now, we are going to go to
and speak with each Alp.
I know that Kayi's future depends on them.
If we can take the Alps' support,
we can achieve our goal.
Do not worry, Bey.
I will attend the headquarters
with you, brother...
...I will not leave you alone.
Thank you, Dundar Bey.
Thank you.
Peace be upon you, Bey.
Greetings and peace be upon you,
Gundogdu Bey. Come and sit please.
I have a lot of responsibilities
but with a brave man like you...
...on my back, we will not be overcome.
Now, it is time for me to take
the burden of the Kayis on my shoulders.
You should have done it earlier,
Gundogdu Bey.
You kept quiet for Mother Hayme's sake.
As you kept quiet, Ertugrul Bey
put you in this situation.
I will be a nominee
in the headquarters tomorrow.
We shall set the path for Kayis together.
Hope for the best. Since I know that
no one can challenge you...
...I can congratulate you now.
You speak like this but tomorrow
Ertugrul will also be running.
Don't say that. How can he come forward
against his big brother? How dare he?
You do not know him. His Alps hang
on his lips, they are very loyal to him.
Even if all the Alps come together,
it is not worth as much as one Bey vote.
Do you not know that, Gundogdu Bey?
You say so but even Tugtekin Bey,
on his last breath...
...wished that Ertugrul
would root at Byzantine boundaries.
Ertugrul could even persuade
Tugtekin Bey, imagine what he can do...
...to persuade the Alps.
-What are you talking about, Gundogdu Bey?
-Do not disdain to Ertugrul.
I want to go on the path of Korkut Bey
and I would like to make...
...one fate from the two tribes, like you.
You know that it is important...
...for you to be the Kayi Bey
for Dodurgas as well.
I want you to know that
I will do anything to support you.
Thank you. Thank you.
This cradle...
...where I rocked my Sungur...
...Ertugrul and Dundar...
...is heartbroken now.
My God...
...don't let my sons...
...to be scattered like beads.
Do not put seeds of discord within
the graceful tribe of Suleiman Shah.
Take my life my God,
do not make me suffer this pain.
Do we have permission, Mother Hayme?
Come in, Abdurrahman.
-You called for me, Mother Hayme.
-Yes, take this cradle to Halime Sultan.
As you wish, Mother Hayme.
Ertugrul's words have confused
the minds of the  people.
I will talk to Beys tomorrow.
You talk to their wives.
Inquire about who their husbands
think should lead the tribe.
-Do not worry, I shall inquire tomorrow.
-Do whatever you can and soothe them.
They are all confused.
I will not give up my marquee
to Ertugrul's whims.
Ertugrul may be upset with me now
but soon he will understand me.
Thank you, Hatun.
When you become a Bey,
you can form a unity again.
The brothers can come together.
You will never be separated again.
We will always be together
and have peace, alright?
Ertugrul Bey and Halime will come
with us when you become a Bey, right?
You will convince them.
He will see the truth in people's eyes.
He will see and he will know his place.
Even if I get angry with him,
he is my brother.
But I shall do my best
for my tribe's, my marquee's unity.
Thank God.
I am always with you, Ertugrul.
please know that in this sacred path,
I am both your wife and your soldier.
You have been my biggest power
in this path, Halime.
You are the answer to prayers of
the oppressed and innocuous, Ertugrul.
What if tomorrow a misfortune
comes up and you cannot be a Bey?
When did we ever take a step back,
to take a step back this time?
Maybe we will lose the seigniory tomorrow
but we will never give up our fight.
-Can I come in?
-Come in, Abdurrahman.
I brought you something.
Put it there, Abdurrahman.
So the divine justice
has manifested at that time.
Tugtekin Bey stumbled upon Ertugrul the
dreamer and almost left Dodurga on fire.
I could not believe my ears
when Gundogdu Bey said so.
God saved Dodurga, as you stated.
If Tugtekin Bey was alive,
what would we do?
Whatever I did for Dodurgas,
surely I will do the same for Kayi.
Gundogdu is a proud man.
I understand that
he is embarrassed to come here.
But he placate my anger
with his visit to you.
Give this gold to Gundogdu.
He does not need to know that...
...these came from me, he should not know
so that your friendship can grow.
If someone like Tugtekin Bey
believes in Ertugrul's tactlessness...
...you will wake them up from
their dreams with this gold.
Alps, Ertugrul Bey is coming!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Alps, when we were children, why did we
dream the day we will hold our weapons?
Why do we fight with love even though
we know that there is death on the line?
Why do we hold a grudge to cruel?
Why do we jihad with them?
Is it not to stop the cruel...
...and make them pay for all they did...
...to the oppressed?
Our aim is provide our descendants
and fellow Muslims, serenity.
Time is entrusted to us, brothers.
The world is waiting something from us.
We shall kill it with our faith
and stand up against the tyrants.
If you are with me,
we shall destroy all of Bartin's castles.
Each of you will be a conqueror...
...and shall waive the flag of justice.
If you support me,
you will never put down your weapons.
Our flag shall not fall.
Now, I ask you,
are you with me on this road?
-In the name of the God!
Justice forever, freedom forever.
All the pain we bear, all the troubles
we face are not enough?
Why do we resist such a life
when there is a better life?
She is right, she is right.
I am asking you,
is not it our right to find peace?
Is it our destiny to wake
up an incident each new day?
Did we not come here from the land of
our ancestors for a more peaceful and...
...a more beautiful life,
for more fertile lands?
Did not we bore all that suffering
for our children...
...so that they can grow up in prosperity?
Halime Sultan, you are right but
we have no say in this. What can we do?
Our task is to help our husbands
to give the best possible decision.
Their right choice will
change the fate of all of us.
The new seigniory election
will be an opportunity for you.
Our fate will change if your men
votes for Ertugrul.
Yes, we hope.
As our numbers increase, our needs grow,
our children cannot be supported.
If Ertugrul Bey is chosen the
Bey of Kayi...
...we will possess fertile lands,
meadows and profitable markets.
We can compensate our labor.
In the name of a new justice, persuade
make your husbands to choose Ertugrul.
-Yes, yes. She is right.
-She is right.
I am telling you that
I will end this duality.
I know that my brother started
some dualities.
He is confusing people's minds.
I will put a leash on him
when I become the Bey.
Gundogdu Bey, most of the Alps think
Ertugrul Bey is right and support him.
The promises of Ertugrul Bey
have boiled the Alps' blood.
Alps want holy wars and...
...tributes. The peace you promise
will not appeal to them.
Beys, Alps call for trouble.
War only brings grief and distraught.
They will die for trophy. We need peace,
not war. Our Alps are on the wrong track.
Whatever it is, the Kayi tribe is
nothing without our Alps.
Our flags are waving thanks to them.
You are right, Alps are our everything...
...but if you do not show them
the right way as their elders...
...what can we do?
Then the fire in the Alps burns us.
There is no word that can stop the Alps.
Everyone is filled with hope
by the words of Ertugrul Bey.
With your permission.
The peace that we expected has come.
All our troubles, all our sorrows
will end when Gundogdu Bey comes...
...to this position.
You will see how strong we are,
when the two tribes are together.
-God willing!
-Turkmen tribes envy our union.
They will be jealous of
our serenity and power.
Selcan Hatun, Halime Sultan speaks
exactly the opposite.
We do not know
whom we believe Selcan Hatun.
There is nothing you do not know.
You know that Halime is my sister.
But both Halime and
her supporters are unaware...
...that they drag us
unwarily into disaster.
When Gundogdu is selected
as a Bey, we will all find peace.
-God willing! God willing!
-We will all be one.
God willing! God willing!
Brave Beys of Kayi. You know, you will not
only choose a Bey to the Kayi tribe.
Your decision will affect
the future of all Muslims...
...who have lost their holy state
under the Mongol oppression...
...all the Turkmen tribes
and the Dodurga tribe as well.
You will choose a guide for
headquarters that will lead us all.
What is happening, Artuk Bey?
Does it suit a Dodurga Bey like you
to be in a situation like this?
What did I do for you to talk like that,
Gundogdu Bey?
You are meddling in Kayi tribe's business.
This headquarters concerns both Kayi
and Dodurga and these two tribes...
...are connected to each other by fate.
Apparently, Ertugrul also
managed to persuade you.
Nobody needs to persuade anyone else.
I speak of what I know right.
Thank you, Bey. Continue to talk
about what you know right then.
I saw what I had to see.
But please let it be known that the ground
you put your trust on is shaking.
Gundogdu Bey?
Akca Bey awaits you in his marquee.
-Do I have your permission, Akca Bey?
-Yes, Gundogdu Bey.
Sit down please. I have to talk to you.
Please.
Ertugrul is very strong.
+He has hold of the Beys and will not
give up what he wants.
You have a work cut out ahead of you.
I said I would not leave you alone.
I will keep my promise.
Take these.
-What is this?
-The gold I bought when I sold my drove.
These golds are halal.
These are halal to you, Gundogdu Bey.
-No way, Akca Bey. I could not take this.
-Gundogdu Bey, we need each other.
It is not about you or me.
Thousands of people in our tents
need us.
I insist on this.
You must take these golds for
our blessed future.
As long as you are the Bey.
Halime?
When did we become like this?
What happened to us?
We all fight with the future of the Kayi.
The Kayi's future?
If we continue like this, we will all
scatter around like leaves.
Don't you see that?
We do not want separation, Selcan.
Leaving you would wound both my and
Ertugrul Bey's feelings.
However, there's nothing we can do.
Gundogdu Bey ignored Ertugrul Bey.
Do not do this, Halime Sultan.
Let us keep the unity as Bey wives.
Ertugrul Bey should visit Gundogdu Bey,
kiss his hand and beg for forgiveness.
They should unite.
We shall conduce to this good deed.
Them uniting meansthe unision of the Kayi.
What did you say? What did Ertugrul Bey
do to beg for forgiveness?
Ertugrul Bey has the same right as
Gundogdu Bey on the seigniory.
We haven't made any mistakes. Contrarily
you've always looked down upon us.
Good luck with that.
Excuse me, Selcan.
They say Ertugrul promised booty to the
Alps.
He can keep promising.
I do what I promise.
Divide these golds to the Alps equally.
Ertugrul may have the support of the Alps.
However, order cannot be established only
by words.
"We do not have any words for the Alps."
you used to say.
Now, you have something to give.
You can use the rest for the caravan
preparations.
-Thank you, Bey.
-You are welcome.
You will be on my side at the headquarters
tomorrow.
Not to worry, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Gundogdu Bey sent you gold to share.
What? Why?
-Thank you.
The future of Kayi is on your shoulders.
The future of Kayi is in your combating
hands.
Do not forget that the future of Kayi
will not be determined by outdated or
coward ideas, but by Alps
who run to death to be conquerors
like yourselves.
Our past is filled with examples of
how young people can change their future.
I am asking you now.
Are you going to be my comrades?
Excuse me Bey, I would like to say
something.
-I am listening to you.
-Gundogdu Bey, Bey.
What happened to Gundogdu Bey?
Why did you stop talking?
Gundogdu Bey gave golds to men to trick
them into choosing him.
Bismillah.
God! Bless the best for us
for our Bey, for our nomad group.
-Amen.
-Help our Bey.
In this new battle he is fighting
help him be successful, my God.
-Amen.
Sheikh.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you Sheikh.
And peace be upon you.
-Welcome.
-Thank you. Where is Ertugrul Bey?
Ertugrul Bey is at the headquarters.
Kayi nomad tent will choose its new Bey
today.
Ertugrul Bey is also aspired to be the new
Kayi Bey.
May God bless him with the best.
-Amen.
Then, let us wait for the meeting at the
headquarters to be over.
-I need to talk with Ertugrul.
-Of course.
Here you are, Sheikh.
Please be seated.
In the name of God, the beneficent, the
merciful.
The one who creates us and fills our
hearts with faith
in the 99 names of Almighty God.
Amen.
Beys, this headquarter is the first one
to choose the Bey after Suleyman Shah's
death.
Gundogdu and Ertugrul Beys put themselves
in for to be the new Kayi Bey.
-Good luck with it.
-Amen.
My gallant boys. My Beys. The best of
my tribe.
When have I ever let you go hungry that
you worry about your daily bread?
What happened, Dundar Bey?
Do you not see we are in headquarters?
I would like to use my right to join this
headquarter as a Bey...
...Gundogdu Bey.
So there are some tricks at the
headquarters.
Is this appropriate, Mother Hayme?
Dundar Bey has the right to join this
meeting like the other Beys.
Seeing that he wants to use his right,
he can join.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Before we begin the election for
the new Bey of the Kayi tribe
Do you have anything to say, Gundogdu
Bey?
Excuse me, Mother.
Our honorable Beys of my blood.
There was only one goal when we came
these lands that was unfamiliar to us
after Suleyman Shah.
We wanted a peaceful life
and we wanted to expand with the support
our state.
Unfortunately, neither of the goals were
realized.
We woke up every day with a new incident.
We long for peace.
We were just about to rebel against our
own state.
When I become a Bey
we will find peace of mind that we have
been looking for.
We will make consultation and take
decisions, then we will immigrate.
We will cement our strength with the
support of our state.
That is all I have to say for now.
He is right.
Do you have anything to say, Ertugrul Bey?
Honorable Beys of our nomad tent...
Why did we leave our Oghuz ancestor's
lands and go through
all the trouble and pain and ended up
here?
Why did we immigrate? Is it just because
of our enemies? For the grassland?
Or the fertile loams?
Was the pain that we went through
for our children
or just for our own peace of mind?
He is right.
While the people who are from our
bloodline or of the same religion
are anxious can we continue to believe in
a fake paradise?
When the lament of the opprressed have
reached the heavens
and when the cruels have seized
the sovereignty
can we concentrate on our peacefulness
without beating them at their own game?
Do you think that they will let this
happen?
The wise Beys of the Kayi' tribe
if you choose me as your new Bey, we will
be beside not only our nomad tent
but also the oppressed.
We will take the Kayi tribe to where
it belongs.
We can only get peace in this way.
Bazaars where we sell goods, fertile
plains, and fertile pastures...
It is only possible through seeing that
dream.
It is time to say new things.
If I am choosen to be the new Bey of Kayi
we will set up and perform
that justice, compassion and moral
together.
We will be responsible for anything that
goes around here.
We will not worry about livelihood and
become a shadow of anyone.
We will not buy away the consent of anyone
with the gold whose source is unknown.
We will not leave the right other than the
right way.
Everyone should know that.
That's all I've got to say.
As I can see, Ertugrul Bey does not want
us to be peaceful.
He does not wake up from his dreams.
I would not entrust my nomad tent to
Ertugrul's faddish.
These are my last words.
Keep this in mind.
One who has not dreams, has no future,
Gundogdu Bey.
Our main goal is to bring the Kayi nomad
tent where it belongs.
Not to turn it into a slave.
And these are my last words.
Thay are both right.
Thank you.
Now that our Beys have nothing more to
say, we can be continue with the election.
I will not use my vote because both
Ertugrul and Gundogdu are my sons.
Whoever wants to see Gundogdu Bey
as the new Bey of the Kayi tribe
can raise their hands.
Gundogdu Bey.
And now raise your hand if you want to see
Ertugrul Bey as the new Bey.
For the seigniory position of the Kayi
tribe
ten men chose Gundogdu Bey and
six men chose Ertugrul Bey.
So the new Kayi nomad tent Bey is
Gundogdu Bey.
Good luck with it.
-May God bless your seigniory.
-Amen.
-May you become a fair Bey.
-May God empower his will.
Amen.
-May God help him with his management.
-Amen.
-May God give him strength to do right.
May his seigniory and his marquee be
close to his people.
Amen.
May God help his marquee and his nomad
tent be victorious at all times.
Amen.
The honorable and wise Beys of my
nomad tent.
You have shown your undoutful perception
with you the decision you've made.
May God bless each and every one of you.
My marquee will be a marquee of service
as it used to be during Suleyman Shah's
reign.
From now on the pleasure is ours and the
rigor is mine.
Your sorrow is mine, your troubles are
mine.
You know that I will work for
at all times.
Also, everyone must also know that
whoever wants to divide our marquee
and whoever causes disunion
that person shall be treated in line with
our traditions.
May God grant us a permanent union and
peace.
Amen.
Bismillah...
Good luck with it, brother.
You should know that
resorting to our enemies' dirty games
whom we fight agains for the seigniory
has destoryed the Kayi marquee and the
nomad group from inside out.
Falling back on illegal ways for
the seigniory
has enabled our enemies to invade our
nomad tent.
I hope that your perception will continue
to guide you from now on.
I can no longer stay at this nomad tent.
Enjoy your new Bey.
What I need to do is leave with a handful
of people who believe in me.
You could not become a Bey in your
own tribe. Where will you go, Ertugrul?
You will be the death of those handful of
miserable people.
Just like the Prophet Ibrahim, who is a
whole ummah by himself
I will take to the road like him and I
will establish a state with these people.
Keep that in mind.
Good luck with it.
Everyone should know that
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Good luck with it.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Good luck with it.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
Hear ye! Hear ye!
Suleyman Shah's son Gundogdu Bey is
the new Bey of the Kayi nomad group.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Tomorrow we will leave this place with
the ones who believe in us.
Tell everyone. It's high time we leave.
Do not be upset, do not be disappointed.
Big victories are won with small defeats.
Even your defeat is a victory, son.
Do not forget that the defeater on this
road is the victor.
Our God says "You are ruled as you live."
Indeed, God knows what is best.
Let us take a walk. I need to talk to you.
I have been waiting for this day for
a long time, brother.
But I do not know whether I should be
happy or not.
So it was our fate to leave the brothers
that we fought together
we sat at the same table together,
we shared a dream together.
We are very upset but...
...everyone lives their own destiny,
brother.
Everyone lives their own destiny.
If it will reminds you of who you are and
where you come from
if it reminds you that you are the son of
Suleyman Shah, you can take my life.
Do you remember now, brother?
I remember.
You remind me of who I am.
You deceived our father and dragged us
into a disaster.
God!
Do not make me forget who I am.
Keep me on Suleyman Shah's path.
Protect our unity and peace.
Aykiz, Father Demir, I swore
I would keep my promise I made you.
I will take your revenge.
I am going to kill that man who caused
trouble to my people and Ertugrul Bey.
I killed Baycu Noyan
who killed our people that were our flesh
and blood.
It will be more difficult for us when the
great Mongols army arrive.
So, you have to immigrate
and to set up a nomad tent where Muslims
can be safe.
More trouble arises in peaceful lands.
Just like the the first Muslims did many
centuries ago.
Mecca's polytheists were tyrannizing the
Muslims.
They tortured to them and made their lives
miserable.
They seized the goods of the Muslims
and they insulted them in every way.
This situation became unbearable for a
handful of the Muslims.
Muslims came to our master and
complained about to this situation.
After our master listened to them
he told them to immigrate to Yesrib,
I mean Medina.
Thereupon, Muslims started preparations
for the immigration to Medina.
However, some polytheists tried to stop
them.
They threatened to kill them.
They torture them in every way imagnable
to prevent them from immigrating.
Muslims took the road with despite these
difficulties and immigrated.
Giving up their brothers, wives, mothers
and their goods and possessions...
They took the road by giving up eveything
they had.
At the end of this blessed journey they
arrived at Medina.
And they established the Islamic state of
Medina there.
They take it upon themselves to save
humanity.
The Islamic state expanded its territories
in no time.
Thanks to their immigration mankind
reached salvation.
This is the purpose of all immigrations.
Immigration is starting over when
eveything seems to be over, son.
Don't forget that this journey to take you
to your destination, not an escape.
Humankind is arefugee in this world.
Your immigration has to be an immigration
for the salvation of all mankind.
I hope, God helps you.
Amen.
I hope, God always keeps me
and my generation as the guardians of
this cause.
Amen.
May He let us live by the principles of
the holy immigration.
I will leave for Ahlat as soon as
possible.
I will choose a place where we can
find peace.
In the meantime, get on with your
preparations.
Make sure that we are not short of
anything.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
Excuse me, Bey.
Please, you can go.
Brother...
...what will happen to Ertugrul?
I understand your pain, Mother.
However, my brother is misguided.
Tonight I will host a banquet in
my marquee.
I will invite Halime Sultan and Ertugrul.
Not to worry.
As the Bey of this nomad group
I will try my best to persuade him to
give up on his obstinacy.
He will not come.
-He will not come for his stubbornness.
-He will come!
Because it is time for separation.
He will come to the table where his
brothers and his mother are dining.
This might be the last time I see
my children, my daughter-in-laws
and my grand children together.
He will come to our dinner table.
Where have you been, Ertugrul?
I was worried about you.
You once asked "What if you cannot
become the Bey of the tribe", Halime...
I've lost the elections.
But this loss will be the beginning of
various triumphs.
I feel comfortable.
There are no accounts I cannot give.
That is right, Ertugrul.
The seigniory will not bless us in our
blessed battle.
Are we supposed to give up on our dreams
because you didn't become the Bey.
It does not matter that you lost the
elections.
There are innumerable people who see
the redemption in your eyes.
At the beginning, we said "If it was
necessary we can go on our own."
I saw the fire in the Alps' eyes, Halime.
I saw that hope in the faces of the kids.
Now I know that we will not be alone.
Start your preparations right away.
Tomorrow we will go with our people
who trust and believe in us.
We will make our dreams come true.
We will leave this place honorably.
May God grant you a long life with us,
Ertugrul.
You've become the hope for the desperate
and have become spark who lost their fire.
You woke up the hearts who
had fallen asleep.
May God be with us, Halime Sultan.
Ertugrul Bey, I want to say something.
Gundogdu Bey is hosting a banquet.
He has invites us, too.
There would be no peace there anymore.
Ertugrul, your mother will be looking
forward to seeing you.
Maybe it will the the last time she will
ever see her daughter-in-laws
her grandchild and her children together.
Do not disappoint her.
Do not break her heart over this.
Ertugrul will not come, Mother.
Ertugrul brother will come.
He would not leave my mother alone
on his last night.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Come and sit, my son.
Bismillah...
This is the last bread...
...we share among ourselves.
I wanted to be together for the last time
with those who have lived in Suleyman
Shah's marquee.
If Gundogdu Bey lets me...
...I wish to express my problem...
...and keep my children together.
Do not mention it, mother.
We spend our life combating and
suffering.
But none of them...
...hurt me as much as Sungurtekin's
pain hurt me.
Now...
...two of my sons...
...will go from my nomad tent and
marquee.
The land which we will travel to will
become the future of the Oghuz Tribe.
We'll leave Suleyman Shah's noble
marquee, just like seeds
blow away when it's their time.
We will plant Kayi's flag to the farthest
ranges we can reach.
It is like the day we headed out of our
ancestral territory.
Our range will be the land where the sun
goes down.
We will not let down Islam and Oghuz's
flag, mother.
We will not let rainy days hinder my
father's marquee.
You should know, this is not only my
way, but also the Kayi's fate.
How many people do you think will
accompany you, Ertugrul?
How many miserable people will fall to
your temptations?
Above all, when you are in such
trouble...
So Ertugrul is marching towards his
death then?
As you ordered, my men will be waiting
for them on the way, Ameer.
You're nothing but a small-time with a
handful of looters, right Ertugrul?
You should complete this task,
Doruk Bey.
Whoever is next to him, kill them all.
I want you to kill his wife,
his children...
...even his horses.
I want to be done and over with it.
Your wish is my command, Ameer
Highness.
When you go to the battle, take Bogac
with you. He will help you.
After you complete your task, kill him,
too
Sadettin Kobek never forgives
betrayers.
Your wish is my command, Ameer
Majesty.
Don't do that, Ertugrul.
Back down before it's too late.
Everyone knows you are the greatest
of Alps among the Kayis.
And everyone appreciates you.
If you go, your absence will upset
all of us.
You will come to nothing, Ertugrul.
You, your Alps...
...and the women that follow you
will lose.
You will all die.
The battle is not lost when you die.
The battle is lost when we become like
enemies.
I see that you have already become
the enemies that I battled against.
By trying to strangle an innocent child...
...and by bribing Beys in the tribe
with gold...
...you have already showed me that
you're the enemy.
-Ertugrul!
-Say no more!
After all that's happened...
...how can I ask you to stay, son?
If I tell you to leave...
...how can my heart bear it?
So, in this world...
...we were meant to live in purgatory.
I've run out of words and patience,
Mother.
May God help the ones who stay or
leave.
Amen.
Ertugrul, give up the Shahzada Yigit
to the Sultan.
Otherwise you will share the same
destiny.
Do not forget this.
I have always believed in the justice of
our Sultan.
I will do whatever is needed.
Do not worry.
With your permission.
Halime.
Excuse me, Mother.
I will leave for Ahlat tomorrow.
It will be a long journey.
I'd better rest for a while.
This spoon has been waiting for you
since the day you were captured.
Even when we gave up our hope,
my mother never gave up.
My dear mother...
Esselamu aleykum ve rahmetullah.
Amen.
Almighty God..
There might be evilest in fortune we see
and goodness in the evilest.
Bless us with the good ones, God.
Expel the evilest.
Give us to good things.
Do not withdraw your support from us.
Do not let us become helpless.
Bless us with good luck and expand our
perception.
Protect them from heading towards a
disaster with the decisions they made.
Protect from falling into disuse.
Help them follow the right path.
Let us live whatever is good for us.
Certainly, it is You who knows the best...
...and it is you who predestines the best
for us.
Amen.
Do not get upset, Hatun.
We did not do anything wrong.
We saved our nomad tent from
a disaster.
It was not so, Bey.
It is very difficult to withstand
the pain of separation from Halime
Sultan, Ertugrul Bey
Dundar, and Gunduz.
Stay strong, Hatun.
We do the best we could do.
Gundogdu...
Is there no other way?
If you act nobly and tell him to stay,
he might change his mind, right?
For my sake, Bey. Give it a try
one last time.
Give my head scarf.
Alright.
Let me talk to him.
Go and see which Alps will come with
us and
how many people will accompany us
on our way.
-Your wish is my command, Bey.
-We will try every single tent, Bey.
Thank you.
You should go and talk to the women.
Not to worry, Bey. I'll take care of it.
If need be, we'll take the road with a
handful of people, as soon as possible.
I will leave for Ahlat for a new homeland.
I wanted to talk you before I go.
I'm not talking to you as the Bey
of the tribe.
I'm not having this conversation because
I don't want to lose an Alp like you.
I just wanted to tell my beloved
brother...
...to stay here.
It is too late now, brother.
Please do not do this, brother.
So not leave me, Sungur, or our mother.
We grew up together.
Our children...
...our dreams, our hopes will grow
together.
Stop with this stubbornness.
We have no common dreams,
no common hopes, brother.
You relied on the murderer who killed
Korkut Bey,
Tugtekin Bey and Gokche Hatun,
not me.
While I was struggling with that man,
what have you done?
You supported him against me.
You kept silent at all of the seditions
in my father's tent.
You gave gold to Beys just to become
a Bey.
You broke all our hopes and dreams.
Whatever determined our identity was
ripped away without consideration.
I see that...
...every cause I lead is a burden for you.
There is nothing more left to us than to
find solace remembering those
memories.
May God help you.
Brother?
-Give your blessing, brother.
-You have my blessing, brother.
Give your blessing, too.
You have my blessing.