Episode 55 will start after 12:28 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
I rose from my ashes and came Ertugrul.
To lead you and your kin to extinction.
To sear your heart.
Welcome to my hell.
You came back to die, Noyan.
Brother, help me!
Ulubilge.
Attack!
As if he vanished off
the face of the earth.
O, Bey, where have you gone?
Brother, someone is lying there.
Someone is lying there.
A Mongolian arrow.
Mongols killed him.
Horseshoe marks.
Ertugrul Bey must have come here.
He went that way.
To the horses, fast.
I came to lead your kin
to extinction, as I promised.
So come, goatherd.
By God!
You will find me...
...on every step,
on every breath you take Ertugrul.
Noyan!
Mother Hayme and
Gundogdu Bey went to Erzurum.
In what condition is
Gundogdu Bey's arm, Bogac Alp?
It is no good.
I'm told that it will be cut
unless a cure is found.
And about Ertugrul? What is his matter?
He coaxed both nomad
tribes' Beys throughout the council...
...to convince them to migrate
to Byzantine border.
-Was anyone convinced?
-No one.
All the Beys want to migrate to Ahlat.
However, Ertugrul Bey says he will
go alone, even if no one else comes.
Ertugrul is left alone in his
nomad group henceforth, Ameer Sadettin.
What is it that makes you so anxious?
Ertugrul is not a fool.
And he is certainly not a lonely lunatic.
He would not take such a way
if he has not a great power behind him.
What kind of power?
I do not know.
But I will find out at the earliest.
Why is Byzantium border
this much important to you?
There are rich lands neither Byzantium
nor Seljuk Empire have influence on.
I want them for myself, Goncagul Hatun.
How can I give this news
to Halime while she is with a child?
And my mother? She talked about
nothing else but Dundar.
My mother, who took to the roads
like a pilgrim for one of her sons...
How will she accept
her other son's absence?
Bey, catch your breath first.
We will think calmly and find a way.
How many hardships have we survived?
-We will survive this, too.
-We will.
Noyan...
...knew Dundar and Yigit were coming.
He did not lay a finger on them
when he had the chance.
That dog desire for something else.
Long live, Sungurtekin Bey!
Alps!
Because of his illness, Gundogdu Bey
gave up Lead Alp duty on his own accord.
The Headquarters
deemed me worthy of this duty.
The time has come
to make changes, to say new things.
Hereafter, the Alps'
benchmarks will change.
We will divide into sections
like the Seljukian Army does.
Every section's duty will be different.
And one will be responsible
for the duty of the section he belongs to.
We will move much like a regular army
against the forthcoming dangers.
Now, all to training!
Go on!
-Tugtekin Bey.
-Sungurtekin Bey.
May your duty be fortunate
for you and nomad group.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
Our Alps will learn a lot
from you thanks to your merits.
However, you speak as if we are in war.
Our nomad groups
may be in peace, Tugtekin Bey.
But the time of peace
is the closest time to war.
For this, our Alps
have to be ready for war at all times.
-Do I have permission, Selcan Hatun?
-Come, Turali.
Turali Alp, come.
How have you been?
-I am fine, thank you, Selcan Hatun.
-Thank God.
Do not be upset and do not be
afraid because Gundogdu Bey left.
I took an oath to protect
the women of our nomad group.
God bless!
Then your first Alp gold
is from Selcan Hatun.
Here, take it.
There is no more fear for us, from now on.
The Alps always obey Ertugrul.
If he put his mind to leaving as you said
his Alps would not leave him alone.
But, without your permission...
...neither the nomad group nor
Ertugrul can take a step, Ameer Sadettin.
You are very well aware of
the governmental tendency.
You are a smart woman. That is good.
True, whoever desires to migrate
has to knock on my door.
Still, I would not want
to let my guard down.
Both Kayi and Dodurga
will learn to obey me.
Or they will meet their match
like the rebel Turkmens.
Although, the latter
would not suit my book.
Sultan Aleaddin does not
like me being daggers drown...
...with this void of
intellect Turkmen tribe.
What will you do?
I will conquer both
nomad group's tents from inside.
Only then Ertugrul can be stopped.
Ameer Sadettin, after all that is
happened, is this possible?
Ertugrul is the hero
for both nomad groups.
It is time he has the taste of a defeat.
To one, the biggest strike
comes from his brothers.
Goncagul Hatun...
...what if I manage to sow discord
among Ertugrul and his brothers?
I'm concerned about Ertugrul Bey's
words at the headquarters yesterday.
It is an adventure to go to the lands
we do not know just when we found peace.
I sit in front of
the cachet of my ancestors.
How can I drag my people
to an unknown adventure...
...while many Dodurgans follow
the words coming out of my mouth?
I do not understand
Ertugrul Bey insisting on...
...going to Byzantium border.
Ertugrul Bey was right about everything
he said to this day, Tugtekin Bey.
You are right, he was.
But he is making a mistake now.
I hope you did not think
like him, too, Sungurtekin Bey.
It is early to talk about
such matters Tugtekin Bey.
Once my mother and brother comes
back to nomad tent unharmed...
...we will counsel.
Whatever necessary will be done.
You are right.
But you know Ertugrul Bey
better than I do, Sungurtekin Bey.
His blood runs fast.
And you know most of Kayi Alps will
follow Ertugrul Bey upon his one word.
Gundogdu Bey knows this, too.
But our path,
as Gundogdu Bey said, is Ahlat.
Beyond that is nothing
but an unripe dream.
After all the calamities,
when we found peace...
...I do not want us to get divided.
Tugtekin Bey, I think
in the same way as you.
But this is not our only problem.
As you know, too, no matter
which way our desire to migrate goes...
...Ameer Sadettin will
certainly create difficulties.
Welcome, Halime Sultan.
Thank you, Banu Cicek.
You bothered for me.
What did I even do?
Especially after all you did
for me with Ertugrul Bey.
Do not mention it.
It seems from your condition
you missed your brother very much.
Would I not? I missed him so much.
His longing fills my heart.
You cannot imagine what a joy it is...
...to know my brother will come to me.
Yet, him leaving is one trouble...
...waiting him to return
is thousands of trouble.
When you longed for this much,
and while his return is soon...
...why would waiting
be trouble, Halime Sultan?
My father and I suffered a lot
because of Yigit becoming a shahzada.
We fled from land to land to live.
We went without food and water for days.
We did not sleep in peace for once.
I always lived with the fear of something
happening to my brother and father.
Now when I am far away
from Yigit, my fears grow more.
Our state's enemies never missed a beat.
They will not, I know.
My fear is they will do
something to my brother.
That is why I worry.
The condition our state is in,
the traitors in the palace...
Yigit becoming shahzada...
My fear heightens when
I think about these.
I hope I will rejoin with my brother
without any harm coming to him.
You keep your heart at ease Halime Sultan.
You will reach your brother
alive and well, hopefully.
Hopefully. Thank you, Banu Cicek.
Dundar? Dundar, are you okay?
When Noyan strips your skin...
...I will be with him, Dundar,
the son of Suleyman Shah.
Tie them up!
Let go!
-Dundar, are you okay?
-Shut up boy!
I am fine, brother. Do not worry.
My God, grant Gundogdu Bey to me.
Give him remedy.
Do not test him with
his incapability, my God.
Sister.
Do not worry, sister.
Brother Gundogdu will find cure and return
from Erzurum with God's permitting.
I hope so, Gokce, I hope so.
I hope you will recover from
what you are going through...
...within a short time.
Gokce...
...I spoke with Tugtekin Bey.
What? What are you saying, sister?
Sister, why did you
speak with Tugtekin Bey?
I wish you had not, sister.
I know, Tugtekin Bey's anger
must have increased now.
I could not stand for you
to fade away in front of my eyes.
Should I have turned my back on your
sorrow and ignore your silent clamor?
Sister.
Please, forgive me.
I do not know what to do,
what to say anymore.
Sister.
Did Tugtekin Bey say
"I will embrace Gokce"?
Did he say he will forgive me?
Or will he continue
to burn me in the fires of hell?
Do not say that, sister.
He will eventually understand the truth.
Know this, a man's anger
is only as much as his love.
Look at Gundogdu Bey and me.
How many troubles we have
been through? How many pains we suffered?
But our love won at the end.
Eventually your love will win, too, Gokce.
Do you mean that, sister?
Does Tugtekin Bey still love me?
Surely, he does.
And do you think it only burns your heart?
His heart is ablaze, too.
His lungs burn with every breath.
I saw it in Tugtekin Bey's eyes, sister.
You stand tall.
Be fortitude.
All rivers fall into the sea.
My sister.
Halime Sultan.
Let me know if you need anything.
Thank you, Banu Cicek.
You are already exhausted enough.
My God, what is wrong with them?
Ertugrul Bey, did something happen?
What is it with you?
Dogan Alp.
Ertugrul Bey, speak, please, tell me.
Turgut.
Bamsi, speak, what happened?
Halime.
Stay strong against what I will say.
Noyan.
-Noyan kidnapped Dundar and Yigit Alp.
-What?
We couldn't catch him.
My brother! Yigit!
Halime.
-Call Artuk Bey.
-Right off, Bey.
I came to see his highness, Ameer.
Your highness Ameer,
Merchant Abdullah wishes to see you.
Merchant Abdullah, huh?
Let him come in.
You are hungry, I guess.
You are in good spirits.
So you captured those two boys.
Yes, that's right.
Moreover, Ertugrul was there, too.
Ertugrul? What was he doing there?
I do not know.
But I sent both boys to my den,
staring into Ertugrul's eyes.
Nice!
Ertugrul must not have
the face to look at his wife's face.
What about Dundar? Is Dundar alive?
What will you do with Dundar?
I want Dundar from you, Noyan.
I need Dundar.
Yigit.
Bey, Halime Sultan
is alright but she is in labour.
Let Midwife Hatun know immediately.
I will do it, Bey.
Selcan Hatun, prepare hot water.
It will be needed when midwife arrives.
I will prepare it right off.
There was still time, Artuk Bey.
But you say my child will be born early.
Did something happen to him?
Bey, keep your heart at ease.
Nothing bad happened
to your child, thank God.
Halime Sultan's sorrow
must have triggered the birth.
I hope, your child will be born in health.
I hope.
That Noyan dog will pay the price
for messing with my brothers.
How is Halime Sultan, brother?
-She is in labour, brother.
-What are you saying, Ertugrul?
Halime's excitement hastened the birth.
Is Noyan's vileness
the cause of all these?
Ertugrul, tell me. How did it happen?
Noyan knew Dundar and Yigit
would return to nomad site.
What do you think, Ertugrul Bey?
Who did he get the news from?
I do not know that but it is apparent
he took someone's help.
I will find both.
I will kill Noyan.
I promise I will kill him!
-Brother.
-Sungurtekin Bey.
Keep your fortitude.
Let us not get into a rage.
We need to take a breath and then think.
What is there to think when my brother
is in the hands of that dog, Tugtekin Bey?
We must go and find them.
I know Noyan.
He will kill Dundar.
If he was going to murder them
he would have done that on the spot.
How can you say that so comfortably?
Then why did not he do it
when he had the chance?
There is a ruse within the ruse.
It is what you say then, Ertugrul.
Do you not know
why I came here, Sadettin?
How can you ask for Dundar from me?
I took Shahzada for you.
Dundar is mine.
He will die tonight.
And the body will go to the nomad tent.
Dundar's body will only fill a grave.
But he is more valuable alive.
It will open many new graves for you.
Damn your graves!
What are you after, Sadettin?
Both nomad groups must come under my rule.
Give Dundar to me
for them to trust me, Noyan.
May you and your rule go down, Sadettin.
I am fed up with you and your games.
You will learn to be patient
if you want to take revenge, Noyan.
Besides, if it was not for me, you would
not even know about these two boys.
You would look at the nomad tent and lick
yourself like a fox looking at a hencoop.
I will make that hencoop's door wide
open for you like I gave you the kids.
-You asked for me, Bey.
-You will go to Geyikli.
He has been looking for
Noyan's den for a while.
You will trace and find that dog.
Your wish is my command, Bey.
Brother, we will take the Alps...
...and rummage
everywhere whether forest or cliff.
Ertugrul Bey, stay with Halime Sultan.
We will do what is necessary.
Tugtekin Bey is right, Ertugrul.
Sungurtekin Bey,
assign all the Alps to research.
Rummage day and night, if needed.
Let us go and prepare
the Alps without losing time.
Halime Sultan is
in the hands of Midwife from now.
When will he be born, Artuk Bey?
That depends, Bey.
It may extend to morning.
Dundar is the last key left on our
hands to open the hencoop's door.
Did you understand me, Noyan?
Hand Dundar to me.
Hand him so you can have the hencoop.
There are three Turkmen Beys
which are enemies to Sultan Aleaddin.
I have informed them.
They wish to come
and see Shahzade tomorrow.
Convince the Shahzade to become Sultan.
Do that, so all the doors
will be wide open for us.
I will take Goncagul along, too.
-Why?
-That is how I like it to be, Sadettin.
But you need to
convince her to come with you.
I do not convince anyone, Sadettin.
I take what I want and leave.
I have no doubt about that, Noyan.
No doubt.
My heart is on fire Ertugrul.
Our child arrives on a much painful day.
Do not think of troubling things.
Think of our child.
Sungurtekin Brother is
going out to search.
We will find and bring Dundar and Yigit.
Bring them both safely to the
nomad tent, would you, Ertugrul?
Ertugrul Bey, she is going into labor.
Keep your heart at ease.
I will always be with Halime Sultan.
I will do all I can for her.
Oghuz women are strong.
May God help us,
you will hold your child healthily.
Did you take the boys, Noyan?
I did.
And now, I came to take you.
Do you want me with you to convince
the Shahzade to become sultan?
I want to see you by my side, woman.
Do you absolutely need a reason?
Fate, Noyan.
Fate brought us together through revenge.
I don't believe in fate, Goncagul Hatun.
I only listen to
the humming of the desert within me.
What would the desert
inside you want, Noyan?
You will see it when you come with me.
Alps, Noyan may lay an ambush on us.
We will divide into groups in order to
not to be ambushed and save time.
I sent a group of Alps
to search the riverside.
And we will search
the forest and the rocky place.
We will leave no land stepped,
no rocks searched under.
All to their duties!
Halime!
Halime Sister, are you alright?
-Midwife Hatun!
-Let us maintain our silence.
Halime Hatun needs especially this.
Midwife Hatun, I guess
my baby is coming. I feel it.
If God permits.
There is still a little time.
-What will we do?
-Let us take you here.
Come.
Calm down.
Take deep breaths.
Calm down. Calm.
-You are alright.
-Very nice.
Calm down. Everything is alright.
You are alright, aren't you? You are.
Very nice. Take a deep breath.
What is the situation?
Our baby is on the way, Ertugrul Bey.
But Midwife says
it does not seem as if it will be easy.
Just a little patience.
Ertugrul Bey, hopefully, Halime Sultan
will give birth to your child safely.
Both nomad groups' midwifes are with her.
You should keep your heart at ease.
Thank you, Artuk Bey. Thank you.
This is the path I mentioned, Turgut Alp.
Since Ertugrul Bey knew Noyan would
be back, he ordered me to find his den.
I have been tracing for a long time.
But the only trace
I could find is on this path.
The marks are quite old.
No one lives around here.
The odd thing is...
...there are spoors of nearly 20 horses.
Apparently someone used this path.
It may be Noyan's soldiers.
They may appear before us any moment.
We will keep searching
without using the path.
And we will go back to
Sungurtekin Bey at night.
Brother, once they come before us...
...we will make them sing
like a bird and learn the den's place.
We did not come
to make anyone sing, brother.
We are here to scout.
Brother, what use a bird
that does not sing is to me?
Bamsi, we will not do anything
even if they come across us.
If they learn we came here...
...we can never find Noyan's trace again.
Do you understand, brother?
Geyikli Brother, did I understand?
You did, brother, you did.
Turgut Brother, I understood.
-Let us go.
-Come on.
Do not ever be scared, Yigit Alp.
My brothers will save us.
I am not scared for myself,
I am scared for my sister.
If something happens to me, she cannot
even be happy for her newborn child.
My mother always dreamed of eating
together with her children, too.
She waited for
my brother Sungurtekin for many years.
And now, for me.
We need to get out of here Yigit Alp.
How will that happen?
We either escape or we die.
Be ready!
-Take the dagger!
-OK.
Untie Shahzade's hands.
He will eat with us.
I have nothing to do with fools
who cannot even handle a boy.
Dundar!
Dundar, the son of Suleyman Shah.
What will happen to him
depends on you, my Shahzade.
He will either go back to
his marquee or he will breathe his last.
You will decide this
at the feast table I prepared for you.
Take him.
-Dundar!
-Let go! Let go of me!
Let go of me!
Halime Sultan, take a deep breath.
Take a deep breath.
Go on. Go on, Halime.
-Bring some more hot water.
-I will.
Go on, Halime.
Take a deep breath.
God bless.
Come on now, Halime. Come on.
Gokce Hatun, how is Halime Sultan?
Do not worry, Bey,
you will have a healthy child.
Our marquee will liven up with his voice.
Hopefully, Gokce Hatun.
Keep strong, Halime Sultan.
Take a deep breath.
Keep strong.
Selcan, are there any news from Yigit?
Do not worry, Halime.
Ertugrul will bring him safe and sound.
Think about your child, now.
You will finally hold him in
your arms, if God permits.
Selcan Hatun is right.
Who did our Beys
let them take until this day?
Now, think about your child.
Come on.
Deep, deep breaths.
We got out of many disasters.
God's willing, you will
get through these rough days, too.
If God permits, Tugtekin Bey.
Halime Hatun is trying to give birth
to your child amongst all these pains.
But I know, she will succeed.
Your love will
vitalise her, and your child.
If God permits, you will hold
your child in your arms soon, too.
If God permits.
When you accept to become sultan
you will not only take your revenge...
...on your father's murderer,
Sultan Aleaddin, my Shahzade.
You will also be the hope of
many Turkmen nomad groups...
...who are guardant to see such
a gallant sultan such as yourself.
Neither me nor my father
rebelled against our state.
You did not rebel and what happened?
They throttled your father
like a crazy shepherd's dog.
Why do you think Kara Toygar
went after you, my Shahzade?
And Afsin Bey after that.
-Send the shahzades, Ertugrul.
-And you send my father.
-What is this?
-This necklace belongs to your family.
-So you are Afsin Bey.
-That is right, Shahzade Numan.
How will I know you are him, or that
this is not Sultan Aleaddin's game?
How do you know these?
Because, Sultan Aleaddin is the one...
...who sent them both to kill your father,
Shahzade Numan, my Shahzade.
I know him quite well.
At one time, my late father
was on duty in the palace.
He told me everything.
In the end, when you were
held captive by the Ayyubids...
...Afsin Bey killed
Shahzade Numan brutally with a bowstring.
The state would not forgive this.
He took his innocent head
and covered it in wax.
Then threw it before Sultan Aleaddin.
The strange thing,
Ertugrul Bey knew everything.
However, just to ingratiate
himself to Sultan Aleaddin...
...he closed his eyes
to this brutal murder.
Where is Afsin Bey now?
He got his deserts, my Shahzade.
He never forgave himself
for killing your father.
He became miserable with remorse...
...and died in the streets
of Konya like an outcast lunatic.
My father told me how he wailed...
...that he fell into a big sin
even on his last breath.
Turkmen Beys will visit you tomorrow...
...to kiss your hand
and pay homage to you my Shahzade.
They have been
waiting for you for a long time.
What about the Mongols?
What is their benefit from this?
Noyan is serving
the Turkmen Beys, my Shahzade.
The moment you accept to become Sultan...
...he will serve you first and foremost.
God, give strength to Halime Sultan.
Ease her birth. Relieve her pains.
Bestow her with the same cure
you bestowed on St. Mary.
Reduce her pains.
Render her birth blessed.
For the sake of your name,
Healer, bestow her remedy.
Destine us to hold
our child in our arms unhurt.
Be with him. Destine us a dutiful child.
Protect him from evil, from mischief.
Keep him away from devil's malice.
Embellish his morals.
Do not deprive him from right.
Render him victorious
on the path to right.
Do not let him forget about the thousand
years of history of our ancestors.
Bless him with favors both
in this world and the other.
God, be our friend and our helper. Amen.
I placed the Alps where you said, Bey.
They will wait til dawn
without blinking an eye.
And I covered the stream bed
with Alps, Bey. Do not worry.
Thank you.
Dogan and Bamsi took
the down road. Geyikli is with them, too.
I should have gone
after him when he ran away.
I should have found him and killed him.
Bey.
We will find them.
I hope Ertugrul is right.
If Noyan wants to use the boys...
...they must be still alive.
If not...
Bey, you will return
to the nomad tent tomorrow.
If you allow me,
I would like to stay with Geyikli.
There is a road I suspect Mongols use.
I would like to stay there and keep watch.
I will stay put
even if Noyan comes across me.
Do not worry.
It is not about Noyan.
It is about finding where
Dundar and Yigit are, I know.
Keep an eye open, Turgut.
Thank you.
You need not worry.
Where did you take Dundar?
He is in a safe place, Shahzade.
If you accept to take the rein of
Turkmens as sultan, like you deserve...
...you will make the decision
about Dundar Bey.
In that case send
Dundar Bey to his nomad group.
And relay Ertugrul Bey
that I wish to talk to him...
...about my father's death
within a short time.
As you wish, my Shahzade.
How will I know Dundar Bey
went his nomad group?
You will announce you are the sultan
in a letter to Kayis and Dodurgans.
They will come and pay homage to you.
After they pay homage to you, you can go
to the nomad group and see Dundar Alp.
Then you can take Dundar Bey by your
side and wage war on Sultan Aleaddin.
What about Ertugrul Bey?
After Halime Sultan pays homage
to you, I am sure Ertugrul Bey will, too.
He will want to come and kiss your hand.
Then you can either forgive him...
...and assign him on
whichever duty you like...
....or give him his punishment
if you wish, My Shahzade.
From now on...
...I would like to
call you "sultan" as you deserve...
...instead of shahzade, Sultan.
May your sultanate be blessed.
May God bless you.
Halime Sultan, it seems
your child will be very stubborn.
He is persistent on not coming.
Halime, drink a little of this milk,
get your strength back.
Artuk Bey said to feed Halime Sultan date.
Mother Mary healed
with date while giving birth.
Go on.
I brought a cure for Halime Sultan.
It's Mother Fatma's herb, Bey.
Selcan Hatun.
We were waiting for you, Artuk Bey.
What is the situation?
Do not worry, Bey, our nomad groups'
midwifes are doing their utmost.
Selcan Hatun, put Mother Fatma herb
into warm water, it should wait.
Keep it at her bedside
and make her drink its water.
If God permits, it will be good for her.
If God permits, Bey.
I had this room prepared
for you, Goncagul Hatun.
I must admit, I was afraid when
I was coming here, Noyan.
Were you afraid of me?
Of everything that belongs to you.
Are you still afraid?
I was restless by Ameer Sadettin's side.
But now, I am where I am supposed to be.
By your side.
You mentioned me about the desert
inside you at the tavern, Noyan.
As desolate as Gobi Desert...
...as fervent as Gobi Desert.
As brutal as Gobi Desert.
Where you were born.
Did you spend your childhood there?
I have spent all my life there, until
you shared the same meal with me.
Then what does the desert inside
you whistle to your ears, Noyan?
Rain.
Now, I am living in an oasis.
Anywhere you are is my oasis.
Father!
Son. Come.
Sit.
Father.
Son.
When an animal dies its soot remains.
When a human dies his work remains.
A father's most
beautiful work is his children.
And a Bey's most beautiful work is...
...his nomad tent, tribe and his people.
If you will become a Bey
and have your name known...
....you should love and show mercy
for your people like your children.
Just as how your heart aches
and your soul shakes for your child...
...you should feel more of
it for your people, too.
Now, you, who was destined
for roads and went beyond them....
...do not desert from the road to God...
...so your children's compass
can be on the way to God.
Son. Hereafter,
it is your and your kin's duty...
...to take over the flag
our ancestors carried.
This duty is as arduous as it is supreme.
Do not quail. Do not go down.
Do not bend.
Fight until you wither, until you die.
May God grant you and your kin...
...victorious on this path.
Amen.
May it be my oath
before the God Almighty...
...the One that creates by saying it,
the One that fills our hearts with faith.
I will not quail.
I will not go down.
I will thrive.
God! I will be a father!
Thank God, who granted me with
being a wife to an Alp like you.
May God grant this union lasting.
May He not give us the pain of separation.
May he bless us
a long life with our children.
Kayi and Kinik became one in this tent.
We made two tribes one, Ertugrul Bey.
May the tribes be one
and our kin be blessed, Halime Sultan.
Where are you taking me?
Answer me!
The captive is escaping,
catch him or Noyan will skin us.
Bey. We could not find any traces.
Are you alright, Bey?
I am alright, Dogan.
Someone is coming.
Sungurtekin Bey, Ameer Sadettin Kobek
is expecting you at the tavern.
-What is it?
-We do not have an information.
But he said it was important.
Alps, go back to nomad tent.
Let other Alps search instead of you.
As you wish, Bey.
Dogan Alp.
Do not worry, young boy.
You are in good hands of Seljuk Empire.
Now, tell me. Who are you?
What were you doing with Mongols?
I am Dundar Bey, son of
Suleyman Shah from Kayi Tribe.
Noyan's soldiers were going to kill me.
I was saved thanks to your soldiers.
So you are Suleyman Shah's son.
I always appreciated what
your father did for our state.
Your brothers, too.
And who are you?
I am Sadettin Kobek,
Ameer of Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat.
I will send news to your nomad tent.
They should know you are fine.
You rest first.
Thank you, your highness, Ameer.
Noyan is waiting for you. Let us go.
What will we do, Turgut Alp?
They are going to Noyan.
We will go, too, Geyikli.
Go on.
Sultan Yigit, Turkmen Beys
came to pay homage to you.
They ask permission to kiss your hand.
Let them come.
-Welcome.
-Thank you, Sultan.
Sultan, from now on we recognize
and esteem you as our Sultan.
My nomad group and I submit to you.
We can no longer
find peace in our nomad tents.
The state needs a new leader.
We submit to you, too, Sultan.
I, Sultan Yigit, accept
your submittance to me.
You should know, as your Sultan,
I will give you the support need.
Your groups will be
introduced to peace and justice.
His Ameer ordered for you to wait here.
As I remember...
...how the Great Seljuk Empire
divided, how it fell to pieces...
...my heart swells with
a deep sorrow every time.
Brothers must always
stand shoulder to shoulder.
They must, so the state
can be everlasting.
Your brother, Sungurtekin. Dundar.
Brother.
Brother, Dundar.
My God, thanks to you. Brother.
You are fine.
You are, you are fine.
How did you run away from Noyan?
My soldiers captured
a few of them and saved Dundar Bey.
Noyan's soldiers were going to kill me.
If it was not for Ameer's soldiers,
I was dead by now, brother.
What about Yigit, where is Yigit?
-Yigit is left at Noyan's den, brother.
-Where is that den, Dundar?
They blindfolded him.
If I knew where he was, I would have
already gone and done away with Noyan.
Oh, kid.
-Let go of Master Turgut.
-Kill me if you will.
Do not be afraid, my shahzada.
These will not be done to you.
He is an innocent boy.
What do you want from him?
You are of noble blood.
The more of us he likes,
the easier it will be for us.
What did you do, Yigit?
Go to the nomad tent
and inform Ertugrul Bey.
But, Turgut Alp...
Do as I say.
Thank God. Nowruz has come and gone.
Winter was rough for everyone this year.
Now, it is time to freshen.
Time to migrate.
Turkmen nomad groups' Beys apply
to my door one by one for migration.
None from you has come yet.
They must have no time.
Your highness, Ameer, why are you
talking about this matter with me...
...and not our nomad groups' Beys?
Who would know how sensitive I am
about the matter of our migration...
...better than you, Sungurtekin Bey?
They will eventually apply to me.
It is not that you will stay
at Pasinler plain forever.
I would like you to migrate to the finest
places for your herds, for your trade.
When you go back...
...tell your Beys of these
sincere feelings of mine.
Apparently, you have already decided
on somewhere, your highness.
I had many places in mind.
However I think Ahlat
would be the most convenient.
Thank you, Ameer Sadettin.
Nomad groups' Beys would like
to migrate near Ahlat, too.
Very well.
Then begin the preparations immediately.
Yet, Ertugrul even calls me a traitor.
But I am giving his brother to him.
Hopefully everyone sees...
...how the state holds the ones
by its side in high esteem.
And send my kindest regards to
Hayme Hatun and Gundogdu Bey.
What if one wants
to migrate some place else?
Who would do
such a divisiveness, Sungurtekin Bey?
And if they attempt to do such a thing...
...I would expect you to decline first.
Suppose, someone wanted to be a divider.
I am the state here, Sungurtekin Bey.
The state showed his merciful side today.
No one should try to see
the ruthless side of the state.
I wrote a letter to Sultan Aleaddin.
I recounted what Ertugrul
did to Gumustekin Bey.
Now, I am waiting for a reply from him.
The one who punishes my margrave without
my acceptance will pay the price for it.
Whether right or wrong.
With her permission...
...I would like to speak with
Halime Sultan about Shahzada.
As you know well, this will suddenly
become the most important situation...
...that will imperil the continuity
of the state for Sultan Aleaddin.
If we cannot solve this matter
before he sets in on it...
...God forbid, we all
will be left buried under it.
Now, go. I will come to
the nomad tent after you.
May God be pleased with you.
I will not forget your kindness.
May God keep your path bright, Dundar.
Meeting a gallant young man
as yourself pleased me beyond measure.
I will always be grateful to you for
granting us my brother, Ameer Sadettin.
Thank you.
Our state will always stand by you.
You should know it.
We captured this Alp by the den, Noyan.
Turgut Alp!
I see you two serpents found each other.
-Does anyone know you came here?
-No.
But you will fall into
Ertugrul Bey's hands sooner or later.
That day...
...will be the day
you die with this woman.
You are lying.
You found out the den's place.
I bear witness,
God is the sole divinity...
...and I bear witness Mohammad
is his servant and his messenger.
His Ameer, a messenger
brought this letter.
You will pay the price for
not yielding to the state's law, Ertugrul.
You will learn who the state is here.
Do not be afraid!
Halime Sultan, hold on.
-Strive.
-There is nothing to be afraid of.
-Hang on, sister.
-Silence, ladies.
Come on now, sister.
You will hold your child in your arms.
Come on, Halime.
-God bless!
-Come on, Halime.
Hang on. Hang on, Halime.
Your child is stubborn, Halime Sultan.
But do not be afraid,
he will be mighty like his father.
-If God permits.
-Hang on.
-Go on, sister.
-Go on, child.
-We are almost there.
-Go on, Halime.
My sister, bless you.
God bless!
Thank God.
You have a child
that will continue your kin...
...continue your tribe, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
Can I go inside?
You should wait for a while.
Halime Sultan is recovering.
May God let him grow up with his parents.
Thank you, brother. Amen.
My Bey.
I hope he grows up
in health and wellness, Bey.
Thank you, Artuk Bey. Thank you.
Congratulations, Ertugrul Bey.
May he bring joy to your marquee.
May he continue your nomad group and kin.
May our Mighty God always keep you happy.
May God keep you with us. Thank you.
Ertugrul Bey.
We have a beautiful, healthy son.
Thank God, he blessed you
both to me, Halime Sultan.
Our marquee was last happy
with Dundar's voice, my Bey.
We are happy again after a long time.
My God made us merry with a hopeful gift
as him on this day of sorrow for us.
May your kin and tribe continue.
May God give a long life to your child.
Thank you, sister in law.
Thank you, My God.
Destine my son with a long life
and blessed holy wars.
Destine him to grow up with his uncles.
Ertugrul Bey. God will grant me
my brother as he did my son, too.
If God permits.
If you have sons...
...name them after Savci Alp
who died for when in war with Mongols...
...Gunduz Alp who fell martyr in my arms
and my late martyr uncle, Osman Alp.
I have always wanted the names of these
blessed valorous men to live in our kin.
If God destines and we have sons...
...may these blessed Alps' names
give honor to our kin...
...strength to our nomad group
and peace to our family.
-May God make you happy.
-Amen.
Your name will be Gunduz.
Allahu akhbar.
I cannot even be happy
to return to marquee.
What will we say to Halime Sultan?
I named my son, Gunduz.
You named him,
may God give him his age, Bey.
Thank you.
I hope Gunduz becomes
a gallant and nimble Alp as you.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
May he have a bright life
like his name, Bey.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
If God permits, your child's voice will
fill your marquee at the earliest.
If God permits.
Dundar!
God, you are almighty.
Brother.
Thank God.
You granted me my son, Gunduz
and my brother, Dundar.
You accepted my prayers. Thank God.
How did you run away from Noyan?
Ameer Sadettin saved me, brother.