Episode 42 will start after 12:35 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You have no more patience left for me...
...my existence, breathe and warmth
in your bad,...
...do you, Gundogdu Bey?
I said that I will give you a son.
I am pregnant with your baby.
I will give a brave son for the
nomad group...
...and son of a Bey for Kayi.
You will name him.
God will decide his life.
He will be the hope for the nomad group.
His father's pride.
Selcan.
Oh Selcan oh!
Permission, Gundogdu Bey?
Come in, Dumrul.
Trader Efrasiyab is here, Bey.
Let him in.
-Peace be upon you, Gundogdu Bey.
-And peace be upon you.
Welcome.
Thank you, Bey.
We prepared the golds and they will be
in the nomad group for a few days.
Very well. Then you get some rest.
Dumrul, take Efrasiyab to the guest tent.
-Welcome him in a suitable way for Kayis.
-Yes, my Bey.
Thank you, Bey.
Do not worry.
I have sealed my mouth and heart for...
...the happiness of Bey until death.
I will not step in the tent you live...
...with Bey, so Bey can be happy
and you can give him children...
...that I could not...
I will not be a shadow to your home.
But now listen to me very well, Goncagul.
If I understand that you and your...
...aunt come together and harm
a hair of Gundogdu...
...then I will kill both of you.
You know that.
And you know that, Selcan Hatun.
Do not worry.
I will give the peace and happiness
that he has forgotten.
I will give him children to make
his family proud.
I will him to remember his manhood
again...
...Selcan Hatun.
How happy you are.
You are playing with fire, Tangut.
Do not you know what a big trouble
Ertugrul is?
I will kill him.
Nobody can liberate him from me.
How do you know that he will come here?
If Noyan learns that you are
messing things up...
You shut up, Karabek.
They will be here sooner or later.
And you will fight like a man.
Or I will kill you like a whore in here.
What an ominous man!
Do not forget!
We will make equal shares.
But one of us draws a blank.
And that will be Dogan brother.
Stop it.
We should make this work done.
Come along.
Tangut!
Welcome, Ertugrul.
We were waiting for you.
Come and eat something.
Enjoy your life before you die.
You ignoble! How did you know that
we will come?
God help me!
Speak now, speak!
Tell me who is Noyan's cur in the palace?
Tell me.
I did something wrong but you forgive me,
Bey.
Talk to me.
Tell me who is Noyan's cur in the palace?
Talk to me Karabek, talk!
-Talk.
-Next will, it be you.
Talk to me, talk.
How did Tangut know that we would
come here?
There is only an answer for this.
They knew of Abdurrahman's intention.
Let us save our brother, Bey.
Noyan that I know will not hurt him
for now.
How will that be, Bey?
Abdurrahman does not know what happened.
Noyan will use Abdurrahman to kill me.
You will be the most beautiful bride
I have ever seen.
We sacrificed ourselves for the future of
Oghuz, aunt.
But mostly, you did this.
You had too much trouble with the old man.
If God permits, one day you will be
very happy, aunt.
If God permits.
I am proud to have an aunt like you.
You should know it.
I did not want to leave Bey alone
on such a day.
The needlework of your clothes that
I knit one by one.
Ornaments of your leather belt which is
light of my eyes.
You have everything that I bought
for my man,...
...valiant from Aleppo...
...to Bukhara from Diyarbakir is on you.
All is for your happiness.
Thanks to God that they will also witness
the happiness of this night.
I am happy to hear that your heart is
thrilled.
I will send you as a groom from my bed
that is poisonous as a snake...
...sharp as a dagger...
...cold as death...
...to your new love, Goncagul's bed.
Do not worry, Bey.
I hope you will be happy forever.
I hope you will find everything...
...that I could not give you love in
my bed...
...baby that she will carry...
...peace in your pure heart with her.
Selcan, I...
Go now.
May God make you happy.
I hope you will have too many children.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Come on in!
Is Tugtekin able to join us?
Tugtekin is resting. You know he is
seriously wounded.
Come on in.
Now we all are here.
Bey, Artuk Bey wants to see you.
Thank you, Dumrul.
I will come and see him soon.
I wish you could come earlier and
have a soup with us.
We came here to have a lifetime soup
with God's permission.
Our reason to be here is...
I am very sorry.
I barely come.
Welcome, nephew.
Thank you, uncle.
Come here.
Welcome, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you.
Our reason to be here is for a good thing.
We came to ask for Goncagul Hatun
daughter of Gumustekin Bey for...
...Gundogdu son according to the
command of God and word of the Prophet.
That the pure and brave heart of
Gundogdu Bey chose my daughter did...
...not only make us happy but also
my daughter, Goncagul.
I want you to know that first.
But such a blessed intention is not...
...limited that these two young persons
love finds response.
It is much more than that.
Just like our Suleyman Shah, from the
deceased Bey of Dodurga nomad tent--
May our father rest in peace.
-May he rest in peace.
-May God rest his soul.
May he rest in peace.
Amen.
If Hayme Hatun asked for this...
...and I remember that beautiful day like
yesterday.
Today is such a blessed day.
We can only wish them good luck...
...and a lifetime in a same bed.
I entrust my only child to Gundogdu Bey
without any hesitation.
I feel comfortable inside.
May God do all the things.
-Amen.
I hope they will have too many children.
-If God permits.
-Amen.
Son, I hope you will be happy.
I hope so too, mother.
May God give you happiness.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, brother.
Good luck with this, brother.
May God give them happiness, sister.
If God permits.
Good luck with that, uncle.
Thank you, nephew.
-Good luck with that, mother.
-Good luck with that, son.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
Welcome. I am sorry to trouble you.
But what I will say is important.
Don't mention it, Artuk Bey. Be my guest.
I brought greetings from your friends
who always love and support you.
They said that Ertugrul Bey is in a
blessed battle.
He fulfilled the duty that he
undertook years ago.
Go and tell him that this brave man
is not alone.
What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
I say greetings from the wise old man,
Bey.
You are one of those who is on duty.
Thanks God.
Where are they waiting?
In Ahlat, the blessed city of Turks.
Thank you.
May God bless you.
Amen.
Ertugrul came our way with his Alps.
I had to kill Karabek while he was
about to tell Sadettin Kobek's name.
How could he know that Karabek will go?
What will happen to Halime Sultan, Noyan?
Send a message to Sadettin Kobek.
Sungurtekin will not front Aleaddin.
How could he follow Karabek?
How did he know his way?
There is a traitor inside of us, Tangut.
He will give me Ertugrul just like
he gave...
...Karabek to Ertugrul.
-Welcome, my Bey.
-Thank you.
This land is a blessed land, Bey.
How could not I know that, Artuk Bey.
I opened my eyes to world in this land.
This city became our spiritual capital
since the day we came to Anatolia.
How many conquerors served here?
And our Sultan Alparslan made his
preparations before the battle...
...of Malazgirt and gathered
his army here.
To take control of this city means to...
...take control of the ancestors, Bey.
Our ancestors built too many
blessed cities.
Samarkand, Bukhara, Tabriz, Rey.
I hope that there will be
a resurrection fire again.
If God permits Bey.
With the help of God.
With 99 names of God
who filled our hearts with faith.
My valiant men from 24 tribes
of my ancestor Oghuz.
Blue sky above us and dark ground...
...witness that Turkish cities are
preparing for a great resurrection.
What kind of resurrection is this
when our union is broken and...
...Mongolians are destroying everywhere?
The darkest moment of the night is...
...the closest moment to the dawn.
Tough days will erase the laziness
and dreadfulness on us.
It will give us a new soul.
24 men of the Oghuz.
Do not forget that the state is not in the
stone buildings.
State is the spirit of Turks and every
Turk is a state.
If there is a Turk on earth...
...then it means a state for us.
Thank you, Master.
Well, what kind of way will we follow
to get rid of this much trouble?
Tonight, it is time to talk on it.
Do not forget that province goes and
tradition stays.
If a nation loses its soul then
it loses everything.
Some of us must die so one of us can live.
It will be the night to choose who will
die and who will live.
Now...
...who wants to die for true order and
who wants to die for God?
To be a martyr is inheritance of
our ancestors, old men.
While time is passing, we do not forget to
desire to be a martyr. Thank God.
-Thank God.
Valiant sons of Oghuz!
Then it is us to choose.
Are you willing to do that?
Thank you.
Then you will die in the battle...
...and you will fight.
Brothers who will die in the battle
choose your best fighters...
...and when you get our orders...
...fight with the Mongolians.
Try to be a set for Anatolia.
And you who will fight go to our lands and
conquer new places.
Now say your goodbyes.
Good luck with your fight.
Get plenty of conquests.
Ertugrul, you stay.
Ertugrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
I do not want to break anyone's hope.
But you know that we are
in a difficult situation.
And I saw the courage of many heroes
in your eyes.
I am honored and happy.
What do you say about the situation of
Turkish places and Islamic world?
This is a big test for us.
Brothers are killing each other.
And if we continue to kill each other
the enemies will continue to rule.
We buried our minds and hearts.
We lost our minds.
If a resurrection will start, we must
first regain our minds and souls.
Suleyman Shah raised you well.
We will have too many conversations
with you.
If God permits.
Now the place you will go is the next to
Byzantine.
It is a very rich and untouched place.
Try to move your nomad group in there.
Take a look there as soon as possible.
I will immediately go.
Now, good bye.
Our future will be as bright as this ring.
The nomad group cries for Ertugrul,
father.
Apparently, they see him as their savior.
While we have a leash on
Gundogdu and Tugtekin...
...Ertugrul cannot do
anything in the marquee.
It is near.
While our kids attain their desire,
Korkut will be dead and buried.
Sadettin Kobek sent a letter.
He says he trusts him completely and
will give him all the necessary support.
All Turkmen nomad groups...
...will be under the rule of
the margrave that I will establish.
Neither Sultan Alaaddin
nor Ertugrul can prevent it.
You know, father, this man does
not even give his sins away...
...without anything in return.
I cannot even imagine what you
could have done had you been born a man.
As for Sadettin Kobek,
we both want the same thing.
Ertugrul's dead body.
You did the right thing by setting up
your own tent, sister.
It would not suit you to stay
in the marquee anymore.
While my Bey's tent and my
mother's marquee cannot bear me...
...I do not want to be
a burden on anybody, Gokce.
Try to contain your poisonous tongue,
sister...
...so that you do not come down on
two newborns' houses like the plague.
The only thing that we do not know is...
...how far those ominous hands
of Ertugrul have reached.
As I said Noyan, maybe his hands
even reached within us.
Who is the traitor?
Hamza or Abdurrahman?
Let us see who he is.
As you ordered, we killed everyone, Noyan.
We brought one of them to you...
...so you can learn
what you want to learn.
Winds, wolves, birds,
all types of creepy creatures...
...whisper in my ear whatever
I need to know, Hamza.
You did not need to bother
bringing him in.
You fulfilled your duties successfully.
I know you are tired.
Go and sleep.
Tomorrow night I will meet
with my loyal dog...
...my eye and my ear
in Sultan Aladdin's palace.
I want you to join me
on this long road to Kurtbogazi.
On the road, we can
talk about the future too.
Now, I want to assign you
as commanders of a region.
You proved that you will be
fearless commanders...
...with the duties you have
completed up to today.
Is that not so, Tankut?
It is, Noyan.
Go now.
Concubines will give you a good wash.
Tomorrow come to me with full energy.
We have a long road.
Thank you!
We will see which one of them
will bring Ertugrul to me.
Aktolgali...
...will roses bloom in this land one day?
Will nightingales sing?
Will our mares, boys and girls be happy?
Will the cries of this land ever cease?
Will Mahsuns be Dilshad?
Will we be united under the crescent?
Unity and peace will be reached,
Aktolgali.
The flag of justice will be flying under
the crescent.
As long as we remain
on the side of justice.
As long as we do not lose our humanity.
As long as we keep our passion
for the cause alive.
May God lessen the burden on you,
valiant one.
Yes, mother?
I hope nothing is wrong, mother.
Is there a problem?
I have nothing else
to think about except you, son.
Thank God, we are all well.
Thankfully.
Your wedding with Goncagul is close.
May God make you and her happy
and feel the peace in both worlds.
You are the son of a Bey.
You have to do everything correctly.
Look, son, Selcan is your woman
and my daughter.
Do not throw her into a corner.
You are right. You are right, mother.
But I don't know what to do.
Always ask her how she is.
Do not neglect her.
While she is alone in her tent,
let her feel the breath of her man.
Both her and the people.
Your wish is my command, mother.
What are you saying?
Bamsi brother, get up.
I am resting, why are you rushing me?
Leave me alone, do not make me get up.
Dogan, leave Bamsi alone.
Brother!
Do not force me to take you by pieces.
I will catch you now!
Do not try to run away!
Do not try to run away, Dogan!
Come here! Dogan, come here!
Do not try to run away! Come here!
Dogan come here!
Come here!
Come here right now!
Bamsi!
Now I am burning, Bamsi brother.
Burning in flames, brother.
Burning in flames.
So, a bird of love has landed
on your heart, brother.
From now on, you will never feel at ease.
You were so ashamed.
Death is galloping towards us on
the back of a furious horse.
Being Bey and Hanim is only good
to some extent, Gokce.
Marquee is not going to be our graves...
...but it will be the cradle of
your and Tugtekin's children.
It will be a mitt to Turkmen and
home to Oghuz, if God permits.
If God permits.
As long as you stay beside your man
in hard times like these.
Bey Tugtekin is both my home
and grave, Aytolun Ana.
Hanim, I want to show some drapes
to our new bride.
-Welcome, Banu Cicek.
-Thank you, Hanim.
How is your sister who went to be
a bride of Avshar's?
-Did she recover?
-With your help, Hanim.
You came a long way, go and rest.
I guess you have things
to do in the marquee.
Maybe you heard,
the Kayis took refuge with us.
I heard, Hanim.
Due to being united with the furious
Turkmen, your job is harder than ever.
You know that.
My God, how will I approach this woman?
-Selcan Hatun.
-Yes, my Bey?
Yes, my Bey?
Even if our tents are separate...
...mother has reminded me that
you are still my woman.
She is right.
Even if I take Goncagul as my wife,
I will stay in your tent some nights.
Just so you know.
If you cannot hold your tongue and
yourself again, the situation will change.
Be warned.
What do you want?
All I want is a peaceful life with
Bey Gundogdu, Selcan Hatun!
Is there anyone preventing it?
Give him the things that
I cannot give my Bey.
Give them so that you will be happy
and age in your tent together.
If you cannot hold your tongue and
yourself, the situation will change.
Be warned!
This is not going to happen
while you are around obviously.
Go your own way, Goncagul go your own way.
I will enter the bridal chamber
with your husband, Selcan Hatun.
I do not want your shadow in my tent
or your smell in my bed. Be warned!
Because I know what kind
of a distorted woman you are.
Look at me.
I know people like you very well.
Like the dust kicked off of by a horse...
...you will turn into mud with
the first rain and smear my boots.
You will disgust me until
I go to a river and wash it off.
And then you will be forgotten for good.
Go your own way.
I do not want to break your heart.
I know that you killed that old woman.
What are you saying?
The necklace you gave her
was on her dead body.
When the poor woman did not want to
take it, you obviously killed her.
The necklace you gave her is proof.
I have it.
I did not say anything not to make you...
...more ashamed in the eyes of my Bey,
Selcan Hatun.
However, with your smallest mistake...
...Bey Gundogdu, Bey Korkut,
and Mother Hayme will learn the truth.
I would have you executed
at the headquarters, Selcan.
Stay away from us and our happiness.
Alps, Bey Gundogdu!
Valiant ones, how are you?
-Thank you, my Bey!
On one side...
...the Alps of the Kayi group...
...on the other side,
the Alps of the Dodurga group.
They are both on my side.
However...
...I want to see it for the last time.
Karakhanids...
...Ghaznevids...
...Khwarzemids...
...Seljuks of Iraq.
All of these were the sons
of the same forefather...
...the ancestors.
What happened to them?
They became a state.
However, when they became
a state they fell apart.
They let the tyrants and infidels in.
Boris, seignior of Erbil...
...Zengis, Salgurlus.
They also became seigniors.
But they could not make it either.
Sons of the same forefather and
ancestors have only one salvation.
To be united.
There is no other salvation.
This is true.
We are...
...two glorious nomad groups of Oghuz.
Until we separate our ways...
...our Alps...
...will belong to the same army,
the same tribe.
From now on...
...the Alps of two tribes do not exist.
There are only
the valiant Alps of my forefather Oghuz...
...invincible veterans...
...and martyrs of Islam.
We will face the Mongols with
this martyrdom, understood?
-Understood, my Bey!
Alright. Show it then.
May God clear your way.
God bless you!
Amen!
Gundogdu is a good commander.
However, you are as good as him.
Do not be offended.
You are the hope of the Dodurga
as he is the hope of the Kayi.
Everybody pays a price, Bey Musteki.
I paid this price with my stubbornness.
Where is Dogan?
Forgive me, my Bey.
What is happening, Dogan?
What is this tardiness?
My Bey...
...love makes one either a fool or proud.
It makes this one a fool.
Do not repeat it.
Yes, my Bey!
Alps!
Bey Tugtekin has recovered and joined us.
For Bey Tugtekin...
...for Bey Gundogdu.
-Long live Bey Gundogdu.
-Long live Bey Tugtekin.
-Long live Bey Gundogdu .
-Long live Bey Gundogdu.
-Long live Bey Tugtekin.
These are very beautiful.
This fabric will look very good on you,
Gokce Hatun.
What does not look good
on the beautiful one?
Praise be, for both of you.
We say it's nice but what will
our sweethearts say?
Hatuns, tell me,
what will a man tell his woman?
Shining brightly in a fine tone...
...my tall beauty sashays.
What else does he say?
Her cheeks are red like
blood dripped onto the snow.
What else?
The one with the tiny mouth
in which two almonds can't fit...
...her eyebrows were
drawn by calligraphists.
And her hair with color of dun.
So, set up a clear marquee
in black lands...
...may your bridal chamber bring
glory to the Oghuz tribe.
Selcan.
Selcan, are you alright my daughter?
What else does one want from God...
...after seeing the happiness of
the people she loves, mother?
For me, it is to see
the marriage of my sister and my Bey.
Han of Hans, Ogeday,
I follow every step
Noyan takes, as you ordered.
He is helpless against Ertugrul.
If it goes that way, it is not possible
for our army to pass Erzurum.
I will write you
about the precautions to be taken.
Tangut.
Tangut?
-Tangut?
-What?
Tangut. Hamza is still asleep.
But Abdurrahman is not here.
-How many coins is this, uncle?
-Five coins.
It is too much.
Who are you watching secretly?
What is this?
Are you looking for an infidel?
Shut up!
The person he is watching
is obvious, brother.
Yes, I understand, brother.
Dogan, we lost our minds in
the way of defeating infidels...
...you will lose yours in the way of love.
Why don't you go to the training stable?
Find an Alp your size and wrestle him.
-How much is this?
-I can give it to you for four coins.
It is too much.
If you are willing to buy it,
I can give it to you for three.
Brother, let it go, Banu Cicek is leaving.
Go, brother, tell your wish to her.
Go.
Go and talk to her. Go.
-Thank you. May it be easy.
-Thank you.
-The pot must be heavy, let me help you.
-No, I do not need help. Thank you.
Go and help people who are in need.
No, let me help you,
I will not feel at ease.
-Let it go.
-No, let me help.
It is not necessary, thank you.
My heart will not feel at ease,
let me take it.
Thank you for your help.
I am so sorry.
You broke the pot.
-What are you laughing at?
-What?
We just sneezed, sneezed.
What is it with you?
Go to the nomad tent
and let Ertugrul know.
Noyan will meet with his spy
in the Sultan's palace.
They will be at Kurtbogazi tomorrow night.
Bey Ertugrul's orders, it is done now,
brother Abdurrahman.
You will not go back to dishonest Noyan.
-What are you saying, Geyikli?
-Bey Ertugrul is suspicious.
He thinks that Noyan knows
what your intention is.
He wants you to go back to the nomad tent.
I know.
Bey Ertugrul thinks of me, thanks to him.
However, Noyan is not
suspicious of me. I know.
If I do not go back,
we cannot find the traitor...
...that sold the nation and the state.
What if Bey Ertugrul is right?
Does not my Bey always say
fate protects people from death?
If death comes,
what can we do as human beings?
Give greetings to my Bey and my brothers.
Hope for the best.
May God be with you.
Brother Abdurrahman.
Brothers!
I just came back from the duty
that Ertugrul Bey gave me.
But I am very bored. Why?
Because I was not able to cut
any non-Muslims.
So I have intention of going back
to nomad tent and eat some food.
Brothers, right in that time
a sound came to my ear.
I said God, finally expected
non-Muslims are coming, Bamsi.
Brothers, I got my weapon
and jump into bushes.
I said with the name of God
but person behind tree
was not a non-Muslim.
What was it?
It was a bear.
A bear!
Whatever brothers, I said, does not matter
either it is a non-Muslim or a bear.
I got my weapon, united my hands
and started to hit.
Hitting again and hitting again!
Brothers, bear escaped!
Since that day
Bamsi became a bear as well.
-Welcome, Artuk Bey.
-Thank you, my Bey, you also welcome.
-Did you bring my cure?
-Yes, I did.
Come and lay down.
I put ointment onto carbuncle on your leg.
Let it penetrate into your wound.
Come here before you go to bed
then we will clean this pus well.
In the morning we will clean
the remained part.
Then you will be recovered.
It will cure your leg.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you, my Bey.
-I hope your joy will be permanent.
-Amen, my Bey.
Thank you, my Bey.
Dogan...
...I hope nothing is wrong?
I see you silent.
He is in love, my Bey, he is in love.
My Bey, you must be tired.
But we have a guest,
a poet from Bayirbucak.
You may wish to join us.
-Welcome, brother.
-Thank you, Bey.
Begin.
Smoke collapsed
On the top of Red Mountain
Martyr's given to its land and rocks
They did not mind tears
They cried and went to Turkmen mountain
Enemies go around 45 mountains
They go and make trouble to Turkmen
Mothers and sisters cry to their martyr
They cauterized Turkmen mountain
They hit and exiled us from nomad tent
May dear God gives us strength
Even if we die
We will not renounce from here
They destroyed Turkmen mountain
Grandsons of Alparslan, Suleyman Shah
Mothers delivered them like leonine
They sacrificed their lives for us
They made Turkmen mountain home
Turkmen, do not lose your hope from God
This beautiful homeland is heritage
From forefather
There will be triumph
Write Turkmen mountain to the history
-Thank you.
-Well said, brother.
-Thank you, Bey.
I hope nothing is wrong, Geyikli?
My Bey, Abdurrahman has news.
I will not surrender to you
and your fickle aunt.
Look, daughter.
Gundogdu is son of Suleyman Shah,
brother of Ertugrul.
If we come to a bad point
it is me to cut it off.
Then I do not want you to cry.
Do you understand?
We took an oath to keep unity of Oghuz.
Do not forget it.
Do not you know until today I have
faced with many things for you, father?
Then be aware of that
I will be doing from now on.
Do not make your mother-in-law wait.
Even if I marry with Goncagul,
I will be staying in your tent some days.
You know that.
If you cannot hold your tongue
and yourself, this will change.
You know that.
What is the matter, Bey?
Abdurrahman brought news from Noyan.
Then he said he will not be suspicious
of me and left to go back there.
Then Abdurrahman must be in
a big trouble, Bey.
Noyan played his last game.
He is going to kill him.
I am sure he will
not kill him immediately.
He will enjoy of killing of Abdurrahman.
What are you thinking, Bey?
Now it is the time.
We will attack to Noyan.
-How is it going to happen?
Noyan will understand he cannot exist
in these mountains
and cannot attack to Turkmen nomad groups.
-With God's name.
Thank you.
Thanks to God
my little table keeps growing.
Became more joyful
with my brides and grooms.
If God permits Ertugrul and Halime
will be in our table.
And then Sungurtekin.
If God permits, mother. If God permits.
If God permits. If God permits.
I have heard of heroic stories of Kayi
while I have been growing from
both my father and forefather.
I have given my daughter
to this such honest and valiant
nomad group thankfully.
I will not leave anything undone.
My daughter married with a valiant
such Gundogdu Bey.
From now on, it becomes my festival.
Thank you, my Bey, thank you.
When we see marriage of
Gokce Hatun and Tugtekin
it will become our festival then.
Thank you, brother, thank you.
But do not forget that only thing
makes me happy
is not taking such a beautiful
woman, Gokce Hatun.
Dear God took my mother from me too early.
Thankfully I have two mothers now.
Dishonest Mongolians
took two of my brothers.
However my dear God gave me two brothers.
Gundogdu Bey and Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you.
I see that grief of yesterday
grows hopes of today.
I can hear powerful steps of tomorrow.
We will see the united power of
two nomad groups, if God permits.
-If God permits, if God permits.
-If God permits.
If God permits.
Stop in a place!
My head is turning because of you!
I do not know where to stop!
God knows what Noyan will do
to Abdurrahman.
Shut up!
My bey will not let Abdurrahman be wasted.
I know it.
He will find a solution.
Today I am tired.
Will you excuse me, maybe you have
things to talk with my father.
Of course, daughter. Go and rest.
Let me join you until the marquee.
For years I have been serving
to Sultan in palace.
Only thing I care was my duty.
I have not even noticed
my growing daughter.
When I returned to nomad tent,
my daughter grown up
and became in the age of being a bride.
It will not be easy for me
to get used to it.
Whatever, things I say are
just words of a father.
If Goncagul immigrates with you
I will be totally alone.
Anytime you want
we always have place for you
in our marquee, Gumustekin Bey.
When you come to nomad tent
we all hated you.
However, we became relatives now.
You are one of our family now.
Thank you.
It comes from your
great heart, Hayme Hatun.
Thank you.
Maybe disaster happened to Kayi family
became something good for being united.
You always mention of unity of
Kayi and Dodurga.
Gumustekin Bey, we got united for winter.
Do not exaggerate this brotherhood
in your eye.
We are the two nomad groups that
have most valiant men of Oghuz tribe.
Why do not keep our unity
forever, Hayme Hatun?
Unity comes from fate against
Mongolians violence
can be a good opportunity to carry us
to margrave, who knows?
You are talking about a margrave that
is connected to Seljuq Empire
and Alaeddin Sultan, right, Bey?
Of course Hayme Hatun, of course.
Strength of Kayi comes from
not bending for anyone.
Whosoever goes after this dream
I can see they will bend for
who from now on.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-Gundogdu Bey?
-Yes, Goncagul Hatun.
Know that I am thankful to dear God
due to meeting with
such a valiant like you.
I am thankful because of you as such
an understanding and discreet woman.
Thank you.
Have a nice sleep, my Bey.
You too.
Dear God, protect me from slanders
and Gundogdu Bey from sin of that
termagant woman!
You even fight with your shadow, woman.
What can I say.
God may give you wisdom.
Everybody has left, mother.
Yes, son, Gokce went to bed also.
Come and sit here.
So tell me, mother
did you think long and hard of
your bride and relative?
Gumustekin is a prestigious man
that had vital positions
in palace of Seljukian.
His respect for us is in the proper place.
Nurture of my daughter, Goncagul
pleases me.
What a mother wishes for
her son more, right?
Thank you, mother.
However...
...Gumustekin is a man
that smelled air of palace a lot.
We have seen in Aleppo.
Dirt and dust of this palace
comes front of eye of person
that disables to see
what is necessary to see.
Keep your eyes always open.
Ertugrul.
Welcome, son.
-Thank you, mother.
-Welcome, brother.
-Thank you, brother.
Son, you look tired, are you hungry?
I can prepare something to eat.
No, mother.
I have things to say to you.
Sit down.
Noyan wants to set a trap
by using Abdurrahman.
Did he learn about Abdurrahman?
You want to trap him with his own trap.
From now on, no more escaping
like a wounded bird, brother.
What are we going to do?
There is no word to say
patience in heart left.
I say to cut things with sword
that tongue cannot handle.
It is time to make a war.
You mean to attack to cantonment of Noyan?
What do you say, Gundogdu?
My brother is right.
It is obvious that he wants to hit
Noyan from both ways
with his traps and his cantonment.
Yes, I say it, brother.
Then we need to talk and persuade Beys
show the world
what can two nomad groups do
when they are united.
I gave you the opportunity of being
a honest commander
in the empire of Ogeday.
I served you all blessings of world
on a gold tray.
What did you do?
You betrayed me, Abdurrahman.
To me, Noyan.
Hell with you and empire of the world...
...corrupt dog!
I will put head of Ertugrul
and this man to the entrance
of their nomad tent!