Episode 36 will start after 12:03 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
I heard that you are looking for me.
Ertugrul.
Ertugrul?
My brave brother.
Thanks to God I have seen you
while I am alive. That is enough for me.
How are news in Konya?
What does Sultan think
about Mongols bandits?
We will send soldiers to borders
after winter.
And they will be ready for war.
He sent me first.
I am checking all the tribes
and areas that nearby.
I am going to tell all the
information I got to him.
What are you doing currently?
What is your goal now?
I heard that you declared war against
Noyan while you are in this position.
Small armies defeated big armies before.
Incompetence is my greatest power.
Noyan does not think I will attack him.
I will attack when he is least expected.
How many men do you have against Noyan?
We will be four men when Bamsi got here.
And I also have Geyikli.
I do not know what you are thinking
but I am sure that you will do
as you say despite of lack of manpower.
I heard what happened in caravansary.
What does Noyan want from you?
I also want to talk with you about this.
It also concerns you.
We had put a spy next to Ogeday.
He has worked to us for years.
They knew that there is a spy
but they did not know about his ID.
But they are so close to find that out.
What does it have to do with me?
Because that spy is your brother.
Sungurtekin.
I am glad to hear that Sungurtekin
is alive and he is not a traitor
as Noyan said.
May you live long.
My mother would be reborn if she knows it.
Do not ever tell to anyone
what I told you.
That is why Noyan wants to catch me
and make me speak.
He wants to learn about spy
and some secret information
of Seljuk Empire's army.
You come to the cranny
near Tandir Hill tomorrow.
I will show you
how to contact your brother
in case if something happens to me.
Nobody except you will know this secret.
May you live long. Do not worry.
I will be there as you asked.
God damn it!
Who was that?
Almighty God knows and sees everything.
Just like Kayis standing beside of their
brothers from Dodurga
in such hard times
made us bigger and more powerful
so I believe that our alliance
will see good things ahead of its.
-If God permits.
Alliance of two nomad groups will open
new gates in this topsy turvy world
with God's permission.
-If God permits.
-If God permits, Bey.
The long and the short of it
we are here because
we want your daughter Gokce
to our son Tugtekin
for the name of God.
First of all
it is a big honour for me and
Kayis that Dodurga Bey is here
in our tent to ask our daughter Gokce
for his son.
Thanks to God me and Suleyman Shah
have such great memories
during our lives.
Those memories were marriages
of Ertugrul and Halime
Gundogdu and my daughter-in-law Selcan.
I hope our Almighty God grants such
good marriages to our children
Tugtekin and Gokce.
-Amen.
-Amen. If God permits.
-If God permits.
I should get sherbets.
-Ertugrul.
-You did not see me.
I did not.
I know that you are going to leave soon
but there is something
that I want you to know.
Korkut Bey.
They came to ask me to his son Tugtekin.
I know that.
You should know that I am the
happiest person about it.
I want you to be happy
more than anyone else.
You think that I will get you
out of my heart, right?
Gokce, do not do that.
We have talked about it lots of times.
It hurts enough, and you...
Go now.
Do not worry. I will not
tell anyone that I saw you.
Marry to Tugtekin.
You should have a family,
children and dreams about future.
Be happy.
May God make you both happy.
-Bey.
-How are you, Turali?
-Thanks to God, Bey.
You will be a brave Alp, if God permits.
If God permits, Bey.
If God permits.
Alps, Ertokus Bey will leave early
in the morning with his soldiers.
And you will meet me at Tandir Hill.
Yes, Bey.
Bey.
Halime Sultan brought these to you.
Thank you.
Bey, it really makes me sad
that you are coming
to your nomad group like this.
Thanks to God we have a nomad group
to come, Turgut Alp.
Thanks to God.
There is nobody around here, Bey.
May God bless you.
You, too, Bey.
Thank you, Bey. Thank you.
How will it end, brother Turgut?
Victory is mine when my weapon's
steel slices my enemy.
If the enemy that my eyes cannot see,
that my weapon cannot slice
is inside of us, then...
What is it, brother?
Alps were worried that there was
one suspicious person in nomad group.
They said that they saw his shadow nearby.
I worried about you.
Thank you, Kocabash. Thank you.
But if he was here you would have already
seen his head in front of you by now.
I do not doubt it.
Excuse me.
We can come with you if you want, brother.
No, thank you. We can take care of it.
Let us hope best for everyone,
if God permits.
-If God permits.
-Amen.
Thank you, girl.
My daughter Gokce.
I and your big brother, Halime Sultan
are honoured by Korkut Bey's offer.
We think it is a blessed thing.
Of course I will make this decision
but I want to hear the excitement
we have from you, too.
It is easy to arrange it but...
...love is meant for two person.
It is a big honour for me to be a woman
of a Bey like Tugtekin.
I will also want to have
this honour all my life.
It will make me happy
that having Tugtekin's
children and life.
Since they think I am suitable for this
I would think it is my duty...
...and say yes, Mother Hayme.
Good luck.
To the people who establish states
and who demolish states.
Greetings from Artuk who is on duty.
Ertugrul found out that
his brother is alive.
Things have became more complicated
in Dodurga nomad group.
Ertugrul is still fighting
despite every challenges.
I will always keep an eye on him.
Ertugrul Bey.
Welcome, Bey. I hope there is
a good reason of you here.
There is. There is.
First of all, I am grateful of
your help saving Abdurrahman.
There will be always someone to help you
as long as you seek for justice, Bey.
Thank you.
However there is a more important matter.
We must find that traitor in nomad group
immediately, Artuk Bey.
There will be always traitors, Bey.
Always there will be.
Important thing is the act of those
whose goal is justice.
So?
So if we want to stop Mongols
we must rebel against them all together.
If you want to light that
resurrection fire
Samarkand, Bukhara and even Jerusalem
must share your dreams, Bey.
My will is your will but if we want
to light resurrection fire
we must burn traitors in that fire.
We burn traitors in that fire
so our fire's power would increase.
It is correct, Bey. Correct.
When will I see Bey during daylight again?
Every dark night has
a divine morning, Artuk Bey.
Night covers up secrets.
Day reveals secrets.
May you always be in safe.
May your secrets always stay as secrets.
Thank you.
Excuse me now, Bey. Keep your eyes open.
We need to find that traitor
in nomad group quickly.
You do not worry about it, Bey.
Day reveals all traitors.
Good luck, son.
My girl.
If God permits you will be so happy.
If God permits.
If God permits, we will arrange
your wedding soon, girl.
If God permits.
They match each other
very well, Korkut Bey.
May you have a long lasting marriage.
Thank you.
Good luck, sister.
Thank you, Bey.
I wish your sister was here to see it.
May God heal her quickly.
-Amen. Thank you, mother.
I had one child before.
Now I have two children, Korkut Bey.
I now have a daughter.
There is more.
There was one other man
who was spying on them like me.
Who?
I could not see him.
He did not see me, as well.
-How come?
Who is he working for then?
There are other things we do not know
going on in nomad group, Efrasiyab.
You should talk about it with Noyan
when you get there.
You also tell him that I have
a great gift for him.
Ertugrul and Atabey Ertokus
will meet at a place secretly.
At Tandir Hill.
Noyan's duty now is cut off their heads.
I wish Ertugrul was with us
on our happy day.
If God permits he will come
to our wedding, Mother Hayma.
If God permits, girl.
Have a good night.
-Excuse me, Mother.
-Gundogdu.
Son, do you want to talk to Selcan
one more time for this
beautiful day's sake?
I do not, mother. I have said
my thoughts. It is done.
Good evening.
Bey.
Your weapon is being sharpened
for new hunts?
My weapon always hunted since I got it.
It is always ready for war.
However your weapon's shining
differently today.
Like it is going to heal a pain.
Like it is going to be a messenger
for a reunion.
It is going to remedy such longings.
It is going to heal such pain so
my mother Hayma will see sunrise again.
We are so close to reunion with
our so longing brother Sungurtekin.
We give our life to one
who makes reunion happen
who heals the pain
who silences the evil tongue, Bey.
May your weapon live long.
May your power never end, Bey.
Thank you.
I want you to keep an eye
under every rock, every tree hole.
You do not care about normal eye.
You care about the eye of here.
Thank you.
May Hizir is your comrade,
Zulfiqar is your weapon
and Duldul is your horse, my hero.
This is what Efrasiyab told.
Nice.
Kocabash acted smartly
by not killing Ertugrul.
He has killed two birds with one stone.
I am going to capture
the best Alp of Oghuz tribes
and the best commander of Seljuk army.
Konya will be shocked
after this disgustful assassination.
-Have a good trip, Atabey Ertokus.
-Thank you.
There are always people
who is trying to get a cut
from Sultan Alaeddin's politeness
and get a position in the palace
because of political ambitions
in such difficult days.
Do not try to do anything
because of your ambitions
in the rooms of Konya Palace,
Korkut Bey.
What do you mean, Atabey Ertokus?
Your brother-in-law Gumustekin
is always nearby of Sadettin Kobek.
Everybody in palace know
what you are up to.
You stay away from political ambitions.
You can get yourself into trouble.
We have been fighting against Mongols
for years for our state and Sultan.
You are threatening my father like
you do not know about it, Atabey Ertokus.
Your son Tugtekin has already been
poisoned, Korkut Bey.
Excuse me.
He is threatening you
while looking into our eyes, Bey.
Sultan Alaeddin will not give
margrave that I want, Hatun.
They think Sultans rule the states.
You should know that ones who think
like that are always wrong, Bey.
You are talking about
Sadettin Kobek, mother?
What state makes state is
the power of Sadettin Kobek
and other statesmen like him.
Politics is also a war, Bey.
As you know, my brother Gumustekin
knows it by heart.
He has been working in Konya such long
time for you and for our nomad group.
He will not be returned
without your request.
What is wrong with you, Selcan?
It is nothing, Halime.
It is nothing anymore.
I dreamed about history.
I was so happy the day
I was going to marry my Gundogdu.
I was very happy.
But now we have separated our tents.
Heavens fell down on me.
And my sister is marrying someone
who I do not want.
Every cloud has a silver lining, Selcan.
You do not worry.
Only silver lining in this cloud
is for you, Halime.
Selcan.
I know that storm in the heart
of Gokce is not finishing.
I also know that you want to be the wife
of Ertugrul Bey if it is up to you.
Let us hope for the best, Selcan.
You will be together again once
Gundogdu Bey is calm down.
It is different this time, Halime.
We have great cliffs between us.
My Gundogdu's eyes do not look as they
were before even he is so angry.
Who knows?
Maybe Bey loves someone else.
So Sungurtekin is the spy
inside of Ogeday.
He has cheated all of us for years.
Even you.
All the children of Suleyman Shah
are going to die.
Sungurtekin. Gundogdu. Dundar.
And of course Ertugrul.
Ogeday will be so happy
when he finds out spy's identity.
Of course he will be happy.
But I gave that Sungurtekin
bastard to Ogeday.
It seems that I will set the cat
among the pigeons.
Ogeday will ask for it.
These Kayis have made my life
really hard, Ulubilge.
So I have to turn their world into hell.
Write it down, Ulubilge.
We must deliver
this information immediately.
-You wait here.
-Yes, Bey.
-Nobody moves.
Death is here for you.
Ogeday is about to win against China.
He will come to Anatolia soon.
May you live long, Sungurtekin Bey.
If God permits you will not become
martyr before meeting your family.
Be careful!
Hamza! Ertokus is escaping.
Follow him with Abdurrahman.
Do not forget that Noyan wants him alive.
I will stay here with my men
and take care of Ertugrul.
Abdurrahman, let us go! Come on!
Soldier. Soldier.
Traitors.
It is me. Ertugrul Bey from Kayis.
You are all traitors.
Kayis will pay for their betrayal.
Traitors!
You are all traitors!
Unskillfuls!
Here we are again, Ertugrul.
Here we are again, Tangut.
You cannot escape from us.
You cannot get rid of Ertugrul.
Atabey Ertokus!
Lay down arms!
How did you find here?
It was impossible for you to follow!
Noyan has told us your location.
Ertugrul was right.
There is a traitor in nomad group.
I said drop your sword.
Come and take it.
Abdurrahman.
Do not forget. Noyan wants him alive.
You will pay for it, scumbag traitors!
You are done this time, Ertugrul!
Atabey Ertokus is not here.
That asshat run away by horse, Bey.
Who is he, Bey?
Tangut. Noyan's right hand.
It seems that
they took Atabey Ertokus alive.
Hamza and traitor Alps did it.
That traitor in nomad group.
They must have followed us last night.
We must rescue Atabey Ertokus.
Gokce Hatun.
-Have a good day, Bey.
-Have a good day, Gokce.
Last night was the best night of my life.
Especially your words to my parents
have been scratched
into my heart forever.
I have always seen the kindness in your
heart when I looked into your eyes.
I have devoted my life to you from now on.
Excuse me.
Wedding is close.
If you act quickly
we may have a double wedding.
Are you so sure that Gundogdu wants me?
After spending so many years
with that woman whose inside
is so drought like desert
your youth and beauty
will petrify my Gundogdu.
You will be his mirage.
He could not take his eyes from you
last night. Did not you see it?
Is it true that him and Selcan Hatun
separated their beds?
Separation? If there was not Kocabash
Gundogdu was going be a killer.
He was going to cut off her head.
He has saved that
shameless woman last minute.
If I were Selcan
I would have gone already.
But she is so indecent.
She will do anything to be in his face.
My job is hard then.
You have no idea.
What should I do, aunt?
Give Gundogdu a little bit of courage.
Then rest will be easy and quick.
I will do anything that I can, aunt.
Since we are going to let Kayis
into our nomad group
since we will be stronger
and take margrave that we deserve
then I will do what it takes.
But I will do it my way, aunt.
Selcan Hatun hates you.
Hayma and Halime
are keeping their distant.
We will lose if we do it your way.
How will you approach them?
Geyikli?
Bey, following path is not an open road.
I saw Abdurrahman and Hamza.
They took Atabey Ertokus as prisoner.
They are taking him to Noyan.
But you should not follow them.
There are Noyan's soldiers around.
There are too many of them.
I say we should wait for Abdurrahman
in my poor house.
Gokce Hatun!
Have a good day, Gokce Hatun.
You, too, Goncagul.
I have thought a lot last night, Gokce.
I have lived in palace in Konya
with my father since long time.
I am so afraid what if I cannot live
nomad group's life?
What if I cannot take it?
But it was not like that.
Thank God it was not like that.
I just missed this life.
I got my courage when I saw that I have
relatives like you and I got happier.
Welcome aboard, Gokce Hatun.
Thank you.
May God give you a Bey
like Tugtekin, Goncagul.
I hope so.
How is palace, Goncagul?
It is like heaven.
It hypnotises you. It holds you in
and never let you go again.
Until an enemy comes
and stabs you in the back.
So it is no different
than our nomad group.
I am glad you think like that, Selcan.
This is the best move for everyone, girl.
My beautiful mother.
I know that you have doubts.
I can see that.
But you must know that
you did the right thing, mother.
May God give them a happy life.
If God permits, girl.
-May we come in, Mother Hayma?
-Come, girl.
Welcome, girl. Come.
Greetings.
I have brought gifts from Konya.
I have chosen these gifts with my father
who loves and respect you.
You should not have to bother, girl.
These are for babies
of Halime Sultan and Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you. You should not have.
I am honoured to take these gifts
on behalf of Ertugrul Bey.
May you live long, Goncagul Hatun.
Excuse me, mother.
Did I say something wrong?
No.
She is sad about Ertugrul's situation.
I do not know what to say.
You have made us really happy
with these gifts, girl.
Thank you.
-If I made Halime Sultan sad...
-No. It is not about you.
There is no such thing.
You are in the family now.
We shared our fate in good and bad days.
I cannot thank God enough
since I have relatives like you.
I am so happy after the blissfulness
that we had last night.
How many days of road left?
We will be there in one day, Bey.
-Dervish.
-Yes, sheikh?
You have been my comrade for long years.
You know what it means to be on roads
and to be comrade?
What is it, Bey?
Sirat-i mustakim, son.
Which means right path.
If we serve to God only,
if we ask for help from God only
it means we are on the right path.
If we walk for reputation and cruelty
we would be out of our path.
May God let us not leave our path.
-Amen.
We would become like this
if we leave our path.
Give a hand.
-Raise your head.
-He is wounded badly.
-Who are you people?
-Who are you?
You bled a lot.
-I have been attacked.
If God permits.
So you have enemies.
Bandits attacked me.
So you do not walk on right path.
We have come this far but we did
not see any bandits or tyrants.
Son, you would get more wound
if your path is not right.
Who are you? Where do you come and go?
We come from there to go where.
You are weak. Do not torture yourself.
I must go.
I must go. I must go.
-Sheikh.
Let him go, dervish. He must go his way.
Let him go.
Give him water.
-I will not forget this favor of yours.
-Alright.
Bey, why did we let him go like this?
He has something that belongs to us.
I hope he will take it to us.
Thank God, our nomad group
is at peace a little bit.
I wish Ertugrul was here, too.
My peace will be clinched.
He should come back, sister.
There is no resentment anymore.
Only Alps know where Ertugrul is.
And they would not tell you
even if you kill them.
It seems that Ertugrul
is not going to return
in order not to give
any harm to nomad group.
I hope he will not cause
new troubles to us.
I think we should arrange a big wedding
for Tugtekin and Gokce.
We should, brother.
This wedding would refresh
and clean our nomad groups.
If God permits.
By the way, sister
since we have peace
in our nomad group again
Kayi Alps should wear their weapons.
What is going on, Dogan?
I am laughing about these infidels
always chasing us.
I do not know if infidels are chasing us
or we are stirring up infidels' nest?
Titus, Ustad, Kurdoglu.
Now Noyan. And also Tangut.
-So?
We are killing these guys
but are they having a chat in hell?
"How did Ertugrul Bey kill us?
How did Turgut chop us with his axe?
How did Dogan hunt us like bird?"
Brother, you have became like Bamsi.
If Bamsi was here it
would not be enough for him.
He would say, "I will go to hell
and kick their asses."
He would even go to hell
to kick their asses.
We miss brother Bamsi.
It is only a matter of time
that he would be here soon.
He would say,
"What have you done without me?"
I hope he would be here without any harm.
Alps.
Traitor in nomad group annoys us.
We are not in comfort till we find him.
We took a big step in order to
socialize two nomad groups, Aytolun.
Thanks to you.
Two kids love each other, Bey.
It is a good thing so we lead this.
I hope rest would be
happen as you want, Bey.
When it is time two nomad groups
will be sharing a common fate.
Let us hope you get the margrave.
It will not so easy
to convince Sultan Alaeddin.
You should be patient, Bey.
You will get what you want.
My brother Gumustekin
will not be returned
from Konya without your request.
Mother Hayme.
What will I do without you?
My beautiful girl.
I will be always there for you.
Mother Hayme.
What if I could not get pregnant
because of that evil knife
that was stabbed to my body?
What if I cannot give a baby
to my husband?
My daughter Gokce.
Sometimes a knife takes out pus
from a wound.
Only God know about it.
We just need to walk on right path.
Come on, have a nice sleep. Okay?
I want to see you happy
more than anyone else.
You should have children
and dreams about future.
We will both be fine, Gokce.
From now on, no more crying.
No more love pain.
I will have love, they will have pain.
My revenge will keep me alive.
Gundogdu Bey.
Good morning, Goncagul Hatun.
Good morning, Gundogdu Bey.
I have heard that you are taking care
of trades of our nomad groups.
That's correct.
As you know, I was in Konya last
five years because of my father's work.
On this wise I have written
and read his letters.
I have tried to help him
with his work as much as I can.
If you want to make use of my literacy
I want you to know that
I want to help you as much as I can.
By the way, I know how to speak
Persian and Greek a little bit.
That's wonderful. What can I say?
That was just I needed.
Serving a Bey like you will
make me so happy, Bey.
Do not mention it. Excuse me.
Base is waiting for me.
Goncagul Hatun.
Yes, Selcan Hatun?
I want to talk to you about a matter.
Sure.
I sometimes went against to your aunt
due to nomad group's matters.
Since Tugtekin is going to marry
my sister Gokce
I think we should end this
disagreeableness between us.
You are a nice girl. Maybe I...
You do not worry, Selcan Hatun.
My Aunt and you are very nice people.
This marriage will unite us all.
I am so happy to hearing this from you.
-Thank you.
So Efrasiyab have seen
all goods we have one by one.
He knows every animal in our flock.
He knows animals by their teeth.
He also knows us better than us.
He knows that we are man of our word.
So I say that we should accept his offer.
But only under one condition.
He will pay coins in advance.
There is no way to sell our animals
and goods using any other way
in such times that bandits are all around.
I think you are right, Gundogdu Bey.
Gumustekin Bey.
Welcome to your nomad group, Bey.
When I see you in such townee dress...
-Is Korkut Bey in his marquee?
We have not expected you too soon, Bey.
They are in headquarters with Kayi Beys.
You have talked about what is right.
I also think it is okay.
Beys, do you have anything to say?
-It is okay, Bey.
It is okay, Bey.
Then good luck to all of us.
-Good luck.
-Thank you. Good luck.
-Thank you.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Welcome to your nomad group,
Gumustekin Bey.
Welcome, Gumustekin Bey.
You have not changed in years.
You are always same.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
Thank you, Korkut Bey.
However I do not have good news.
Sit down first. You have come a long way.
Bring ayran to Gumustekin Bey.
Brave Beys of two nomad groups.
As you know last three years
I was on duty at Konya palace
as our state's request.
I left my nomad tent
and served for Sultan
with the permission from Korkut Bey.
Of course I am honored to do my duty.
Especially fighting against
infidel Mongols.
I have seen a lot,
I have experienced a lot.
My duty at palace is finished now.
I left Konya and was happy
to be appointed in my nomad group
till war day by Sultan's order.
However, I have never thought that
I was going to have
such contemptibleness,
such shame, such pain!
What did happen, Gumustekin Bey? Tell us.
They have attacked Ertokus Bey
and his soldiers on their way.
What are you saying, Gumustekin Bey?
They have just left nomad group
safe and sound yesterday.
A soldier who survived the attack
came to Seljuk headquarters
and told us what happened.
I could not believe what I have heard.
I personally went there.
They slaughtered young boys
without hesitation!
And Atabey Ertokus?
He was not there.
It seems that they captured him.
Who is responsible for this
contemptibleness? Mongols?
I wish they were, Bey.
I wish they were
so we would console ourselves
by thinking their shahada.
Who then? Who was it then?
Talk to us, man!
Do not go all round the houses!
Who did this contemptibleness?
Ertugrul and his Alps!
Know your place, Gumustekin!
Stop right there!
The one who is saying that my son is
involved such contemptibleness
must be looking for some disorder!
I will make that person pay
for his slander.
-No way! It must be a lie!
-It is a slander!
Ertugrul Bey does not do that!
Thank God, marquee customs and state
manners taught us our place, Mother Hayme.
That soldier who survived says that
he saw Ertugrul.
I also could not believe it. But then
I went there and saw with my eyes.
What did you see?
Kayis' arrows, Alps who died
and their weapons.
You can go there if you wish
and see it with your eyes.
12 Alps have betrayed us
and joined Noyan's army.
It is obvious that these belong to them.
My brother never involves
in such betrayal.
Did this soldier see that Ertugrul Bey
do it and slander him?
Yes, he personally saw it.
That he was walking among wounded
and taking lives.
I cannot believe it.
Sultan's stooge Saadettin Kobek
was also there
while soldier was telling about
what he saw.
And this is his order.
What does it say...
...Bey?
Ertugrul will be slaughtered
as he is seen.
That is enough!
Enough!
I will find the truth behind it.
My son is about to victim of a slander.
I will never let it happen.
Gumustekin is not a random man, mother.
He is an important commander
who has served for Alaeddin.
I do not care about who he is, son.
Nobody can convince me that
Ertugrul killed them.
And capturing Ertokus?
They fought against Mongols together.
They are friends from war.
They are lying. Lying.
Mother, I will not believe
even if my brother would confess it.
That's an obvious conspiracy for him.
This conspiracy is not just for him,
it is for all of us.
Mongols themselves
who organized this conspiracy.
If what you said is true
then Mongols' evil hand
reached out to the palace of Alaeddin.
-Is it true, mother?
-It is true, girl.
Now palace's coyotes are trying to claw
my hero who has been left alone
by his mother, father and nomad group?
What do you know about it, Halime Sultan?
All I know is this, Gundogdu Bey.
You made him fell a prey to wolfs
and birds with his hand
which can not hold a sword.
You threw him away in front of Noyan.
May good things happen to us.
To the people who establish states
and who demolish states.
Greetings from Artuk who is on duty.
Things in Dodurga nomad group
got completely mixed up.
Ertugrul is accused by
slaughtering of Ertokus.
Artuk who is your eye that sees
says that Ertugrul is innocent.
Duty will be carried out when you order.
Come on, little bird.
It is time for you to fly.
I will leave to collect herbs.
Get the horse.
Gundogdu Bey is really important to us.
We must take him to our side.
Do not offend him, brother.
Father.
-Welcome.
-Greetings, girl.
And as I told you
Gundogdu is the best son-in-law
you would ever have, brother.
He seems like a truthful person.
What if he gets in our way in the future?
There is always a groom for
a beautiful lady like Goncagul, brother.
What do you think, girl?
I think just like my aunt, father.
He will be one of the closest brave guys
next to you when we got margrave.
How much we can rely on
that soldier's words, Gumustekin?
Ertugrul does not do such thing.
You also know that.
I only rely on my eyes and state's order
that Saadettin Kobek affixes a seal, Bey.
I said that we should unite against enemy.
I have estranged my children,
my daughter-in-laws...
...from myself one by one.
Bey.
Our nomad group is in pain
than ever before.
Betrayals. Cruelty.
It is not about unite after all.
It is about becoming one heart.
One heart.
How will it happen
while our heart is bleeding?
Mother. Are you okay, mother?
I am fine. I am fine, son.
If we do not find Ertugrul
and solve this situation
Kayis will fall apart.
If something happens to Ertugrul
our nomad group and marquee
would collapse, mother.
Mother.
It is Halime.
I cannot find her.
She took her horse and left.
Bey, excuse us.
What are you doing here, Halime?
We have talked about it.
You were not supposed to be here.
It is too dangerous here.
Seljuk Empire released a statement
about you, Ertugrul.
I knew it.
Who had this information?
Aytolun Hatun's brother. Gumustekin.
Welcome, Bey.
Gumustekin! I want to talk to you.
Gundogdu, Gundogdu.
I know that you are mad at me.
I know your deceased father
and brother Ertugrul very well.
I have loved and respected both.
I have always witnessed
how they gave power to Oghuz.
Then you should know that my brother
did not play a part in this.
I want to believe that with all my heart.
I have been praying to God so it
was not be like that since I heard it.
Gumustekin, my brother is innocent
and I am going to prove this.
Ertugrul will not be executed
without a trial. He could not be.
Our state is not bandit.
However if he would not be surrender
and walking in the mountains
soldiers will capture him.
Then I can not do anything.
Do your job as his brother.
Get him so he will stand trial.
The sword of customs has no scabbard.
He would get his reputation back
if he is innocent.
It is the time for you
to be a brother, Gundogdu.
Get him and bring him to justice.
What will we do now, Ertugrul?
How will we escape from this swamp?
You do not worry, Halime Sultan.
God is the greatest game spoiler.
Every situation is against you, Ertugrul.
You are accused of killing
soldiers of Seljuk Empire
while we have Mongols evilness.
Enemy always after me since I have set
my heart on this path, Halime Sultan.
As long as they are after me
I will continue to be death of them.
Bustle, fear, hopelessness are unmanly.
Go back to your nomad group.
Do not tell anyone that you talked to me.
There is a traitor in nomad group.
Everybody should keep their eyes open.
I will do my best
to reveal the truth, Ertugrul.
But you should not keep me away
from yourself in this war you started.
Let us become martyr together
if it is in our destiny.
We remain separate on this world but
we shall come together on other world.
Separation glorifies love, Halime Sultan.
But destiny is in love with endeavour.
We will endeavor so our enemies
will go down on their knees.
We will endeavor
so traps will be collapsed.
so justice will be served.
Loser!
How did he slip through your fingers?
Alps were there with their arrows!
I also got wounded!
Why did not you get killed
and come back to me?
So I kill you?
Where is Ertokus?
What did happen to him?
Ertokus is here, Bey.
Let go! Let go!
I have finally got you, Atabey Ertokus.
Gundogdu Bey.
I have read the order.
It says that they will catch him and
take him to trial.
And if he resists it is permitted
to kill him.
I know that.
I have talked to your father.
Gundogdu Bey.
My father devoted his life to
his state and the union of Oghuzs.
He will never ignore justice against
Ertugrul Bey and Kayis.
You believe my father.
He is the only person who will
solve this matter justly.
Or none of us can ben sure
what will happen next.
You should know that I believe with all
my heart that Ertugrul Bey is innocent.
Thank you.
I have talked to Gumustekin, mother.
Halime.
Where are you coming from?
I strolled with my horse, mother.
I do not know why but I think
you are coming from Ertugrul.
Halime Sultan.
If you want me to save my brother
from this trouble
you need to tell me where he is.
Where is Ertugrul? Tell me the truth.
Halime.
If we cannot find Ertugrul
matters will get out of our hands.
Tell me, so that I can go talk to him
and to find a solution.
If you know his location
and do not tell us
you would be sending him
to the gallows with your own hands.
You should have thought about this
before you threw him in dark pits.
If you want to know where he is,
he is everywhere in order to protect
his nomad group not just from Noyan,
but also from your faults.
He is in every tree hole,
under every rock.
As long as Ertugrul is alive
then there is hope for Kayi tribe.
If something happens to him
our hopes will run out, Gundogdu Bey.
Excuse me.
Don't you worry, mother.
I will find my brother.
What did you talk with Gumustekin?
He said that he will seek justice.
That there will be a trial and he will
prove that Ertugrul is not guilty.
Justice? Whose justice is it?
Gundogdu, you are still talking
about justice in front of me.
What do you think, Hamza?
Did Abdurrahman Alp prove himself?
He did.
He now deserves to be your warrior.
Hamza!
You just as clueless as your Bey Gundogdu.
But still
Abdurrahman bested
my most trusted men one by one.
Ertokus. Grasshopper jumps
only twice before he finds trouble.
You fell on my lap on your third time.
I know about the traitor that old man
put next to Ogeday.
Go to hell, you wretched snake.
Ogeday will send Sungurtekin's head
to me in wax.
I will put Sungurtekin's head
to their nomad group's entrance.
I thought rotten head
would not be useful for me.
I want his mother and siblings
to recognise Sungurtekin's head.
You will never take
those you want from me.
I will not yield Sungurtekin's and
Seljuk Empire's war plans.
I already got what I want, Ertokus.
I am going to send you to Ogeday.
What will Sultan Alaeddin think
when he finds out we have
his glorious commander?
He will think that he has lost the war
before it even begins.
I was able to convince Gundogdu
with my words.
I will reach Ertugrul with his help.
-And then?
-Ertugrul will get what he deserves.
A greasy noose.
Gumustekin.
What do you want from my son?
What's the matter with you?
-Hayme Hatun...
-Shut up, Aytolun!
Sister Hayme.
Listen to me carefully, brother.
And you, too, Gumustekin.
My son is not responsible of
these murders.
I will never believe your written order
or your words
before hearing it from him myself.
If you persist...
...and torture the people
and Beys of my tribe...
...in hopes of finding something...
...Kayis will leave here tomorrow.
We will resist the armies of Gog and Magog
in this dead of winter
just like we have resisted
our enemies for 1000 years.
Just so you know!
Mother Hayme.
I have the order from
The Great Seljuk Empire.
The Empire can keep it's decree,
as long as we have the mountains.
Tell that to Sadettin Kobek.
What kind of a wedding
you want, my gazelle?
-I never thought of it.
-How come?
How can a woman
not think about her wedding?
I have not.
Then you should immediately.
We should start the preparations.
Tribes' Beys around here will attend.
If God permits.
I will think about it, do not worry.
-I want to ask something.
-Anything, my gazelle.
What will happen to Ertugrul?
What is it to you, Gokce!
What is it to you!
Is that what you ask
after what I have told you?
I was just curious.
You know that Ertugrul
is like a brother to me.
From now on, you have no right to be
curious about Ertugrul. Okay?
If God permits, Tugtekin
will take good care of Gokce.
I hope they will be happy.
If God permits.
If God permits this marriage
will bring peace to our tribe.
If God permits, Bey.
However with Tugtekin's ambition
there will not be any peace
for sister Gokce.
-Bey.
-Abdurrahman.
I made it, Bey. Noyan trusts me.
But they killed soldiers from Seljuk
in front of my eyes, Bey.
I couldn't do anything.
Your duty was the hardest, Abdurrahman.
If you can handle it...
...you may save the lives of
thousands of Alps.
Where is Ertokus Bey?
I have delivered him to Noyan with Hamza.
They will leave tomorrow
to take him to Ogeday.
Go back quickly, Abdurrahman.
If they feel your absence
they may get suspicious.
-There is one more thing, Bey.
-Say it.
Your brother Sungurtekin.
-They are also talking about him.
-What do they say?
They found out that he is a traitor.
They sent a message to Ogeday.
Sungurtekin? What is going on, Bey?
Get ready, Alps.
We are going to get Ertokus Bey.
In the name of God!
You are here just in time again
Ertugrul Bey.
Thank God we met again.
-Are you alright, Ertokus Bey?
-Of course!
Noyan is more powerful than we thought.
Our enemy should be powerful
for us to show our might.