Episode 34 will start after 12:01 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
I know the fire in you, mother.
My heart burns, Gundogdu.
I sent your brother to Mongol
while he could not grab a sword.
What if he is taken prisoner?
What if he is wasted?
-May God forbid.
You know, my brother is hard to kill.
He will get over this, as well.
If God permits, son.
If God permits.
Calm yourself down, mother.
Every trouble's remedy comes from God.
I wish I had been speechless
and would not have said it.
You could not escape this time, Ertugrul.
Split up! Search the area! Come on!
Come on!
Treacherous dogs!
I am the new Bey of nomad tent, Ertugrul.
From now on, you will obey me.
Here! He is here!
Halime, wipe your tears.
Do not let your troubles burden your baby.
My baby suffers even before he is born.
He met fires of hell
even before he is born.
Ertugrul Bey will come back soon.
Mother Hayme will forgive him.
How could a mother exile his own son
from his nomad tent?
How?
Ertugrul's hand has not healed yet.
He has not put himself together yet.
While we have so many enemies
how could a mother
send his son to his death, Selcan?
Mother Hayme talked with rage, Halime.
She must show her rage to her brother.
To her brother's mealy-mouthed wife.
What is my man's fault?
-Halime.
-What is his sin?
Halime, stop. Where are you going?
Let me go, Selcan Hatun.
I will show my rage now.
-Halime.
Mother Hayme!
How could you exile your son
from nomad tent?
How could you say it?
How could you consent to leave me
without my husband
and my baby without his father?
My daughter.
What are you saying?
I say a lot if you understand.
He could not go far.
So you want to play a game.
You will have one, Ertugrul.
Move!
You send your son, Ertugrul,
to hell Mother Hayme!
Halime, do you hear what you are saying?
Me?
You stopped asking for help
in Korkut's tent
and now you are giving us
advice, Gundogdu Bey.
Know your place!
Who are you to talk against
Mother Hayme and Gundogdu Bey?
Go to your marquee and wait for your man.
Now!
Mother Hayme!
Raise her, Bey.
Raise her, Bey!
Mother!
Mother.
Come now, jackals.
He is weak, stay sharp.
Tankut.
This way.
So let us go, Hamza.
What are we going to do?
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul!
You could not escape!
Split up.
You, that way! You, this way!
You, follow me! Come on!
The prey is ambushed.
She carries the burden of nomad tent.
Hayme Hatun has the blues.
Immediately, you shall free
your heart from that grief.
How could I bear all this grief and pain?
You could, mother, with permission of God.
Mix this with water and make a syrup.
If God permits, this will heal her.
-If you excuse me.
-Let me see you out.
Pack up equipment and follow me.
May God bless you, Artuk Bey.
Take care of your mother, Bey.
My mother lives in grief, pain and worry.
May God not let anything happen to her.
-Amen.
We need you, Mother Hayme.
Do not die, please.
You tousled nomad tent
many men fall martyr because of you
you ruined Ertugrul
now you want to ruin Mother Hayme!
If something happens to Mother Hayme,
I will kill you myself.
God damn it! God damn it!
Find him!
Go!
Find the men you left as guards
and punish them one by one.
Do you understand?
Ertugrul was always on my sight, Bey.
It is impossible that
he would free Abdurrahman.
What about his Alps?
His Alps did not come to tent, Bey.
They were in their tent.
I made them followed all day long.
So how did this man escape?
Bey, there are wheels within wheels.
It is obvious that someone who is jealous
of you and Tugtekin did this.
Someone discredits your dignity.
Unfortunately, they succeeded it.
I will go and find them.
Tugtekin, you should not go anywhere.
This should not be inextricable.
You should stay in nomad tent.
Kacabash, take your best Alps,
set out and follow them.
Find Abdurrahman, Ertugrul and his Alps
then bring them back.
Now!
Go and find them.
Find them and show no mercy.
Do not worry, Bey.
If you do not find them, I will whip you
in nomad tent, Kocabash.
Go now.
You stay here, and you two come with me.
Move. Move!
If I do not kill you and your loved ones
may Earth has my blood!
Move!
Look what I have become thanks to you
while I am a doctor.
How can I make it up to you, Bey.
Thank to Turali.
Now, put these on.
But, Artuk Bey...
...the only thing I did not do
was wearing woman clothes.
How did you imagine your escape
in day time from nomad tent?
Come on, don't push it. Put these on.
Abdurrahman, Ertugrul Bey and his Alps,
Dogan and Turgut
whoever comes across
we are assigned to take them
to nomad tent.
If they fight back, you can kill them.
This is headquarters' judgment.
-Where are we going?
Make the preparations.
I go to Artuk Bey.
Go out, Turali. Have a look around.
Your horse is ready.
You will go to Geyikli's cave.
Turali will take you to horse.
Thank you, Bey. May god bless you.
Come on, hurry up.
Peace be upon you, Bey.
And peace be upon you, Kocabash.
What is the matter?
Do you understand how could
Abdurrahman escape
because his body was not around?
While Alps like you who have their mind
on other thing are on duty
more treachers will escape, Kocabash.
I am here to take some more syrup
which you prepared for Mother Hayme.
I will make it ready, Selcan Hatun.
Do you need anything, Kocabash?
No, Bey.
If you excuse me.
Do not rush anymore, mother.
We will get over this trouble
with God's help.
My self-sacrificing and smart son.
If God permits.
Permission, Mother Hayme!
Come in, Dumrul.
Kocabash gathered Alps they will
go after them, Mother Hayme.
It is obvious they will fight.
They thought Ertugrul Bey
freed Abdurrahman, mother.
What did you say?
Mother! You are tired,
let me talk to my uncle.
It is enough, it is time to bring them
into the line!
What does going after my son mean
even after I exiled my son?
Do they want to kill him?
Ertugrul!
How much lucre did you take to betray
your nomad tent, treacherous dog?
I was innocent, Ertugrul.
Your brother, Gundogdu,
did not believe in me.
He accused me of being a treacher.
I fight to death for him
without batting an eyelid.
I thought of him as a father.
I did not deserve this.
Did you become Noyan's dog
because of what Gundogdu Bey did?
Ertugrul!
I will make you regret
the day you were born!
Archer!
It is not going to work, Bey.
Two nomad tents could not bear this pain.
Flames that Ertugrul put us in will burn
all of us sooner or later.
His mother exiled him. He is gone now.
What if...
...Hayme did it?
Do you hear yourself, woman?
She would have lost her
reputation among Alps
if she had wasted her husband reminder?
Perhaps, she was afraid of it.
She did it herself.
She silenced us by exiling Ertugrul.
You showed that you are a Kayi mother
by showing no mercy
to your son, Mother Hayme.
I am a mother but my brother is
neither an uncle nor a Bey, Aytolun.
Korkut Bey knows how to behave, Hayme.
Look at me, Aytolun.
Do not ever try to be The Bey's wife
in my father's nomad tent.
I send you where you came from.
So, not every dog barks in his own yard.
If God permits, we will
get over these hard times.
You sent your Alps
after my son and his Alps.
Like a treacher, a murderer, a bandit!
They said you sent men after him.
What would I have done, Hayme?
My duty is performing
headquarters' judgment
and keeping the peace in nomad tent,
is not it?
So, you will bring peace by fratricide.
If they are not involved in this
they will come after my Alp
and we will talk about it.
Or, if they disobey headquarters'
judgments and freed Abdurrahman
then they will pay the price
according to traditions.
You are making a mistake, brother.
You are making a mistake.
If any of them gets hurt,
I will make you pay for it!
What's happening, father?
Your aunt is offended because we sent men
after treachers, Tugtekin.
We welcomed them for a long time, aunt.
They freed Abdurrahman.
Have not you fed up living
with treachers yet?
Stop Tugtekin, do not fan the fire.
Uncle.
Mother.
We assembled the headquarters here.
We said we would be one and united.
We gave our words.
So what is this situation now?
We are down at the first shot.
But it was obvious.
We said, son.
Yes, we said.
But I exiled my helpless son
from nomad tent.
What does sending men after him mean?
I put my nomad tent
in enough danger, Hayme.
I shared my tent with you.
But I am at the end of my rope.
Those traitors will come here
sooner or later.
All right, then find them.
I hope you are not get
involved in this, Hayme.
Mother Hayme knows what happened.
But she is silent not to stir nomad tent.
Whatever.
-Have a nice day.
Ertugrul Bey is exiled by his mother
as he deserved...
....so there will be peace
in our nomad tents.
Is not it, Wild Demir?
If you stick your heads in the sand,
there will be no peace, Aytolun Hatun.
While the trouble comes right at us
you left no peace in nomad tent
by saying peace.
We know who dreamt of war
with his lame hand.
Many perished in battle field like jades.
Battle is not performed
only with sword, Aytolun Hatun.
But with heart and word.
Ertugrul Bey said what he thought.
But you are so deaf, blind
and even black hearted that...
Enough, Wild Demir.
Enough.
I thought your duty was to forge the iron.
But you could not hold your tongue.
Shame on you.
She is worse than snake.
She gets suspicious.
She sees how the wind blows.
Be careful about her and your words.
We should not be seen together.
You speak the truth, Bey.
You speak the truth.
Where are they, Turgut brother?
Ertugrul Bey said they will come after us.
So, why are not they here yet?
What if something happened to Abdurrahman
while they were freeing him
from caged tent?
Dogan, enough.
You are right, Turgut brother. I am sorry.
Abdurrahman?
What happened to you, Abdurrahman brother?
You are a woman.
I saw a bird in forest.
He was flying around.
I captured him and brought here
to poor's cave.
The only thing I have not done
was putting on women's clothes
but I did it at least.
Brothers, there is no death
for us on land.
Calm down, mother.
Even if they follow Ertugrul,
they could not find him, do not worry.
They cannot find neither Ertugrul
nor his Alps.
I know they could not find him, Gundogdu.
But, what does sending men
after my son mean?
How could I accept the edict
that Korkut wrote about my son
as a mother and Bey of this nomad tent?
He sent his dogs after my son
because exiling him was not enough.
Tell me, Gundogdu!
I exiled him myself.
What should I have done, take his life?
I do not know what is happening
but we both know Ertugrul.
We know he disregards dangers.
If he did it
he saved both Kayis
and your father's honor.
What are you saying, mother?
Did not Ertugrul cause all these trouble
by saying headquarters'
judgment and traditions?
So, our headquarters and traditions
are worthless now?
What is this?
Perhaps, I should have said this
at the very beginning.
I should have said this when we took
shelter in my brother's nomad tent.
I made a huge mistake by accepting
my brothers offer! A huge mistake!
-Mother!
-Go son, go Gundogdu!
-Is there anything missing?
-No, Aytolun Hanim.
All the preparations will be done
before merchant Efrasiyab arrives.
Good.
If your eyes are shining on a day
like this, you have good news.
Gokce accepted to come Erzurum
with me, mother.
This is good news.
You will be together
until she will be in your bed.
Call Gokce to our marquee tonight.
Tell her that my mother and father
want to have a dinner with her.
Do you understand?
I do, mother.
Do not ever break Mother Hayme's heart
until hard times are over.
She is the only one who can prevent you
from taking Gokce
in your bed and as your wife.
Do not forget this.
We got rid of Ertugrul one way or another.
Hayme will sit in her corner
when the time is right.
Then...
...Dodurga and Kayi will not overcome...
...as long as you and your father lead us.
He escaped again.
As long as he escapes and I get bored.
Do spirits tell me to let him alive?
As if I do not let him live
everything will be in vein.
What do spirits tell me, Ulubilge?
Ertugrul beat you severely.
Pray that I saved your life.
What does Noyan do with shaman?
He talks to spirits.
He wants to know
what great spirits tell him.
What do spirits say, Ulubilge?
If Ertugrul is not murdered
the earth will be his.
And his sons will conquer everywhere
what is on this world.
I will destroy him and everything
he will have.
Everything.
Ertugrul Bey is here.
Are you alright, Bey?
Help me take this out.
What happened, Bey?
Tangut. He chased me with Hamza.
-Bastard!
-Rascal!
They chased us, too.
I am sure there is spy in nomad tent.
They follow every step we take.
Another Kurdoglu.
They ambushed us out of nomad tent
while we were going to lay
an ambush to Noyan.
He attacked you now so you are right, Bey.
There is a treacher in nomad tent.
We will not have peace until we find him.
What will we do, Bey?
We have no nomad tent now.
We have no Alps, too.
We have only our swords and our hearts.
Whether we will be a martyr
or we will take jackals' heads.
It is an honor to die by your side, Bey.
So, listen to me carefully.
From now on, we will act as they deserve.
How, Bey?
Aytolun Hatun invited me to dinner.
She has something to talk.
Tell Mother Hayme I will go there.
What will you do in that woman's meal
at the dead of night?
I seek a piece of peace, sister.
Just peace.
To stay away from you, Halime.
Do you begrudge me this?
That woman's only desire is biting
our weakest link off, nothing else.
What does Aytolun after, Selcan?
I will find out at all cost.
I will not let her to take
my loved ones one by one.
Grape molasses is sour.
It lost its flavor.
Are you making up excuses
not to drink it, Bey?
You will drink grape molasses
so you will attack your hunt
like a raging bull.
You made me mad at this age.
Raging bull will attack you tonight.
-Our guest is here.
-Good evening, Bey.
May I sit down?
-Welcome, daughter.
Sit down.
In the name of God.
Enjoy it.
Peace be upon you.
No need, go on.
Dumrul, help me.
I want exact number of animals
tomorrow, Dumrul.
Cattle, small cattle, all of them.
Yes, Bey.
Count young animal that were born
in spring separately.
I think we should not sell them
to the merchant.
We will need them to augment
the herd after war.
You heard my mother.
Yes, Bey.
-Here, Bey.
-Thank you.
The meal is ready, mother.
God, thanks to you countless times.
You re-united us.
You did not leave our
nomad tent to tyrant.
Thanks to you, God.
-Amen.
Once, we fed many people on our meal.
If God permits, those day
will come again, mother.
If God permits.
Where is Halime?
She is not hungry, mother. She is asleep.
So, where is Gokce?
Aytolun invited her to dinner.
She went to marquee.
If a family is not together in a meal
that nomad tent and tribe are not united.
I could neither be a mother
nor keep my nomad tent up.
What are you saying, mother?
It is obvious, beautiful eyed Selcan.
If there is no peace in meal...
...no one eat there.
If there is no one, there is no unity.
May God bless your hand, aunt.
Thank you, Gokce.
For so long...
...I have never...
Gokce, what happened?
Did we say something wrong?
No, no.
I have not had a peaceful meal
for so long.
What you have gone through
was not easy, Gokce.
Then, your brother, Ertugrul...
...caused many troubles to you.
Hayme made the right decision
for all of us by exiling him.
Isn't it, Gokce?
You speak the truth, aunt.
I hope he will not come back
with new troubles.
Oghuz always found a way out
even in darkest times.
Two nomad tents' merging
is a blessing of God.
We must appreciate this blessing.
Our merging is not limited
with Ertugrul, Korkut Bey.
We must enhance the bound
between Kayis and Dodurgas.
Then no one will take a stand against us.
Meal is ready, Bey.
Hope you like it?
Did you, Bey?
God bless your hand, Turgut brother.
You did it better than Halime Sultan.
Bey, if Halime Hatun hears that,
I get in trouble.
Turgut brother, Aykiz Baci
thought you a lot.
Sit down, brother.
Sit down and have your meal.
Aykiz Baci is not dead, Turgut brother.
She is always with us.
She fell martyr.
I know, Bey. I know.
If you knew, you would not be sorry.
If you knew, you would not be in pain.
If God permits, you will fall martyr
one day and meet with her.
If God permits.
You speak the truth, Bey.
You speak the truth.
I will rip this pain out of my heart.
What is the situation in nomad tent, Bey?
They blamed you.
They have a point.
That is why I do not talk.
We swore that we would lose
our mothers, our lovers
and our heads for Islam.
Now, we will pay a price for our swear.
Korkut Bey's marquee
is troubled, too, Bey.
My uncle lost his foresight.
Tugtekin has crazy ideas.
He is in love with Gokce.
The leading eye of my uncle's marquee
is Aytolun Hatun.
She is the root of all evil.
They thought Ertugrul is after Noyan
so he could not realize what they do.
They are mistaken, I could.
I realize.
Aytolun Hatun, on the one hand, tries to
take my brother Gundogdu to their sides
on the other hand, she wants to marry
Tugtekin and Gokce.
Why do they want to marry
Tugtekin and Gokce?
Gokce Hatun cannot not have a baby.
If Aytolun Hatun knows this secret,
she has a secret agenda.
We will find out soon.
From now on
if someone tries to trap us, I will
crash his world about his ears.
If you excuse me, now. It is late.
Come back any time, daughter.
Dear God did not give me a daughter.
But be my daughter and bring joy
to our home.
Thank you, Bey.
I will walk you to your marquee.
-Good evening.
-Good evening, my daughter.
What happens next?
Any girl wants to be with Tugtekin, Bey.
We will understand on the way to Erzurum.
Why do you want this marriage
too much, Aytolun?
The problem of two nomad tents' merging
will be solved by marriage of these.
Kayi people's love will be assured by son
of Korkut Bey, Tugtekin. That is why.
You are cunning.
The winter here is severe.
This winter will be hard for all of us.
What are you doing, Gokce?
How could I bear to see you in the
same marquee with my wife and child?
How could I live with you
like pangs of conscience?
Gokce?
-What?
-I said winter.
If you are in peace with the ones you love
no one cares about winter.
Good night, aunt.
You, too, Tugtekin.
Why did not you tell me that
you go to dinner to Korkut Bey?
I told my sister, Mother Hayme.
Next time, tell me either, too.
It is obvious that Korkut Bey
cares a lot for you.
-Good night, Bey.
-Good night.
You heard Kayi Alps are anxious.
They are more anxious after Ertugrul left.
I know, aunt. I know.
They fought more battles
than any other Alps did.
They always stood up against our enemies.
I took my son's mission and entrusted
my Alps to you in battle field.
Do not offend them ever again.
Ertugrul brother is gone
so there will be no problem, aunt.
We will find out treachers
sooner or later.
I want you know, that I want to offend
neither you nor those brave men.
I hope, you will not. Good night, son.
Good night, aunt.
What am I going to do with you, Selcan?
You are my Bey.
Do whatever you want.
I should not have laid hand on you.
I should not have put you and me
in this shame, I know. But...
I die for you.
It is your decision,
fit it my duty to obey.
But give your decision.
What you have done to me
and our nomad tent is always
in my mind, Selcan.
I was about to forget it
but you reminded it again.
And your delusions...
Your reasonless anger to Tugtekin,
my uncle and Aytolun.
It is not reasonless, Bey.
You have such a clean heart
that you cannot see it as I do.
You mind your uncle's words
for the future of your tribe.
You could not see.
-God give me patience.
You cannot stand to me,
to my existence...
...to the breath I take...
...to the warmth of me in bed...
...and everything. Right Gundogdu?
Restrain the evil in you, Selcan.
Restrain so you will not cause
more trouble in nomad tent.
If you cause any more trouble,
you will pay the price.
I will not say anything else to you.
I am afraid of losing my way.
The way and the secret are
hidden in legacy, Ertugrul.
May it be good.
The legacy calls me.
Listen to me.
Noyan collects information
about these lands until main
Mongol army arrives.
He wants to browbeat us by small strikes.
In this situation, we need
to alarm nomad tent.
Turgut and Dogan, you will
go back to nomad tent.
After you arrive, contact
with Artuk and Wild Demir.
But be careful.
Tugtekin wants to entrap you.
So, go in secretly or find
a good reason to go in.
Understood, Bey.
We will take care of it with God's help.
When you arrive nomad group, you must
have your finger on the pulse.
Everyone is a suspect.
I suspect Tugtekin's Alp, Kocabash.
If you suspect someone, keep him in sight.
Do not cause trouble in nomad group.
When we find the treacher in nomad group,
we could entrap Noyan.
What about me, Bey? What about me?
You are all in it.
I send you to hell, Abdurrahman.
Do not ever give up.
Do not make a mistake.
If you make a mistake,
we may not see you again.
I give my life for this duty, Bey.
I hope, God is with me.
If God permits.
Try change Hamza's side.
Try to win his rotten heart.
You do not have to send
the news immediately.
Noyan will test you.
First, gain Noyan's confidence.
But what will you do, Bey?
I go to take my legacy.
It is time to battle, brothers.
It is time to shove down enemy's throat.
Come on, in it win it.
Give me your blessings.
You have it, Bey.
If I have your blessing,
you have my blessing, too.
Come on.
He is furious because of
Ertugrul's escape.
He might cut you in pieces
and feed the jackals.
Do not worry, I know
what Baycu Noyan feels.
Baycu Noyan.
Baycu Noyan, I am at your service.
All these lands to Byzantine
will be ours, Efrasiyab.
Erzurum, Malatya, Konya, Alayi,
all of them.
Do you want to take your share
from every trade in these cities?
I am a merchant, of course, I do.
I want every lucre of it.
You will earn more than you can imagine.
But we have a business, first, Efrasiyab.
We will tyrannize Kayis and Dodurgas
as they have never seen.
As, Ertugrul escaped
and as we could not find him
so he will find us.
He will beg me to kill him on bended knee.
I am at service, Baycu Noyan.
They will dread Mongols
until Ogeday's army arrives.
We will make them pauperize for a bite.
First, we will give them too much gold.
Then, every one of them will perish.
They will have no strength
to feed to horses.
Your Persian servant is skillful,
he will not let you down.
So, move on.
My soldiers will escort you
till their boundaries.
We have not find any track yet.
Set out today.
Search everywhere, Kocabash.
When you see them, do not let them
escape, understood?
Yes, Bey.
If you capture them, show no mercy.
We will not let them cause more trouble
in nomad group.
We have our meals when the sun rises
and sets in this marquee.
Daughter in laws make these meals ready.
The meals my husband does not participate
is a poison to me.
Cooking meal that he does not participate
is a torture for me.
Turn your face to me.
I said turn your face!
Halime, do not push my limits!
Do you think only your husband suffered?
Do you think only you are hurt?
Many Hatun's husbands fell martyr.
Turgut lost his Aykiz.
None of them has whined as you do.
My husband exiled from his nomad tent
for which he gave, life by his mother.
He died the death.
He was not exiled by his mother
but Hatun of Kayi, Hayme Hatun.
He was not your husband,
he was Alp of Kayi, Ertugrul.
If you will be a Bey's wife,
know this first.
From now on
if you could not hold your tongue
I know how to cut it.
Tell me, what is your
trouble, Selcan Hatun?
I have only one trouble Aytolun
and it is you.
What does your sick mind think?
What does your cunning mind think?
What do you want from my sister?
You captured her,
what do you want, tell me?
Know your place, Selcan.
You are a parasite in
my husband's nomad tent.
Like you are a parasite
in your husband tent.
You are a snake in my uncle's bed!
A snake that must be beheaded!
-Let me!
-Aytolun Hatun!
Please, she does not know
what she is saying.
Lay down your dagger.
Let me to bring her into
the line, Gundogdu!
I will bring her into the line, please!
-Do you hear yourself, Gundogdu?
-Shut up!
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
I will not let her to capture my sister!
Selcan, beat it!
I will see you in the tent.
Beat it!
Aytolun Hatun, please keep this
between three of us.
I do not want any discrimination
between two nomad tents.
She is a sick woman.
Forgive me for saying that
but this is the truth.
Because of that, I keep this between us.
But keep that woman away from me.
Otherwise, I will not keep quiet.
What did you give to hussy Aytolun?
Tell me. Was that strength syrup?
I said tell me!
Strength syrup, Hanim.
Does that syrup
kill a sick man like Korkut?
Ilkish!
Of course, it kills, Selcan Hatun.
Selcan!
Where are you damn woman?
You were right, Selcan.
I cannot stand to you.
To your existence, to the breath you take.
To the warmth of you in my bed, anything.
Anything!
So our hunt today is you.
Who are you?
I am the Alp of Kayi Seigniory.
My name is Abdurrahman Alp.
What are you looking for here?
Hamza Alp and Noyan.
I am here to talk with them.
What will you talk with them?
I heard that Kayi's soldiers
have allied with them.
I am here to obey them.
To obey?
Those who want to obey
would get themselves into trouble.
Let us see about your destiny!
Leave your sword.
Leave your sword!
Tie him!
Let us take a little bit rest here.
I am hungry.
Brother! You are always hungry.
Where do you keep those you ate?
Let us prepare table.
Let me find firewood.
Brother. I do not get it.
Does one Alp draw a sword to another?
How can we slaughter them?
We let them into our table.
We got a lot of trouble.
You will see about that when we got them.
We will let you go soon.
Can you find the way?
We can.
There are Turkmens ahead.
Our swords have not tasted of blood
for a while.
Let us not go back with nothing.
We should take some presents.
Get ready.
Let us go. With God's hand.
Brother! Welcome.
Greetings.
You were right.
We have wasted our lives
for children of Suleyman Shah.
So you are the Alp of Suleyman Shah,
Abdurrahman Alp.
I have been looking for you
in the mountains for days.
I am here to join you, Baycu Noyan.
Welcome to the army
which is the strongest one...
...in the world, Abdurrahman.
Hamza.
Be a host for your brother.
Thank you.
We found them unexpectedly.
Thank you very much, brothers.
We owe you a life from now on.
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
We were looking for victims
to save from Mongol cruelty.
And we found them.
Tell me. How could you escape
while you were going to be executed?
Thanks to the people who aware of justice
in our nomad tent.
How could Ertugrul and Hayma Ana
let them execute you?
I do not give my blessing to them
for what I have done for them.
Ertugrul sold me out in order
not to break customs.
I will revenge on them some day.
Brother Abdurrahman.
I will be the leader
of that nomad group someday.
They will pay one by one for what they
have done to us on that day.
We must find Bogac.
-Are you okay, brother?
-I am okay, brother. I am okay.
He has saved my life.
Efrasiyab, a Persian merchant.
You should come with us to nomad group.
We should tell what happened here
to Tugtekin Bey.
So Tugtekin Bey would understand
that you guys are not traitors.
We must change horseshoes, Gundogdu Bey.
Do whatever it takes.
Dumrul, bring it to me when it is ready.
Yes, Bey.
May it be easy.
What is it, brother?
Horseshoes will be changed.
What are you doing?
I have talked with community.
They are worried about winter.
God is great. We will go to caravansary
once Persian merchant we expect got here.
Are you still mad at me?
Surely I am.
Why?
Because you are acting without thinking
just like my brother Ertugrul.
Because of that you and your nomad group
will always be in trouble.
So you have catched traitors?
Bey...
...they have saved us from Mongols.
What did you say?
Mongols attacked us.
And they have saved us, Bey.
I told you that you act without thinking.
So traitors have saved your Alps
who went to capture traitors, right?
And who is this man?
I am Persian merchant Efrasiyab.
Welcome. Welcome.
Turgut Alp! Dogan Alp!
Where is Ertugrul Bey?
He has said hello to you, Sultan Halime.
Did not he come with you?
He did not.
Where is he then?
He also did not tell us where he went.
What do you mean he did not tell?
How could you come back to nomad group
leaving him like that, Turgut?
Could not you say "Stop!"?
Could not you say "Bey, you can't go
anywhere without us?"
Did you scare to die with him?
Even Aykiz is more brave than you.
You were supposed to be an Alp.
We have been waiting you for long time.
You know, everywhere is dangerous.
We go slowly.
Where is your caravan?
I go first. If I don't smell fishy
then my caravan would come.
Alright.
This tent is at your service.
Take a rest. Enjoy it.
-We will meet and talk tonight.
-Thank you.
You have hard work here,
Persian merchant. It is really hard.
You are so clumsy and gump Alps!
Those who I ordered you to kill
have saved your lives!
-We have been blindsided, Bey.
-So I wish you were killed!
Whole nomad group heard about it now!
You have soiled your Bey's name.
Bey, we could not have expected Mongols.
And they are not traitors after all.
We owe them our lives.
You owe them your lives?
Then I take your life instead of them
so you pay for it.
You owe them your life?
Bey!
May I come in, Hayma?
Yes, you may, brother.
Ertugrul's Alps are back.
Yes.
They had saved those Alps of yours
who you sent after them.
I know that
you feel resentful towards me, Hayma.
And you are right.
But I have to do it
for tranquility of my nomad group.
I have excluded my helpless son
from there.
But you could not say stop to your son.
And a presumptuous woman who could not
hold her tongue is sitting...
...in this nomad group which was ruled
by my mom and aunt once.
And you should know about it.
Aytolun is the woman
who made me return to this life.
She should get the same respect as I get.
Now, leave all aside.
I think that we should start a family
between two nomad groups.
We should start it so our fellowship
would become stronger.
Family?
Whose family will it be?
Tugtekin and Gokce.
Ertugrul Bey have said that
there's a traitor in nomad group.
We suspected that it was Kocash
but we have saved him from Mongols.
It is now our job to take that snake
from its nest.
Where is Ertugrul Bey?
He said that he will go to take package.
Did he say that?
Yes, Chief Demir.
Do you know what is it?
When you have asked about
where is my hometown...
...I have replied you that "Everywhere
where there are our fathers' graveyards."
One day, these lands
where there is your graveyard...
...will be our hometown, father.
It will be the hometown of our blood
and Muslim ummah where...
...your blessed foot stepped,
everywhere that my sword reached...
...and every inch of land.
I have never hesitated.
I will not.
As you have said to me...
..."Hesitation comes the day when
valiant burried alive."
I will not let them to bury neither me
nor Kayis alive.
I know what to do well, father.
But I am here to ask for forgiveness
for the hearts which will be broken...
...and brother's blood
which will be spilled.
I wanted you to know that I will not stop
fighting until I see that blessed state.
I am sentenced to take a long ride, Bey.
Give me your blessing, father.
"Give package into his hand."
Futuvvet Master is waiting for you.
Are you ready for your duty?