Episode 48 will start after 12:13 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You experienced thrashing
not the victory, Noyan.
I want to remind you that.
If I experienced thrashing
my head would already be taken, Kobek.
-God!
-Help!
Welcome to hell of Noyan, Ertugrul.
-Who are you?
-Demon of this hell.
Welcome to world of Mongolians.
You would regret that you let me go.
I will cause great death you all.
Defeat that incites anger.
Do not play with my fate.
Bey.
I should know that you
would not let Noyan go.
And I should know that
you will wiggle, Wild Demir.
The tracks are to Kervansaray.
They took Noyan there.
Do not worry. I will kill that dishonest.
Now you go to the nomad tent.
You go back and make so many zulfiqars
for so many valiants.
Do not leave nomad tent alone.
-My Bey.
If you excuse me, I would like to come.
This is a way with no return, Wild Demir.
My Bey.
Is there any other way
to go to my daughter?
Come along, brother.
I hope nothing is wrong, Turgut brother?
You wriggle like you ambushed.
We undertook the load of fate
since birth, Bey.
Does it leave us alone a second?
Tell me your grievance and
I can undertake your load.
This way also is ended, Bey.
Where will we go now?
What did it fall to our share
from this journey?
It is like that this way
tired you, Turgut Brother.
Let us take a little rest in the marquee.
This is not the way, Bey.
To not know what is in your mind
makes me tired.
I sacrifice my life for you, Bey.
We are in the way with you until death.
But who told us that we should
take this road?
Why is so important that
who told me that, Turgut brother?
Since when what I told became
to be queried?
Not at all, Bey. Not at all.
I am just upset that I do not have the
same place in your heart and mind.
You do not tell me any of
your secrets anymore, Bey.
There is a time for everything,
Turgut brother. Just be patient.
Just be patient.
We should eat a little bit
and then I will go to Ahlat.
Wait for me here.
We wait for you for a lifetime, Bey.
-Good luck.
-Thank you, Bey.
The meal is prepared delicious, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
You are healed now, Abdurrahman.
Thanks to you, Bey. May God bless you.
You did not leave me alone for a second.
You healed me.
Thank you. Godspeed.
Praise be, Abdurrahman.
Alps missed you very much.
They want to see you in the education area
as soon as possible.
With God's help, I will do that too, Bey.
If God permits.
Take it.
Godspeed.
Why are you distressed, Bey?
I should not send Sungur alone
after Noyan.
Bey, do you think that it would be
better, if you would send 500 Alps?
You will be millstone round
Sungurtekin's neck.
He did not go for a war. He went
to settle an account for a cruel.
My brother did not want me beside him.
Bey, you are the main Alp of
two nomad groups.
It is unknown that what kind of way
is this and where it is going
and where it ends.
It is also possible that he will go
after Noyan to China.
You are right, Artuk Bey.
You are right but my mother is very bad.
She is living the pain of separation
without enjoying coming together
with her child.
Bey, you had to release Noyan by
following the commands of the state.
And Sungurtekin did what it
is necessary for his family.
The rest is will of God.
Do not devastate yourself.
Thank you, Bey. Thank you.
Sungurtekin.
Where are you, son?
Mother, I brought you water.
Thank you, daughter.
Do you have another request, mother?
Ertugrul is in a place
and Sungur is in another.
Now, my two arms are broken.
My two eyes, two ears and two livers.
For God's sake, do not devastate
yourself like this anymore.
A new trouble every day.
A new separation every day.
God! A new pain comes
before my breathe reaches to another.
Everything is going to be
all right, mother.
We have peace in our marquee
and we were not expecting that.
Ertugrul and Sungurtekin Bey
will also come.
Our nomad group will be in peace, mother.
Do not think about these anymore.
Do not worry.
Peace!
How can peace come, daughter?
Sometimes, I lose my hope.
We share the same tribe with those
centipedes entering our tent
and stealing the seal.
Noyan went but the betrayal is not over.
Mother, there are still people entering
our tribe and that you did not query.
You said that you will not stop
following however it ends.
Who do you mean, daughter?
You said that you will query your brides
as your daughters, mother.
Call Goncagul for me.
I would like to listen her.
Your wish is my command, mother.
Do you seek for the sun of world Seljuk?
With this rudeness and this wildness.
What about you?
When will you give up on being
a wife of palace?
You want to dominate all over the world
but you do not know
how to behave properly.
What about you?
What happened that you knew
how to behave properly?
Your lands, blessed cities and
holy shrines are under control of us.
Your corpses will be dispersed
like sands in desert.
Only the endless curse of humankind
will remain.
Stop it. Do not give me that!
Tell me what you want.
Noyan, if you pollute my table
with your saliva again
unfortunately the taste of my good meal
will be destroyed with your dirty blood.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Welcome, Ertugrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
Thank you.
I hope your journey was smooth.
Thanks to God.
I found everything that I want.
We will not listen these, son.
Who will listen then?
Excuse us.
Welcome, Ertugrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
Tell me about your blessed journey.
Tell me so I can hear what I want to hear
for years from a valiant like you.
Ah, Noyan, ah!
What did Ertugrul do to you?
Do not forget!
Your life is still in my hand.
Your Sultan will learn everything.
Now, we will eat our meal properly.
I will go and explain
the situation to Ogeday.
Do not forget to tell him
that I saved you from death.
I will convince him to come
with a big army.
-What if he will not be convinced?
-Then I establish my own army and come.
Do not underestimate Seljukian.
What if you met with a bigger army?
Sultan Aleaddin is getting stronger
every day.
What do you want?
I will be the new sultan in Anatolia.
And you will help me.
I will ask for an army from you and Ogeday
when it is time.
Above all. You become a sultan.
If you become a sultan woe is us!
The world becomes reversed!
Do not lose your seriousness, Noyan.
Do not get upset, Sadettin,
do not get upset.
The army of Ogeday will be with you.
I will go and take a rest.
You do what is necessary
and then let me know that.
There is a big crysis
on the Byzantine borderline.
Non-Muslim people want to get
rid of the rulers that persecute them.
They expect a mighty ruler that will bring
order to their fertile lands.
Villagers are in a miserable condition.
People lost their belief
to people who share their beliefs.
Bandits who escape from justice
are being seen everywhere.
And migrant Turks settled in there
struggle to survive.
They cannot help people
that are being persecuted
by Byzantine because they are not
able to solve their own matters.
Briefly, you say
whoever rules these land with justice
will gain power.
Days of depression
strengthen a brave man's weapon.
Opportunities are crystal clear.
But nobody takes a look at them.
The ones look at them, becomes prosperous.
But it will be tedious to move
my nomad tent there.
If I move my nomad tent there
I will become the biggest enemy
of migrant Turks
the local people and Byzantine.
It is right.
Wherever livelihood is limited
and people to be fed are plenty
the battle is tough.
Son, it is not only about Kayi.
The people of Anatolia
and the Islamic world
fight each other
instead of seeing the real enemy.
Byzantine is on one side,
and Mongolia is on another.
And we fight each other.
What about traitors?
These inglourious people
can only slow our struggle down.
So, who are you, then?
We are nobody, son.
Only nobody.
And we will be nobody forever.
What about me?
Is being comrade of nobody
not enough for you?
Thank you, sir.
Come on, son.
Maybe moving your nomad tent
there will take years.
But do not give up.
When you have Byzantine as your only enemy
there will be plenty of friends for you.
Do not worry about traitors.
They will have the real torture in hell.
So, it is for us to be determined,
not giving up.
If God permits, I will do everything
in order to move my nomad tent
to the Byzantine borderline.
If God permits, son.
He still sees himself
as the commander, right?
After all, he is still the commander.
To hell with him!
Listen to me carefully.
I will not only deliver you Noyan.
Your rewards are not only these.
I will also give you
the seal of Oghuz Khan.
Take it to Ogeday personally,
and obtain whatever position you desire.
I will never forget this favor.
But there is a cost for every favor.
The cost of this one is to tell Ogeday
that the new sultan will be Sadettin Kobek
and to support me.
You?
Sultan?
Okay.
Okay, Sadettin Kobek. Okay.
I gained big power with your help.
I will never forget this favor of yours.
I will struggle severely for you
to be the sultan in these lands.
Then, take Noyan
and give me my imprisoned commanders back.
Now Ertugrul, the son of Suleyman Shah.
It is time to renew your oath you made
on the way of this holly battle.
This is your sword.
Hone your sword after weighing it on the
scale of justice with breath of wisdom.
May your sword give hope to the oppressed,
and spread fear to the persecutors.
This is your flag.
I hope 72 nations will find peace
under the shadow of your flag.
And it flaps in the sky until doomsday.
Bismillah.
This is the Holy Quran.
It explains the truth, lightens the dark
and secures the justice.
May it always be your guide.
Now, have your say.
I swear to God
who fills our hearts with belief
to sword and the Holy Book
that the Sun will be my flag and the sky
will be my tent as I fight to death.
I will secure the justice
and spread fear to the persecutors.
If I deviate
from the cause of this holy battle
or beg for mercy from the enemy
may my sword be covered with my own blood.
May God be with you
on the way of this holy battle
Ertugrul, the son of Suleyman Shah.
May battle be yours,
and the victory be God's.
They must be the ones
who came to take Noyan.
And these three brave men
must be the Seljuk commanders
Ameer Sadettin Kobek told us about.
But, why do they wait here?
Since both sides act cautiously...
Obviously there are wheels within wheels.
What shall we do, Bey?
Boru, prepare the prisoners.
We are going to bring Noyan back.
-Opportunity will come to us, Wild Demir.
-If God permits, Bey.
If God permits.
How could you let him go?
How can he chase
the Mongolian army and kill Noyan?
He did everything to go.
God, what did I do?
May I come in, Bey?
Yes, Goncagul Hatun. Come in.
I know that Noyan's leaving
made you upset.
I wanted to come and ask
how you are doing.
I thought you would be happy.
Thank you. Your presence is enough for me.
What is that?
This arrow is the one my father threw
into the sky to start the preparations
for the bridal chamber tent.
That night,at the location
which this arrow fell
–I got to my mother's womb.
-Really?
I brought it to you
so that it brings us luck.
Hopefully.
So, we should find a place for it.
What is the matter, Selcan?
I was going to say that
the meal is ready, Bey.
I am not hungry. Thank you.
Selcan.
Come here.
Sit down. I have matters to talk
with both of you.
Do not consider that peace will come
to our nomad group
just because the two states
made peace.
Problems get more and more.
From now on, I do not want any trouble
neither in Mother Hayme's marquee
nor in my tent tor my women's tents.
Do not create more troubles.
Do we have a deal?
Yes, Bey.
Do not worry, Bey.
I hope Selcan Hatun becomes a sister
to me as she is to Gokce Hatun.
She will, she will.
You will, right, Selcan?
I will do my best, Bey.
As long as we have hearts of gold.
With your permission, Bey.
The permission is yours.
If you do not leave the Seljukian lands
in three days
you will be deemed as peace breakers
and be murdered.
When I come back I will destroy
the Seljukian lands completely.
I want you to behave as an old sister
with your pure heart. You know that.
Do not doubt that, Goncagul Hatun.
It is not a trouble to behave
as an old sister.
As long as I find a heart
inside your chest.
Goncagul Hatun.
My mother wants to see you.
I hope nothing is wrong.
I do not know, Goncagul Hatun.
You will find out when you go.
Maybe she wants to finish
her unfinished business.
The consignation stolen from the marquee.
Maybe she wants to listen you.
Who knows?
Did I say right?
We will see what she will tell.
We will see.
Where are you going, Selcan?
We will see if Banu Cicek
will continue to be stubborn.
They said you called me, Mother Hayme.
Here I am.
When Sungurtekin was here at the dinner
why did you step in
where my son stays?
Why do you ask me this, Mother Hayme?
I asked you a question.
I am waiting for your answer.
The person who knows it best
is Gokce Hatun. Ask her if you want.
I am asking you, not her.
Why did you step inside?
I understand you very well, Mother Hayme.
The hand of a betrayer is
on the honorable marquee of Kayi.
It is your duty to find this hand
and cut it.
It is not your place to remind my duties.
I asked you a question and
you give me your answer.
You are very angry because you had
such a weakness in your marquee.
But you know that I entered into there
because Gokce Hatun wanted it.
It was not my own will.
Gokce went out to take fabrics.
You were alone inside. What did you do?
When I was alone
I dreamed of the biggest dream
of a young girl, mother.
I looked at the fabrics that Gokce Hatun
showed and dreamed about the dress
that I will wear before
I marry my man.
The dress that I will wear in the night
that I will give myself to your son.
I think the person who kidnapped Selcan
Hatun from this nomad tent
can take what he wants from your marquee.
Sooner or later
The person who stole that seal
from my marquee will be revealed.
Just as they found Selcan
and brought her back.
Then I will hang that betrayer
in the middle of the nomad tent.
And believe me, no one
will be able to save him.
The spring is coming, Banu Cicek.
This winter was fruitful. Praise be.
Flowers will bloom in mountains.
Do not worry, Hanim.
Have a nice day, Hatuns.
I hope nothing is wrong.
I am going for a visit.
To whom are you going?
An old woman was killed a while ago.
Do you remember, Aytolun?
I am going to her grave.
Who knows who killed that poor woman.
Praise be! How loyal you are.
May someone be loyal in the nomad group
in which murderers run wild.
Right, Aytolun?
May it be easy.
What is she talking about, Hanim?
She is just mad.
She is trying to push it to the limit.
Never mind. Never mind.
Peace came here and now our war begins.
Where did these golds come from, brother?
Those are the sharpest swords
that I will use to abolish the obstacles
in front of my margrave one by one.
They are from Ameer Sadettin Kobek.
You do not need to use these golds as long
as there are stupid people as Sungur.
What about him?
Wild Demir and Sungurtekin disappeared.
Everybody in Hayme's marquee
is too sorry to say a word.
It is obvious that peace bothered them.
It is not good that both
of them disappeared.
It is obvious that they went after Noyan.
What is it? I hope nothing
is wrong, daughter.
Mother Hayme...
...called me to her marquee
and queried me.
Do not worry.
I gave the necessary answer.
She is still chasing
the case of the lost seal.
If she queries even Goncagul then it is
obvious that Selcan is in this.
Do not forget Halime, aunt.
She overstepped the limits so much
that she even queried her own bride.
Our job will not be easy at all, brother.
Obviously,
we will not be comfortable
in this nomad tent
unless we bring the Kayis' marquee
down on them.
Daughter.
You know that Gundogdu is more valuable
than these golds for my margrave.
I hope he will not get under
my feet like others.
What if he does?
If he does, he will get in the grave
with his mother and brothers.
Bey.
The bastard is coming.
-Bey.
-Our target is Noyan.
Our duty is to watch for an opportunity.
If it is necessary, we will trace him
to hell, Wild Demir.
My brave children did not miss
their father, Tangut.
All of them are very sad, Noyan.
Seeing you like a beaten dog
is very hard for them.
My sons are blood-thirsty
for their father.
What else can a father who brought death
but not the victory to his sons expect?
Ogeday will make you pay for this, Tangut.
Feel sorry for yourself, Noyan.
The day you will die
will be the feast of all servants.
These weasels will fight
each other, Bey.
Today, only Tangut's blood
will be spilled here.
Incautious people who believe his words!
Put your swords down.
Run like hell.
None of you will be harmed.
You have my word.
We should go, Noyan. Our horses are ready.
Kill them all!
Do not let them escape!
Coward!
It is time. Follow me.
I will come back to make
your bloodline extinct, Sungurtekin!
Tell Ertugrul to wait for me!
I will strike as thunderbolt
on your nomad tent!
Noyan!
For God!
Wild Demir!
Bey.
Take my daughter's revenge.
Tell Ertugrul Bey, too.
I shahada that the God is the only One
and Prophet Mohammad is his servant
and his messenger.
Wild Demir!
What is the matter, Bey? Why did we stop?
You continue. You continue.
Thank you, Bey.
Peace be upon you, Bey.
I hope nothing is wrong, mother?
Why do you have a face like a wet weekend?
We should go inside, son.
Be seated.
What is wrong, mother?
Trader Efrasiyap turns out to be
Noyan's man.
What are you saying, brother?
He kidnapped
Selcan from the nomad tent.
Do not worry. Selcan is fine.
I managed to bring her back.
Hamza Alp was martyred.
I also managed to bring Noyan to
the nomad tent.
Thank God, we see these days.
What about Noyan?
He was just about to be executed,
Emir Saadettin Kobek came.
There was a peaceful agreement with
our government and the Mongols.
What does it have to do with
Noyan bastard?
We handed Noyan over
to Mongols in exchange of
three prisoners of Seljukian commander.
What are you saying, mother?
How could you let something like
this happen, brother?
We did not want to damage our
government's peace agreement.
Just think about what
this bastard murderer who
even kidnapped Selcan Hatun
to achieve his goals would do to the
women of our tent if he gets the chance.
How could you leave him knowing that
he would take revenge on us
and our loved ones?
What did Sungur Tekin tell about this?
How did he let you free him?
He persuaded us and
the men of two nomad groups
to follow the peace agreement.
Tell me, brother,
what would you do
if it were you?
Did we not come to these mountains
to die for our government?
Now, are we supposed to break our
royal decree?
Blood flows, peace finds its way, brother.
The peace that comes from that sick
bastard does not avail
to neither our tent nor our state.
You could not take precautions.
Mother, I'm telling you as well.
We paid for the mistakes you
made before with our many lives.
We will see what is going to be
the price of this mistake of yours.
Where is Sungur Tekin?
He went to chase after Noyan.
Wild Demir must be with him.
-What happened to you Wild Demir bey?
-Wild Demir Bey.
What happened to you Wild Demir Bey?
Oh, my Wild Demir Bey.
Who did this?
Tangut.
I killed Tangut. However, Noyan
managed to escape.
Yes!
Father!
Wild Demir?
There are wheels within wheels,
Ulubilge.
Otherwise, Tangut, who is shaken
like a cow in front of me,
could not dare to counter me.
If Saadettin Kopek
had not thrown a bone to him,
he would not have dared to do this.
Send his body to Saadettin Kobek.
He should see his own death.
We should set off to go to Ogeday
right away, Ulubilge.
You are badly hurt, Noyan.
You should rest.
We do not have time to waste.
I should prepare a bigger and stronger
army for war.
Our state made peace. Saadettin Kobek,
who is the most precious Emir
of our Sultan came to our nomad tent,
only to solve this matter.
They do not care about any of these.
They are so disorderly as to chase
Noyan just to kill him.
They have killed Tangut.
Noyan has succeeded to escape.
As long as Sungur Tekin
and Ertugrul lives,
they will continue to get
in our ways and be trouble for us.
The hammer smith who died.
Is his funeral tomorrow?
Yes.
I will attend his funeral before
going to Konya tomorrow.
You will do the necessary.
Now that they are
very close to the deceased,
I want to share the
pain of my brave brothers.
Did I mishear you, Emir Saadettin?
I say they have to die, yet you are
here talking about sharing their pains?
Which one is more powerful,
Gumustekin?
This or your weapon?
What your weapon cuts
will eventually be soil.
But, what this cuts will be eternal.
If you want to be the margrave of
Seljukian, you should know this better.
Whoever tries to take care of his
business only with his weapon
his life lasts only as long as
his weapon cuts.
The real dexterity
is to know being permanent
like this Seljukian engraving.
It is to bring his people light
with bloodless victories.
As for Sungur Tekin and Ertugrul.
I prefer them fighting for me
to their stinky dead bodies.
How will this happen?
You will know when the time comes.
Now, you go.
-Emir Highness.
-Yes?
A stray horse brought
a wicker basket to the yard.
I thought you may want to see.
You bastard Noyan!
Noyan. You fortunate rascal.
So, you got the seal of Oghuz Khan,
Sungur Tekin.
Good. The seal of the state
is in good hands.
Take his body to the woods.
His death shall be the feast of ravens.
What makes the land
a homeland is a grave.
You gave your life to make
this land home.
Your wife, two sons and your daughter
became martyrs in the battlefield.
Now, you have been martyred and
reunited with them.
You should know that
I will not stop until my last breath
to make here the homeland.
I swear in front of your dead body that
I will establish the home
you longed for in Byzantine lands.
You should know that I am with you until
death in this blessed case, Bey.
I have waited for a brave man like you
for this blessed case all my life.
May God help us!
It shall be the voice of injustice in
your brave hands. It shall be the wrath.
Wonderful.
Thank God, for giving you to us.
Ertugrul is right again.
Wild Demir firstly paid
the price of conceding Noyan.
-I hope it will be the last one, mother.
-If God permits, daughter.
If God permits.
Peace be upon you, my brothers.
My condolences to us, brothers.
My condolences to us, Bey.
Whoever we love
is departing this life one by one,
Bey.
Then, it is our duty to die
for the rest, Turgut.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Ertugrul Bey, Wild Demir is gone.
He was going to make my first weapon.
He was going to make me an Alp.
Do not worry,
brave men like you will never be alone
in these mountains.
After this, Turali is entrusted first to
you, then to me, Bey.
Of course, Artuk Bey,
of course.
Allahuakhbar!
Brave sons of Oghuz!
I'm Wild Demir from Kayi tribe.
For so long,
I flared up the flames,
I melted the iron.
I made weapons from steel.
I became ancestor to son,
son to ancestor.
Allahuakhbar.
Mortal life. Life ends with death.
Now, I'm joining the caravan
of the departing.
However, I am leaving without worry.
Ertugrul Bey, relieve yourself.
When the time comes,
the roses bloom,
the sun rises, and winter meets spring.
God who gave you
the urge to conquest
will make you a conqueror.
With thousands of mounted raiders,
you will run from continent to continent.
The sparkles that splash off of your
horseshoes will make the cruel fear.
Your conquests
will meddle with the winds.
The flag of our ancestors' inheritance
will cover the horizon.
I know that there will
be a poor Wild Demir.
He will tell
your sagas to children.
Spreading from mouth
to mouth your sagas
will give strength to the
poor and fear to the cruel.
Under the flag, nobody will hurt anybody.
This road is tough, this road is full
of suffering.
Your burden is heavy.
May God help you and
be with you, Ertugrul Bey.
Emir Saadettin.
Ertugrul brother and I
want to talk to you.
First of all, my condolences.
I heard you are close
friends with the hammersmith.
I wanted to attend the funeral
of this honorable brave man.
My condolences.
So, you are Ertugrul Bey. The source of
pride for our Sultan.
What happened is bothering us,
Emir Saadettin.
Tell me, tell me.
If there were not traitors in the palace,
Sungur Tekin would
not have been exposed
and he would have kept
to his duty for his state.
If you had not galloped
for the bastard Noyan,
he would have been executed
and wasted away.
Be at ease. We have cleaned all the
traitors at the palace one by one.
Obviously,
you have not cleaned enough.
The traitors in the palace can reach
through my nomad tent, Emir Saadettin.
Which cleaning are you talking about?
You should know that I will find and
cut the hand that holds the strings.
Wherever it comes from in the palace.
If you had obeyed
the commands of the state,
this poor hammersmith
would be alive today, Ertugrul Bey.
How can you say that in
the face of all the things
we have done for our
government for years?
Obeying the state does not mean to
obey when you wish,
rebel when you do not.
You should obey even if you are hurt.
So that the government
will rely on you.
Now, listen to me carefully.
I was holding Tangut's strings
from the beginning.
It was going fine until Ertugrul got
involved in the Karabek issue
and blew everything.
Then, Sungur Tekin came. I pulled
his leash tight and he cut my horse.
What are you saying, Emir Saadettin?
If you had not shown up with that old
hammersmith showing heroism
Tangut was going to kill Noyan and
take your responsibility of years.
I would make Tangut commander
instead of Noyan.
I would make him drown in gold.
However, you and the old hammersmith
messed it up.
This state was not established
while herding goats like you do, Beys.
Of course, there was always support
from brave men like you.
However, government is way above
your apprehension.
No wonder that we have been
standing tall and strong
for hundreds of years in these lands and
thousands of years in the world.
I told
everything to Sultan Alaaddin.
He is to write a letter and confirm
my words to you soon.
I wish two brave men like you
will learn to obey
the state and its commands.
I have my eyes and
ears on you after this.
I hope
you will not disappoint me again.
We will take the revenge of Wild Demir.
Noyan will die eventually.
I will do whatever is necessary
for him to die.
Be sure that it will be
vouchsafed to you.
Because it is your right.
May God protect you.
-What do you say, brother?
-I do not know, Ertugrul
who will we trust, if we do not
trust the man that comes after Sultan.
-What do you think?
-I will wait for the Sultan's letter.
I am not feeling at ease.
The seal must be in safe hands
from now on, Ertugrul.
I want you to give the seal to
the white beardeds.
From now on, my duty is over.
I will go
wherever my nomad group goes.
Peace be upon you.
In the name of God,
the compassionate,
the merciful, the forgiving God.
My Maker!
We showed ingratitude, we abominated.
We lost the dignity of being Muslim.
We could not be grateful enough for your
blessings. Forgive us!
My Creator!
You made a cave as a castle,
spider web as an armour,
a piegon as spear for
Muslims against the cruel.
God! Get us from the
borehole that we're in today.
Give us help and mercy so that
we can reach our dignity again,
we can be worthy of being Muslim,
being free as human.
You help our brave men so
that we do not bow to the enemies.
Give us help so that we
will not give our freedom to cruel.
We shall be victorious always.
Amen!
We're mourning for the brave son of
Oghuz,
the hammersmith Tarkan, Wild Demir.
There is not a day without mourning
in this nomad tent.
I know that both tents
have suffered a lot.
Many of our brave sons got
martyrized.
I wish Wild Demir will be
the last Hayme Hatun.
And peace come to our nomad tents.
There is peace between the two states.
However, Noyan will not know peace.
He will not stop. He will be back
eventually to be our death.
You should have thought of it
before you handed Noyan over
to Emir Saadettin, Sungur Tekin.
What happened has happened.
From now on, we must think of future.
If we had been afraid of death,
we would not have fought
for our government
in the mountains of Erzurum
against the Mongols.
Now, peace is hope for us.
We all must continue our lives.
I say, if you approve, I would like to
solemnize the marriage of my son and
Gokce.
You are right, Korkut Bey.
His martyrization set
our hearts on fire.
Our pain is great.
But, as you said, life goes on.
We shall solemnize
the marriage of our children soon.
-May it be easy, Hatuns.
-Thank you.
May it be easy.
You are heavily pregnant Halime Sultan,
what are you doing?
I washed three pieces, Ertugrul Bey.
Do not see me as Sultan's daughter.
I am the girl of nomad tent.
He is struggling to become
a more brave
and stronger man in your belly.
There is a great uproar inside of me,
Ertugrul.
He is fluttering to conquer
the world.
What if it is a girl?
If it is a girl,
then, she struggles
to be as beautiful,
brave, and smart as her mother.
I can imagine him riding horse in
these mountains with you, Ertugrul.
From Erzurum to Afat,
Diyarbekir to Aliagi.
-Maybe from Enguru to Sogut.
-Enguru?
We will hit the road as soon as it is
spring and trees blossom, Halime Sultan.
Where to, Ertugrul?
Our son will ride in Byzantian borders.
Did you talk to Mother Hayme and
Gundogdu Bey?
Not yet.
Ertugrul, we just got out of trouble.
It means going into a new trouble
just as we have found peace.
What would they say to this?
We will see when it's time.
However, all I know is that we will hit
the road as soon as our baby is born.
Wherever you go we go Ertugrul.
You should know that
we are three from now on.
I shut Korkut's wife Duru's tongue...
...which is as big as my boot
as poisonous as a snake...
...with this poison.
Now in the same marquee...
...I will decay the heart of that old man
who is her husband...
...with the same poison.
I asked so much from you, Aytolun.
But the worst was that I asked
you to be Korkut's wife.
That old man's smell on me
will vanish sooner or later.
But your margravity...
...will always be a loadstar to Oghuz.
As Tugtekin and Gokce are playing
with each other in the nuptial...
...the old man who is his father,
will draw his last breath.
The wedding night...
...will be the night for Korkut to die
and you to reborn, brother.
How I can make up for your help, Aytolun?
If you will excuse me, brother.
I have things to do in the marquee.
If you help me find what that
whore Aytolun hid in the tent...
Enough! I will never betray
my Hanim and Bey!
What is that you know
but do not tell, Banu Cicek?
Solving this issue comes
before everything.
It is your duty to your Bey, Korkut?
Banu Cicek!
Banu Cicek?
Where have you been?
I am looking for you.
-What are you doing here?
-I am tidying around, Hanim.
Is now the right time for tidying around?
First finish the things, I told you to do.
Your wish is my command, Hanim.
Banu Cicek, your head is in the clouds.
Since Kayis came,
we cannot get rid of troubles.
Look sharp.
And never forget your duty
in this marquee.
Dogan Alp?
My condolences, I wanted to say.
Wild Demir was more than a father to you.
I know.
Thank you.
Look, Banu Cicek. The things
that happened last time...
All the things that happened last time
are bygones.
Let us forget about them.
Anyway, I was so rough to you.
I went too far, I held my dagger to the
throat of a brave man like you.
Thank you.
Banu Cicek.
Tell me now. Why do you doubt Aytolun?
I can not tell you but you must know...
...that whore Aytolun spinned the web
on Uncle Korkut's marquee...
...like a poisonous spider.
Now, she is spinning on
Mother Hayme's marquee.
Because of you,
I entered Korkut Bey's tent.
I searched everywhere like a thief.
I was about to be caught.
Now, you will tell me,
but you will tell me the truth.
Or I swear to God, I will cut
your throat Selcan Hatun.
Now tell me. Why do you doubt her?
Banu Cicek.
You know that...
...Aytolun was Uncle Korkut's lover...
...before Aunt Duru died.
I learned that from the old woman.
I would learn more but she killed her.
But I know, I know Banu Cicek.
What do you know? What more do you know?
Aytolun killed my aunt Duru
to be the Hanim of marquee.
-God is immortal!
-God is the one!
God is immortal!
I told him not to come.
I told him many brave men would expect
many zulfiqars from him.
Even if two worlds come together...
...I would never let Wild Demir,
Noyan go freely from this nomad tent.
We will avenge the blood
they shed, Ertugrul...
...for both our many brave men
and Wild Demir.
Without finding the traitor
in the nomad tent...
...we can never avenge our many brave men
or Noyan's death, brother.
How was the seal captured by Tangut?
Why did he revolt against Noyan?
All of the answers are here, Ertugrul.
In this nomad tent.
Ameer Sadettin already gave
its answer, brother.
What are you trying to say, brother?
Whoever tried to use Tangut,
may use anyone in our nomad tent.
It is high time to talk with Gumustekin.
Banu Cicek.
The necklace is very important to me.
Aytolun killed that poor woman
to silence her.
Goncagul threatens me...
...to tell everyone I killed that
old woman using my necklace.
What else should I tell you
to make you believe me?
Duru Hatun was a mother
both to me and my sister.
She brought us up.
She was a second mother to us.
Will you help me?
To avenge Aunt Duru as well?
The necklace is in Korkut Bey's marquee.
How are you, Goncagul Hatun?
I am fine, Bey. You?
Thank you.
How is Gokce Hatun?
She does not know what to do
due to her excitement.
-It is not easy to be a Bey's wife.
-You are right.
It is not easy to have a marriage
with a hero like Tugtekin.
You are right, Bey. I feel the same
excitement in my heart.
Know that we will be married
as soon as possible.
If God permits. Until the day comes,
my heart will carry this excitement Bey.
If God permits.
Alright, I will take my leave then.
She suddenly got in, Bey.
I could not stop her.
What do you want Selcan Hatun?
Whatever you will say, say later,
can you not?
I know what you were doing with Aytolun,
behind Aunt Duru's back...
...before she died, Uncle Korkut!
What are you saying?
Do not try to act brave with me!
Just listen to what I know!
You lost your mind.
Maybe, who knows?
But first, listen what I will tell you
then decide if I lost my mind or not!
Be seated.
What I will say may tire your old heart.
Do not worry!
What I will tell you will stay between us.
No one will know.
However, only you will know what to do
after you listen to me.
Do you remember the poor old woman
murdered near the nomad tent?
Aytolun killed that woman, Uncle Korkut.
Do you know why?
The woman took the most precious
necklace of my mother from me...
...to tell me what she knows
about Aytolun.
And then she told me that before
Aunt Duru died, Aytolun was your lover.
She would tell more but she asked
for more gold.
To give her what she wanted,
I went back to the tent.
When I went back, she was already dead.
Aytolun killed that woman.
Do you know why, Uncle Korkut?
Do you know, what she would tell me?
I know, now.
Aytolun killed Aunt Duru
to be the Hatun of marquee!
Get out of here!
I told you to get out of here!
My necklace is in your marquee.
Aytolun is hiding it.
To blame me, if I talk.
God damn you, you sinister woman!
You are nonplused of jealousy that
Goncagul will be your husband's wife...
...so you can not hear yourself!
My necklace is right here
in this big chest.
If I hear one more word out of you,
I will kill you!
If you do not settle this matter,
from now on...
...you are the second killer
of Aunt Duru to me.
You should know that!
You are fast.
But I am faster than you.
Long live, Gumustekin Bey!
Apparently, Gundogdu Bey
needs to train you more.
Is it not so, Ertugrul Bey?
You are right, Gumustekin Bey.
I have wanted to train with an adept Alp
like you for so long.
With your permission.
Permission granted, Ertugrul Bey.
Something is going on, indeed.
If Ertugrul Bey says it is training,
clearly he wants to tame the man.
Brother, it is high time to tame
this inauspicious man.
Let us see, what is wrong with our Bey.
Finally, I have found the right Alp
to train with.
If God permits, finding the traitor
who terrorized our marquee...
...will be your destiny as well,
Gumustekin Bey.
What are you trying to say, Ertugrul Bey?
I mean the seal stolen from my mother's
marquee, Gumustekin Bey.
It is such a treason...
...that one end will stretch to Mongol
and the other streches until Konya.
It is clear that you have things
to spit out but not able to say.
I mean Emir Saadettin Kopek.