Episode 50 will start after 12:23 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
Let go of my hand.
Are you still protecting this woman?
I understand you. You are in grief.
But you should be patient.
We need to find out who did this.
I will be by your side on finding out the
truth, no matter whoever gets hurt.
But you need to be patient.
What are you talking about?
The woman you protect, is a murderer!
I protect nobody, Tugtekin.
But I know that nothing is as it seems.
If you act on your anger,
we will never find out the truth.
-Take this woman already!
-No! She will not leave!
Enough! Enough! Enough!
What do you think you are doing?
Tugtekin, take this away!
What are you doing when my brother's body
is still there?
Take this girl away!
Do not do this, my son!
Mother! Mother! Mother!
Let us take her to the marquee, brother.
Come, Ertugrul. Come.
Come with me.
People heard that Korkut Bey
is dead, brother.
If God permits, we will take this woman
to the caged tent.
Wait here.
Alps, attend to the people.
Yes, Bey.
They will take Banu Cicek out.
Do not worry my brother,
we will shield ourselves.
Kill her!
Catch her!
Kill her! Murderer!
We want justice!
We want the killer of our Bey!
We want her to die!
Kill her!
We want her head!
We want her dead!
Father.
Bey, let me prepare your father's body
for the funeral.
Your steadiness at the funeral,
will prevent peoples' anger.
Come, Bey. Come.
Son, until the woman
who did this to your father...
...chokes on her own blood...
...you can not stop.
Tugtekin Bey, after the funeral, you first
duty should be setting the court.
Today. Let justice be upon us quickly.
-Let us go, Bey.
-Come, Bey.
Come.
I failed, brother.
I could not kill that woman.
Our victory day has finally arrived,
Aytolun.
First you should get back on your feet.
Excuse us, Bey. We will take
Aytolun Hatun out of here as well.
Heal my sister, Artuk Bey.
Like you healed my leg which was
about to get cut, you heal her as well.
Hopefully, Bey.
Do not leave this matter
to the court, Bey.
Take my life now.
Take it and end my suffering.
I will bite the dust anyway.
At least you should not be harmed.
Be at ease, woman.
You can never know who is going
to get the sword of justice.
Be patient.
Look at you.
It is all my fault.
Please do not say that.
Cicek Hatun, we already know the score.
I will not let you be the prey
on those jackals' table.
Go away!
What is going on, Dogan Alp?
Are you workholding
with this murderer?
When the truth is revealed,
you will be sorry for your words, Bogac.
Let us pray for you to not be the one who
will feel sorry.
One who goes after this woman...
...will be known as a murderer too.
Dogan Alp!
Dogan!
I am fine, Bey. Do not worry about me.
Turgut.
Take care of Dogan.
-As you wish, Bey.
Come on, brother.
Do you believe that this girl
is innocent, brother?
I am after the truth, brother.
The way I see it, you are after the
truth as well.
Otherwise, would you ask for
Selcan Hatun and Goncagul Hatun...
...to be questioned?
We are in great pain, Mother.
We will harden our heart.
But, until we find the one who killed
my uncle, there will be no mourning.
My brother's dead body at one side...
...Selcan's words...
...and the seal they left
on my nomad tent at another...
How could we overcome all these disasters?
This wounds all of our hearts, Mother.
But we cannot be beaten down
by our pain or our anger.
First of all, we should lay my uncle
to his final rest.
Artuk Bey wants to see Ertugrul Bey,
Mother Hayme.
Let him in, Rahman.
I have to talk to you, Bey.
Go ahead, Artuk Bey.
My mother knows everything.
She can hear what you have to say.
In all these ruckus, I could not even
express my condolences to you.
Thank you Artuk Bey, bless your heart.
Go ahead Artuk Bey, we are listening.
I heard Gumustekin Bey and
Tugtekin Bey talking about this.
They want to set the court
immediately after the burial.
Gumustekin wants to kill and get rid of
Banu Cicek as soon as possible.
That way, he wants to close both the seal
and the murder matter for good.
We can not let that happen.
If he is determined to do this,
how do you plan to stop him, Ertugrul?
After the burial, we will talk to Tugtekin
and convince him to do the Bey ceremony
as soon as possible.
What if the court will be set tomorrow?
What is going to change, son?
There is a long night ahead of us and
it is enough for us to save Banu Cicek.
I'm in great pain.
But all I know is that I believe in you.
Do not let me down.
Excuse me, Artuk Bey.
You are the bravest woman I know, Aytolun.
You did not abstain from
sacrificing yourself.
Thanks to my aunt, the things
we wished for, became reality, father.
As long as Banu Cicek lives
our goals will be our graves.
Do not worry, Aytolun.
Everything will come to an end
in the court I set today.
Selcan will dig her own grave
with her accusations.
And Ertugrul...
As soon as I get the Bey sword myself
taking care of Ertugrul
will be Tugtekin's job.
There is something I wish
to ask you, Artuk Bey.
That old woman who Selcan Hatun
has been talking about. Who is she?
Before I came to this place as a medic,
she was healer of nomad tent.
After Korkut Bey gave me the medic duty,
she kept herself in silence.
Healer, you say?
Then she would know
how to made a poison, too.
Yes, she does Bey.
They were poisoned by the same vile
yet while my uncle dies
Aytolun Hatun lives.
It sickens me Artuk Bey.
Selcan Hatun says that, when the old woman
came in here, Aytolun dismissed her.
Obviously, there is an ominous secret
between Aytolun and this old woman.
Whatever this secret is
it kept her alive, while killing
my aunt and my uncle.
I will not let them take their secrets
to their graves.
I will not put forth Banu Cicek
to their make believe court.
They will kill her.
I can not let them do this to Banu Cicek.
Dogan.
Stop, brother. Keep your anger in check.
This is not the way to do this.
Our Bey will surely find a solution.
No, brother, we should save
our sister Banu Cicek.
Bamsi, stop this. Do not feed the fire.
Permission!
I have a few questions for you, Dogan.
Are you ready to give up
everything you have?
-Yes, I am Bey.
-To be exiled?
-Yes, Bey.
-To die?
Always, Bey.
You will Banu Cicek escape tonight.
Now listen to me carefully.
You will take a medicated sherbet
made by Artuk Bey to Banu Cicek.
Alps will not probably let you in.
Give the sherbet to the guards
and make them fall asleep.
There should not be any bloodshed.
In this cold weather, nobody will say no
to that hot sherbet, Bey.
Fasten the horses that you will use
to escape with Banu Cicek.
After you escaped, nobody
should be able to blame
Turgut or Bamsi for this,
do you understand that?
-Understood, Bey.
-What are we going to do, Bey?
You will watch over Dogan. Make sure
that nobody follows you or sees you.
-As you wish, Bey.
After the escape, you need to go to
Kurtbogazi and wait for my message.
-Understood?
-Understood, Bey.
If you are ready, we should leave.
We have a funeral.
-Good luck with that.
-Thank you.
What is wrong Turali?
Did you miss Father Demir?
Is it possible not to Bey?
Did you not miss him?
Come here.
I too, miss him.
I miss him as much as you do.
But last night Father Demir came to me
and talked to me.
Where did he come?
I saw him in my dreams, Bey.
So?
What did Father Demir say to you?
He said that someone made a weapon for me.
And I will go to war with it right
beside Ertugrul Bey.
Ertugrul Bey will make me an Alp.
And he said that I will be a great Alp.
Come here then.
If God permits, Turali.
If God permits, my boy.
If God permits.
Pig's tripe has bursted, all of its dirt
and disgraces revealed, Halime.
That's what I'm afraid of Selcan.
From now on, all of their worries
will be Ertugrul.
Did you get what you wished for,
Selcan Hatun?
Yes, I did. After everything has revealed
in the court, I will get more.
And you will not be able to find even
a single little hole to take cover in.
I do not know, who still stands
not affected by your accusations.
But when this is all over
you will lose, Selcan Hatun.
Do you know why I am happy Goncagul?
You can not act on the sly no more.
Your only weapon is living like a bug
in nooks and crannies
and distress the ones that
you are able to get a grip on.
But you will not be able to do
that anymore.
I whirled your own evil around you,
let us see if you can escape from that.
Let us see how you will be
able to deal with
all those sins that you commit
in the past.
You are the most cruel woman
that I know Selcan Hatun.
You even have your own sibling's blood
on your hands.
Selcan. Please do not do that.
How do you know all these things?
I know. I know that you ambushed
Ertugrul Bey with Kurtoglu
and I know that you persuaded Gokce, too.
Who would believe a woman like you?
Let us see what will you do
when the people of two nomad groups
knows what a shrew you are!
Selcan, are you alright?
Selcan.
Heaven only knows why.
What happened Selcan?
What is wrong with you?
I think I am pregnant, Halime.
Pregnant?
Aunt.
Mother.
I am fine.
I wanted to be your side.
Mother Hayme and
Ertugrul Bey arrived, Bey.
Let them in.
When I looked at you
I saw my brother's eyes.
My father is gone, aunt.
He will be always in you with his courage
and his sense of justice.
I hope so.
Go ahead.
-My condolences, brother.
-Thank you.
Let us be seated.
Son, do not leave your people leaderless
for even one night.
The murderer who killed our Bey
will pay for her crime Hayme Hatun.
The punishment should be decided
by the newly selected Bey.
That's the proper way for a Bey.
My father is also a Bey in
our nomad tent, Mother Hayme.
But he is not the Bey of the nomad tent.
This is not matter of state, this is
an internal matter of the nomad tent.
And the Bey is entitled to judge
his people.
With his sense of justice
and with his graces.
He should show that he is handling even
the death of his father justly with grace.
Hayme Hatun, you are wrong.
Mother.
Mother Hayme and
my brother Ertugrul are right.
My people expect justice from me.
I was so focused on my anger and pain,
I forgot my people.
Leaving the nomad group even
for one night without a leader
is not proper by our morals
and my father's marquee.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
Excuse me.
What is it, my daughter?
Mother Hayme and Ertugrul Bey
came to the marquee, father.
They persuaded Tugtekin
to hold the Bey ceremoni soon.
He wants to be elected as Bey
and rule the court himself.
Then he will question
both Selcan Hatun and me.
I do not know what can come out of this.
I am afraid, father.
Do not be afraid, daughter.
Then we will take precautions.
How, father?
Tugtekin already made up his mind.
He might already have sent
the news to everyone.
So now it is time for Tugtekin to learn
Selcan Hatun's accusations.
Tell your aunt that she should
put a bug in Tugtekin's ear tonight.
As for you, I will send Gundogdu to you.
Tell him what kind of a woman his wife is.
If Ertugrul wanted to left the court
for tomorrow
surely he has something else in his mind.
I need to know what he and
his Alps are doing at all times.
Permission, Gumustekin Bey?
Come in, Gundogdu Bey.
Excuse me, Bey.
-I was thinking of you.
-What is the matter, Bey?
Hayme Hatun and Ertugrul.
Persuaded Tugtekin to hold the ceremony
and set the court for tomorrow.
It seems the justice will be served
by our new Bey tomorrow.
I hope that your brother Ertugrul
is not pursuing any other goals.
Why did you want to see me?
Bey, I need to talk to you about something
for the sake of the court.
Court is in our new Bey's hands now,
Gundogdu Bey.
Okay, then I will take my leave.
Ertugrul.
I heard that you persuaded my mother
to postpone the court date. Why?
Are we not looking for justice, brother?
This is not a matter of state, brother.
This is a matter of the nomad tent.
And the Bey should be the one that
secures the justice. Am I right?
Try not to do something wrong, brother.
In all these wrongs, finding the truth
will be Tugtekin's duty brother.
Certainly, it will be his duty.
However you should know
as the leader of the Alps,
I will know everything you do.
You made my brother furious, Ertugrul.
He is always like this.
I did what needs to be done.
And I will continue to push him
until he sees the truth.
-Permission, Bey?
-Come in.
You asked for me, Bey.
Bogac Alp.
I know your loyalty to Tugtekin Bey.
He is suffering much.
It is time for us to support him
in his dark days.
I will give my life for Bey.
I think that Ertugrul is doing
something wrong.
Assign the Alps that you trust
to keep an eye on Ertugrul's Alps.
If you have even the slightest doubt,
come here and let me know.
As you wish, Bey.
-We want to talk to you about something.
-What is it, son?
In this dark day, it is hard
to talk about this, I know.
But...
Migration time has come, Mother.
Where did that come from?
Mother, as you very well know,
my deceased uncle was
the one who kept two nomad groups
together. And now he is gone.
It is possible that Tugtekin
will be elected as Bey.
And sooner or later, he will learn
what Selcan said.
Also, you can guess what will happen when
Dogan lets Banu Cicek escape tonight.
Even if we prove that
Gumustekin stole the seal
and the one who killed my uncle
gets punishment
I finally understood one thing, Mother
the soil that our almighty tree will
take root, is not here.
I know that in my heart.
Our constrained stay in our
Dodurgali siblings lands is over.
Spring is coming, mother.
There is no time to loose.
After the things that happened,
I agree with you two.
But where can we go, son?
Places that we will be able to prosper
become stronger and stand tall
with the will of God.
Where is that place, son?
We will go to west, mother.
To the Byzantine border of our state.
Well, what does your brother Gundogdu
says about this?
Let us pray Al-Fatiha for
our deceased Korkut Bey.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
In the 99 names of God,
who at will creates
and fills the hearts of his creations
with belief.
Dear Beys of Dodurga.
You honored our seignory headquarter.
In your presence, I ask God
to bestow his graces upon our Bey.
May God reward him with his heaven.
Amen.
Dogan.
Turgut brother, what are you doing here?
Did you forget what Bey said?
I alone should take the horses
that we escape with.
We are being followed Dogan.
Do not let them know.
You can not take the horses anymore.
Who will take them then?
Abdurrahman.
It seems that Gumustekin
sent his men to follow us.
What am I going to do tonight?
How can I lose them?
Even if I did, they will get
more suspicious, right?
-How can I let Banu Cicek escape now?
-Stop.
I am thinking.
Bamsi and me will quarrel tonight.
And you will seize this opportunity
to flee from the tent.
But they need to think
that you are in the tent.
After that, it's up to you, brother.
-I will run right after what?
-Come on. I will tell you later.
Untie the horse, go to Abdurrahman
and tell him the situation.
He will take the horses. And I will
take the saddles to the tent.
-Alright, brother.
-Alright.
Getting assigned is always desirable,
Gumustekin Bey.
I know that the ones who wish to be Bey
are feeling ashamed of saying so.
As you have the honour
of holding the cerenomy
we would like to know
what you have in your heart.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
I believe, the one who is
worthy of this rank
is the one who served for our community
and Korkut Bey's brave son, Tugtekin Bey.
As you desire in your heart, Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Gumustekin Bey.
Hearing those words from a worthy man
such as yourself, made me glad.
I also nominate Tugtekin Bey as our Bey.
We respect Tugtekin Bey dearly.
However, we all know that
he could not become successful
as the leader of the Alps.
I also wonder how will he do
as the Bey of Dodurga.
To tell the truth, I think with
his experience and knowledge
the one who fits this rank perfectly
is Gumustekin Bey.
You asked for me, mother?
Come son, sit down.
We do not even have time to mourn
for my brother. But...
...there is something that I need
to know what do you think about.
Yes, Mother. What is it?
Two tents can no longer
walk in the same road, son.
This is how I see it.
How can you say that, mother?
Don't you know that Noyan will come back?
Are you not aware of that
the peace is temporary?
We need this unity.
Remember what they did to us
while we were migrating.
Remember all our pain,
all those martyrs, mother.
We neither have a place to go
nor have a place to stay.
I think we should stay united.
This is my opinion.
What is going to happen when Tugtekin
hears everything tomorrow in the court?
If this unity will brake with
some accusations, then so be it.
But, if God permits, tomorrow
the court will decide justly
and this unity will continue.
At least until we can get back
on to our feet.
This unity needs to stand,
until we get rid of Noyan, mother.
Did Ertugrul said something
to you, mother?
Look, mother. You should not follow
Ertugrul's whims.
You should not drag all these people
to follow him with you.
Mother, think this over.
If you insist on doing this,
I swear to God I am not with you on this.
You should know that.
That you deem me worthy of the Bey rank
made me feel quite fortunate.
Thank you all.
However, this rank suits Tugtekin Bey.
As a son of Oguz, Tugtekin Bey
has all the virtues to be our Bey.
Thank you.
Gumustekin Bey, we trust your words.
However, how can you be so sure that
Tugtekin Bey will be able to overcome
the responsibilities of this duty?
While fighting against the
Mongol heathens,
Tugtekin Bey came back from the dead
and revealed his ability to be our Bey.
The bravery and the sense of justice
of Korkut Bey
is manifested through Tugtekin Bey.
And he proved this again and again
in all the wars that he fought!
Thank you.
In that case, let the decision be made
by Dodurga Beys.
Anyone who wants Tugtekin Bey to be
the Bey of Dodurga, raise your hands.
Tugtekin Bey is the new Bey of Dodurga!
Hope this will bring good fortune
and prosperity to our community.
Amen.
Tugtekin Bey...
...may your rule bring peace
to our nomad tent.
If God permits...
...like the deceased Korkut Bey,
you will be a just Bey
who take care of his nomad tent,
his kin and his bloodline, Bey.
If God permits, Artuk Bey.
Beys...
...I appreciate that you all see me
worthy of this position.
Alright.
I would like you all to know,
I will carry this flag
that I took over from my father,
with great honour.
-May God help us.
-Amen.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Permission!
Are you ready?
We are ready, Bey.
However, Gumustekin put his Alps on our
tail. They are watching our every move.
Abdurrahman took the horses, Bey.
We will elude them at night and
do the necessary. Do not worry.
Thank you.
I trust you. Be on alert.
When they will learn about this, first,
Tugtekin will sic his Alps on us as.
Do not dissent.
What I want from you is to bow to them
when Tugtekin's Alps come.
Is it clear, Bamsi?
It is clear, Bey.
Give your blessings, Bey.
I give you my blessings, Dogan brother.
May God be our helper.
Your virtue as Bey will bring welfare
and safety to Dodurga Tent.
Thank you.
Your experiences will
guide me, Gumustekin Bey.
God bless you, Tugtekin Bey!
God bless you!
Brave men of Dodurga!
We survived many battles, many suffers.
Because of our deceased Korkut Bey
we walked over every obstacle in our way.
The blood flowing from our weapons
swept like a holy river.
This is how we will do it after this.
I will revenge my deceased Korkut Bey.
Now, the time for Dodurga
is to get rid of traitors inside of us
and to rear up!
God bless you, Tugtekin Bey!
Tugtekin Bey.
The inspirations regularly coming to
our Prophet was interrupted for a time.
At that times, Hazrat Gabriel
was not seen to himself.
Thereupon, some of the polytheists
mocked with him like
his God forsaken Mohammed
his God left him.
Our Master of Prophet who was facing
brutal responses of polytheists
since the day he invited people
from the religion of God
was the object of their mocking this time.
This matter was upsetting him a lot.
His biggest helper was his God
beyond any doubt.
The inspirations coming from God
was giving him strength and power.
It was showing him how to act
in his way of invite.
With the interruption of inspirations,
our Prophet was devoted of his God
his only abutment and
his only consolation.
At that very trouble time of our Prohpet
Duha Surah was told.
His God told his Prophet that:
"By the forenoon and by the night
when it is still.
Your Maker has neither forsaken you
nor hated you.
And indeed the hereafter is better for you
than the present.
And verily, your Maker will give you
so that you shall be well-pleased.
Did He not find you an orphan
and gave you a refuge?
And he found you unaware and guided you?
And he found you poor and made you rich?
Therefore, treat not the orphan with
oppression and repulse not the beggar.
And proclaim the Grace of your Maker."
This surah gave strength and gospel
to our Prophet.
There are certainly morals
to us, Islamic Ummah.
We shall know that our Lord never forsake
us even though darkness
and cruelty spreaded
all over the universe.
It is our duty to build goodness
and morals without doubt
or quail in this universe
that is full of evil,
dissension, where cruel defeated poor
where brother kills brother.
The reward of this grand battle will be
given to us
Hereafter if not present.
This is the pledge of God to faithful men.
This road is certainly tough.
But our God says:
"Do you think you can ascend the heaven
without suffering like your preceding?"
The biggest sound on the sky will be
the sound of truth and right.
As long as we keep our faith.
And fighting without doubt.
Gumustekin convinced people who thought
Tugtekin is young and not up to being Bey.
Well, if it is not about being Bey
of Dodurga, what does this man want?
What do you think, brother?
He must want to achieve a higher place
if he did not become candidate
for being Bey.
What does this mean, Ertugrul?
He must eventually receive recompense from
Konya for his services to Ameer Saadettin.
With a big bone in his mouth.
He is going to want to smush me
with that bone first.
Then everybody near me.
He cannot afford that, Bey.
His murderer is Aytolun, Bey.
Tell me everything.
Tell me otherwise I will cut you
like a sacrificial here. Tell me!
Aytolun killed the old lady!
Goncagul knows this as well!
Ah, Selcan, ah! What did you do?
Selcan is a troubled woman, Bey.
It is obvious that you are a merciful man.
You have a clean heart that you do
not put aside of your wife of years.
I know you have many burden.
Being this mournful and alone
does not behave you, Bey.
I do not know what to do anymore.
My almighty God guide me to the right.
May truth reveals erewhile
so that I come to light.
Do not let everything to end for my wife
when we are trying to stand straight
against Mongols by uniting
two nomad tents.
I resorted to you from every evil,
every malignity.
Do I have permission, Artuk Bey?
Come in, Dogan Alp.
Dogan Alp.
You do not worry.
You will protect Banu Cicek from cruelty
of tyrants with God's willing.
Look, I prepared a sherbet that could
make a bear hibernate in summer.
May God bless you, Artuk Bey.
I had many battles but I have
never been afraid of death.
However, now, I am afraid that
I cannot protect Banu Cicek.
I wish you prepared something that
could set my mind ease.
"For God is with those who restrain
themselves and those who do good."
You shall relieve yourself, Dogan Alp.
-Thank you.
Behind this veil of mystery, there are
betrayals that could debilitate
not only our nomad tent but also
our government, Mother.
How could you reveal the truth after you
kidnap Banu Cicek, Ertugrul?
I will draw Gumustekin on myself, mother.
This is the only way to protect
both Selcan and Tugtekin.
What kind of a game is this?
Not a game, mother. It is war.
A war that we will go through
without weapons but with mind.
Sometimes, you have to set another fire
to quench the fire.
Gumustekin is going to have
to attack me desperately.
Then, I am going to find
his weak point and attack.
My brother Gundogdu is going
to see the truth by this way.
Gundogdu resented me when he heard that
I am with you.
He does not talk to Selcan, either.
He is alone in his tent.
What did my brother tell you when you
said it is time to migrate, mother?
He said, "Our way is together
with Dodurga.
We cannot separated when there is
a big trouble like Noyan."
So...
...what will happen if your brother
says no, Ertugrul?
Then, we will go, mother.
What if I say no?
Then, I'll go with those who believe me.
If nobody believes me
I will go alone.
Bamsi, what did not you understand?
We are chased.
We should detain the Alps chasing us
for Dogan to kidnap Banu Cicek.
This is why you and I'll fight.
When Alps are detained with us,
Dogan will disappear.
Now, you understand?
-Of course I understood that, brother.
I do not understand why we have to fight
for Dogan to kidnap Banu Cicek.
Brother, we need Alps these days.
I am heavy-handed.
Why are we sacrificing you?
I took the sherbet from Artuk Bey.
Are you ready?
Dogan brother, look. We should not kill
Turgut to save Banu Cicek sister.
It is a pity.
He will become disabled at worst.
Do you think me as athehist?
How can you mock with me?
I am neither like bears you killed in your
dream, nor like athehist you killed.
Watch yourself. I shall not be the
last image you saw, Hamza.
-I understood, brother.
-You understood.
-I understood you.
-Good.
Come.
Bamsi, do not touch me ever
or I will kill you!
Turgut, come here. Come here, Turgut!
Go away! It will be bad!
Come here! We are not over yet!
Turgut! Bamsi! What are you doing?
What if Bey sees you?
Dogan! You stay out of this!
Go sleep! I do not want to deal
with you as well!
What the hell! I am going to sleep!
How could you talk about Selcan Hatun?
Do you have no conscience?
Stop, brothers!
Stop! Do not do this!
-How could brother do this to a brother?
-Stop, do not do this!
-You wanted this! Come on!
-Come on!
Come on!
Stop! Stop!
Enough.
Leave each other.
-It is enough!
-Stop!
How could brother do this to a brother?
Enough. Stop. Stop.
-Shame on you!
-Bamsi, enough!
-Calm down!
-Enough. Stop.
Come here!
Leave me! Leave!
Okay! Okay!
-Congratulations to your Seigniory, Bey.
-Thank you.
Congratulations to your Seigniory, Bey.
Thank you, Yigit Salur.
-Congratulations to your Seigniory, Bey.
-Thank you, Durgun.
Mother Hayme and his family are here
to congratulate you, Bey.
Welcome them.
-Excuse me, Bey.
-Of course.
Welcome, Mother Hayme.
Congratulations to your
Seigniory, Tugtekin.
Thank you. Please sit down.
Congratulations to your Seigniory,
son of my uncle.
Thank you. Thank you. Please.
You will be the honor of Dodurga
with your Seigniory, Tugtekin Bey.
-Thank you.
-May God bless you.
Thank you. Please.
I wish you bring power to your tent
with your justice, mercy and strength.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, please.
Congratulations to your
Seigniory, Tugtekin Bey.
Thank you, Halime Hatun. Please.
-Peace be upon you, brothers.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
What is going on, Dogan?
I brought hot sherbet to Banu Cicek Hatun.
What are you doing with this
murderer woman?
It will be revealed if she is the murderer
or not tomorrow at the court, brother.
Black sheep and white sheep
will be separated tomorrow.
Go away, Dogan. We cannot let anybody in.
Okay, then.
You shall drink. It will make you warm.
If you have on your conscience,
you shall give some to Banu Cicek Hatun.
May your Seigniory keep alive.
May justice seep into you.
Amen.
Bey, in our morals, Seigniory celebration
is unfortunately based on another grief.
Grief of Korkut Bey will always
be in our hearts, you should know.
Thank you.
The holy day will come when I end the
sedition that is gnawing my nomad tent.
Gumustekin Bey and Goncagul Hatun
are here, Bey.
Let them in.
Welcome.
May God make your Seigniory
permanent, Bey.
Thank you. Sit down.
God bless your Seigniory, Bey.
Thank you, Goncagul Hatun. Thank you.
Sit down, please.
Beys of Kayi believed on me like the
Beys of Dodurga
and came to congratulate me by honoring
my marquee. Thank you.
I hope that association of two tent will
continue until we stop Mongol atheists.
If God permits.
The biggest inheritance
that Korkut Bey left us
is the association of two nomad tents.
It is all of our duty to do necessary
for handing it to this.
Like my father said, two nomad tent's
sharing a common fate is above everything.
I will show the assertion of this
holy position that I took
over in my painful day with my justice
and mercy, like Ertugrul Bey said.
I hope the murderer of my father will be
served right in tomorrow's court.
If God permits.
If God permits, if God permits.
Dogan Alp!
We are leaving, Cicek Hatun.
Are you out of your mind?
Why're you doing this?
Do you know what will happen to you?
It is the order of Bey. Let's hurry.
I should kidnap you to reveal the truth.
First, we should take the guards
inside and tie them.
Do I have permission, Gundogdu Bey?
Come in, Gumustekin Bey.
I am afraid that the accusation
at two nomad tents is damaged.
Is something wrong?
When Tugtekin Bey hears about
Selcan Hatun's confessions tomorrow.
We cannot restrain him easy like this
when he will heard.
Goncagul will testify at the court
as you wish.
But, you should know that
her words are going to harm both
nomad tents deeply not only us.
You should be ready
for this, Gundogdu Bey.
Tell me what you know, Gumustekin Bey.
Ask this to my daughter, not me.
She shall explain it all over.
Then, if you let me, I want to speak
to Goncagul Hatun.
Go, then.
Maybe you will prevent the disaster
that will happen tomorrow.
I want to wish you good night, mother.
Do you want anything from me?
Gokce daughter went to bring fresh water.
I will take medicine that
Artuk Bey prescribed.
I will be better tomorrow, if God permits.
If God permits. If God permits.
You shall stay straight
in the court tomorrow
so that everybody shall see the
puissance of our Seigniory.
You are the only support of me at this
very painful day of me, mother.
I know. I know.
I never doubt that.
My son, late justice
is no good for anybody.
Especially when there are
ominous clouds over us.
What do you want to mean, mother?
Nothing.
Mother.
Our peace that we have when your father
is alive must have resented somebody.
They have spreaded rumors about us.
You'll hear this at the court yourself.
It is hurting me more to hear about
these impure gossips
while I am mourning for my Korkut Bey.
What are you hiding but knowing?
It is very hard for me to talk about
these at my Bey's marquee.
However, since you ask
maybe it will be better for you to know
it as the Bey of this nomad tent.
Do I have permission, Goncagul Hatun?
Come in, Gundogdu Bey.
I have the permission of Gumustekin Bey.
I want to talk to you.
I heard that you want me to testify
at the court, Bey.
Obviously, Selcan Hatun confused you
as well, with slanders.
You broke the pitcher where unpleasant
secrets were kept.
It is the best. It was about time.
I will tell everything.
I'll testify at the court.
Then, you will learn all of it, Bey.
Goncagul Hatun, I do not know
if I see the court.
Tell me everything right here right now.
I do not have patient any more.
This necklace is the necklace that
my mother gave to Selcan at the wedding
and her mother gave it to her formerly.
Why do you have it?
Selcan Hatun is a more dangerous woman
then I guess, Gundogdu Bey.
Excuse me for saying this.
It seems that she wanted to create
trouble with this necklace
that is the inheritance of her mother.
What do you mean, Goncagul?
I saw with my own eyes that she tried to
buy that old lady with this necklace, Bey.
Tell me. Tell me everything.
Tell me, mother.
What are you hiding from me?
Selcan, she is creating trouble
in the nomad tent again.
Like plague her lies are
spreading around the tent.
Tell me mother. Tell me so that
I can do the necessary.
Dying
is better than being
slandered by her.
She says
I had illegitimate
relationship with Korkut Bey
when your mother was alive.
Every word comes out of that
ominous woman.
I did not press the issue
for not upsetting your father
when he was alive.
I am exhausted any more.
Selcan has kept talking
since the day Gundogdu Bey
wanted to marry Goncagul.
Is this her problem?
Yes.
I did not want to talk about this.
But maybe it is better for you
to hear this from me.
Tell me, mother. Tell me. Tell me.
What do you mean, Goncagul?
Tell me straight.
I was returning collecting healing herbs
for my father's feet.
I hear something.
I saw them talking fevered.
Old lady threw away the necklace
that Selcan gave her by saying that
she could not do this to Aytolun Hatun.
I knew Selcan was up to no good.
I wanted to go and tell this to my aunt.
By the time, we heard about that
an old lady's body was found.
When everybody left
I went and got the necklace from
where the old lady threw it.
-What did you tell her?
-I did not tell.
-I say what did you tell her?
What is this?
I did not tell her anything!
She forgot about the necklace out
of her guilt.
Maybe, she searched but could not find it.
I took the necklace and hide it.
I understood everything.
What did you understand, Goncagul?
Tell me for God's sake. What?
That Selcan killed that old lady.
Then, she started to threaten me every day
to get off Gundogdu Bey's back.
One day, I could not resist and tell her
that I had the necklace
and I knew everything.
I know that you killed that old lady.
What are you saying?
There was your necklace on her body.
It is obvious that you killed her.
Because she did not want to take it.
The proof is your necklace.
And I have it. I kept quiet for you
not to be any more shame for Bey.
But with a tiny mistake of yours,
Gundogdu Bey, Korkut Bey
and Mother Hayme will learn the truth.
I will make you executed, Selcan.
Stay away from us and our happiness.
Goncagul, do you know what you say?
I know.
And I will tell about all of this
at the court, Gundogdu Bey.
Selcan killed that old lady, is that so?
Yes.
She will answer for this at the court.
What else do you know?
It does not behave me to speak
if I cannot prove it.
No, Goncagul. No.
I am not judging you here.
All I want to know is the truth.
Is what Aytolun Hatun told is true?
Is it true?
My beautiful sister.
When will you give up ruining
your life at the entrances?
When will you give up bandying about?
I am out of patient now!
Tell me the truth now!
Tell me, is it true?
Tell me the truth anymore!
Permission!
-Bey!
-Get out, Gokce.
-Tugtekin.
-Bey.
-I said get out! I said get out!
Bey, I will not go anywhere
until I learn the truth!
This devil sister of yours was spreading
about illegitimate relationship
with Aytolun Hatun and my father.
Even before my mother died!
Sister, is this true?
Yes. But not slander. All truth.
-Bey.
-Tell me, Selcan Hatun.
Tell me that I will not be your death.
Tell me!
Do I have permission, Mother Hayme?
What gives, Abdurrahman?
Mother Hayme, Tugtekin Bey
got into Selcan Hatun's tent.
She slandered my aunt and Korkut Bey
like they were having affair
before marriage.
On the top of it
she said that my aunt killed Duru Hatun
because she wanted to be woman of Bey.
What should I say more, Gundogdu Bey?
She tried to cheat Banu Cicek
with her slanders and to kill them.
Do you know why, Bey?
For me not to become your wife.
She tried to cross us by blaming me,
my aunt and my father.
Is it not enough?
What is done is done to that stupid girl.
I will not let Selcan Hatun
to get out of this blameless.
Even if I gain your anger,
I will not let this go.
Take this necklace, Bey.
Give it to your mother.
So that, she will see herself
how unconscientious her daughter is.
-Speak woman!
-Bey!
Please do not do this.
Tell me what you know about Aytolun Hatun
and my father. Talk.
Nor is this all, Bey. There is more.
The ignoble who set you on me
told you less.
Speak.
Have you never suspected that your mother
who could get water
from a flint died suddenly, Tugtekin Bey?
-What do you mean?
-Do you not still understand?
I shall tell you one more.
Both your mother's and your father's
murderer is still in your nomad tent!
Tugtekin Bey!
Tugtekin!
Don't do it, brother.
Did you know about
her slanders?
You knew, but kept quiet.
Is that so?
She says Aytolun Hatun killed
my parents. But you still tell me to stop.
We shall wait until the trial,
Tugtekin Bey.
Screw your trial!
Are you on her side, too?
Ertugrul! Tugtekin!
Mother Hayme, your daughter Selcan
is involved in my father's death.
I will make her talk.
She will talk at the trial
whether you like it or not.
Now, get out of here.
You are making things worse.
I ran out of patience, Mother Hayme.
Whoever comes my way,
will have his share of my rage.
Neither your words nor your tent raid
are what is expected of a Bey.
I know you are grieving
and I will keep quiet.
But, go away.
You are with her, too?
Tugtekin, get a hold of yourself.
Questioning Selcan and
punishing her if necessary
is my duty.
Not yours.
Selcan. Go to your tent.
Mother.
I hope you don't have anything to
do with this, Ertugrul.
One day you will beg for
forgiveness from all of us, cousin.
If you are involved in this,
there will be blood.
-Abdurrahman.
-Yes, Mother.
Place two guards in front of
Selcan Hatun's tent.
At once, mother.
-Did Banu Cicek get away, Ertugrul?
-Dogan was there to help her, mother.
Selcan is my lady.
We've shared the same bed
for years.
How could she do this to us?
What did she do?
What are you talking about, son?
Your late mother's necklace.
Selcan gave it to
the old lady who died.
Goncagul said she saw it herself.
Goncagul Hatun's words
don't prove anything, brother.
Don't tell me anything, Ertugrul.
Let's just keep our mouths shut
until the hearing.
Goncagul says Selcan
killed that woman.
This necklace is the proof.
So, Selcan must be involved in
my uncle's murder, mother.
Selcan ruined us, mother.
Not only us but the whole tribe.
Gundogdu Bey.
Please open your eyes.
Tugtekin Bey raided
Selcan's tent just now.
Don't you see how they
are playing tricks on you?
Halime!
Tugtekin.
I care about neither Ertugrul,
nor my sister, nor my mom.
You should know that
I am with you forever.
Your marquee is my home.
Thank you, my love.
I don't doubt that.
I know that you will be with me
when it is time to
avenge my father.
Did you learn everything?
Everything?
Everything.
Then, it is up to you
to clear our name
at the court tomorrow.
Tugtekin!
What have you done?
Bursting into the tent
of Bey's lady?
That tent is my honor,
don't you know that?
He's still grieving, Gundogdu Bey.
You would have done the same thing.
I found about all the dirt
from her poisoned tongue.
What could I do? She should
be grateful that she's alive.
Know your place, Tugtekin!
If this is the matter,
her blood is halal to me.
-Is it your duty to execute her?
-Your mother said the same thing.
-What kind of a snake you married?
-Tugtekin.
Enough!
Obviously, everybody
wants to see Selcan dead.
However, nobody cares about me
and Korkut Bey's dignity.
How can we live with this shame?
Gundogdu Bey, how?
How?
Mother.
-Peace be upon you, brother.
-And peace be upon you.
I made some food for you.
You should cross the mountains
before they notice you are gone.
May God be with you.
God bless you all, brother.
I will always remember your help.
As long as I breathe, everybody
will hear about your courage.
Thank you.
-Who did this?
-Dogan Alp.
He came over and I don't
remember the rest.
We all passed out.
Don't let the trial take too long,
Gumustekin Bey.
The longer that it takes,
the angrier people will get.
It will be all over before noon, Bey.
Everything is crystal clear.
Then, it will be Selcan's turn.
She will pay for her slanders.
I will go to Konya right after the trial,
Bey, if I have your permission.
Ameer Sadettin Kobek wants to see me.
Permission is yours, Gumustekin Bey.
Give my regards to Sultan Aleaddin
and Ameer Sadettin.
-May I come in, Bey?
-Come in, Kaya.
Bey, Banu Cicek has escaped.
-How?
-I don't know, Bey.
However it happened
after Dogan Alp's arrival.
-Ertugrul!
-What does Ertugrul have to do with this?
There must be something
they are afraid of.
Otherwise, why would they do this?
Now, do you understand
why they postponed the hearing, Bey?
If Turgut and Bamsi are still in
the tent, catch them immediately.
As your command, Bey.
There is no need for a trial
anymore, Bey.
Their blood is halal to you.
However, don't you forget that
Gundogdu stands for justice.
Obviously, it is Ertugrul who
misleads Hayme Hatun.
Thus we discovered the
source of treason.
When I'm in Konya, I will discuss
this with Ameer Sadettin.
We will destroy Ertugrul,
with the help of the state if needed.
Why did you get involved in
something dangerous like this?
Is it because you believe me...
...or because Ertugrul Bey told you to?
I would die for Bey
if he wants me to.
However, this time...
This time, what?
It's different this time.
I don't know how to say this.
However...
It is for you this time.
I...
I cannot send you to the gallows...
...when I can't even bear
to see you bruise your arm.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
There is no death for those
who die for their beloved.
There is no grief for those
who stand up to cruelty.
There is unity and love
for those who take the road.
Come with me.
Did you help
Banu Cicek escape?
You never believed
that I love Tugtekin.
You always thought I was after
him to avenge Ertugrul.
You wanted us two married
for your own interests, although
he loves me like a sister.
Now, you are trying to prevent
brother Gundogdu
and Goncagul's marriage for
your own interests again.
With your evil ideas and slanders.
Enough!
Don't you see, evil is all around us
and spreading its poison?
Don't you understand,
Korkut Bey's death is just a beginning?
They'll kill whoever
in stands their way
until they reach their goals.
This also includes
Gundogdu and Tugtekin Beys.
Enough already.
Don't be so naive, sister.
You think everybody is like you, right?
How many people did you hurt?
You broke up families...
...including your own.
Wasn't that enough?
You always wanted me to be
a Bey's wife. I am now.
But not through your
dirty games this time.
It's because I love him,
and he loves me.
If you were involved
in Banu Cicek's escape...
...if what Aytolun Mother said is true...
...do not doubt that I will do my best
to see you punished for it
as the wife of Tugtekin,
the Bey of Dodurga.
-What is going on?
-Get out!
-What is going on, brother?
-I said get out.
We will, brother.
We'll get out.
-Where is Dogan, Turgut?
-He was gone when we woke up.
Maybe he went hunting, Bey.
-Where is Dogan, Bamsi?
-We don't know, Bey.
Right, brother Turgut?
We don't know.
We do not know, Bey.
Let's see what your Bey
has to say about that.
Tie them up and take them away.
Things are more
difficult now, mother.
They will be harder
on us after this.
We have to stop this dirty game.
Let this all come to an end.
Enough already.
Ertugrul, come here!
It is time, mother.
Come outside, Ertugrul!