Episode 53 will start after 12:30 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
You are going to pay for
what you did to my parents.
What are you saying, Tugtekin Bey?
Don't you see that I risked my life
to find your father's killer?
Go to hell, scumbag!
Put that away!
Know your place, Tugtekin!
Remember that I am the margrave.
Let Halime go, Aytolun.
We learnt that Selcan was meeting
Banu Cicek in secret, Hayme Hatun.
I said let her go!
Let Halime Sultan go
and then we can talk!
Tell Abdurrahman
to go to the marquee
and come back here with
the Dodurga Alps at once.
Why do you want that?
You don't trust me either?
Or do you think it was us
who killed Korkut Bey?
I can't trust any
of these scumbags.
Tell Abdurrahman to go at once.
Abdurrahman, be quick as an arrow.
Go at once.
As you please, Mother Hayme!
Ertugrul, I know this is all your doing.
I don't know who else you may poison
with that venomous tongue of yours,
but I will chop it off. I told you.
I swear I won't die
before I chop your tongue off.
Tugtekin.
What did this traitor tell you
to poison your noble soul?
If my brides were in on this,
why are you here with your swords?
You want to punish them
on behalf of Korkut Bey?
Just like how Gumustekin wanted
to take justice into his own hands.
Quietly, sneakily, treacherously.
-Tell me!
-How do you know this, woman?
Are you curious?
Let me explain.
I know that...
...you killed Duru Hatun and Korkut Bey.
I know that upon
Sadettin Kobek's orders,
you stole the seal given
to Sungur Tekin by Sultan Aleaddin
and took it to Kobek.
And that he gave it to Tankut.
Stand back!
Or I'll kill them both.
Are you afraid that they'll
find out how despicable you are?
You don't know what you are saying.
Stand back. Or else your
grandchild and bride will die.
Gumustekin thinks that he set a trap,
but he'll be trapped by my sons instead.
Ertugrul and Tugtekin
went after him.
You're lying.
They are not powerful enough
to defeat my father.
We have been fighting
scum like you for years.
You don't understand
how powerful we are.
Gokce!
Do you believe their lies?
Tell me!
How ominous people you are!
Both of you, go to hell!
You're not powerful enough for us.
Everyone in your marquee
will die today!
Tugtekin Bey!
Tugtekin Bey.
His blood is halal to you
as your mother's milk.
But do not get overwhelmed
with your anger.
Show your justice to Turkmen
nomad groups, Tugtekin Bey.
And show your justice
to vile Sadettin Kobek.
Thus, you will not end up being wrong
when you are right.
His death will not be that easy.
You will be judged before two Beys
in my state tent
and you will be executed shamefully
before the people, Gumustekin.
Everybody will see how corrupt
you and your sister are.
What are you saying, Tugtekin Bey?
Don't you know me?
I know you are the killer of my mother
and my father, Gumustekin.
You will get what you deserve.
Aytolun!
Do not!
Let my brides go!
Take me.
No one can harm you
as long as I am with you.
If you want to be saved, take me.
And then do whatever you want.
-Mother!
-Daughter!
From now on, your share is death.
It is over.
After you die,
no one will learn the truth.
No! No!
Aunt!
-Aunt!
-Selcan!
Aunt!
Halime daughter! Daughter!
-Daughter!
-Are you okay, Mother Hayme?
-Go follow them, go!
-As you please, mother.
Daughter Halime.
Halime.
Halime!
-Daughter!
-Halime.
You are a snake, you nested in my tent.
How did you kill
those innocent people without pity?
This is a trap of Ertugrul.
See the truth Tugtekin.
Or it will be too late.
Both my mother and my father...
How did you kill those people?
This is heartless!
Talk, you damned, talk!
They are the killers of your father.
They killed your father Tugtekin.
Do not believe them.
The anger of Ameer Sadettin
may destroy our nomad group.
Come to yourself.
You will pay the price for everything.
Take me to Ameer Sadettin.
Then you will see the truth!
-Halime!
-Daughter!
Halime I am begging you, open your eyes.
-Mother, Halime!
-Daughter.
Gokce, go to the nomad group
and call for help.
We need to take Halime
to the nomad tent. Hurry up!
I will.
Daughter.
God save her.
God, help us.
Daughter!
I am not afraid of you.
I am afraid that our nomad group
may come to grief.
Tugtekin Bey!
No one becomes lofty when
he treats grimly to a tyrant.
Stop!
He deserves to die in shame in front of
his nomad group. Let it be like that.
It is over, Tugtekin Bey. It is over.
All of them will get their deserts.
Come on.
Come to yourself. Come.
Goncagul!
Either you will come with me
and consent to the penalty that court
will give you and your father
or you will die in here.
I will die.
I may die, but you will die with me.
-Gokce Hatun! Are you okay?
-I am okay.
Hurry up. Halime Sultan is dying.
Come on, inform the nomad group
to call for help.
-We found the killers of Korkut Bey!
-Where are they, Gokce Hatun?
They are near the stream bed.
Come on, help them immediately.
Be quick. Tell them to take a gurney.
Give me the horse.
I will kill you!
Stop right here, corrupt woman.
It is not that easy.
I will not be easy on you as aunt Duru.
Show me if it is easy to kill a person.
Come on!
Show me if it is as easy to kill someone
as you say you love Gundogdu
by looking his eyes.
I loved him.
I loved him so much.
If it was not for your cursed tenacity,
I would have given birth to the babies
that you could not.
I do not believe in your love.
Now decide, you will die here
in my hands
or in the hands of
Gundogdu. It is your choice.
Halime, daughter.
God, please do not make my son suffer.
Oh God!
Daughter.
Horses will be here in a minute, mother.
Okay, daughter.
Halime, Halime.
I am begging you, open your eyes.
God help us!
You should know one more thing
before you die, Goncagul.
I am bearing Gundogdu's child.
Selcan Hatun!
-Selcan Hatun!
-Where is she?
-She escaped.
-Hurry up, go!
-If you are fine, I will follow her.
-Go!
Thank God!
I found the black knot where I lie down.
Aytolun and Goncagul intented
to kill Halime Sultan.
I saw them while they were getting out
of the nomad tent.
They put on their weapons, so that is
why they were leaving that fast.
Look at those betrayers!
They are in cahoots with Gumustekin.
Alps went to take Halime Sultan.
Yes, it seems that they are
creating trouble.
-Mother.
-Selcan.
Mother.
-How is she? Is she fine?
-She is still unconscious.
Where is Goncagul?
She escaped, mother.
Abdurrahman went after her.
But she conduced to find
the remedy for Gundogdu.
Those blacks knots are
the remedy for my Bey.
I found the mushrooms and
she will come to grief.
Go daughter, rush it. Come on.
Alright, mother.
Goncagul escaped, Mother Hayme.
I could not pick up the trail.
Perform a funeral salaat for Aytolun.
Take her! I do not want her to bemire
my land anymore.
As you please, Mother Hayme.
When you turn back to nomad group,
charge 20-25 Alp to follow Goncagul.
As you please, Mother Hayme.
Come on, be quick.
Slow down.
Daughter.
There is no time to lose, Tugtekin Bey.
We have to go back to the nomad tent
and make a court.
The beys of two nomad groups
need to see the truth.
They need to know.
The Turkmen nomad groups that accepted
the mangraveness of Gumustekin
must stick by the decision of court.
On the contrary, we will take on
not only Ameer Sadettin
but also Turkmen nomad groups.
-Turgut.
-Yes, Bey.
Wake this undignified up. We are going.
As you please.
Wake up, jackal.
It is time to payoff.
I will see your corrupt head rolling
in the middle of the nomad group.
You will all get your deserts.
Your eyes say different things!
The light has gone out of your eyes
because of fear.
Stray into us. Let us see your height.
Ertugrul, if he will not speak,
we can not prove his connection
with Ameer Sadettin.
We do not need a proof, we need to
bring Ameer Sadettin to his knees.
And this day will come eventually.
Alright.
We are ready, Bey.
Let us go.
Take it, Bey.
Gundogdu, I am begging you, please eat it.
Open your mouth.
Come, have one more spoon.
Can I come in, Bey?
Artuk bey, they took Halime Sultan.
Isak.
Stay here with Selcan Hatun.
Make Gundogdu bey have this medicine.
Do not worry, Bey.
For the sake of El Shafii.
The remedy for Bey is those
mushrooms, Selcan Hatun.
He will be better, if God permits.
If God permits, Artuk Bey.
Almighty God will heal him.
Everything is from God, Selcan Hatun.
If God permits, dervish Ishak.
Come on, Bey.
Hold on Halime, I am begging you, hold on.
You and your baby will be better.
-Mother.
-Daughter.
Daugther, this too shall pass.
Hold on Halime, please hold on. We came.
Slow down, do not shake her. Slow down.
How is Gundogdu, Artuk Bey?
Selcan Hatun came just in time
with the remedy, Mother Hayme.
He will be better, if God permits.
Oh God.
They are taking the killer.
Killer! Killer!
You will get your deserts.
Give the killer of our Bey to us.
Give him to us.
Ertugrul.
Do not worry Hayme Hatun,
we will take care of her.
From now on, you will curse
every breath you take.
Even if you kill me, you can not escape
from the anger of Ameer Sadettin.
I am your mangrave.
You can not escape from the anger
of Ameer Sadettin!
Yesterday, you are met as a mangrave
in this nomad group.
But now you are met as a miserable dog.
Your owner will get his share from
this merry day eventually, do not worry.
Aytolun is dead, Gumustekin.
And Goncagul escaped.
But when they find her, she will get
the punishment that she deserves.
And you will get your deserts.
Mother Hayme, if you permit,
I want the Beys of two nomad groups
to judge this dog.
We will do whatever it takes
to administer the law, Tugtekin Bey.
Kayi tribe, Dodurga tribe!
Today is the justice day.
We beared this killers for a long time
like a tumor that is stuck
on to our fleshes.
We washed ourselves with the blood
they spill for the purpose of remedy.
We accepted this killers to our state
tent, to our headquarters.
We considered them brothers,
sisters, mothers.
But it is time to cut off this tumor.
I know this wound will not recover.
We will carry this wound
inside us until we die.
This is a lesson for us
and we will carry it
so that we will not come across with
a shame like this again.
May God not give a pain,
a shame to us again.
Amen Bey, amen.
All of you believed
in the lies of Ertugrul.
You rised against the state
and killed my sister.
The calamity of two nomad groups
will be a lesson to the whole world.
Everybody will see that the blood of the
rebels is halal.
You will not be freed
even if you apologize.
Turgut, take Gumustekin to latticed tent
until the judgement starts.
As you please, Mother Hayme.
Get up!
You will all get your deserts.
-Walk!
-Do not talk, corrupt man.
Is everyone all right, mother?
They tried to kill Selcan and Halime.
Selcan is fine.
But Halime took a knock.
Artuk Bey is with her.
Artuk Bey!
Do not worry Bey, Halime Sultan and
your child are healthy. Praise be!
Thank you.
-Can I go in?
-Of course.
Halime Sultan is looking forward to you.
Ertugrul!
Halime Sultan!
Ertugrul, our child is all right.
Thank God, you are all right as well.
I was frightened Ertugrul.
I was frightened that
I could not protect it.
God gives and takes the life,
Halime Sultan.
You saved the honor of our nomad group.
My child and I will pride with you
throughout our lives.
Take your hands off me!
I am your mangrave.
You can not do this to me.
They said God may give hellish torture
when you are alive.
I saw it with my eyes now.
Thank to God who showed this.
Amen.
Come on, let us go.
Ertugrul!
We found the killers of you and my father.
We inflicted punishment on them.
Instigations are over at last.
Rest in peace.
Thank God, I got rid of the delusion
I got in.
I will be a Bey that is proper to you
and my nomad group.
The betrayers, tyrants, cruels will be
far from our nomad group.
Bey.
You proved that you are proper
to Dodurga tribe.
From now on, feel easy.
Your mother and father rest in peace.
Bey.
Please, do not entomb me alive.
How can I trust you Gokce?
I believed in you.
I loved you.
I made you my wife.
Don't you see that you entomb me
while I am alive?
How is my brother, Selcan Hatun?
If God permits, he will not collapse.
If God permits.
Sungur, Ertugrul, is it over?
It is over, brother. We brought
Gumustekin to the nomad group.
And the other two snakes?
Aytolun is dead, but Goncagul
escaped, brother.
That corrupt will get what she deserves.
If God permits.
As I have brothers like you,
as I have a wife like Selcan,
Kayi tribe will overcome anything.
I did not respect your words, forgive me.
Brother.
Artuk Bey said he needs to rest.
Gundogdu will be all right, do not worry.
Give that corrupt what he deserves.
Thank you, sister in law.
May God bless you.
You saved Dodurga tribe from this trouble.
Peace came to my nomad group.
What did we do Cicek Hatun?
If you were not here
lots of blood would spilled and maybe
truth will not be revealed.
If you have a trouble,
you know where I am.
Excuse me.
Banu Cicek Hatun!
Where will I find you
when our nomad groups
migrate to different places?
Know that you are always in my heart.
Dogan Alp.
Helpless Turkmen nomad groups
who suffer from Mongol trouble
will be crushed in the hands
of Gumustekin and Kobek.
When Turkmen seigniory learn
about the court and it's result
they will understand the trouble they are
saved and they will justify us.
After the court, Sadettin Kobek us
a hard time like a wild creature.
In that time, the support of Turkmen
seigniory will be important for us.
The justice of our court will cut
the indefility as a knife.
Artuk Bey, lead the headquarter court
if Tugtekin Bey considers it appropriate.
Mother Hayme says right.
My anger hinders my justice.
If you consider it appropriate,
I have to do what my duty requires.
I do not want to behead him.
If Ertugrul Bey did not wake me up
from that woolgathering
my halters would be in the hands
of that cur.
They would fool around my nomad group.
Beheading...
...Gumustekin is Ertugrul Bey's duty.
Tugtekin Bey, beheading Gumustekin
is halal for you.
Ertugrul Bey, I insist.
When he perish
I want to look into him in the eye
and give hellfire to his heart.
Fine Tugtekin Bey, fine.
Ameer Almighty.
Ertugrul enslaved our mangrave
and took him to nomad tend.
What the hell are you saying?
Tugtekin Bey and Sungurtekin coalesced
and arrested me and my soldiers.
-Tugtekin Bey?
-Yes, Ameer Almighty.
Three of them coalesced.
They said Gumustekin Bey and
you are both betrayers.
So they raised against the state at last.
Recruit your soldiers,
we are going to Kayi tribe.
As you please, sir.
The Beys of two nomad group brought me
to the head of court
because I do not have kindredship
with Korkut Bey.
All we want is the justice Gumustekin Bey.
Understand this.
None of you can judge me.
I know that in this tent court
not justice but instigations
of Ertugrul will win.
I will exclude this court and
the decision of that court.
Know that.
The court is about to start.
If you have something to tell,
you can tell it when you are on trail.
Sit down.
I will not kneel in the face of no one.
The one who created and filled
our hearts with belief.
With the 99 names of God.
In the name of God.
Goncagul learned that Selcan went to pick
up black knot alone from Dervish Ishak.
It is obvious that she informed Aytolun.
Is this true, Dervish Ishak?
It is true, Artuk Bey.
What happened then Hayme Hatun?
Aytolun and Goncagul followed my brides.
I took Abdurrahman Alp with me
and followed them.
I found them while attempting
to kill my brides.
Lie.
It is all lie.
My sister and daugter are innocent.
They are innocent.
I had to get Aytolun killed.
And you Selcan Hatun?
You told that you followed Goncagul
while she was escaping.
What happened then?
-I found her.
She wanted to kill me with her dagger
and I protected myself.
But then she escaped. That is all I say.
Sungurtekin Bey, what happened
when Gumustekin Bey catched
Ertugrul Bey and Banu Cicek? I want
to listen it from you one more time.
As Ertugrul and Tugtekin Bey said,
he disclaimed everything.
But just because we want the justice
we took him to the nomad group,
presence of Beys.
The decision is belongs to our court.
Do you have something to say,
Gumustekin Bey?
When this damn game is finished
I hope you will all get your deserts.
You will answer for this.
Do you have something to say,
Ertugrul Bey?
I wish I would kill him before.
Somebody else is at the back
of that case, Artuk Bey.
Gumustekin Bey's crime is firm.
I want you to give him one more chance
to confess the murders
which is encouraged by Sadettin Kobek.
We would do a beneficent thing
by revealing the betrayer before he die.
Is it true, Gumustekin? Will you confess?
I will not submit to your lies Ertugrul,
I will not.
Not only you but also all the the Beys
who participated your lies
get their deserts.
Ameer Sadettin call to account from
the fools who believes your lies.
Gumustekin Bey, know your limit!
I do not afraid any of you.
You will pay the price. You will.
Son of Konur Alp, Gumustekin.
According to the witnesses,
you are guilty.
It is proved that you, Aytolun Hatun and
Goncagul Hatun commited these murders.
You will get your deserts.
Tugtekin Bey, have you got anything to say
about the execution?
Reprisal is your right.
I want the execution to be
made by Ertugrul Bey.
He saved the pride of two nomad groups.
I want to see his eyes while dying.
Alps, take the guilty in front of the
state tent for the execution.
Kill him!
My people, I am slandered!
Do not believe in the lies of Ertugrul!
Kill him! Kill him!
Do not believe in his lies!
Do not believe in!
-Kill him!
Kill him!
We want justice!
Brothers, do not do it!
Do not be a tool of his slanders.
I am innocent.
Aytolun Hatun and my daughter
are innocent.
They seduced the innocents.
They killed my sister.
Ameer Sadettin will pay off all from you.
I am your mangrave!
Do not do this!
-Kill him!
Kill him!
It will be brought to book from everyone
that killed the mangrave.
You all will be punished by state!
All of you. All of you.
Think about the answer you will give
in the presence of God, Gumustekin Bey.
Tell Shahada.
Ameer Sadettin Kobek!
I am ordering you for the sake of
Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat!
Stop the execution.
Ertugrul...
...put that sword.
I came here to find
out and release the unfounded claims
about mangrave.
Beys of two nomad groups
judged not the mangrave but the murderer
of Korkut Bey and Duru Hatun.
He will be executed.
Ertugrul, do not go beyond the limits!
Soldier!
Ameer Sadettin Kobek, I heard myself
that Aytolun and Goncagul killed
Korkut Bey and his wife Duru Hatun.
I am witness for this situation.
What is the blame of Gumustekin?
He used his sister and daughter.
He commited the murders
in order to be a mangrave.
He used both Kayi tribe and Dodurga
tribe to attain his aim.
Have you got any proof Ertugrul Bey?
I am witness as well, Ameer Sadettin.
Lie! It is all lie, Ameer Sadettin.
He poisoned both Hayme Hatun
and Tugtekin Bey with his lies.
It is all lie.
Hayme Hatun, Tugtekin Bey.
Now I will take Ertugrul and Gumustekin
to Kervansaray.
And I will question them.
Revealing the truth will be my duty.
Otherwise, the Beys of two nomad groups
will be considered as a rebel
against the state!
I will not hesitate to do
what has to be done.
This is my last warning.
You dig your own grave, Ertugrul.
You dig your own grave.
We do not afraid of dying for the
sake of Yusuf. Graditute to God!
I am telling you for the
last time, Ertugrul.
Give me my mangrave.
Soldier!
Now you can take your mangrave,
if you want!
Do not think that you will not
pay the price, Ertugrul.
From now on
you will deserve what the enemy
of state deserves.
Shame on you too.
Shame on all of you!
Now, afraid of me.
Afraid of the anger of the state!
Hereupon you will forget the peace
when you enter your tents
you will forget sleeping
when you go to bed!
The ones who forgot the loyalty
to the state
and be loyal to Ertugrul
will pay the price.
Kayi tribe!
Dodurga tribe!
You are the glorious children of Oguz!
I see the fear in your eyes
which I have never seen before!
The fear that I have never seen
in a disaster or in a war!
I know that, this fear comes from
your millenarian state love
and obey to the Ameer.
But do not afraid of Ameer
who is the piece of garbage!
Do not dread!
Because, you are always
stand by your state!
And you will always stand by your state.
It is our duty to stand in front of them
with justice instead of have a fright from
the devils that are lurking in the state!
Now go, mourn for the people that the
sinister murderers took from you.
May God rest them in peace.
-Amen!
We were fair, we acted
with respect to God!
We avoided to revolt to God!
Undoubtly, God is the one
who sees what we do.
God bless you Ertugrul Bey!
Is he still got fever?
Not reduced, Bey.
Can you give us a second, Selcan Hatun?
Do not worry.
Artuk Bey will do what has
to be done, Selcan Hatun.
I will go deeper and take off
the purulence.
It is going to hurt too much Gundogdu Bey,
you had better hold him tightly.
You ruined Ameer Sadettin's
reputation, Bey.
He will make a trouble.
Sadettin Kobek will not chase
after two nomad groups.
It is obvious that he will take
precautions not to ruin his reputation.
He will cover this case.
He will see me as an enemy
not our nomad groups.
This is what you want, Bey.
He will ride for a fall as he set a trap
like Gumustekin.
Bey, but I want you to know,
that Gundogdu Bey
is not chief commander anymore.
-What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
-His situation is not good, Bey.
We have to do what has to be done
in order to maintain the security
of our nomad groups.
I would tell to Hayme Hatun
when the time comes
but I want you to know it first.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Bey, you should know that
you are not alone.
Thank you, Artuk Bey. Thank you.
Let's begin, Bey.
-Gundogdu!
-Sister, sister!
Be calm, be patient.
This too shall pass, be patient.
Come, sister.
Gumustekin Bey, I promise you that
I will take the revenge from the ones
who did this to you.
Do not be worry yourself.
I will not bring to light
this nomad group
Ertugrul and and his beloved ones
until I get your revenge.
Come here, Tugtekin Bey. What is wrong?
Alps that went after Goncagul came back.
They could not find her.
There is no place to run,
of course they will find her.
Alps will keep on searching.
I will not be relieved while that woman
keeps breathing, Mother Hayme.
What are you doing, Turgut?
Welcome, Bey.
Turali, will take his first step
being an Alp.
He will be circumcised.
An Alp should has his sword.
If father Demir was here, he would
make the first sword of Turali.
Now, it is my duty, Bey.
Wonderful!
Azrael does not have mercy to his enemy.
If God permits, in the hands of
a brave man like you
it may be the sound and rage of injustice.
He was upbringing the iron,
he was giving soul to the flame.
The swords he made was
murdering non-Muslims.
Oh big, Wild Demir!
Very well then, Turgut.
Let's see what Wild Demir tought to us.
Thank you, Bey. Let's start then.
Let's start.
In the name of God!
-God!
-Only one God!
Big steel mountain where the sun
cannot wander.
Moon cannot wander beneath.
Axe cannot cut the great tree.
Ayaz Khan with moon and sun.
My moorland which is adorned with clothes.
Leafed, blessed beech tree.
Akyayik who is the owner of quick.
Oh, Sky God!
My waters kill thousand servants.
Cloud eyed Bugra Khan.
Ice footed Bey man.
Cloud. Moon. Bugra.
My these lands be our homeland which
we fought, wandered and spilled blood.
Our homeland!
My brave men who follow Genghis Khan!
We came to these lands for revenge!
For revenge!
-For revenge!
For blood!
For revenge! Happy revenge!
Ameer Sadettin Kobek Almighty!
Welcome, poets.
Come on, sit down.
Goodness comes with you
it is dispersed like desert winds
in the absence of you, Ameer Sadettin.
You are an ocean
with your politeness us poets became
a drop of water in the ocean.
Why are you so angry, Ameer Almighty?
Do your people renege and play a trick
for raising hell about you?
We know that, they will get their share
from the sword of your justice.
Your greatness is because of this.
-Justice?
Justice!
Justice is the thing that comes
with revenge.
Justice is the shadow of revenge.
Greatness is not about being dignitary
it is not even living very close
with death.
It is knowing how to win.
If you qualify your revenge,
you can be great.
Revenge!
Oh, revenge!
Life!
Revenge is as warm as the
breath of sweetest lover
as innocent when your child
put his head to your shoulder.
I have never heard such verses.
Who is this great poet, Ameer Almighty?
-It is me.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Come on eat your meal.
Do not make it cold.
Thank God, your fever is reduced Bey.
You will be fine, if God permits.
If God permits, Hatun.
Gumustekin, what happened to him?
Ertugrul Bey scattered his head
in the middle of nomad group.
God bless!
Gundogdu...
...I want to tell you something.
I am pregnant!
I will give a child.
After all these pain...
...I know this child who is vouchsafed
from God will grow up...
...and be a brave man who behooves you.
No, do not think like that.
It will be a child
who behooves a mother like you.
Brother, what are you thinking about?
You do not have the remedy of my trouble,
brother!
My trouble is about love...
...not about beating a bear.
Brother, do not brush me off brother,
I have knowledge.
What are you saying brother?
What knowledge?
Tell it brother, tell it.
Tell it to me brother.
I will ask to Banu Cicek to be my wife.
But I do not know how to say that.
Brother, I thought you will found a state
and collapse a state.
Look brother, you will say...
..."This heart if mine, it burst into
flames, your expectancy glare down on me."
I could not understand, what will I say?
Which part did not you understand,
brother?
I will say one last time...
..."My heart burst into flames,
your expectancy glare down on me".
It is good.
"This heart of mine,
it burst into flames...
...your expectancy glare down on me".
It sounds good.
What will I say more?
And you will continue like this...
..."Your glances pierced my heart
like an arrow...
...your beauty is a well hole
and I am falling into it as Joseph.
I am like a dry leaf in a lonely desert".
How do you know these brother?
It is knowledge brother, knowledge!
You cannot query a man with knowledge!
And like Geyikli brother said...
..."Do not look at the one who tell...
...look at the one who make you tell,
brother."
You will look at the one
who make you tell.
My heart burst into flames,
your expectancy...
You will apply this cure to the wound
Banu Cicek Hatun.
May God bless you, Artuk Bey.
I have patients, do the things I said,
May God cure you.
How is your wound, Cicek Hatun?
Thank you Dogan Alp.
It is fine, with the cure Artuk Bey gave,
it will get better if God permits.
If God permits.
If God permits, Cicek Hatun,
if God permits.
Cicek Hatun...
...your heart burnt me.
What kind of eyes you have...
They pierced my heart like an arrow.
You are a well hole and I fell into it.
You are a desert and I got lost in it.
What are you saying Dogan Alp?
I do not even know what I say.
Really Bamsi!
Well, with the help of God!
I do not know words like these
Cicek Hatun.
Banu Cicek, I want you to be my wife.
I want you to accept me as your man.
If you say so...
...then I will be life to your life
and cure to your heart.
From now on, your tent is my palace.
Your life will be my heaven.
Your trouble will be my food,
your joy will be my spring...
...my life will be your life.
Dogan Alp?
Thank God!
I... I could not understand.
I asked you to be my wife
and you said yes, right?
I said yes!
I asked you to be my wife
and you said yes.
-You said yes. So you will be my wife!
-Yes Dogan Alp.
Then I should go and tell Bey
what happened.
Ertugrul Bey may come and ask permission
for you from Tugtekin Bey.
Alright.
Did you say yes?
I said yes!
She said yes!
God!
Halime Sultan...
...why did you get up?
-I am fine.
-Artuk Bey said you should rest.
I am fine Ertugrul Bey,
you do not need to worry.
Our child keeps saying it is hungry and
it's kicks are severe.
And I want to be with you
in a good day like this.
Permission, Bey?
Come in, Abdurrahman.
Ertugrul Bey, Dogan Alp wants to see you.
It is obvious that something happened.
He cannot fidget.
Let him in.
Bey, if you permit I have a wish.
Tell it Dogan Alp, what happened to you?
My remedy is you Bey.
As you know, Banu Cicek and I!
When should we ask for Banu Cicek Hatun
from Tugtekin Bey?
Whenever you and Mother Hayme want.
We are ready, Bey.
Good.
We will ask for her from Tugtekin Bey
tomorrow night...
...and we will enter the spring
with the union of two lovers.
God may bless you Bey!
Lam Aleph.
Thank God, our nomad group
is cleaned from betrayers.
From now on, everything will be fine.
Right Turali?
You are right Turgut Alp.
Artuk Bey will circumcise me
in the earliest time...
-...and he will give me my first sword.
-If God permits.
Look at my Turali Alp! He is a lion!
Praise be! Praise be!
Brothers, peace is something beautiful!
From now on, I will continue
to my education more.
Alright Bamsi, tell us, don't you have
advices to us?
We want to take advantage of
your knowledge.
Brother...
... the thing what behooves a wise person
is not advising by...
...telling but by experience.
Thank you.
Bamsi Alp articulated us
poor dervishes' feelings.
Brother, intimidating the truth is hard...
...the one who seeks the truth is
sallow...
...for the wise person,
enjoyment is less and suffering is more.
Oh God, so that is the reason why you are
as thin as a rake.
So that is why.
Do you think like that?
This education life made me feel hungry.
I need to eat. Is there any lamb?
There is brother, do not worry.
I will cut a big lamb for you.
Cut it brother, cut.
Cut a lamb, cut a ram.
Why do you want to learn knowledge,
Bamsi Alp?
Brother...
...God address comments to us.
He gave us Koran.
Now, if I do not read it,
I would be ungrateful.
Alright!
Thank you, brother!
God!
What happened Dogan?
Banu Cicek accepted
to be my wife, brothers.
Tomorrow, mother Hayme and Ertugrul Bey
will ask for her from Tugtekin Bey.
Oh! My lad! My ram! Praise be!
Good luck with it!
Come here brother!
Come here!
In the name of God.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you brother,
come in brother!
No brother, no. Come in.
They said one cannot heal
without eating my mother's meal.
Brother Sungur knows this well.
So we came here.
-Welcome!
-Come in, son. Welcome.
Welcome daughter.
-Thank you, mother.
-Come here, sister in law.
-Thank you.
-Take a seat, Sungur.
Here we go.
-Take it brother.
-Thank you brother.
Mother.
Thank you son.
Come on! In the name of God.
Permission, Mother Hayme?
Come in, Abdurrahman.
Mother Hayme, a messenger brought
news about Dundar Bey and Yigit Alp.
If God permits, they will be here
in few days.
Thank God!
God, thank God.
I will be able to sit down to same meal
with my children!
In migration time, knowing that
my children will be with me...
...then now,
I will not afraid of anything.
The indefinite that dried our blood in
our veins is over!
If God permits, spring may bring us
peace and justice.
-If God permits!
Come on, eat.
Bey...
...I do not want any secrets
between us no more.
All the secrets make bleed our
etched wounds.
Do you have another secret Gokce?
There was a man of Kurdoglu.
He spread terror to the nomad group
like Gumustekin.
Ertugrul Bey was seriously wounded.
That man came to kill him when he was
dying.
I was there...
...and I tried to protect Ertugrul Bey...
But he wounded me seriously
with his dagger.
I am afraid that that wound...
...may have took my womanhood from me,
Bey.
I am afraid of not giving you a child.
Almighty Ameer, Merchant Abdullah
came from Tabriz.
He has important news.
Merchant Abdullah?
Take him inside.
But search him properly.
Do not let him take anything as a weapon.
Come on.
As you please, Ameer Almighty.
You do not need that much precaution,
Sadettin.
I threw the things you did to me
in the past to the water of Amu Darya.
I heard that Ogeday drum you out of
his army.
And besides, he put a prize on your head.
And I heard that
Ertugrul cut the dog's head...
...that you trust and ruined
your reputation.
What do you want?
I want Ertugrul.
Just as you do.
Do not you afraid that I may kill you?
Sadettin! I have all the letters
that you wrote me.
What would happen if your
Sultan sees them?
-What do you want?
-I told you, I want Ertugrul.
So you will do it alone?
I am not alone Sadettin.
I heard, you are wondering
with some looters....
...that Ogeday drum them out of the army.
They are the most pitiless killers
of Mongol army and there are you...
...I trust you the most.
Tell me, what is in your mind?
Let me tell.
My men want pillage, prize
they are seeking for gold...
...and you do not want to disquiet
in these lands.
Neither you do not want my men
to attack...
...the nomad groups for prize nor
a rebellion of...
...Kayi and Dodurga tribes because of the
soldier that you sent for Ertugrul.
Both of us want Erturgul.
I will take his head to you.
How?
I want to finish my unfinished business
with Ertugrul...
...Ameer Almighty.
Of course with your help.
Tell your soldiers to fight not for gold
but for the blood of Ertugrul.
I will always make them satisfied...
...as long as you bring
the head of Ertugrul to me.
My duty is to disconnect the road between
two nomad groups...
...which is connected because of you.
I will flop down on them like a nightmare.
Every other day that they live will be
torture for them.
Ameer Almighty!
-What happened?
-There is a woman that wants to see you.
-Who is she?
-She says that her name is Goncagul...
...Ameer Almighty.
Good, she can wait.
You should have something to talk.
If you are right, I will a give you
more valuable present than gold, Noyan.
Wait there.
Take her in.
Are you alright, daughter?
I want to take the revenge of my aunt
and my father, Ameer Almighty.
I do not have anybody but you.
I am subservient to you until I die.
Daughter!
Come here child.
Sadettin Kobek will pester us more.
So I think that we should proceed
our union...
...with Dodurga tribe until the
next spring.
This will make us more powerful.
We can enlarge our flocks.
Selcan Hatun and Halime Hatun can show
their abilities. We can sell our rugs.
There are brave men at the age of Alp,
we can train them.
And in the spring, we can migrate.
I think we should council it
in headquarters.
Mother.
Do you think about a place
when the migration time comes?
No son.
But I want to council this matter
with my Beys in the earliest time.
Thank you!
Brother Ertugrul, do you have a place
in your mind?
I want to go to the lands where
the roots of Kayi tribe will take...
...with the ones who sit at that table.
To the lands where our sons and
daughters can pray after we die...
...and the place that they can dig
a grave.
If god permits, we can decide together.
If God permits.
Well said brother, if God permits.
Mother Hayme,...
...if you permit, I want to say something
to you.
Tell it, daughter.
I don't know when or where our nomad group
will migrate.
But I want to hold on tight to that lands.
Thus Halime and I can raise
our babies in our own homeland.
Oh my God!
I am pregnant mother!
If God permits,
I will give birth to a child this time.
My son!
Thank God!
You destined me to be together
with all my children before I die.
Children...
...your burden is heavy,
our job is difficult and our strength...
...is linked to a slender bristle.
May Almighty God help us!
-Amen!
May our seignory be constant.
May our seignory be beneficial
in the way of God.
-Amen.
-May the light of Kayi tribe shine.
Thus it can brighten the ones
that are in darkness.
Prevent our strength, our power,
our mind our words away from home.
May prevent us from the malignancy of
encroaching.
And may God not separate us
from our religion and morals.
Amen.
May God not forget us from where
we came and where we go.
-Amen.
May God not sheer us from our
Ancestor Oghuz.
-Amen.
May God not separate us!
Make us one, make us together...
...make us big, make us alive!
God, connect us each other with love and
respect.
Amen.