Episode 51 will start after 12:27 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
Tugtekin!
What's going on?
What is all this?
What's going on here, cousin?
Why did you capture
Bamsi and Turgut?
Ertugrul's Alp, Dogan helped my
father's killer escape last night.
The guards saw him.
The sword of justice has no scabbard,
Tugtekin Bey.
When she is found,
we'll do as needed.
Turgut and Bamsi?
Why are they tied up?
I ask the questions here,
Ertugrul Bey, not you.
Only God can question me,
Tugtekin Bey.
You should let them go
if you have no proof.
And it is Mother Hayme's duty
to punish them if they are guilty.
Ertugrul is right, Tugtekin Bey.
Remember what happened the last time
you slandered my son and his Alps.
Do not forget that these
brave men saved your life
and brought you back to the tent
on their backs, alive and well.
Abdurrahman!
Untie Bamsi and Turgut's hands.
Tugtekin!
Apparently Dogan committed a crime.
He will be punished for this.
However, if you know anything else,
you should tell it to mother.
If there is an account to be settled,
Mother Hayme will handle that.
But it's not acceptable that you raid
a Kayi marquee like this.
-Listen to me carefully, Mother Hayme.
-No!
You listen to me carefully.
If you have no proof,
let them untie my Alps.
After then, I will invite you
to my marquee
and listen to you carefully.
That's all I have to say.
Now, please come in.
If you wish, I'll hear your
complaint as we share my breakfast.
Mother Hayme.
Dogan Alp must be found.
No matter what.
Since you want to settle this,
I will find Dogan Alp and bring him.
As for Ertugrul...
I swear that if both Dogan Alp and
Banu Cicek are not punished,
I will hold Ertugrul responsible
for everything.
And this is all I have to say.
Samsa. Prepare the Alps.
You will get them dead or alive.
Sir...
...with your permission
we would like to set off now.
You have my permission, son.
Don't you despair.
God tests his believers with challenges.
There is brighter day
after every dark night, of course.
We shall succeed
with the help of God.
When Ertugrul Bey has an idea,
he will make it work eventually.
I will pray for that.
May God grant you
long life and glory.
God be with you.
God bless you.
Do you realize what
Tugtekin's rage will lead to, son?
His rage will eventually
guide him to the truth, mother.
All we need to do is take
a firm stand for justice.
Don't tell me you weren't in on this,
brother. What have you done?
Brother Gundogdu, Ertugrul
has nothing to do with this.
And you expect me to believe this,
is that so, Sungur?
This nonsense will end
at the trial, you said.
Why did you postpone it?
To get Dogan out, right?
Gundogdu.
It is clear that Dogan did this for a girl
that he loved and thought to be innocent.
It's my duty to settle the score
with them when they are here.
For love? Is that so, mother?
Is that all you have to say?
Ertugrul has been digging our
graves for some time.
Now, I wonder how he'll get us out
of these graves he dug himself?
Tugtekin Bey.
I won't let you get away
with this, Ertugrul.
Even your mother who fell for your
tricks won't be able to save you.
Gokce.
-Do I have permission, Bey?
-Come in, Samsa, come.
The Alps are ready, Bey.
You stay at the nomad tent.
Ertugrul and his Alps won't leave
the tent. Keep an eye on them!
Understood, Bey.
You shouldn't go after them, Bey.
Leave it to Gundogdu,
the Alps' leader.
You are the Bey of this tribe now.
You should stay at your marquee
and make them to do as necessary.
It would be especially unwise to leave
when Ertugrul is in the tent.
I am ready, Ertugrul Bey.
Wait to hear from me
in your tent, Selcan Hatun.
Artuk Bey will send Goncagul
to Karakayalar somehow.
You will make her see and follow you.
Banu Cicek will be waiting
for you at Karakayalar.
Goncagul must hear
everything you two say.
She must hear that you'll meet
Banu Cicek before sunset tomorrow
and that Banu will bring the evidence
to you. And she must believe it.
She will then tell everything
to Aytolun Hatun.
And Aytolun Hatun will go there
when you want her to.
Do not worry, Bey.
What if Goncagul can't persuade
Aytolun to go see Banu Cicek?
What happens then, son?
If she believes that Banu Cicek has the
evidence about those murders,
she will go, mother.
Ertugrul Bey, what if something
happens to Selcan?
My brother, Sungur will be
with Selcan Hatun all along.
Don't you worry.
So, this was why he
postponed the trial.
It was to help
Banu Cicek escape.
I erred on the side of caution last night
and had three Alps follow
Ertugrul's Alps.
Turgut and Bamsi started a fight
in front of the tents out of the blue.
Dogan helped Banu Cicek
escape during the commotion.
I am certain that Ertugrul is also
involved in this, Tugtekin Bey.
How else could it be, Gumustekin Bey?
Dogan couldn't have done this alone.
However, he won't be alone
when he pays for this, either.
Come in, Gundogdu Bey.
Tugtekin Bey. Gumustekin Bey.
I thought it'd be best if you go
after Banu Cicek and Dogan.
That's a wise decision, Bey.
You can rest assured that
I'll bring them to you soon.
Thank you. But, show no mercy
if they reach for their swords.
Do not worry, Bey.
We will do as necessary.
Gumustekin Bey and I
are always on your side.
Thank you.
-With your permission.
-Of course.
What is going on?
We have to leave a sign
so that they can find us.
Dogan Alp, wait.
Here.
Mother Hayme.
Tugtekin Bey ordered Gundogdu Bey
to look for Dogan and Banu Cicek.
Gundogdu Bey says that
he and the Alps will leave at once.
Just like you thought, Gumustekin Bey
is teaching the rules to Tugtekin Bey.
Brother Gundogdu will take Dogan
from where I want, when I want...
and bring him safely to the nomad tent.
-Let's go, brother.
-Let's go.
Let's go and finish the job.
Mother, with your permission.
God be with you.
Gundogdu Bey!
Keep your eyes open, Bey.
May God spare you from
the traps of traitors.
Amen.
-I hope you will find them and return.
-If God permits.
Find them so that this betrayal
will no longer cause us suffering.
Do not worry, Goncagul Hatun.
Nobody can stop us from
being together again.
You better start preparing
for the wedding.
I'll marry you as soon as I return.
You should know.
-Be safe.
-May God be with you, Bey.
Mother Hayme.
I want to have
a word with you.
Come, have a seat.
Tell me.
Mother Hayme, Tugtekin Bey
lost his mind after what happened.
He doesn't even listen to me.
It's as if he's gone
deaf and blind.
If we don't stop him,
there will be a lot of blood.
Tugtekin is going through
very hard times.
I'm afraid that things he will experience
in the future won't be easy either.
As for you, you are
the wife of a Bey now.
You are supposed to calm him down
no matter how enraged
he may get at times.
He will turn to
you to calm down.
Don't forget what I just said
no matter what you go through.
From now on, don't come to me
like a little girl
every time you're in trouble.
Stand up straight like
the wife of a Bey would.
I know how to send Goncagul Hatun
to Karakayas, Bey. Don't worry.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
-You set up a very good trap.
I'm sure you
will be victorious.
However, the real battle will begin
when the truth has been revealed.
Exposing that jackal, Gumustekin
is the most important thing.
God sets the best traps, Bey.
He will get his share of God's traps, too.
Gundogdu Bey is ready to leave,
Ertugrul Bey.
They are watching our every move.
All right.
Now it is your turn, Artuk Bey.
It is time to lure the prey.
Thank you, Bey.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you.
Your horse is ready.
I replaced the shoes.
She's ready for a ride.
Thank you, master, appreciated.
You are doing much better,
Aytolun Hatun.
However, I think there is still
some poison left in your body.
It will cause internal damage
if you don't get rid of it all.
What should I do, Artuk Bey?
Isn't there a cure?
There is a way, Aytolun Hatun.
Don't worry.
The cure is the thorny herb.
However, it is a rare herb. It can be
found around here, in Karakayas.
I would go collect some, but I have
so many patients waiting for me.
I will go, Artuk Bey.
I would do anything
to see my aunt healthy again.
Goncagul Hatun, you go collect
and bring these herbs to me.
I will take care of the rest.
-With your permission.
-Permission is yours, Artuk Bey.
I am going hunting, brother.
Let's see what game I'll
come across in your tracks.
-Good luck, brother.
-Godspeed, brother.
Thank you.
Take care of yourself.
They went this way.
Come on, brothers.
What is going on, Bamsi?
I will go back to school.
Education is important, brother.
Do you think fighting heathens
with weapons is the only way?
An ignorant Alp is much like
a warrior without a sword, brother.
And yet, the war's only just begun.
Thank you, brother.
But, studying is nothing like
fighting a bear. Did you think it through?
Brother, everybody will see what a
mighty Alp I am in this great battle.
And Ertugrul Bey says...
"If we become the sea,
all rivers will merge with us."
Come on brother.
We shouldn't be late. Come on.
Okay, okay. Wait.
Let's go.
May God be with you!
They are still behind us.
Do not worry, brother.
Nobody can harm the qualified.
God will protect us.
God will protect us, brother.
Why do you look like a reindeer
that stumbled upon a hunter?
Are you looking for someone?
We are not looking for anybody, Bey.
We are just looking around like
Tugtekin Bey told us to.
Fine, fine. You should.
But stay alert. Sometimes,
the hunter ends up as the hunted.
Our tribe always has a place
for brave Alps like you.
God bless.
Here you go brother.
What is wrong, brother?
Why are you laughing?
We're laughing at you, Bamsi Bey.
You couldn't read it.
Come on dervishes,
let's listen to Bamsi Alp again.
Go ahead, brother.
Dervish brother...
...couldn't I study
without having to read?
-Turgut?
-Yes, father?
Aykiz?
I want a grandchild
as soon as possible.
I want to hug and love her.
Aykiz!
I am out of words now, father.
We will stand in the way of
those after slander and unrest.
It's time to avenge those
who made these lands miserable for us.
We are close.
They can't be far away.
I can't bear to see you
like this, Cicek Hatun.
I'm worried about you, Dogan.
Don't worry about anything
when I am with you.
I know.
My only consolation in these hard times
is that you are here with me.
I will always be with you. In bad times
as well as good times, I hope.
Bey.
Bey. I placed the signs
like you told me to.
Gundogdu Bey and his
men will be here soon.
You know what to do, Banu Cicek.
Dogan Alp told me everything, Bey.
Selcan Hatun will bring
Goncagul to Karakayas.
You should be on your way too.
It is your duty to make her believe
that the evidence is real.
What if she doesn't believe us, Bey?
They will believe because
they are afraid of being
exposed for these murders.
Aytolun messed up everything
when she failed to kill you.
This is why she is angry.
She won't be able to stand
seeing you and Selcan together.
She expects to take
the evidence from you,
kill you both,
and blame you for everything.
You won't be alone in Karakayas.
However, you must be alert.
Bey, I'm worried about Dogan Alp.
I am afraid of Tugtekin Bey's wrath
when Gundogdu Bey catches him
and brings him to the tent, Bey.
Aytolun will not come to Karakayas
when Dogan's with you.
She must think that you
are alone to fall for our trap.
This is why, we have to do this.
Also, do not worry.
Neither brother Gundogdu nor my mother
would let anything happen to Dogan.
Bey is right, Cicek Hatun.
Do not worry about me.
Go and expose the treason
within the nomad tent.
Godspeed.
Cover the prints of her horse.
Make sure she's not followed
Of course, Bey.
We are facing two brave men
like Gundogdu and Tugtekin Beys.
It won't be easy.
May God be with you.
The marks are fresh, Bey.
They can't be far away.
Good. We will split into three.
You surround Kurtbogazi
from the left and right.
Yes, Bey.
-May I come in, Gumustekin Bey?
-Come in.
I have a letter from
Ameer Sadettin Kobek.
-Is he in Konya?
-No, Bey. He is at the caravansary.
I know everything you do now.
You won't be able to do as you please
around here from now on, Ertugrul.
-Do I have permission, Bey?
-Come in.
If you excuse me,
I have a request, Bey.
Tell me, Samsa.
We lost track of Ertugrul Bey.
-What are you talking about, Samsa?
-We don't know what happened, Bey.
He left the tent suddenly.
We went after him.
However, suddenly he disappeared.
We searched everywhere,
but couldn't find him, Bey.
We ran into Sungurtekin Bey.
How many times have you
been tricked by them now?
Didn't I tell you to
stay alert?
Are you an idiot, Samsa?
Are you an idiot?
How could so many men can't keep
track of a single man? One man! One!!
-Bey...
-Shut up.
Shut up!
Get out! Get out!
What are you up to this time, Ertugrul?
Do not leave
your man by himself, Gokce.
Stay with him.
Calm him down.
I have really important things
to tell you, Aytolun.
Come.
We are reaping the rewards
of our efforts today, Aytolun.
Tell me brother.
I'm dying to know.
I don't need to go to Konya anymore.
Tonight is the moment of truth.
Ameer Sadettin is going to meet
with the Turkmen Beys...
...and officially announce the margrave.
Thank God, brother. Thank God.
After every trouble comes a reward.
Those we gave up, those we sacrificed,
the troubles we've been through...
We are getting rewarded
for all these.
Now is time for joy.
The time has come, Aytolun.
In fact it's overdue.
Our troubles are over.
Our future is as bright
as the sun in the sky.
Where is Tugtekin?
The Alps going after
Ertugrul lost track of him.
He is very angry.
They are with Gokce.
I'll go and tell Tugtekin
about the meeting.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in, Gumustekin Bey.
I have very important news for you.
Bey, I'll go and see if
Mother needs anything.
Go ahead, Gumustekin Bey.
I received a letter
from Ameer Sadettin Kobek.
He invited all the Turkmen Beys
to the Caravansary
to discuss an important issue.
What is the important issue?
I have no idea.
I am curious, too.
However, I know that this is my first
important duty as a Dodurga Bey.
We need to show all Turkmen Beys,
especially Sadettin Kobek,
that Dodurga is in safe hands.
Thank you.
Then, we'll leave together.
Forgive me, Tugtekin Bey.
I need to hit the road early.
Ameer Sadettin is waiting
for me at the Caravansary.
I will go to Caravansary right after
I tell Hayme Hatun.
What's up, Gumustekin Bey?
So far as I can tell,
Ameer Sadettin Kobek wants to have a
chat with me at the palace.
In that case,
I wish you a nice trip.
Thank you, Bey.
Bey, take care of my daughter
and my sister.
You can trust me,
Gumustekin Bey.
With your permission, Bey.
After we heard that Tugtekin Bey
burst here like that in the morning,
we no longer feel at ease,
Mother Hayme.
When we think about
what happened previously,
we're worried, Mother Hayme.
Didn't Ertugrul Bey turn out
to be right, that time?
Didn't he punish the traitors
and save the tribe from trouble?
Didn't he clear his name
from that accusation?
You are right, Mother Hayme.
You are right.
However, we still do not feel at ease.
What will happen if they can't find Banu
Cicek? Dogan is no ordinary Alp.
He's Ertugrul Bey's aide.
Ertugrul Bey will be
held accountable in the end.
What is Ertugrul Bey trying to do,
Mother Hayme?
We respect Ertugrul Bey,
just like we respect you.
However, spring is upon us.
What about our herds,
our nomad group?
-He is right.
-What is going to happen then?
Never mind tomorrow,
even today is uncertain.
I will discuss this matter thoroughly
with Gundogdu Bey when he returns.
We expect to hear good news
from you, Mother Hayme.
-With your permission.
-Permission is yours.
Mother Hayme!
Gumustekin Bey wants to see you.
Send him in.
Ameer Sadettin invited all
the Turkmen Beys to caravansary
to discuss an important matter,
Hayme Hatun.
If you have nothing to say,
and done with making me stand up
here like a servant,
I request your permission.
I need to be at the caravansary.
The Kayi will accept the invitation.
They are headed for Kurtbogazi.
You look like you're having fun, Dogan.
Where is that killer?
Banu Cicek didn't kill anyone, brother.
Where is she?
She escaped the cruelty
of humans...
and took refuge in God's justice.
Where is Gundogdu Bey?
Is he going to save you?
Banu Cicek is here!
Did Ertugrul Bey have
anything to do with this?
No, he didn't.
I did what I did because
I love Banu Cicek.
Banu Cicek!
Stop!
No victory that we did not pay
the price for is ours.
How happy is he who paid the price.
This letter will be delivered
to the vizier of Georgia at once.
Yes, his highness Ameer.
So, Korkut Bey passed away
and the new Bey is his son,
Tugtekin, you say?
And my Sister Aytolun lives in
Tugtekin's marquee
as she was entrusted to his father.
It seems that you encircled
Tugtekin's marquee rather good.
When you become the margrave, he will be
on your side then, that is good.
And he also will do as I say.
What if he becomes besotted with
the idea of becoming the margrave
himself as well, like his father?
What if he rebels against you?
Then, I will behead him as I did
his father before, Ameer Sadettin.
-Gundogdu?
-Gundogdu will marry my daughter.
I have him on a tight leash as well,
Ameer Sadettin.
He will not be going against my will.
Well done, Gumustekin.
You are fulfilling the promises
you gave me, one by one.
I learned how to manage politics in
the palace from you, Ameer Sadettin.
So, there is nothing left to discuss
with Beys tonight.
Without delay
I will inform the Beys that I want
to see you become the margrave.
I believe you have no problems with it.
None, Ameer Sadettin.
Now go and take rest.
Tonight is your night.
May God keep you from harm's way,
Ameer Sadettin.
Where are you, Banu Cicek?
You should have been here already.
What is it that you are after,
Selcan Hatun?
God, why are these things happening to us?
May God help us.
Banu Cicek! Sister, what happened to you?
Come and lean on me.
Come here.
Wait.
Are you alright?
I came across with Gundogdu Bey's Alps.
Why are all these things happening to us?
Help me to remove the arrow
from my shoulder.
Alright, wait.
Selcan Hatun. Draw the arrow at once.
Do not hold back thinking that
it will hurt. At once!
Hang on. Do not worry.
Hang on, my sister.
With the name of God.
Did Goncagul come?
She did.
Aytolun will not be able to evade us
this time, Selcan Hatun.
I have found the evidence related
to the death of Duru Hatun.
This time, the one hanging
in the middle of the nomad tent
will not be me, I will be
the one hanging them.
I will be here before sundown tomorrow.
I will bring you the evidence
that I have found.
That evidence will bring the end of
the snake named Aytolun in court.
Do not worry about me.
Do not tell a word of this to anyone.
I do not trust anyone but you
in the nomad tent.
May God help you.
Thank you.
Come.
-May God help you.
-And you, sister.
Like a bird in a trap.
As they struggle, they will lose
their wings, then their claws
and finally their necks
to the sword of justice.
The Sheikh of Ahis Kirmani would like
to see you, his highness Ameer.
Let him in.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
I was not expecting to see you,
Sheikh Kirmani.
I would like you to know that
we always pray for your well being.
How happy I am.
Be seated.
We always pray for our enemies
as well as our friends, Ameer Sadettin.
I have never heard of one to pray
for his enemies, Sheikh Kirmani.
We say, "my Creator, show compassion
to those who are evil,
who creates mischiefs
who rebels and who lives as bandits."
Why would you do that?
The art is to see the goods that
come from those who are evil.
They torture us so much that ultimately
they save us from evil
and carry us to goodness.
We mainly pray for those who phonate
the young and kill them without mercy.
Because they teach us to be cautious
and give us the will to fight.
I came here to cognate
the Newroz with Kayis.
This also presented me the opportunity
to come and see you.
Kayis you say?
We came here with our prayers to see
Ertugrul Bey who taught the cruels
who wanted to slaughter us, their place.
So, he is the one who saved you
from the attack you suffered?
Thank God who brings out the good
within every evil.
-Goncagul?
-Aunt.
I saw Selcan and Banu Cicek met, aunt.
What are you saying?
How can this be?
I was out collecting herbs, I saw Selcan
then I became suspicious.
I secretly followed her until
she reached Karakayas.
Then Banu Cicek showed up.
-She was hurt.
-Hurt?
Alps have found her and
shot her with an arrow.
I heard them talking, aunt.
Alright. What did they talk about?
It seems that they have evidence
related to Duru Hatun's death, aunt.
It is impossible.
They will meet again at the same spot
tomorrow before sundown.
Banu Cicek will bring the evidence
to Selcan.
Then everything will be
revealed in court, aunt.
What are we going to do after that?
What are we going to do, aunt?
Wait, stop there.
You confused me.
I can send the Alps and kill them both.
What about the evidence?
What if the Alps take it?
Then, what are we going to do?
Then...
I will go and get it myself.
You said that Banu Cicek is hurt.
Dealing with both of them will be easy.
Then we all can have a sigh of relief.
And Selcan will be regarded as a murderer.
What about Dogan?
What if he comes as well?
How can you deal with him, Aunt?
Aytolun Hatun.
Come in, Kaya.
Gundogdu Bey caught Dogan Alp
and brought him here.
It seems that those two women's death
will come by my sword.
Where is Banu Cicek, Bey?
We could not catch her. However,
our Alps are after her with Nurul.
Why did you help Banu Cicek escape?
Did Ertugrul Bey order you to do so?
I did what I did for my love,
Tugtekin Bey.
But, if I believed that Banu Cicek
was a murderer
I would bury my love to my heart
and bring her to you.
We have found Banu Cicek, Bey.
She managed to escape but
I shot her with an arrow.
-Banu Cicek!
-She cannot get far.
No! Banu Cicek!
Send more Alps after her. Do not come back
here unless you find her body.
What heartless men you are!
I am telling you that
Banu Cicek is innocent!
Since Dogan Alp admitted to his crime,
let Mother Hayme decide his punishment.
Since she wanted that, I need
to show respect to her wish.
However, do not send him
to the caged tent, Bey.
Tie him up to a pole around here. And
have Dodurga Alps to keep watch by him.
No one gets close to him.
After we return from
Ameer Sadettin's feast
I would like to see
Mother Hayme's justness.
What invitation is this?
His highness Ameer, invited all the Bey's
from neighboring nomad tents.
So Dogan, what is going to happen now?
Is it better like this?
I am telling you that
Cicek Hatun is innocent!
You made a pure hearted woman
fall prey to the wolves!
Take him away and tie him.
What is the current situation,
Selcan Hatun?
Goncagul believed what she heard,
Ertugrul Bey.
Indeed, it was obvious that she was
so scared from the way she ran away.
Obviously, she believed them.
But there is one more problem, brother.
Banu Cicek was hurt when she arrived,
Ertugrul Bey.
I removed the arrow from her shoulder.
She said that she will take care of
the wound herself and then she left.
She told me that she will
come to Karakayas
before sundown tomorrow,
just like you said.
I heard that Ameer Sadettin invited all
the Bey's from neighboring nomad tents
...to Kervansaray tonight.
So, Banu Cicek is hurt.
And there is a feast tonight.
Tugtekin will be in Caravansary as well.
We cannot be sure what
we might be up against.
Seems we are running off
the rail, brother.
They killed Korkut Bey. Then without
delay Kobek is on the move.
I will find out their
real intentions tonight.
What are their intentions, son?
They do not only wish to rule the Turkmen
nomad tents as they please, mother.
Their real intention is...
Dogan has been caught.
Banu Cicek has been shot.
Tell me, brother. How many more will
fall victim to these graves you dug?
When will you open your eyes
and see the truth, brother?
Enough, Ertugrul. I am fed up
with your meaningless nonsense.
Enough!
Enough, already!
When will you two brothers get along?
I will give you two a task.
Maybe this time, you two can get along!
I would like you two to go
Ameer Sadettin's feast as substitutes.
Mother! Do you not know what Ertugrul
thinks about Sadettin Kobek?
How can you assign him
as a substitute as well?
Seems that Ameer Sadettin would like
to talk about some crucial matter.
If he asks something from you
you should not agree to anything
that you do not approve.
If one of you says no to a matter,
the other will adapt to it.
Understood?
Go, then.
Banu Cicek is a courageous woman.
She will get to Karakayas on time.
No giving up, no surrender.
You all know what to do.
Tomorrow, the truth will be revealed.
Where is Banu Cicek?
Tugtekin.
I know Dogan Alp well.
Even if you do all that you can,
you cannot get a word out of him.
Also, did you not say that Mother Hayme
will settle his punishment?
Enough.
This is enough for today.
We will see what Mother Hayme will do.
Tugtekin Bey!
Since when beating an Alp who is tied,
brings honor to a Bey?
When did it become suitable for you
to advise Beys, Ertugrul Bey?
Until the truth reveals itself,
stay away from my Alp.
Keep your anger in check.
At least until we come back from
Ameer Sadettin Kobek's feast.
Is Mother Hayme
not coming to Caravansary?
No. She assigned us both as substitutes.
We will come.
This is also your doing,
is it not Ertugrul?
You cannot settle with just us
you have to go out and disturb
Turkmen Beys as well.
To find the truth, I will disturb
whole world if necessary.
Come here, boy.
Ertugrul Bey from Kayi tribe is also here.
There is a crucial matter, indeed.
Has Gumustekin Bey said anything to you?
His highness Ameer would like
to discuss a matter with us.
That is all I know.
-Hope for the best then.
-Hope for the best.
Do you think that a good word would
come out both of their mouths, brother?
Ertugrul. Please, brother, do not.
Do not forget that we are here
as substitutes for our mother.
Do not worry, I will not.
I will stand against anything that
stands opposed to my nomad group.
Ertugrul.
His highness, Ameer Sadettin Kobek!
It is an honour,
great Beys of Turkmen tribes.
It brings me joy to see you all here.
I see almost all of the neighboring
Turkmen Beys are here.
Seeing our precious Tugtekin
and Gundogdu Bey
who raided degenerate Noyan's place
and smashed it, among us
brings me so much happiness.
Also, I cannot stop myself from
mentioning Ertugrul Bey
who with his courage and boldness won
many wars and kept our heads high.
I would like to show my appreciation
to him again, in your presence.
So do we, Bey.
-You are welcome, as well.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Please, honor me by sharing all these
blessings on my table with me.
With the name of God.
Go ahead, enjoy.
It is not good that Hayme Hatun
sent Ertugrul here, Ameer Sadettin.
Is Gundogdu not your son in law?
Do not worry.
Mother Hayme? Turgut and Bamsi are here.
They would like to see you.
Send them in.
As you wish, mother.
What is it?
Mother Hayme, it's Dogan.
He learned that Banu Cicek is hurt.
But we were not able to go and tell him
that she is well and healthy.
The Alps of Tugtekin Bey, do not
let us near him, Mother Hayme.
Even if he stands out there ashamed,
hungry and thirsty in the cold
the situation will not affect him,
Mother Hayme.
However, he is worried about
his beloved, Mother Hayme.
Only you can help him
with his pain, Mother.
If you let us, we would like to ask you
to go and tell Dogan
that Banu Cicek is alright.
Otherwise he will be miserable
all night, Mother Hayme.
If there is anything to do,
you can do it, Mother Hayme.
We are thankful to you for not only
inviting us to this grand feast
that suits your high rank
but also wanting to discuss a crucial
matter with us, Ameer Sadettin.
You honored us by inviting all nomad tent
Beys who did not fret
from going against Mongols for our State.
First of all, I wish God's grace upon
your deceased father, Tugtekin Bey.
Thank you.
We share your pain.
-My condolences.
-May God bestow mercy upon him.
My condolences.
Thank you. May God give you all
longevity. Thank you.
I understand that you want to know
the crucial matter I want to discuss.
Then let us talk without delay.
To reinstate the order of our state...
...and to make Turkmen tribes
more prosperous and powerful...
...I would like to form
a new margrave seigniory.
A new margrave seigniory?
How can it be?
And on this occasion, to a worthy Bey,
who you all know very well...
...to Gumustekin Bey...
...I would like to issue
this difficult assignment.
Mother Hayme.
Stay out of my way.
Tugtekin Bey commanded no one
to approach him, Mother Hayme.
Mother, they shot Banu Cicek.
Patience, Dogan.
Who knows what will happen to any of us.
God is almighty.
And who knows
maybe she has found somebody to
heal her wound.
If God permits, mother.
May God bless you.
Ertugrul Bey put up with many things
for Halime Sultan.
I see it better now.
It is all worth for the sake of love.
Tomorrow is another day, Dogan Alp.
Thank God.
The most beautiful example of unity
and peace is in front of us,
Ameer Sadettin.
Kayi tribe and Dodurga tribe were
forces to be reckoned with
but now they are stronger than ever.
He is right.
-Avshar Bey is right.
-True.
The words of Avshar Bey Omer
confirmed my actions.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Without a doubt, for this important duty
Gumustekin Bey is the right choice.
He has always lent his support
from Konya in our times of need.
It gives me great honor that he is
a Bey of my nomad group.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey. Thank you.
With your permission, Ameer Sadettin.
Go ahead, Ertugrul Bey.
We are representing the Kayi tribe
in Mother Hayme's stead.
My mother bestowed me and Gundogdu Bey
with this duty.
Gumustekin Bey told Mother Hayme that
you wanted to discuss
an important matter with us.
It is true.
But I fail to see any connection between
your intentions
and what is actually happening in here.
You are not here to discuss anything
other than giving us your commands.
-What are you saying, Ertugrul Bey?
-Do you hear what you are saying?
-What do you mean his commands?
-What are you saying, Ertugrul Bey?
Brave Ertugrul, were you offended by us?
What makes you say such things?
What you are doing here is as wrong as
Noyan being taken away
from my brother Gundogdu's hands
while he was being executed,
Ameer Sadettin.
And some Turkmen Beys are not here
while we are talking about
important matters as this.
He is right.
-Other Turkmen Beys should be here.
-He is right.
Our rights and wrongs define us,
Ertugtul Bey.
I hope almighty God does not shame us
with our decisions.
-Amen.
It is my duty to prevent us from
making a decision
that may shame us one day.
Yes, he is right.
Other Beys should be here
if we are going to make a decision.
Your insolence is wearing our patience,
Ertugrul Bey.
When I heared the words of this
forthcoming brave man
my confidence in Turkmen tribes
strengthened.
On the contrary
we will always value the objections
of Ertugrul Bey.
Thus we can correct our mistakes.
What do you think, Gundogdu Bey?
His highness Ameer.
I am sure that you intend to make the best
decision for our unity and peace.
But Mother Hayme
put Ertugrul Bey and me
in charge under one condition.
Kayi tribe will not accept any decision
that we both do not approve.
I do not have anything else
to say for now.
Thank you, Gundogdu Bey.
Your good intentions are enough for us.
So I want to hear the final say of
Kayi tribe from Mother Hayme's mouth.
If God permits, I will visit your
nomad tent as soon as possible.
We would be honored. We will be waiting.
So this margrave may bring us all
good fortune.
Gumustekin Bey.
We know that you are in God's side
and we trust you.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
-Let's hope for the best.
-May it bring us good fortune.
-Thank you.
-May the God be with you, always.
Thank you.
Your weapons can protect us
from our enemies
but how can we protect ourselves
from all this treachery, Bey?
We do not know what to believe
and who to trust anymore, Ertugrul Bey.
Things need to get worse
before they get better, my gazelle.
In the end, the truth will prevail
among all this treachery.
The only thing you need to do is
becoming aware of the happiness
that grows inside you.
Time is near.
After our baby is born, our marquee
will be blessed with fortune.
Bless the day that you tracked
that gazelle and found me.
I will be by your side
until my dying breath.
So their aim was to make
Gumustekin the margrave.
They will put a collar
on the Turkmen tribe
and put Gumustekin in charge
like a guard dog, mother.
Gumustekin is still in caravansary.
They are making decisions about all of us.
I will not allow this, brother.
I will reveal their trap, do not worry.
-What will you do, son?
I will take Gundogdu and Tugtekin
to Karakayalar.
They will see the truth for themselves.
You became the Bey of Dodurga nomad group
and my brother was selected
as the margrave.
Dodurga tribe will be exalted among
Turkmens.
Glory belongs to our nomad group.
None can stand in front of our future.
You are right, mother.
Our days of suffering are behind us.
A bright future awaits our tribe.
From now on, everything should be
worthy of our nomad group.
It is time to say new words
and do new things.
Nothing will be the same.
Goncagul Hatun.
Bring order to the weavery before spring.
Arrange everything.
I will take care of the bazaar myself.
As you command, Tugtekin Bey.
Then I should finish what I have started.
Aunt, I can not let you go there alone.
I do not want you to to be a part of this,
Goncagul.
Banu Cicek is wounded.
Your aunt can take care of both of them.
Do not worry.
Brother.
I have things to say to you.
We need to talk.
What is happening, brother?
What are you up to again?
Let us go to marquee.
We cannot talk in here.
You go on, Alps.
Gundogdu Bey, Amer Sadettin Kobek
is waiting for you in caravansary.
Thank you. I am coming.
I need to go as soon as possible, brother.
We can talk later.
So he left the destiny of other
Turkmen Beys to Gumustekin.
I cannot believe the things he has done
to bewitch Gundogdu and Tugtekin.
Gumustekin is a wretched man who wouldn't
shy away from using his
daughter and sister
to achieve his purpose.
I am sure that Amerr Sadettin
knows everything.
They are not doing all these to keep
Turkmen tribes in line, Bey.
Amer Sadettin Kobek has a bigger aim.
It is obvious that he has a
higher ambition.
I know, Artuk Bey.
His aim is to spin a web around Sultan
Alaeddin's palace like a spider.
Just as he brought a lap dog after
becoming a margrave,
he will use a loyal man as Shahzade.
It is our duty to foil his scheme.
Of course, Bey.
Ertugrul Bey, Aytolun Hatun
has left the nomad group.
-Turgut.
-Yes, Bey.
Tell Gunkut to tell Tugtekin that he saw
Banu Cicek near the nomad group.
He cannot resist to follow her.
-As you command, Bey.
Go to Selcan Hatun and tell her that
Aytolun Hatun has left the nomad group.
At once, Bey.
God help you, Bey.
Amen.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
-May it be easy.
-Thank you, Bey.
-Have a prosperous day.
-May it be easy.
-Thank you, Bey.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you, thank you.
-May it be easy.
-May God give you a long life, Bey.
Welcome, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you. Welcome, Bey.
Thank you, well met.
How is the business in the bazaar?
There is not a problem, I hope?
No, Bey. So far so good.
May God protect you.
Thank you, amen. Thank you.
Have a prosperous day.
-Thank you, Bey.
-May it be easy.
From now on, we should take care
of the regulation of bazaar.
We should listen to the troubles of people
and help them.
Help them any way you can.
But if you see a craftsman causing
trouble or defying orders, punish him.
As you command, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
-Have a prosperous day.
-Thank you, welcome.
Thank you.
You took the trouble of
coming to our bazaar.
If you accept, I want to give this
pot I made as a gift, Bey.
Do not mention it.
I would be honored to accept the gift of a
master craftman like you.
-Thank you.
-But we should give this pot
to a person who needs it.
It would be a sin to keep it
when there are people in need.
-You are right, Bey.
-Let us keep our people alive.
So that they may keep our nomad group
and marquees alive.
-You are right, Bey.
-Have a bountiful day.
-Thank you, Bey.
-Thank you.
Bey! Bey!
I saw Banu Cicek down the river bed.
She was on her horse and I could not
follow her without my horse.
May I, Selcan Hatun?
Come in, Turali.
Come in.
Ertugrul Bey sent me.
Aytolun Hatun went out
from the nomad tent.
Thank God!
Thank you, my brave Alp.
Tracks end here, Bey.
Bogac, Samsa, take Alps
and keep searching.
As you command, Bey.
What are you doing here, Ertugrul Bey?
Did you come to save Banu Cicek?
When I look at you, I see the same
wild horses racing in my heart, Tugtekin.
You have a deep love for your nomad group.
And you are making your ancestors proud.
But I see that the wild horses in your
heart are blinded by your rage.
Anger is a treacherous cliff, my friend.
Be careful about what you are saying,
Ertugrul Bey.
My patience is running thin.
Remember the trouble Noyan put you in.
You are in a bigger trouble now.
Today, you will prove that
you are the Bey of Dodurga.
I came here to take you to Banu Cicek.
I will show you the trouble
they put you in.
Don't be stubborn, come with me.
See the truth with your own eyes.
Patience, Tugtekin.
Aytolun will be here here shortly
with grief.
Banu Cicek, sister.
Are you alright?
I am fine, Selcan Hatun. I am fine.
-How is your wound?
-It is okay.
We were worried about you,
we could not sleep all night.
Selcan Hatun, Does Dogan Alp
know that I am alive?
Do not worry, sister.
Dogan knows that you are fine.
-Good, good.
-Let me look.
Selcan!
Come here, you wretched woman.
How did you come here, you witch?
Give that to me, immediately.
How do you know what I have?
How did you find our place?
Just do as I say.
We proved that you killed
Aunt Duru and my uncle.
From now on, we are not afraid of you,
your brother
and your imbecile nephew.
Do you want this evidence?
Come and take it, come on.
But you will have to
kill us first to get it.
You will never prove that I killed them.