Episode 29 will start after 12:20 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
We are near Noyan's route.
Two people shall scout.
They should be fast and talented.
Abdurrahman, Hamza.
-Yes, Bey.
You scout before us.
You never know where these infidels
will come from.
We shall not be caught unprepared.
-Your wish is my command, Bey.
Come.
Bring me Gundogdu and Tugtekin's head.
No one will get out of here alive. No one!
You should not tire yourself,
Halime Sultan.
You are pregnant.
It feels good to work, Aytolun Hatun.
It is easier to wait for my man this way.
Tugtekin and Gundogdu
will avenge your man.
They are both brave warriors.
Ertugrul, what kind of a warrior was he?
I could not have met him.
Ertugrul...
He was really different
with his friendship
his mirth and sincerity.
Ertugrul was the hope of
our nomad group, Aytolun Hatun.
Ertugrul had been our hope
on our most desperate days.
Ertugrul was the one who pulled
all of us out of
the betrayal that surrounded
Kayis like a wen.
I heard that your sister
was a part of this betrayal
and then she repented.
Gokce Hatun.
Ertugrul is like your brother.
I am sorry for what happened.
May God give you patience.
I know people like you well.
I know well how you carry poison
with your silver tongue.
The sins you committed in the past has
gained you big life experiences, Selcan.
Stay away from our women, especially
my sister Gokce and Halime.
Curb your poisoned tongue
so the winter can pass quickly.
Ertugrul!
Go ahead!
I have a bad feeling.
You cannot escape the fate, Bey.
It is forbidden to me
to leave blood in those infidels' veins
to leave breath in their lungs.
Aburrahman and Hamza
has not come back yet.
Bey, they are coming.
Tugtekin, they are coming!
May God help us.
Thank you. For all of us.
Wait!
Hold your position.
This way! This way!
Find that dog!
Find him or I will kill all of you!
Idiots, go ahead!
We must run away, braveheart.
With your last bit of power.
In the name of God.
It is an ambush!
-Hide!
Strive.
Keep on, brave heart!
Keep on for the love of God!
Go ahead. Go ahead.
This way!
Look at the river! Run to the path there!
Quickly!
-Someone of us entrapped us, brother.
-What are you saying, Tugtekin?
They knew we were here.
Making strawmen, ambush within ambush.
It was all a trap.
Who would do this?
Brother, you better look for the
traitor among your closest Alps.
The Alps who are not with you here now.
Half of mine are dead or hit.
Hamza, watch this dog carefully.
We must make him talk.
Master!
Have I not told you to not to leave
this Mongol alone?
We saw a Mongol who is watching
the nomad tent.
-Did you catch him?
-We did, Mother Hayme.
Before he died, he said,
Noyan will set off tomorrow.
Hamza.
Leave me here, run away.
You will die because of me.
Trust me. We almost arrived.
Keep on. Go ahead.
Attack!
-By God!
I want their head! All of them!
God is almighty!
God is the truth!
This way!
Some more! A couple more steps
and we will arrive.
Go ahead!
The trace is going this way.
Go ahead, quickly!
Wait, wait.
Damn! Where is he?
Where is he? Where?
Move. Move!
I know this man. His name is Bilyu.
He has been lost for hree days, sir.
Then Ertugrul is not alone.
Someone spied our headquarters.
Then took him under his care.
Find him! Find them!
Find them! Move!
Move!
You had endured against these
hellhounds, brave heart.
Be patient for a little longer.
Father, what are you doing here?
From now on I do not have a purpose
other than being a martyr.
Go ahead.
By God!
The decision of spending the winter
together reassured everyone, Hayme.
May God bless you, brother.
But I am thinking about
Gundogdu and Tugtekin.
They are both furious.
They are both fueled with revenge.
I am afraid they will do something bad.
Noyan.
The devil who is against them,
is not to be underestimated.
Our children are the
future of two nomad tents.
They know that. They will err on the
side of caution for it, Hayme.
Gundogdu would not be cheated.
Wild Demir, stop!
We need him alive.
We need to find out who ambushed us.
Stop. Do not.
Stop.
Lie down, infidel!
We united two nomad groups.
But this will not be easy, brother.
Why do you think so, Hayme?
Who do you think would be most angry at
two nomad groups spending winter together?
Noyan.
He is going to do everything to bother us
inside and outside.
He is going to engrave us.
And he will not let us breathe
from outside.
Dogan.
Help me.
-Alright, Wild Demir.
Easy.
Resist, gallant man, you will be better.
Press it on your wound.
Someone in here betrayed us.
He tattled us to Noyan.
Who would risk being ambushed
and do such a thing?
Maybe the traitor is not here, right now.
Hamza and Abdurrahman went to scout
but they did not come back yet.
They were eager to before us.
It is obvious they knew
that there was a trap.
Ignoble man! Your mouth is
worse than a camel's tripe!
Would a good word ever
come out of your mouth?
Be grateful to your Bey
or I know what I would do to you.
-What will you do to me?
-Dogan!
-Kocabash!
Tugtekin is a brave man.
When I look at him, I see your youth.
But he resembles Ertugrul's old,
petulant times.
Ertugrul learned the art of war
on the lands of hardest enemy.
He learned diplomacy in Aleppo
from his relations with Ayyubids
and the finesse of art of war
from his fight with Templars.
Above all he learned the merit of
recognizing his enemies.
Tugtekin is far away from these
experiences, yet, brother.
Fighting with Mongols
cooked Tugtekin, too, Hayme.
Do not worry.
We will overcome all of it.
In the end, it will not be easy, brother.
It will not be easy.
Bey, I hope you are fine.
Where is ignoble Noyan?
Where have you been?
You sent us off to scout, Bey.
Allow me to question them, brother.
What are you talking about?
What does he say, Bey?
Answer Tugtekin Bey's questions.
Bey, do you know that what you are saying?
My Bey.
-Do not interfere, Wild Demir.
-They are our dear ones, Bey.
So Kurdoglu was.
Keep on, brave heart.
I need to find a way to carry you.
In the name of God.
Two warrior tribes.
Both have brave Alps.
The smallest spark could trigger
a civil war.
That is my biggest fear, brother.
We must obey the order.
Damn with this order
and who obeys this order...
Which one of you tattled us to Noyan?
Which one?
Or was it both of you?
I do not have answer for you!
Call Bey! Call him!
You fool!
Your Bey does not trust you,
do you not see?
You left alone the Mongol
you brought to nomad tent.
You caused Wild Demir to kill him
out of his pain. Why?
Because you did not want him to talk.
Do not try my patience!
You cannot call me traitor!
Why? Or will you tell your master, Noyan?
Enough!
We need to take measures
to prevent this conflict.
Brother, we would not even need Noyan,
for us to be destroyed in such a conflict.
We would do it ourselves.
I want these two to be executed, brother.
Bey, do not do what this tactless said.
Abdurrahman is entrusted
to us by Suleyman Shah.
And Hamza is your bravest Alp.
He put his head in the lion's mouth
for you in many wars.
If you do such a thing,
it would have big consequences.
Thank you.
Do not hurry.
Enough, stop, enough!
Look at this! What happened to the dye!
I told you, woman!
You did not listen to me!
Leave me alone. I do not need your help.
Go away, I can do it myself.
-What is happening here?
Aytolun Hatun, look at this.
She messed up a vessel of dye.
Are they here to help us or to scourge us?
I told her to blend it slowly.
She did not listen to me.
She is no different than a goat.
Enough! I said enough!
She will not listen to you,
you will listen to her.
You will not forget who is landlord
and who is guest here.
If you forget that,
I know how to remind you.
You remind who of what, Aytolun Hanim?
Selcan, I will remind who they are
and where they came from.
Firstly, they are refugees here.
We would die of starvation
than to help them.
If it was not for Korkut Bey,
you would have fallen prey.
No one can disrespect my women
in my sewing workshop.
We do whatever Mother Hayme
taught us, Aytolun Hanim.
She would want us to do our job right,
come hell or high water
even if we die of starvation.
If you put many woods under the boiler
so the herbs in it
could encolour quickly
you cannot get the color.
Even if you do, the color would not be
permanent when the rug is weaved.
You cannot find customers in bazaar.
So, us, Kayi women
would rather not do our job
than to do it deviously.
Think about it.
Ask your Bey and tell us your decision.
If you want, we will come
and do our work right
or you will do your work
as you know, without us.
We are leaving, Hatuns.
I will execute them, brother.
I can't bring trouble into my nomad tent.
Here we are thinking that
you were a decent man.
We thought that
you were to avenge our Bey,
but you turned out to be coward.
-You are a fool and coward.
-Dogan!
What do you think you're doing?
Will we draw a swords against
each other?
Does what you're doing become an Alp?
What kind of a combat is this?
Kocabash!
Stop it, for God's sake!
Stop it!
The head of the Alps is Tugtekin!
You will do as he says!
And that is that!
-Who is inside?
-Mother Hayme.
Alright, you can leave.
What's on your mind, brother?
We must reinforce our relations as
relatives to prevent such conflicts
in the future, Hayme.
Even we are at war,
we need to cement
the trust between the two tribes
with weddings and headquarter
meetings.
The best way is intermarriage among
the two tribes.
-More power to you!
-Thank you.
It is high time you got married, Gokche.
To become a widow like Halime?
That's God's will, Gokche.
However, you acting like one of
Ertugrul's widows isn't helping.
How soon you forget that I am barren
women who cannot even have a baby?
And it's all because of you.
Because of your ominous ambitions.
See?
I have become just like you.
I am doomed to live as a barren spinster.
Tell me. Who will marry me now, sister?
Tell me!
Gokche.
Gokche?
What is the matter with you?
Are you good, sister?
We must bury our pain deep inside
and keep living.
The life will show us its blessings.
Do not let your beautiful eyes
stare only to the ground.
Do not miss out on your kismet.
Ertugrul was the hope for the
nomad tent and beauty girls like you
will bring many Ertugruls into
our nomad tent.
With your feminineness and beauty.
Suleiman Shah.
My Suleiman.
I need you so much.
You left me alone
in this mortal world.
How I will get through it all by myself?
What is it that you know about
Gokche and not telling me, Eygis?
Nothing, Hanim.
This winter will be hard, Eygis.
You are all alone.
If you want to keep working with
Artuk Bey in peace,
do not lie me.
What is it that you know about
Gokche and not telling me?
Tell me! Who does Gokche yearn for?
Ertugrul.
Stop working, Halime.
You are pregnant.
At least have mercy on your baby.
The baby is a keepsake
from Ertugrul Bey.
Pull yourself together.
I need to do something.
I will not stop until Ertugrul comes back.
Or I will lose my mind, Selcan.
Let me go and do my bit.
Welcome to the humble adobe of Geyikli
of the Bayir Bucak Turkmens.
The security of our nomad tent is the
most important thing, brother.
We cannot bring them
into the nomad tent.
We will pay the ultimate price.
The responsibility of making decisions
was conferred to you
at the headquarters.
I will respect
whatever decision you make.
However, executing them
would be a very harsh decision.
I say let's banish them.
What about Ertugrul's Alps?
I see that they disrespect you.
However, they're our own flesh
and blood.
Moreover, Mother Hayme
loves them, too.
So, until this matter is resolved,
banish them, as well.
They objected the decision
of the head of Alps, brother.
They rebelled against us.
What are they still talking about?
Gundogdu Bey does not let Abdurrahman
and Hamza to be executed.
Who is Tugtekin? Do we not have
our own headquarters?
Do we not have
Hayme Ana to govern us?
Tugtekin is the head of the Alps.
His decision cannot be questioned
even at the headquarters.
We aren't here to look around, but
to fight under the orders of our Beys.
-We fought and we won.
-We won, but we were betrayed.
We had many martyrs.
We humiliated Tugtekin.
Gundogdu Bey
has his work cut out for him.
They are coming.
Bey?
Have you decided?
Abdurrahman and Hamza
will not be executed.
However
they will not be released, either.
Both will be banished.
How is that possible, Bey?
Dogan? Turgut?
You two will be banished with them, too.
What are you saying, Bey?
You will not come back to into nomad
tent until the war and winter is over.
You will take care of
Abdurrahman and Hamza.
This is what's been decided.
Since we infamized Tugtekin,
we are the troublesome
Alps of Ertugrul in his mind's eyes.
Damn it!
Noyan's will be furious.
Ertugrul escaped and to make matters
worse, the ambush failed.
What should we do?
If they make Bortlu talk, Kocabash's
identity will be compromised.
This is worse.
So do we need to rescue him?
Or Kocabash must find a way
to kill Bortlu.
He must kill him.
Eventually
Noyan will make them pay
for their inaptitude.
Do not worry about me, father.
Do not worry about us, Master Demir.
You are my only sons alive.
Take care of each other, for God's sake.
If something bad happens to you...
Go ahead, go now!
Ertugrul Bey would never act
so tactless, Gundogdu Bey.
Give me your blessings.
There is no blessing
left for us to give you.
Tugtekin, as for you...
You are nothing, let alone being
the head of Alps...
Shame on you all!
It hurts me, as well, Wild Demir.
However, there was no other way.
I need to make Bortlu talk in any case.
After breaking everyone's heart
can finding out the truth
bring peace on us, Gundogdu Bey?
You've saved our nomad tent from
a big trouble, Bey.
You are right, Kocabash.
That is the only way to teach them.
Not to worry.
I will find a way to rescue you.
Do not say a word.
Otherwise they will skin us both alive.
Halime.
That is love.
Is love not, God killing you inside,
then rescuing you from within?
Halime.
Fetch some water!
-What happened?
-We need to take her to the tent.
Mother!
-Halime.
-What happened?
Eygis told me that she was bleeding.
Now she is fine.
However, I am worried about the baby.
The poor girl couldn't stand the pain.
She needs to rest now, Hayme Hatun.
Otherwise Ertugrul's child
may not survive.
My daughter.
How I can live without him, Mother?
What about your baby?
If you were to die,
how can the baby live?
Isn't it time to stop torturing yourself?
You must live for your baby.
You are awake, Bey.
You know me.
Tangut and his bandits resounded
the forest with your name.
-Who are you?
-They call me Geyikli.
I've been living in this forest
since I was born.
Thank you.
Get up and eat some, so that you can
go after infidel Moguls in the morning.
You will recover soon. Come on, lad.
You shall eat it all up.
It was not easy making this.
If you eat all of it,
I will give you red meat and kumiss.
Fresh kumiss; without alcohol.
What does Noyan want from you?
I know why he came here from Tabriz.
He came here for you.
If he caught, but hasn't killed you,
it means he wants something from you.
You know a lot.
When one lives with bears, birds,
wolves and insect,
his ears and eyes sharpens.
It is obvious that you haven't given
Noyan what he wanted.
What did he want from you?
To become his follower?
Yes.
You need to be careful
in every step you take, Bey.
Because from now Noyan poses
a threat to everyone you love.
You are a fortunate one, dear to God.
We caught that human
piece of garbage called Bortlu.
And we killed a lot of Moguls.
Then what happened? Nothing.
That is a victory or a fiasco?
They are going to say they won victory
by killing a couple of infidels.
Then they will kill the Alps of the
Kayi tribe without even blinking an eye.
I don't think the Kayi tribe will ever
recover from this, brother.
That's how I feel.
Brother? You don't know what
you're saying.
I know what I am saying, brothers.
Suleiman Shah died.
Ertugrul Bey, as well.
From now on, the Kayi tribe
will be vanished.
You are angry and you do not know
what are you saying, Hamza.
I know what I am saying.
Do you not realize, brothers?
Gundogdu Bey will be occupied with
finding a way to go after his uncle
and his uncle's son  to bring peace
to his tribe.
You know the rest.
Crusaders from the
and the Mongols from the east.
There is nowhere left for us
to take shelter.
Ertugrul Bey used to say that
we need to fight to the death.
That's what we must do.
From now on,
we should be ashamed of being alive
for each day that
passes away without combat.
I neither want to go back to my
nomad tent nor to keep living like this.
They took our beloved ones from us.
From now on,
we have no other options, but to fight
to death against these infidels.
We are not banished,
until the winter is over.
We are banished to fight until we die.
Everyone should know this.
May God grant us with long lives
so that we can kill them all.
Turgut Alp is right. We shall not live
without combating.
How could you do this?
They've paid for their betrayal,
Mother Hayme. It had to be done.
Tugtekin, if you are this hard,
it is easier to break you.
How can you banish
Ertugrul's Alps just
because they infamized you?
Is that so easy to waste my gallant
boys?
They've given our enemies hell
for years.
How could you forget that?
Shame on you!
You did what was necessary.
I will talk to Hayme.
After all, she lost her son and her
nomad tent was destroyed.
She is in pain.
You captured one of the best
commanders of Noyan.
You walked all over them.
I am proud of you, my gallant boys.
If Ertugrul and Suleiman Shah were alive
they would be proud of you, as well.
And that is what matters.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you, Hatun.
You came back with victory.
However, you wasted your Alps
with your own hands, they say.
Hatun, it is good now that the two
nomad tents have become one.
We've trusted each other.
We supported each other.
And we won with God's will.
There must be a price for this, right?
And the first ones to pay the price
are your brother's Alps.
Do you know why?
Gundogdu, the ambitions which captured
us once
has captured this nomad tent
as well.
Be careful. It will not end
as well as we thought it would.
I wonder what the prices
we shall pay after Ertugrul's Alps.
My mother is waiting for me.
God.
You brought him back to me
safe and sound.
Thank you a thousand times.
Show him the right way.
Tugtekin Bey, you promised me
to avenge the bloodshed.
-That is true, I did.
-I've heard that you kept your word.
May you be happy in two worlds.
When the time comes,
I will plant Noyan's head
right in the middle of this nomad tent.
I will do it for you, Gokche Hatun.
I will make Bortlu talk, Mother.
Even If I would lose my human feelings
I will make him talk.
I will find out whether Abdurrahman
and Hamza are guilty or not.
I told my brother.
It will not be easy for the two nomad
groups to live together in winter.
But that is the right thing to do,
mother.
But what about the price, you will pay?
We cannot let anyone waste our Alps
easily, Gundogdu.
I do not know whether Abdurrahman and
Hamza are guilty or not, Mother.
However, if I dug my heels in, they would
execute Hamza and Abdurrahman.
They are both keepsakes of our father.
Executed I say!
What should I have done?
Should I revolt against Tugtekin?
It means that we would set off again
to find a place for the winter.
I decided to banish them
before anyone got hurt.
Do not forget this, mother. At any rate,
Tugtekin and his Alps risk their lives
for my brother Ertugrul.
We almost died, because
our Alps were misinformed.
We, two nomad tents share our destiny.
I'm not under my brother's command.
And you are not to take orders
from Tugtekin. Realize that.
I know that, Mother.
I do not take orders from anyone.
You should know that from now on,
I will do whatever I think is best.
I will take my leave.
Go and eat your meals.
I will keep watch.
Not to worry. I am here to rescue you.
How can you do this?
They should believe that
you escaped on your own.
Otherwise they will find out that
someone has sent Noyan a message.
Do not worry, Kocabash. Hurry up.
Save me from Gundogdu
and Tugtekin's tortures.
Not to worry.
Escape from under
the tent when you get a chance.
The back of this tent
is arranged for you to flee.
-Be careful.
-Do not worry.
Tugtekin Bey wanted to me to watch him.
Leave, Kocabash.
Do not torture this man.
If you punish him,
you cannot make him talk.
I am going to beat you so bad that...
...you will pray to God to stop breathing.
We all knew this is going to be rough.
It has been only two days.
Small things pile up like water drops
and it will be a flood
that all of us will drown in that flood.
You speak the truth, Mother Hayme.
Before the flood, we must find a way.
Water washes away but
land stands, Mother Hayme.
And we, parasites
do not understand it, Aytolun Hanim.
You will find a way for sure.
Selcan, my daughter.
Before winter comes,
we must go and sell our goods.
We have limited time but also
a lot of work to do.
From now on, Selcan will work
under your command, Aytolun.
I talked to women who put down their tool,
they will start tomorrow.
You made a right decision, Mother Hayme.
Kayi woman is proud, Aytolun.
They do best of their work but
know that if you humiliate them
you will do all the work on your own.
My brother's wife death worried all of us.
Because we loved her.
But you kept my brother alive.
You eased two sons' pains
who were killed by Mongols.
You are a skillful woman.
If you want us to be one and united
there will be a lot on your
shoulders, Aytolun.
Where is Sadettin Kobek?
I have been waiting him for days.
He sent his greetings.
Aleaddin Keykubat gave him a new mission.
So, he could not come.
He is ready to do everything.
He wants to be new ruler of Anatolia.
Look at me, Karabek.
I will give you one last mission.
Tell Sadettin Kobek
he would never promise coming
but not to do that next time.
Or I will make this lands his grave.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-Innkeeper.
-Yes, Bey.
-Do you have lamb?
-I do, Bey.
Bring each of us a lamb than.
Yes, Bey.
-Give Beys pilaf and ayran, it is on me.
-Yes, Bey.
Thank you.
But know that we, Alps, do not take gifts.
Are you Alp?
Who are you?
I am a merchant.
I bring goods from China
and India to Anatolia.
What do you do?
-We are...
...Kayi nomad tent's Alps.
Suleyman Shah's nomad tent.
How do you know our Bey?
I knew your Bey closely.
Then, come and sit with us,
share our food.
You are in safe hands, brave man.
May find peace.
-I must go.
-Stop, brave man, you must rest.
Where?
Lots of heroes like you were here, Bey.
Lots of brave men were shaped here.
Be patient.
If you are out of this hell,
all world shall scare of you.
I am out of that hell, Geyikli.
What if my mother...
...my brother...
...my lover...
...my nomad group...
...my Alps ould not get out of that hell?
What could I do then, Geyikli?
Pull yourself together, gain strength,
do not make haste.
Look how miserable we are, Geyikli.
We pay for our mercy in our motherland
and jackals attack us.
I swear...
...that my sword will be covered
with their blood...
...I will not let those tyrants
in these lands!
This my story, brave Alps of Kayi.
Why are you here, then?
We left our nomad tent
after we lost Ertugrul Bey.
So, you are alone like me.
Alright.
So, I have an offer.
Offer?
I travel and trade goods.
I struggle with bandits and tyrants.
Mongols routed the lands I travel.
The long and the short of it
I need brave and honest fellows
who will protect my goods.
-You want us as your men.
-No.
I want you to be my partner.
My goods lessen in every attack
and I lose some of them.
But you would be with me, I travel
without losing any of them.
So, my profit increases.
I share my goods with you
instead of losing them to bandits.
What do you think?
-Look.
We draw our arms to fall a martyr.
We do not draw swords and
give our lives for lucre.
We are also attacked by infidels,
you could fight to them.
And I give you some profit.
You will win in both worlds.
You do not understand us.
Do not waste your breath.
If we fight for lucre
our arms would be useless,
our courage breaks.
We are friends and let us
keep it that way.
The decision is yours.
The offer is mine.
Do not worry.
I am waiting for my father.
He said he would be here soon.
Your father is sad.
Mother Hayme...
...she is a good woman but she is
as stubborn as his late father.
If you want to command
two nomad tents Alps
and show that you are a great warrior
you must get along well with her.
And there is Gokce.
If you want to take that girl
to your bed sooner or later
you will ask for her permission first.
I will do my best for Gokce
but other matter is more complicated.
-What shall I do?
-You need to talk to her.
You are a young man who uses his tongue
as good as his sword.
She has just lost her son.
She would see Ertugrul in you
and lower her colors.
I think you must handle it quickly.
We are solving our problems
one by one with Tugtekin, Bey.
Right, Tugtekin?
You speak the truth, mother.
If you excuse me, mother.
Mother.
He could be right but he does
not object exiling Alps
and it sticks in my throat!
Mother!
We shall not forget who we are
and where we came from.
Kayis are not glorious as they used to be.
We suffered a lot.
Gundogdu brother did what is right.
Ertugrul's Alps will come back
when winter is over.
Abdurrahman and Hamza...
...truth will be revealed sooner or later.
Moreover, you and Gundogdu decided to give
commandership of Alps to Tugtekin.
Whatever, I am in over my head.
Gokce.
Bring food to Halime, she should eat.
Come on, my daughter.
Alright, mother.
Be careful about Aytolun
and Tugtekin, mother.
They want to poison my Bey.
As they want to poison my sister Gokce.
Gokce?
Tell Kobek...
...to persuade Sultan Aleaddin
to give tribute to Ogeday.
Or I will level these lands
with the ground.
Sultan would not agree that.
If Kobek persuades Sultan,
he would be next ruler.
Understood?
Peace be upon you.
Can I talk?
Yes, Hamza. Of course.
As I said, if he wants the goods,
he must pay the price.
Bring my offer to him, quickly.
Do not worry.
Come.
What is the matter, Hamza?
What makes you up late?
Does your offer still stand?
So, that is what makes our Alp up.
Look, Hamza.
I need brave men to protect
my goods and life.
Is it profitable?
More profitable than 10.000 sheep.
Are you in?
Hamza is missing.
What do you mean missing?
He took his arms and horse and left.
He must be around, brother.
Where will he go to?
I talked to innkeeper, he said Hamza left
with merchant early in the morning.
Bastard.
So, he decided to be servant
of that merchant.
Kayis are worthless now, Bey.
Ertugrul Bey was the last hope
of nomad group.
After he died, it is over.
They broke your heart, Hamza.
I have served to my nomad group
and Gundogdu Bey ever since
I could remember.
I fought countless battles.
I got nothing now.
I could not go back to my nomad tent,
Gundogdu Bey exiled me.
Even though he knows I am innocent.
He wasted me to ingratiate
himself to Tugtekin.
Take this lucre and
pull yourself together.
I will meet a merchant.
Wait for me in inn hill.
I shall come with you.
Merchant is coward, Hamza.
If he sees you, he thinks
I would seize his goods.
Alright, Bey.
Permission, Aunt Hayme?
Come. Come in, Tugtekin.
Sit down, Tugtekin.
I thought about what happened yesterday.
I understood that I acted
impulsively, Aunt Hayme.
But my anger was major.
I lost too many brave men, aunt.
I do not know how
but I know Hamza is a traitor.
If there were not Gundogdu brother...
So, what about Ertugrul's Alps?
They became rascals wondering
on mountains, aunt.
They are rascals after Ertugrul's death.
They disobey orders.
If I forgive them
I could not influence my Alps.
Whatever, we will talk
when winter is over.
When I look at you...
...I see...
...Ertugrul...
...in your eyes and your chin.
Permission, Mother Hayme?
Come in, daughter.
You asked for Gokce but she went
to Keltepe to pick up grass.
All right, daughter. Tell her
to see me when she comes.
Look, what happened to us.
First, our Bey fall a martyr.
Then our nomad tent was routed,
now our brothers are traitors.
Talk Abdurrahman brother, what happened?
I do not know, Turgut.
We captured a Mongol and made him talk.
We reported to our Bey.
You know what happened after.
Noyan baited us.
He set a trap.
That is what happened.
Mongols are treacherous!
If Ertugrul Bey was here,
he would find a way.
We must alert the nomad group.
Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-Another country heard from.
Do you know him?
I wish I had not.
Who are you? What do you do?
It is obvious that you had a trouble.
Come and let me serve you food.
Thank you, Geyikli. We are fine.
Go to your way.
Come, come. I have a gift for you.
-Where is Gokce Hatun?
-She went that way, Bey.
How are you Gokce?
I was passing by and saw you.
I wanted to ask how you are doing.
I am fine.
You should always smile like this.
When you are sad, I mumble.
I do not know what to talk to you.
That bad?
You could not imagine.
Noyan is coming! Noyan is coming!
Gather up! Gather up!
Where is Ertugrul?
He escaped, sir.
What do you mean escaped?
So, I would kill you first!
Ertugrul will die!
He will die even if I must sacrifice
whole Mongol army!
What about the Mongol trap?
Trap failed.
They captured Borklu.
What if he talks?
What if he reveals the spy in nomad group?
What if they learn where we are?
He will die, Noyan.
Kocabash will do it.
Look at me, Tankut!
I gave you a mission,
you screwed up everything!
If you fail me again,
I make dog food from your flesh!
Has not the infidel talked yet?
No, Bey.
Guard, where is Borklu?
Where is Borklu?
-He attacked behind and escaped, Bey.
Where does this madman take us?
This is not a good sign.
May god help us.
Gundogdu is chasing me.
Finish him.
Ertugrul Bey?