Episode 56 will start after 12:20 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
Stop!
As your Sultan,
I order you to drop your sword.
Child.
Do not forget you are
under my liege, Noyan.
Is that not right, Goncagul Hatun?
Sultan is right.
Even if 50 of your soldiers become one,
they would not match Turgut Alp.
I would like an Alp such as
Turgut Alp to be under my service.
Just as I want a strong soldiers
like yourself to be under my service.
My sword will serve you so well...
Sultan is right, Noyan.
We both know Turgut Alp quite well.
If he submits, he will be useful
for our Sultan's liege.
I would like to see a valiant man
as Turgut Alp in my army.
If he does not submit,
I, myself will do the necessary.
Is it understood, Noyan?
Then do it now.
To hell with you
and these ignobles that use you.
You became the shame of
Ertugrul Bey and Halime Sultan.
Shame on you!
Soldiers, take Turgut Alp and tie him.
Let his anger subside.
I will talk to him myself. Take him!
Did you write the letter
for the nomad group, Sultan?
It is just the request
of submission we wanted, Noyan.
Let us see what the Beys
will do when they read this.
We reached the end, Noyan.
Be a little more patient.
Give the letter to Kungur Bey.
Let him send it to the nomad group.
They tied both our hands.
I last saw him
when they took me out of the den.
He was shouting at them not to kill me.
I can still hear his voice.
Why did they put Yigit there, Dundar?
What do they want from him?
Noyan had no intention
to kill Yigit, Halime Sultan.
Keep your heart at ease.
You should know, Yigit is still alive.
How can you know that, Dundar?
Tell me. Speak.
I heard it when they took me,
they are preparing a feast for Yigit.
Dundar is right.
They will not kill him, Halime Sultan.
They will want to
use Shahzade as Ertugrul Bey said.
Yigit Alp will not allow it.
Halime, Gunduz is crying,
come and check on him.
How can this miserable man
who Ogeday discharged from his army...
....manage to get into this big of
a game with a few ravagers?
And how can he dare to use Shahzada?
Who is behind this?
We have to find out all of these.
Can you still not see who
is behind Noyan, brother?
Ameer Sadettin.
What are you saying, Tugtekin Bey?
I told you he saved my life.
I see you think
the way Ertugrul does, Tugtekin Bey.
I do not believe a word
Ameer Sadettin says, Sungurtekin Bey.
Unfortunately, the situation became more
grave than you addressed in your letter.
I came to know that three Turkmen Beys
submitted to Shahzada Yigit....
...as their Sultan
by the Ayyubids' instigation.
I have not even an ounce of doubt...
...that this group of revolters will
gradually increase and get wilder.
And unfortunately my dire suspicions
about Halime Sultan and her husband...
...Ertugrul Bey coalescing with these
revolters gradually grow stronger.
Praying these doubts of mine
are nothing but a misgiving...
...I would like you to know that
I will go to Kayi and Dodurga Tribes...
...on the purpose of
examining the situation on the site.
As you addressed in your letter...
...it will be good for you to come to
Erzurum with your army, at all costs.
Come then, Sultan Aleaddin.
Come, so you may
fall prey to your loyal dog.
Your horse and
your soldiers are ready, his Ameer.
Very well.
His Ameer, you called for me.
This letter will be conveyed
to Sultan Aleaddin immediately.
And tell Merchant Abdullah
to meet me in the place.
As you wish, Ameer.
See what fate can bring, Goncagul Hatun.
I, mighty Noyan with stormy
Mongol blood running in my veins...
...am yielding to an infant in arms.
Shahzada Yigit will bring us
Ertugrul, his brothers, his mother.
Then we will knead our anguish,
our venom with their blood.
Be patient a little longer.
Be patient a little more, Noyan.
And you?
And you, Goncagul Hatun?
What about your game?
What does Sadettin ask from you for me?
What did he promise you
as he promised to Tangut once?
Tell me.
To hell with that ignoble, Noyan.
He is frightened by you, Noyan.
He wants to know every step you take.
He does his best to learn
when you will stab him on the back.
A clever man like you
surely knows these, Noyan.
Do you think of me as stupid to not know
Kobek will kill us both when time comes?
I have no one
but you on this earth, Noyan.
Do you not know that?
Why, do you think Sadettin went into
such a dangerous way to kill Ertugrul?
I know Kobek well.
He thinks he is using
both of us to kill Ertugrul.
Yet, this is not his real matter.
Ertugrul is the hero
for both nomad groups.
It is time he gets a taste of defeat.
To one, the biggest strike
comes from his brothers.
What if I saw discord
among Ertugrul's brothers?
If he only desired to kill Ertugrul...
...he would have
already done it with his army.
What is his matter then?
Let it be your duty to find it out.
We shall learn so we can know
which soup's seasoning we are.
Sadettin's time will come, after Ertugrul.
Whoever betrays Noyan will pay
the heavy price of his betrayal.
I wanted you to know that.
Then?
Do you know how did
the khan of the khans, Cenghis Khan...
...form such a big worldwide
state on the vast deserts, all alone...
...even though he was
betrayed so many times?
That is the path God commanded me.
Whoever walks with me on this path,
I will bring the world to their feet.
Noyan.
Ameer Sadettin sent word.
He would like to see you.
Let us see what he wants this time.
Ulubilge, keep the boy sweet.
And Turgut may live for a few more days.
Turgut was not alone when he came to den.
Ertugrul and his Alps
will attack tomorrow morning.
Let us not fail in showing them
hospitality when they arrive.
He made Noyan kidnap Dundar and Yigit.
And he deceived me
by handing me Dundar, is that so?
Exactly so, brother.
Ertugrul, I was by Ogeday's side
for years, I have seen many ruses.
Did this man get into
such dangerous games...
...only because you cut off Gumustekin's
head and laid his reputation to waste?
Why?
Why, Ertugrul? Why?
Why would he get into such games...
....when he could get you killed easily?
Tell me that first.
Do you know why Sultan does not
have any spies among Ogeday's army?
Because we both made a mistake.
We stopped Ameer Sadettin from using
Tangut, putting him in the army to spy.
That is what I am saying.
Why would this man down on us like
puerperal fever rather than killing me?
Do you think I never think about these?
You should know...
...Kobek's problem is not the reputation
he lost because of Tangut or Gumustekin.
He has a much wider range.
That is what daunts me.
And he wants to use
all of us for this range.
Can you not see that?
Open your eyes.
Ameer Sadettin is here, Bey.
Attend to his horses
and soldiers, Abdurrahman.
We will greet him before the marquee.
As you wish, Bey.
You should know, he came
bringing a new trouble on us.
-Ertugrul.
-I know what I am saying, brother.
As I know the shadow
how he covered your eyes with.
Luckily, I have a head enough to
know that I should not trust anyone...
...to the end in the palace,
except for our Sultan.
Let me do what is necessary.
Where will it lead to?
Will you come to your
senses when Kobek bites you?
Enough! For God's sake, enough.
I hate that ignoble as much as Ertugrul.
Let him come to our marquee.
Let us see what he has got to say.
Welcome, his Ameer.
Thank you, Sungurtekin Bey.
Tugtekin Bey.
Welcome, Ameer Sadettin.
Thank you, Dundar.
You must have things
to talk, if you excuse me.
May God bless him
to the ones he loves, to you.
Thank you.
Go ahead, his Ameer.
Halime.
I must hear what
Ameer Sadettin has to say.
I know, it is about my brother.
Halime.
Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat
found out Shahzada Yigit was kidnapped.
Himself wrote me a letter and
asked me to take measures urgently.
Shahzada Yigit is not
a threat to our state.
Shahzada Yigit's betrayal
is a grate danger...
...not only for the continuity
of state but also for all of you.
For all the Turkmen nomad groups.
Shahzada fell into the hands of
both Ayyubids and the Templars.
Yet, he did not become
an instrument in their game.
He always showed his devotion
to his state, to his Sultan.
They said the same for his father, too.
But as you know better, Shahzada Numan
submitted to Ayyubids at his last times.
He even attempted to rebel against state.
How is it certain that
his son will not be like him?
I have witnessed him standing straight
against the ones who wanted to use him.
And what if I say three Turkmen Beys
submitted to him by kissing his hand?
I will not believe it
until I see it myself.
I do not know Shahzada.
However, as far as Ertugrul Bey told...
...I do not deem it likely
he will resort to such business.
Water sleeps but the enemy never does.
Tugtekin Bey...
...it is apparent Noyan coalesced with
the revolter Turkmen nomad groups.
It must not have been hard
to deceive this poor boy...
...who wants to avenge his father.
Perhaps, that is why
Sultan heralded an edict...
...that contains Shahzada Yigit
to be killed on the spot.
And he is coming here with
his army to treat this matter.
Halime, please, sit down.
Halime, please.
Halime, please stop. Stop.
We have suffered many pains with you
at the Templars castle, Turgut Alp.
You have never hesitated
to sacrifice yourself for me.
I owe you my life, above all.
I could not find it
in my heart for Noyan to kill you.
Have you not had any lessons
from what you have been through?
How can you still claim sultanate
upon the word of this ignoble herd?
I was a child at that time.
I am not, anymore.
I know the time has come, now.
I will follow the path my destiny shows.
You are in great negligence.
I pity you, boy.
Your life does not worth as much as
this wood under my feet, Turgut Alp.
The day has come, fate is upside down.
I will bereave the reign I deserve from
Sultan Aleaddin, my father's murderer.
You should know my words.
If it continues like this...
...you should know that your death
will come from Ertugrul Bey's hands.
He, too, will submit to me when
the time comes, Turgut Alp.
How come Noyan suddenly came across them?
How did they know they returned?
We will find it out together,
if you help me in finding him.
Do you want us to bring Shahzada Yigit
to you for you to slain him?
As I see, neither you nor Tugtekin Bey
respect my or Sultan Aleaddin's words.
Despite everything, I came here
trusting your loyalty to the state.
Perhaps, I made a mistake.
Now, I am asking you for the last time.
Is there anything
you know but keep from me?
No there is not, his Ameer.
We learned whatever we know from you.
I hope you are right, Sungurtekin Bey.
And I understand you, Ertugrul Bey.
You reproach a betrayal
as such to Halime Sultan's brother.
Halime, what are you doing?
However, past is composed of recurrence.
It is true.
Our past is extant
with glorious victories.
But it is also a witness to
many shahzadas' treachery.
And experiencing it again is negligence.
Maybe that is the reason why...
...every breath Shahzada Yigit
takes is a threat to our state.
My brother would not revolt
against his state, Ameer Sadettin.
Find Noyan, bring Yigit to me.
Halime.
May God bless your son to you.
May He let him grow up with his parents.
Bey.
A letter came from Turkmen Bey, Konur Alp.
The Alp who brought the letter
said that this was urgent.
What does it say, brother?
I am the Sultan, shadow of God.
I, the delegate of justice and equity...
...want Kayi and Dodurga nomad groups...
...to submit to me as many
Turkmen Beys who submitted to me.
Fight with me to rescue our state...
...from Sultan Aleaddin's torment.
Fight, so you may settle
in any place you wish.
The Sultan, shadow of God.
Sultan Izzettin Keykavus.
Yigit Alp wants Hayme Hatun
and Tugtekin Bey to submit to him.
Shahzada Yigit unashamedly deemed
himself worthy of the name Keykavus.
He renders himself as
God's shadow on earth.
This is a sin!
This is sin!
I was right again.
I wish I was not right.
But I was.
If you receive any information...
...you will let me know immediately.
The arrow has left the bow now.
The blood that will be shed
cannot stay in the vein.
Do not forget...
...who gets involved in this will share
the same destiny with Shahzada Yigit.
Ameer Sadettin.
You need not worry, Sungurtekin Bey.
Ertugrul will remember
his loyalty to the state, for sure.
But there is his love for Halime Sultan.
I am afraid he will fall to his weakness.
Sultan must have thought alike.
He gave you a mission
to kill Shahzada Yigit.
He wrote this letter to me.
However, I do not see
any harm in you reading it.
Read it.
We need to sort this out
before Sultan Aleaddin arrives.
Shahzada Yigit's head must be
taken to Sultan within a short time.
Or else many people will die.
You should know,
my door is always open to you.
May God help us.
His Ameer. Ertugrul Brother loved Yigit.
If he uttered words that
offended you, forgive him.
Do not worry, Dundar.
I know about everything.
You are the future of Kayi Tribe.
May God protect you.
His Ameer.
I hardly contained myself
to not to draw my sword...
...and cut that dog in half.
If it was not for my nomad group...
...for you, I would make
my nomad group merry with his carrion.
Its time will come, too, Tugtekin Bey.
Sooner or later, its time will come, too.
What about Sungurtekin?
He exceedingly confides Ameer's words.
It is evident, he will not see
the truth until Kobek bites.
Tugtekin Bey, I will set off
immediately to find Yigit, if you allow.
What will you do, brother?
Will you take the boy's life?
If necessary, yes.
This not only our matter.
It is a matter of the state's continuity.
Geyikli is here, Bey.
-He says he brought an important news.
-Let him come.
We found Noyan's den, Bey.
-Where is it located, Geyikli?
-It is at Dumanlıdag.
We saw three Turkmen Beys.
We followed them.
Mongols greeted them on the way.
They took the Beys to the den.
They must be the Beys
Ameer Sadettin mentioned.
He was right again.
-Where is Turgut?
-He is waiting for us there, Bey.
He is tracking how many
they are, where the watchmen are.
If we set off soon,
we will be there by night.
The ridgeway is too steep.
We cannot travel at night.
Geyikli is right, Tugtekin Bey.
Let us make our preparations,
we will take off at dawn.
Go to Dogan and Bamsi's tent. Rest.
And tell them to be ready.
As you wish, Bey.
Brother, I want Yigit alive.
I want to hear
the situation from him, too.
Promise me on that.
Sultan has an edict about Shahzada Yigit.
If you will act weakly, do not come.
We will talk about it when night comes.
If Ameer Sadettin did not ask for
Oghuz Khan's seal from my dad...
...they would be alive now.
He handed your father to Ertugrul's sword
when he wanted to kill me.
My only solace is, thanks to that mite...
...I have a real man like you, Noyan.
And what about the smart one, Gundogdu?
You would have been
his woman if these did not happen.
He will die like Selcan, Noyan.
I will kill them both.
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you, Bey.
Bey?
Sungurtekin.
He said Sadettin Kobek would not get into
such a big game only to get rid of me.
He is right.
I think alike, too, Bey.
Sadettin Kobek must have
another deal other than this.
However we should not forget,
Yigit grew up. He is matured.
What if he was mesmerized
by the sultanate throne...
...and his eyes were blinded?
I think Yigit is doing what he is
asked to survive, Artuk Bey.
But if the ones that tempted him
deceived him with a sultanate tale...
...the aftermath will be calamity.
God forbid, this would be
calamity for all of us, Bey.
And Kobek? What is his deal, Bey?
He said it with his own words
in my mother's marquee.
To bring Sultan Aleaddin to Erzurum
by using three imprudent Turkmen Beys.
And he achieved it.
My real fear is Kobek's target
being Sultan Aleaddin.
What are you talking about?
You said Sultan
was coming with his soldiers.
He cannot attempt
such a thing against Sultan.
Sultan's soldiers protect him
only from his enemies, Artuk Bey.
They cannot protect him from
his own ameer in Erzurum.
Then what will you do, Bey?
I will do nothing.
They will do what they will.
My part will be to go into
the trap they laid with my own feet.
They already enacted the death warrant.
They named my brother as a traitor.
How can they believe it, Selcan?
My brother would not fall
to the sultanate greed...
...with the instigation of a betrayer.
Do not worry Halime. The truth will
come out before Yigit is harmed.
What if they execute my brother
before the truth comes out?
Halime, your heart's fire
makes you say these.
Please, do not think bad.
God wiling, you will
regain your brother unharmed.
If God permits.
God, bless my brother to me.
Is there permission?
Come in, Ertugrul Bey.
What kind of games are played
upon my brother, Ertugrul?
I cannot understand.
It is obvious that Kobek
is using Yigit for his aims.
And he has Noyan
in his palms, playing with him.
We will not stand idly while
they are setting these traps for us.
Keep your heart at ease. I will save
Yigit from those carrion crows.
There is not one trace of Yigit,
Ertugrul. How will you do it?
I found Noyan's den.
What are you saying, Ertugrul?
Ertugrul Bey, Mother Hayme
and Gundogdu Bey are coming.
-Welcome.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Welcome, Bey, may God heal you.
-Thank you.
Welcome, Bey.
-Welcome.
Gundogdu!
Are you healed?
-I am fine.
-Thank God.
-Mother!
-Daughter!
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
-Mother!
-Dundar!
Son!
My son!
-Welcome.
-Thank you mother.
Thank God.
My boy has become an Alp!
-God bless, brother!
-Brother.
-Welcome, mother.
-Thank you, son.
They said you were ill.
-I hope you are alright.
-Who said it?
Whoever said it lied, brother.
I am rock solid. Thank you.
Brother.
-May it be gone, brother.
-Thank you, brother.
How is my daughter, Halime?
We had a son, mother.
We named him Gunduz
as my father bequeathed.
God bless, brother!
-Congratulations.
-Thank you, brother.
Congratulations. May he grow up
with his mother and father.
Amen, mother.
Thank God! Now our marquee will be
merry with the voice of our children.
If God permits,
our children will grow up together.
-If God permits.
Thank God.
I should hold
my grandchild in my arms now.
Mother.
Noyan laid an ambush
while the boys were coming back.
I was there, too. I could not stop it.
Noyan kidnapped Dundar and Yigit.
Welcome, mother.
Brother.
Ameer Sadettin rescued Dundar from
Noyan's hands and gave him to us, mother.
I am fine mother. Do not worry.
And Yigit?
He is in Noyan's hands, brother.
Halime.
Welcome, mother.
Gundogdu Brother.
Thank you, my child.
Congratulations.
May he grow up with his parents.
May God protect him from evil.
Thank you, mother.
May God bless, brother. Praise be!
Thank you, brother.
May my mighty God render you sacred.
May he continue your kin, your tribe.
May he keep you away from calamities.
May he render you beloved in both worlds.
May God not shear you from your father's
mercy, from your mother's affection.
Amen.
May benison reach
to my nomad tent with your arrival.
-Amen.
My God, who bestowed you to us
will hopefully bestow Yigit Alp, too.
Hopefully, he will return among us
in goodness and health, in no time.
If God permits.
We found Noyan's den mother.
Thank God.
If God allows, we will
pull Yigit out of this trouble.
-If God permits.
If God permits.
Was Turgut Alp alone when he got caught?
He was.
There certainly was someone else with him.
They must have already
sent a message to Ertugrul.
They will not venture to come at night.
They will attack my den
tomorrow when the sun is rising.
They will not find Turgut Alp there.
Then what?
They will attack with
a bigger rage to save Turgut like Yigit.
I have laid such a trap on them that
none of them will get out of there alive.
Ertugrul will die tomorrow.
Ertugrul's death does not
serve my purpose yet, Noyan.
What are you saying, Sadettin?
I tell you Ertugrul will die, you say
it does not serve your purpose.
I am tired of your secretive moods.
What crosses your mind?
Say it, so we know, too.
All three of us want Ertugrul's
head, there is no harm in it.
I will give you Ertugrul when it is time
for it. But everything has its time.
First, I want to mar the alliance
between Kayi and Dodurga nomad groups.
So, what is on your mind? Tell me.
While your soldiers are trapping
the Alps going to the den...
...you will kidnap
Gokce Hatun from the tent.
What will you do with
the Fiery Boy's wife?
Gokce Hatun will bring you Tugtekin.
Were you not taking oaths
you will extinct Ertugrul's kin?
Here is your chance.
You will kill Tugtekin,
who shares Ertugrul's blood.
You will kill him...
...so I can bring loyal Sungurtekin
to the position he deserves.
Turgut will be waiting in this area.
The den is here.
When Turgut tells us
where the watchmen are...
...and how crowded they are...
...we will attack the den.
We should leave the horses here.
It would be smarter to go on foot.
If Noyan notices we came,
we can never see Yigit Alp's face again.
We have to take him
from him unhurt, brother.
What will happen
if we take Yigit unharmed.
We cannot bring him here.
If we give him to Ameer Sadettin,
he will execute him right there.
What is necessary should be done there.
What are you saying?
Are you talking about killing him there?
Sultan's edict is evident, Ertugrul.
He will be executed on the spot.
There is no coming back
from this. Not for any of us.
We cannot endanger our nomad group...
...for a foolish boy
who declared his sultanate.
Brother, Yigit is Halime's brother.
We are not only going
there to free Yigit...
...but also to shatter Kobek's game.
You are still saying
the same things, Ertugrul.
You told us how both Yigit
and his father were made...
...a cat's paw
of the Templars and Ayyubids.
You have seen and lived all these things
and you still want to save that boy?
This boy announced his sultanate.
He asked for both my mom
and Tugtekin to submit to him.
Do you not see
they are using him, brother?
What does it change, Ertugrul?
Sultan Aleaddin is already
on the way with his army.
He is coming here.
For now, three nomad groups
resorted to revoltion.
Perhaps other nomad groups
will join the revoltion after.
Every minute, every day
Yigit is alive is a threat to the state.
Do not drag us to unpredictable ways
because he is Halime Sultan's brother.
-What I...
-Enough!
Enough!
Before one trouble ends, the other starts.
And you fall out with
each other as if it was not enough.
Ertugrul, Sungurtekin is right.
Yigit is not only a threat to
the state but to us, as well.
Do the raid
and wreck his den on Noyan's head first.
As for Shahzada Yigit,
since you do not trust Kobek...
...then you will surrender him to
Sultan whom we fought for, for years.
After that Shahzada Yigit's life...
...will be left to
Sultan's mercy and justice.
His Ameer.
Welcome, Bogac Alp.
We will go somewhere
with Alps to raid in the morning.
But the Beys keep where
we will go like a secret.
I know where you will go.
But you will not go to raid with them.
What do you order me to do, his Ameer?
One last mission, Bogac Alp.
One more mission.
God willing, when we finish
this business, I will go to Konya.
I want you to come with me
and be under my retinue.
However you deem fit, his Ameer.
Then you will hand over
Gokce Hatun to Noyan.
Noyan?
Do not worry. Noyan now knows
whose side he will fight, as you do.
He chose to be
a loyal servant of state as you.
-I am at your service, his Ameer.
-Very well.
What would you like me to do?
First...
...you will find an opportunity
and enter Tugtekin's nomad tent.
Sit down.
How are the preparations going?
You will set off before
the sun rises, Sultan.
Your loyal Beys will take you
to your auspicious army.
And my soldiers will
accompany you, Sultan.
Many valiant men who are ready to die
for you are raring to see you, Sultan.
When Sultan Aleaddin comes,
yourself will take his head, my Sultan.
You will avenge your father's shed blood.
Kaya Bey of Kefersud
and Kutlu Bey of Harput...
...has set off with their Alps
to join your army, Sultan.
Your being has empowered us, Sultan.
May God bless you to us.
Is there any news from
Sultan Aleaddin, Noyan?
We heard he set off
from Konya with his army.
Now it is time for revenge for all of us.
We will rescue Yigit Alp and make
Mongols scarcer than hen's teeth.
Then we will migrate to Byzantium
border with our minds at ease.
Even though the conditions
are arduous the time to migrate has come.
No matter how arduous
the conditions are....
...there is always
a solution for us believers.
Let's keep our hope abiding, brothers.
Where we will migrate to
will not be a palace, brothers.
Many troubles will pursue us there, too.
Brother, as long as
the love of God is within us...
...is there any palace
more divine than heart?
Thank you, Bamsi Brother.
-God bless your hands, Banu Cicek Hatun.
-Enjoy, Dervish Ishak.
God bless your hands, sister.
Thank you, Bamsi Beyrek.
God, we are grateful to you
for the food you give us.
Feed the hungry, the helpless,
the orphan and the homeless as you fed us.
God, do not test us with hunger
and put to the proof with fullness.
Make us of the ones
who appreciate the food you give.
And render us of the ones
who are always grateful to you. Amen.
-Amen.
Where are your thoughts lost in?
I am talking to you.
What are you thinking about?
Brother, I was thinking about
the beauty of being grateful.
The man who knows
to be grateful, knows himself.
Who knows himself, knows God, brother.
Who knows his God,
sees and knows his helplessness.
With that he becomes always grateful
to blessings God gives, brother.
Thank you, Bamsi Brother.
I saw your excitement when
Halime Sultan gave birth to her son.
Your joy when Ertugrul hold his child.
Ertugrul Bey has been a brother to me.
And Halime Sultan
has become my sister now.
And their child is
more than my own child.
Gokce.
You told me, I taught you
to love and to be loved.
Why me?
You taught me to love, Bey.
You taught me not to be
a foolish child but a real woman.
Thus, it is you.
Even though you hate me...
...even if I don't have as much worth...
...as the dust on your boot...
...I will love you until my last breath.
If it is in my destiny
to love and not to be loved...
...I will bow to my destiny.
Gokce.
Even if you cannot give me a child...
...always give me life.
I feel your pain in my heart, Halime.
Be it my oath,
I will not make your brother a prey...
....neither to Noyan nor Kobek.
I will burn down
Noyan's den and save him.
I have not an ounce
of doubt on it, Ertugrul.
I remember how you
saved us from  the Templars...
...as if it was yesterday.
Yet...
Why quiet, Halime?
It is different this time. The ones
who think of my brother as a traitor...
...desire his flesh,
his blood like hungry wolves.
What if...
...Yigit wants to become
Sultan by his own will?
What are you saying, Ertugrul?
How can you deem it likely
Yigit would fall to such negligence?
Let's pray he did not fall
to such negligence.
Or I have to surrender him to
Sultan with my own hands.
If he did such a thing,
it is my duty to take his life.
Bey. Tugtekin Bey.
The horse is foundering.
It obviously hurts.
It cannot ride.
What is it, Bogac?
What is wrong with the animal?
Bey, it was fine when
we left the nomad tent.
But now there is an oddness.
Bogac, return to nomad tent.
Do not be a burden to us at war.
As you wish, Bey.
Artuk Bey, the ointment you asked
me to make for Gundogdu Bey's arm.
-Here.
-Thank you, Dervish.
Dervish Ishak,
may God be pleased with you.
You suffered so much for me.
Do not withhold your prayers from us.
No need to mention.
God is the one giving both
the trouble and the cure.
Thank you.
-If I may be excused to leave.
-You are excused.
-Here, Selcan Hatun.
-Thank you, Bey.
The furuncle is almost dry.
The head doctor
in Erzurum showed his skill.
-Your arm is getting better.
-Thank God.
I have almost regained my strength, too.
I would like to be at war
with my brothers in short time.
Do not worry, Bey. What you said
will happen soon, if God permits.
If God permits.
However, I do not see Ertugrul's and
nomad group's condition as too well.
Rest assured, Bey. Just as how
Ertugrul Bey succeeded before...
...he will do all he can after this, too.
Surely, surely Artuk Bey but this time
the continuity of the state is in danger.
Ameer Sadettin coming to the nomad tent,
Sultan Aleaddin knowing it...
...gathering his armies, setting off...
These are not good signs.
Moreover, my brother
renders Ameer Sadettin...
...as his enemy rather than Noyan.
This is no good.
Geyikli.
Are you certain it is here?
Yes, Bey.
Turgut Brother said
he would wait for us here.
Bey. Or is what I think...
What is it that you think?
I do not understand.
They captured Turgut, Bamsi.
Turgut Brother.
Turgut Brother!
What is it, brother?
They have Turgut, brother.
He said he would wait for us here.
He would have come forth
by now if there was not a trouble.
There is no time to lose then.
Let us hit the road quickly.
If Noyan captured Turgut,
it means he knows we will come, too.
There can be traps everywhere.
Let us move carefully.
Okay.
Our beloveds will return safely, Halime.
If God permits,
they will bring Yigit Alp, too.
If God permits, Gokce.
I want you to find peace,
be happy with your son now.
All together, Gokce.
Altogether, if God permits.
I have treated you
badly many times in past.
And I hurt you many times.
Forgive me, will you?
Come.
I do not have
one sibling anymore, I have three.
May God unite us with
the ones we love, Gokce.
May he save them from war, from captivity
and destine them to come to us safely.
Amen.
So you are out hunting, Fiery Boy.
You do not know that
you will be the prey and lose your wife.
Do not draw. Let them pass and go.
Let us rest here a while.
Sit here.
We are close to Noyan's den, Bey.
The den is a little bit ahead.
He has both Turgut and Yigit.
Our one small mistake
may cost their lives.
Do not worry, Ertugrul Bey.
We must take them out of there safely.
That is what I want, too, Ertugrul.
First, let us reach to the den safely.
May God help us.
-Amen.
Come on, brothers, in the name of God.
Look at you.
You will be sultan...
...of this herd of ignobles,
in those shiny clothes, is that so?
Is this what you want?
Do not push my patience, Turgut Alp.
So you were weak, coward
and wretched like your father.
I curse the day
I saved you from the Templars, Yigit.
I will execute him myself before
my Alps who submitted to me.
That is enough.
I want to take to road and take
the rein of my army immediately.
Be ready. We are going.
Long live, Sultan!
Alps!
My God.
Help Ertugrul.
Do not withhold your help from him.
Render him victorious on this path.
Give him strength to save my brother.
Permission to enter, Gokce Hatun?
What is it, Bogac Alp?
Ertugrul Bey and Tugtekin Bey tangled
with each other. We separated hardly them.
What are you talking about?
Why did they fight?
We could not understand it.
-Where is Tugtekin Bey?
-He went to Duru Hatun's grave.
-Son, is there permission?
-Of course, mother, come in.
What are you doing?
I am tired of resting, mother.
We wanted to walk a while with Selcan.
It would be good.
What is it? I see you are distressed.
Go ahead, come and sit.
What is it, mother?
Last night, Ertugrul and Sungur's
situation saddened me quite much, son.
They went to raid our most thorny
enemy's den in that state.
I could not sleep a wink until morning.
Do not worry, mother.
They will be back unharmed.
And you know very well, Ertugrul
will always take his own way.
Yesterday, with you,
today, with Sungurtekin.
I always see discord among my sons.
What will happen tomorrow?
When we cast off this trouble,
what kind of trouble will find us?
Mother. Migration knocks on our door.
Ertugrul made it clear he may even
turn his back on headquarter's decision.
He will go to Byzantium border
on his own, if necessary.
Let's call a spade a spade.
Time to migrate has come for Kayis.
If necessary,
Ertugrul will set off alone...
...and many Alps
will set off with him, too.
It's better
if you prepare yourself for this.
And what if the headquarter
decides on going to Byzantium border?
What will you do then, son?
Mother, you know me well.
I have always respected
the headquarter's decisions.
But I do not think the headquarter
will make such a decision at all.
Ertugrul will go on this path alone and
he will drag many of our Alps with him.
You are all Kayi's power, son.
And its future.
I am ready to do anything to
keep four of you together.
We can go to the headquarter,
we can choose a new Bey.
The others will comply with whoever
will be chosen Bey at the headquarter.
Mother.
Do not think of these now.
Everything finds its own right path.
Among all these trouble.
Let's walk a little.
Let's visit my uncle and
Aunt Duru's grave and pray. Huh?
Where is Ertugrul?
Tugtekin Bey!
Bey!
Where are you, Bey?
Do not waste your breath
in vain, Fiery Dame.
Fiery Boy went to the den to kill me.
-But he will be a prey like you.
-What are you talking about?
The last I saw you, you were begging
to Ertugrul like a wretched lover.
What are you doing here?
We are swarmed with enemies.
I could not accept you leaving.
So, her name is Gokce.
You were a covetous dame.
You somehow managed
to become a Bey's wife.
You enchanted that Fiery Boy of ours.
And I will take
his head off, thanks to you.
What do you want from me?
Not you, I want Fiery Boy. Your husband.
Let's see how much he wants you.
Help me!
I should have been
with my brothers, mother.
I should have fought with them.
Its time will come, too, son.
You are an Alp now.
Ertugrul Brother is making a mistake.
Yigit betrayed us all.
He is a traitor as Sungurtekin said.
And not only us, he betrayed
to the state, to our Sultan.
I will not forgive him all my life.
What does my mother say?
She is trying for
the two groups not divide...
...but it will be hard with my brother.
What is it?
This has blood on it.
Bey.
They hid them behind the trees, Bey.
Mother.
This place is not safe.
We should go back immediately.
Dundar, go to the nomad tent
and gather the Alps here. Quick.
Do you think it's Noyan's doing?
Who else would do this vagary, mother?
Help me!
Gokce!
-Gokce!
-Hatun!
-Selcan, stop!
Selcan!
Help me!
Help!
Gokce!
Hatun!
Selcan, stop!
Gokce!
Selcan!
I have had enough of you!
Get her on my horse.
To the den!
Gokce!
Would you believe?
We met again, Selcan Hatun.
Let my sister go!
You are a vixen as always.
However, I need your sister.
Would you believe?
Everyone is here.
Noyan!
Check everywhere.
They might have left a trace.
They cleared the den.
Be careful.
They might have set other traps, too.
That Noyan dog did not
have the courage to combat.
Bey!
It's Gokce's dress.
There is a letter on it.
What does it say?
Fiery Boy...
...while you were dwelling at my den...
...your wife fell prey to me.
The war is starting now.