Episdoe 31 start after 12:06 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
It is hereby declare that...
...Dogan and Turgut
Alps will live in nomad tent...
...under the command of Ertugrul Bey
until the winter is over.
Also, Abdurrahman Alp will be jailed in a
cage until we determine...
whether he helped setting an ambush to
Tugtekin and Gundogdu Beys or not.
May the God Almighty save us from
making mistakes.
Amen.
May he give us strength to perform
headquarters' judgments.
Amen.
Do you have any words, Ertugrul Bey?
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul...
...will obey headquarters' judgments.
God may save us from paying
the price of your judgments.
Amen.
Yet I want you to know this...
...a brave man's stare
is sharper than a craven's sword.
When will headquarters end?
Why didn't you attend to headquarters?
We barely returned to nomad tent,
thanks to Ertugrul Bey.
How could I attend to headquarters?
Dogan.
I think judgments of headquarters
will not be good for us, brother.
Heaven forbid, Brother Turgut!
Bey?
Ertugrul Bey?
What happened, Bey?
They hurt us like no other.
Ertugrul Bey?
The headquarters is over.
Apparently, he is like a boy
whose toys were taken away.
You knew headquarters' judgment
would be good.
Apparently, Beys will not let Ertugrul to
get our nomad tent into trouble.
You have a poisonous tongue.
You are shameless beyond words.
I do not know what you are after
or what is your intention but
if you continue doing this,
I will make you pay for it, Aytolun.
-Sister!
-Gokce, stay out of it.
Your words hurt me, Selcan Hatun.
Future of our nomad tents is my concern.
Do you think that I don't know
you are a two-faced snake?
Look, I am silent for the sake of
this beautiful girl.
But do not push my limits.
What are you after?
What am I after?
She wants to poison us.
You, me, Halime.
She wants to plant her flag
in our marquee.
You... You are sick.
You are so sick that
you make everyone sick.
From now on, keep your words to yourself
in this nomad tent.
So that we can have peace.
I heard what happened in the headquarters.
Do not worry.
It is always stormy in winter.
Bey, I...
...made a huge mistake.
What mistake, my gazelle?
I told my mother that
your hand is ruined...
...and you seek vengeance when
you cannot grab sword.
I affected her judgment
in the headquarters.
How can you do that?
How?
I was scared that
I would never see you again.
I was scared that our baby would grow
without his father, Ertugrul.
If you are so scared that I would be a
martyr, you'd better never see me again.
And stop seein me as a man.
-Ertugrul.
You...
You are sick.
You infect everyone
with your corrupted heart.
You were only one who was against
headquarters' judgment, Wild Demir.
My thoughts do not matter, Bey.
What matters was what Ertugrul Bey said.
Ertugrul Bey said he would obey
headquarters' judgment.
You made a huge mistake by taking away
Ertugrul Bey's Alps and his position.
Can you take away the love of Ertugrul
in his Alps' hearts?
The duty of steel is to become sword.
Mares are trained to become horses.
And men are trained to become warriors.
If a man cannot grab a sword,
he cannot be an Alp, Wild Demir.
You wield a sword with your heart,
Tugtekin.
A horse is trained with love.
And an Alp is trained with conscience.
After all these years
you think that wielding a sword
and riding a horse makes you an Alp,
you are mistaken, Tugtekin.
Shame on you.
Wild Demir.
Wild Demir, know your place.
If you take me for a sword
you have forged...
...I will make you pay for it.
-Tugtekin.
If you cannot control your anger,
you will be led astray from your path.
Sit down, Tugtekin.
Sit down.
What is Ertugrul going to do, Gundogdu?
-He is like a crazed stallion now.
-So, we tail him.
We don't want him to cause trouble
for our nomad tent in his state.
That crazed stallion will run with all his
might to find a way out...
...or he will perish on his journey.
Then we should tame the stallion.
Tugtekin.
You are brave but you do not know
the one you are dealing with.
What am I trying to say is,
all rivers fall into the sea.
We have more urgent matters
to handle than Ertugrul.
-What happened, nephew?
-Uncle, winter is coming.
We are running out of food.
We need to get more wheat immediately.
You are right.
We can buy wheat from Armenian villages.
We have not sold our cattle yet.
Women must ready the goods
in the weavery.
We need to get our tribe
out of this state of war.
Our tribesman must get back to
their lives.
People are on the edge.
Let them have some peace.
The mission is yours.
Do what is necessary.
Yes, Bey.
I have good news for Noyan.
Dear mother, my dear mother.
Your son has lost his heart.
I fell in love with a beautiful woman.
I cannot confide my feelings.
I am helpless.
Brave man of the battlefield
has become a mute now.
I knew I would find you here.
Why did you bother to come here,
Gokce Hatun?
I wanted to talk to you alone.
Do you always visit your mother?
I always come here since the day
we buried her.
At least your mother has a grave to visit.
My parents do not have even a grave.
What happened to your mother, Tugtekin?
She died in my arms while
she was having dinner.
-May her soul rest in peace.
-Amen.
Why are you here, Gokce Hatun?
Well...
Ertugrul Bey's requests
were denied in headquarters.
Yes, they were.
Tugtekin, you must help Ertugrul.
Help him so you can move forward together.
Ertugrul never lets down his people.
He does not but Tugtekin does, right?
I did not mean that. You misunderstood me.
I think they did not do Ertugrul justice.
That is why...
-Enough, Gokce Hatun!
Always Ertugrul.
I cannot put my nomad tent in danger
because of his ambition.
He should have taken care of
his nomad tent
instead of spending time with his wife.
He should have been a real Alp to see
the trap laid by his traitor men.
Don't talk to me about Ertugrul
ever again!
Ever!
Alright.
What happened, Hatun?
Nothing, Bey.
Tell me, what happened?
I am scared that we are going to
perish in this place
when we are running away
from Mongol invasion.
Do not beat around the bush, tell me.
You rely on your uncle and
Tugtekin too much, Gundogdu.
God, give me patience.
Selcan, I do not rely on anyone.
But if Kayi tribe wants to live
and get out of this trouble
we have no choice but to live with them.
Aytolun manipulates your uncle
and Tugtekin but you cannot see it.
And this truth you cannot see
will be our end someday.
Where did that come from?
Gokce.
Aytolun wants to take her
under her control.
Like she did to your uncle and Tugtekin.
Gokce?
You are talking like this because
she is not with you anymore.
You are jealous because
she is close to Aytolun.
She is my dear, my sister. I raised her.
Selcan, you are talking like this
because she is an adult now.
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
You heard it, Hatun.
That is right, you raised Gokce.
But you did not just raise her,
you thought of her as your family.
You took her for your unborn child
and cared her that way.
What am I trying to say is
Gokce does not need you,
you need her.
-Enough.
-Is that wrong?
Enough.
You are doing this because
she is with Aytolun now.
Give her a break.
She lives in your shadow instead of
getting married.
Save your concerns to yourself.
I have more important things to do.
Sins of my past will never leave me.
Never.
What happened, Kocabash?
My horse threw me off.
Do you need help?
I can handle it.
Are you sure you did not fall of it?
That horse doesn't look like
it has a temper.
They say you are not the commander of
Alps anymore.
Looks like being the son of Suleyman Shah
or defeating the Crusaders...
...was not enough to save you.
In the end you are no more than a
pathetic Turkmen.
Apparently, you know that
I have a lame hand.
And your tongue grew bold.
-Take my life then.
I will take it when the time is right,
do not worry.
From now on...
...do not try to ride a horse
you cannot control.
Bey is not an Alp anymore, right?
Neither a Bey in headquarters,
nor the commander of Alps.
Mother Hayme and Gundogdu Bey.
How could they do it?
Everyone is scared that they won't be
able to stop Ertugrul Bey against Mongols.
-You summoned me, Wild Demir.
-I got something to tell you.
What happened?
Judgments were given about you
in headquarters.
Dogan.
Turgut.
You are under the command of Ertugrul Bey.
Any mistake would get our Bey in trouble.
Act accordingly.
What about me?
Your situation is more complicated,
Abdurrahman.
Take of your weapons
and give them to Alps.
-Do you hear yourself, Bogac?
-Dogan!
You must take an Alp's life
before you get his arms.
I will do it without blinking an eye,
Dogan. Tread lightly.
-Then come and get it.
-Abdurrahman!
Hand over your arms.
What are you saying, Father?
Wild Demir, please.
It is headquarters' judgment.
You will stay in the prison tent
until we learn if you helped Mongols
by betraying Gundogdu Bey
and Tugtekin Bey.
My Bey ordered me not to give quarter
if you resist.
-I will gouge your eyes out!
-Turgut!
Abdurrahman! Hand over your arms!
Hand them over!
What if his innocence cannot be proven?
Then he will die there.
Prison tent.
You have lost your mind.
My brother's innocence will
come to light sooner or later.
Then, you will pay for this!
Enough!
Abdurrahman! Enough!
You will pay for this.
Samsa!
The real conflict starts now.
Abdurrahman!
-Where are you going?
-Take care of my arms.
Where are you going?
To where I have to go.
Halime.
Halime!
So, you have cornered Ertugrul
with Mother Hayme.
Only now your conscience burdens you so,
Halime?
We said that it was not easy
to be the wife of an Alp
and you laughed at us.
This is as far as a palace girl can go.
Gokce.
Haven't you had enough?
Look at this.
You hate me.
How long will this go on?
I do not care about you, Halime.
I don't care about you being here
or not. Not even a little.
I am talking about
what you did to Ertugrul.
If you have a drop of conscience,
think about what you did with my mother.
Let me go!
The arrow that strikes the eagle is made
from its own feather, Ak Tolgali.
My mother...
...my brother, my lover...
...have stopped me.
They told me not to overstep my bounds.
They told me to stay put against a tyrant.
"You cannot hold a sword, stop dreaming."
they said.
And what did I say?
I will never bow down to the
order of this mortal world...
...and let these tyrants do as they will.
Never.
Son of Suleyman Shah does not give up.
He never asks for mercy.
All these lands you see are ours, Hamza.
The men who stood with us
has bathed in glory.
You are with glorious people.
But Kayi Tribe is my tribe.
They will be spared, Noyan.
We do not care about the herd, Hamza.
Our problem is that herd's shepherd.
We want you to be the shepherd this herd.
Mongols will not remain in these lands.
After we leave, you will shepherd
the herd on behalf of us.
You will be a Bey.
They cast Ertugrul out of headquarters
and took his status of Alp away.
Your tribe is on fire, Hamza.
We need to put it out.
I have put many fires out in the past.
But you will not touch the herd...
...after you take their shepherd away.
I swear on holy spirits.
The herd will be yours.
Hamza is in our hands.
But we have been here for so long,
why don't we hunt?
We do not hunt, because we want
our prey to grow fat.
So, they will be worth our while, Tangut.
Have patience.
-May it be easy, daughter.
-Thank you, mother.
Any words about Ertugrul?
No, mother.
He was like this when he was a kid.
He strived until he got what he wanted.
He would never give up.
Then, he would find a way to convince us.
Today, I saw his thirst for vengeance
against the Mongols in his eyes.
Nobody would endure that much agony,
yet he survived and came back to us.
If I had given permission to him
to fight with the Mongols
he would have perished along with his men.
I cannot endure this pain,
Halime, daughter.
I was scared, too, mother.
I was too scared to lose him
for the first time.
Every Bey in headquarters
fears the Mongols
yet none of them can say it out loud.
People are on the edge.
I hope Sultan Aleaddin will rush to
our aid with his army soon.
-If God permits.
-If God permits, mother.
If God permits.
Fortunately, Bamsi is not here
or we'd have to
deal with his craziness as well.
I wish we all could be like him.
All of this has happened because
we listened to the voice of reason.
I am tired of listening to the
voice of reason.
I have nothing to lose.
Tugtekin Bey called Alps
to the training yard.
Look at them.
How long do we put up with them, brother?
It is time to put you in your place.
Turgut and Dogan.
You are as stubborn as Ertugrul Bey.
You are reckless men
who do not know obedience.
Do not bother.
We have talked among ourselves...
...and decided that we are hopeless.
From now on, we are not Alps of
this nomad tent.
Since we are under
Ertugrul Bey's command
and he is relieved of his position,
we are not Alps as well.
Until he time he resumes command,
we will not take any order from you.
Who do you think you are to glower at me?
Alps, take them down!
Stop!
-Brother!
-I cannot let you do this, Tugtekin!
Sheathe your swords!
This is no battlefield!
From now on, none of the Alps will
draw a sword against each other!
And you!
If you are no longer Alps anymore,
leave this place!
Let everyone know that!
Turgut! Dogan!
Do not think about crossing my path!
You, too.
We will not show mercy to you
or the dogs would you put our trail.
Bey.
My uncle, Tugtekin, my brother
they all want to pass winter
by waiting for the Mongolian army.
They think Noyan will do the same.
But they are wrong.
How does a hand hold a sword?
How does a sword seek a hand?
You are alone, the sword is alone,
the nomad tent is alone.
The whole world is alone.
Less has conquered many in the past,
Geyikli.
We know how to snap infidels' neck
without swords as well.
Tell me, who are these infidels?
Do they reside inside of you?
All right.
They are inside and outside.
You and Abdurrahman will be my
biggest aides in this.
You said Abdurrahman was taken prisoner.
It is in my favour.
They took Abraham and
cast Josseph in a well
they crucified Jesus
exiled Moses to a mountain
but God granted them
strenght and they were saved.
Well said.
We will send Abdurrahman
to Noyan as a spy.
He will be Noyan's man.
What do you want me to do?
And what do I ask of you in return?
I want you to escort Abdurrahman
to Noyan's place.
What you want sounds nice
but seems a little hard to do.
There is no such thing for you, Geyikli.
Look who's talking now.
The one who is untrappable.
Thank you.
You pillaged everywhere.
You can't go far with this cruelty, Noyan.
This is not cruelty, Hamza.
We are merely giving an honorable death
to the people whose time has come.
How long will your campaign last?
Until Genghis Khan's children
will rule the world.
Just like the God is the
only ruler in the sky.
The world will know peace
and happiness on that day, Hamza.
You have many Turks in your army.
My mother is a Turk, too.
We are brothers on my mother's side.
Why did you attack Kayi Tribe?
To capture Ertugrul.
We were going to make him
the ruler of Anatolia.
But we found you now.
Do not forget, Hamza.
Only the blood can purify humanity.
Your anger captured you.
Give me a break!
Give me a break, mother!
Give me a break! Give me a break!
You must control your anger patience.
You must learn to use it
as a weapon for your enemies.
What are you saying, mother?
Ertugrul is here, among us,
in headquarters!
His Alps threatened me
in front of everyone!
They humiliated me! They challenged me!
I was silent to their arrogances.
I was silent for Gundogdu brother!
I was silent for my father!
Your anger prevents you
to see your victory.
You got rid of those irregular Alps
after Ertugrul.
Now it is easier to perish them for you.
You won a huge victory today, Tugtekin.
You won this victory by fling Ertugrul's
being one-handed in his teeth
and being silent to arrogance of his Alps.
You call this victory, mother?
Victory is everything which takes you
to your goal, Tugtekin.
Mark my words.
Now...
...Gokce will be last part
of your victory.
She did not call for us, she is coming
herself so we are wrecked.
Welcome, Mother Hayme.
Are you mentor of these
crazies, Wild Demir?
It was our decision not
to be Alp, Mother Hayme.
I raised both of you as my child.
How could you do this without asking me?
We made a mistake by not telling you.
But what happened to Ertugrul Bey...
Then, they came for Abdurrahman.
We are no good to anyone, mother.
-Forgive us, mother.
Just like fire grows with air
Alps trained by obedience in nomad tent.
You broke your traditions.
You gave your decision without
asking your Mother Hayme.
You could not be patient.
From now on, you are not a man.
Mother Hayme.
Wild Demir.
Do not break your traditions, too.
Do not discuss my words.
Bey, your hand is as strong as your heart.
It did not wear well to damages.
My hand and my heart could bear
Mongol tyranny, Artuk Bey.
But my nomad tent could not.
Do not think people are
as brave as you, Ertugrul Bey.
If anyone were you, you would be anyone.
Is this lame handed Alp
could grab a sword again?
I wish you heal with the name of God
and get rid of everything
that gives you pain
every evil eye and every evil person.
I hope you get better soon.
Thank you.
Why did you vote against me
in headquarters?
If I had voted for you
you could not have found me
in headquarters
when you needed me again.
Who are they?
They are the ones who will take your duty.
I mean, the ones want to obey.
-Duties?
They are Beys, officers and viziers.
Welcome before Noyan the representative
of great Ogeday.
If you were not perfect...
...I would kill all men.
But I would not kill women.
We are ready, Efendi.
My favorite scent is woman after blood.
I fit the horse with shoes, let it rest.
Thank you, stableboy. Thank you.
So, you are back.
We did not feel the absence of you
because of your Alps, Turgut and Dogan.
They are not Alps to be on your side.
They did it by challenging Tugtekin
in front of everyone.
They humiliated us.
Instead of worrying about these,
be careful about the danger coming.
Our nomad tent is under a treat
like it has never been.
There is a treat, you are right.
But the treat is you, my brother!
You and your rascal Alps!
I said I would obey headquarters
judgments, brother.
You were going to obey headquarters
judgments, tell me another one!
You did not obey your father's
headquarters judgments, do not fool me!
What do you want, brother?
If you want me go, I will go
without hesitation.
You put us in shit up to our necks,
now you want to go, huh?
What do you mean?
I mean, calm down and stay with your wife.
She did not have a good day
because of you.
At least, a winter would be
in peace in nomad tent.
-Tangut.
-Yes, Bey.
They will eat it standing.
They will.
Can they eat it?
They had better eat it.
Whatever, they are coming from away.
They may sit down.
Sit down. Sit down.
Enjoy it.
Tangut.
Yes, Bey.
The animals of Anatolia are delicious.
They are, Bey.
They did not give you food
in Aleaddin's palace, I guess.
Meat is delicious.
I cannot stop myself.
Have them all. Enjoy it.
Enjoy it.
Let us get down to business.
The Beys want to show obedience.
They want to be tied to Ogeday's state.
Is that right, Beys?
-It is right.
It is right.
Why do you want to be with us?
To be Bey and grow with you.
Because we could not stop you.
To be together and found stronger states.
I wish your Beys and Sultans
would be as smart as you.
We always need Beys like you.
Being with you is dangerous for us.
What do we get in return?
Return?
Bring it!
Open it.
Everyone will be happy.
Thank you.
Everyone.
Are you ready, Ulubilge?
If you betray to your own Beys and Sultans
you will betray me sooner!
Eat!
Eat! Eat!
We make Bey whom we want,
not the ones come to us.
Comprehend us fully, Hamza.
Know the value of it, Hamza.
Bring my food to my tent.
I know you are offended to me.
You do not share your troubles, either.
It hurts me more.
How could I be offended to you, mother?
I would sacrifice my very life to you.
Perhaps, I made a mistake.
When I gave my decision and
raised my hand in headquarters
other Beys raised their hands after me.
It is too late to think
about this, mother.
We got hurt.
We got hurt so much that
the nomad tent of Suleyman Shah
took shelter in another nomad tent.
My brother and you gave wrong decisions.
We had to, my son.
We had to.
Perhaps but
we will understand when you pay
for your decisions.
How could I let you to put yourself
and your nomad tent in danger
with this hand?
I am your mother.
Please understand me.
You are mother and Bey.
We must obey you.
But...
...I will do what is right for me.
Do not worry.
I will not stand against you.
But do not stand against me.
Or I understand I have no place
in this nomad tent and I leave.
Be aware of this.
When will Ertugrul Bey come
and talk to us, father?
Our Bey has his plans. Have patience.
Have patience? How long do we have
to bear this?
I could not bear anymore.
I heard that you are not Alp anymore.
We did it without asking you, forgive us.
Even we exiled from nomad tent
or get hanged, we are with you.
We want them know.
If we are together till the end, be ready.
Be ready for what, Bey?
First thing is freeing Abdurrahman
from caged tent.
Whenever you want, we are ready Bey.
But...
...it must be as if he escaped.
Then, Bey? What are we going to do then?
Have patience.
Bey, what do you want from me?
Make something
that would be armor to my hand
and give strength to my lame hand.
Bey, I will make something like a claw
that would wrap your hand.
You hold your zulfiqar with it and
you will take our revenge with it.
Leave us alone.
Bey, do not. Tugtekin Bey ordered.
He could talk to me, leave.
How could I go to Noyan
while I am in cage?
We will let you out.
Be ready and wait for it.
It is a good thing you are caged.
When you go to obey Noyan,
you will be more persuasive.
He hates not just me
but everything, everyone.
It is all my fault.
Do not wear yourself off.
We are all going through hard times.
Gokce, too.
She did not mean that, I am sure.
She meant it, mother, I know.
I took everything she got.
Her hopes, dreams of starting a family.
She cannot have a baby.
My daughter, do not worry.
I talk to her, alright?
Mother, Aytolun took Gokce
under her control
and poisoning her and I cannot
do anything about it.
Please mother, save my sister
from that woman.
Alright.
I will talk to her. Do not worry. Alright.
I collected goods of Kayi
remains from attack.
I will talk to a merchant tomorrow.
But as far as I heard
there is not much wheat left.
I do not think so.
They want to earn more
by saying there is less.
So, level them with ground.
Easy cousin, what are you saying?
You cannot fight all the time,
you must be a merchant sometime.
Gundogdu speaks the truth.
Nomads do not know pleasure of gold
while herding.
I hope you like our food, Gundogdu Bey?
I made them with my hands for you.
Thank you, Aytolun Hatun.
They are all delicious.
Mongols are going to attack us
like pack of dogs.
There are less nomads.
The women of day always spend time
with their husbands in bed
even if they do not give a baby, Bey.
In old times if a women
could not have a baby
she would bring another woman
to family to have a baby.
Also, the men of today have patience,
they do not divorce infertile women.
Tell the one who sent you here
Ertugrul Bey would kill me next time.
Good night, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Gokce.
Bey.
What they did to you in headquarters
was not right.
Even after what you did
for our nomad tent.
They gave an unjust judgment.
Thank you, Gokce.
I feel sorry for your hand.
I learned what that infidel
did to your hand.
May god curse those inglorious bastards.
I pray that I get hurt instead,
you get hurt.
I will pray for your hand
every night and day.
To grab your sword to take revenge
for bloodshed.
Hope for the best, Gokce.
Thank you for your prays, too.
What are you doing, Gokce?
We talked about this two years ago.
It is over.
Or it is not?
I wrote you in my heart
with fire, Ertugrul.
How could I forget you as long as I live?
How? Tell me how?
What are you saying, Gokce?
How could I bear to see you
in the same marquee
with my wife and child?
How could I live with you
like pangs of conscience?
Tell me!
How could you get this idea?
How?
Good night, mother.
You, too, my daughter.
Is Gokce alright, Ertugrul Bey?
Artuk said train until
you grab your sword.
So, train, Bey.
But that was not my question.
Gokce is alright.
I am sick of Gokce, Ertugrul.
She still loves you.
And she raised a scorpion in herself.
That scorpion will poison all of us.
We all know Gokce's scorpion.
But...
...I do not know who bite me
on headquarters.
How could you get this idea?
How could I bear to see you
in the same marquee
with my wife and child?
How could I live with you
like pangs of conscience?
Gokce?
Bey.
What are you doing here
in the dead of night?
I could not sleep, Bey.
You cried.
Enough. Give me a break.
Gokce.
I...
I do not know what happened to me.
Tell me if you need anything.
If you excuse me.
Bey.
Stay here.
Stay here with me.
I pulled you apart today.
Forgive me.
I wish only you pulled me apart.
Who pulled you apart, Gokce?
Tell me and I will bury them.
I have buried them, do not worry.
They cannot pull me apart from now on.
Do we have permission?
Come in.
I want to see Tugtekin Bey.
He is out and Korkut Bey is asleep.
Do you have something to say?
No, Hanim.
Tell me, Kocabash.
I can see in your face that
something has happened.
Ertugrul is up to something.
I do not know how to say it.
Tell me.
If it concerns our tribe,
it concerns me.
First he met with his Alps secretly.
Then he met with Abdurrahman
in caged tent.
He sent guards outside while
he was talking to Abdurrahman.
They are up to something.
Wild Demir is with them, too.
Listen to me closely.
I know you respect Tugtekin Bey.
Thank you, Hanim.
Likewise, Gundogdu Bey.
He has trusted you a lot
since you saved his life.
So, warn Gundogdu Bey.
Tell him that Ertugrul disappeared...
...and met with his Alps and Abdurrahman
tell him everything you know.
Open his eyes.
Open his eyes...
...so that Ertugrul will not harm
Tugtekin Bey.
Do you understand?
Yes, Hanim.
I understand very well.
No one shall know where I will go...
...or when.
What about me, Ertugrul?
You shall not know, too.
You will wait patiently.
I know your fight is not
just for our baby...
...but all Kayi babies.
That consoles me.
I shall pray for you every day.
I will grin and bear it.
They say patience leads to salvation.
Ertugrul, you need to talk
to your brother.
You must bring him to
your side whatever the cost.
Selcan is also very troubled.
All right.
I will talk to my brother
for one last time.
Do not worry.
Are you going to let him leave
like this, Baycu Noyan?
Yes.
Until he is lost from view.
He is wondering whether
I will keep my promise or not.
He must think that he is free.
What if he goes and does not come back?
Then he will die.
-To earn your friendship.
-Thank you.
Let your watchman to be around me.
Noyan's eyes are on you.
If you want to catch the big fish, Tangut,
you must use big bait.
Do not forget this.
Take them.
You are doing it wrong, move!
Gokce, what happened?
Why are you upset at this time of the day?
Leave me alone, sister!
Selcan Hatun, where is Gundogdu brother?
He went to a caravan to bargain,
Ertugrul Bey.
Gokce, did something happen
between you and Ertugrul?
Thank God, I come across a real Bey,
son of Suleyman Shah.
Thank God, we met.
Welcome to Erzurum, Merchant Ahmet.
I brought greetings and prayers
to you from Konya.
Peace be upon you.
My uncle Korkut and Mother Hayme
also sent their greetings to you.
Thank you.
Your caravan was raided,
I am sorry to hear that, Bey.
Thank you. May our friends saved.
Thank you, Bey.
Bey, that swine called Noyan is also here.
May God give you strength and patience.
If God permits.
-After you, Bey.
-Bey?
We took the security measures you asked.
You can be rest assured.
-Alright.
-After you, Bey.
Take care of the horses and the tribe.
Ertugrul!
Are you going to ironworks?
Yes, uncle.
Let us walk together, then.
I know that the situation
of your tribe hurts you.
It is unacceptable that the mission
your father gave to you...
...was taken by my son...
...and your sword holding hand's
condition.
But do not forget.
I am your uncle.
Your mother is my blood. So are you.
I want you to know that neither you
nor your siblings...
...are different from my children.
There is nothing to worry.
May God heal your hand first
and you come back among us.
What I say is...
...if we want to live in these lands,
we must pay the price.
We cannot deserve these lands
without blood.
Protect Halime Sultan.
Do not leave her alone.
Your baby will bring peace to
your mother and your tribe.
Do you understand me, son?
Thank you, uncle.
May God give you a long life.
In conclusion, we seek an honest merchant
who will not take advantage.
A man who will not overprice...
...because the Mongols are after us,
an honest man.
May God be my witness...
...there is no bazaar I have not been
between from Constantine to Konya.
Your animals are fat, your rugs are
vivid and people love them.
Thank you.
Your drapes are worthy of palaces.
Doing business with Kayi is
profitable for all merchants, Bey.
If God permits, we will have a deal.
I have no doubt about it.
If God permits.
So, if both sides are willing,
let us start with the help of God.
You must be hungry.
-Did Alps take their food, Kocabash?
-They did, Bey.
Thank you, so we can start.
With the help of God, enjoy.
What do you think about the situation?
I listen to many people in many cities.
I do not know how but it seems that these
bastards will not stop even in the winter.
They lay waste everywhere not caring for
even mosques and churches, Bey.
Seljuk does what it can
to protect its people.
These bastards want to wear out
the people so that they cannot fight.
We must stop the fear in people
who are paying tribute to Swine Noyan.
We must be their hope...
...so that those bastards
cannot ask for anything.
We have to stop the gold cupidity
of the merchant...
...who is supplying food
to the Mongolian army.
We have to, so that he knows that his hand
would be cut by us...
...if he takes their gold once again.
From now on, we do not have time
to wait for the enemy and defend.
We will attack that bastard called
Noyan and give him hard time...
...so that he will understand his army
cannot encamp here.
I will go and check the Alps, Bey.
-Bey.
-What?
I said, I will go and check the Alps, Bey.
Alright.
Be careful about the looming danger.
Our tribe is under a threat
like it has never been.
There is a threat, you are right.
But the threat is you, my brother!
He trusts me with his life.
I can kill him anytime.
Him and his lickspittle merchant.
Noyan said let them go to the tribe.
He has another deal
with the merchant and Gundogdu.
As Efendi Noyan wishes.
Accept this, Bey.
You have not taken our goods yet.
Why are you giving me all this gold?
To show how much I trust you.
Know that I will take the herd
and the rugs.
Go back to your tribe at ease.
Thank you.
I am profitable in this business,
I will take the goods.
I will give rest of gold
when I take the goods.
When the time is right,
I will get you out of here.
Your safety is our duty, do not worry.
With your permission now.
-Thank you, Bey.
-Good bye.
Good bye, Bey.
Wild Demir, you made us happy
when you accepted the mission.
-Thank you, Bey.
-God bless you.
-Amen.
Thank God we have an experienced
and strong ironsmith like you.
Amen!
Dodurga and Kayi tribes,
enjoy your new ironworks.
-Amen!
I start with the name of God.
With the name of God.
Dear God, accept our sacrifice.
Amen!
With the name of God.
God is the Greatest
There is no deity
worthy of worship but God
God is the Greatest
to God all praise is due.
There is no deity
worthy of worship but God
God is the Greatest
to God all praise is due.
There is no deity
worthy of worship but God
God is the Greatest
to God all praise is due.
With the help of God!
Why did you do this?
What changed your mind
and you opened the ironworks?
Bey, whatever I did...
...I did for Ertugrul Bey.
Thank God, we handled this, as well.
-You did well, Bey.
-Thank you, Kocabash.
The poor will be happy at last.
Every man has a different way
of handling the matters.
This is mine.
Do you know why?
If people are always on war,
one day they get fed up.
Tell me, what do Dodurga Alps
think about this?
Our Beys reasoned out and
gave the right decision.
No one has a doubt.
But Ertugrul Bey...
...and his Aips, Turgut and Dogan.
What happened to them?
Ertugrul Bey is a great Alp.
Everyone knows his fame in Rumelia.
But our Alps are anxious.
Why are they anxious?
They are anxious that he would cause
a discord within the Kayi Alps...
...and that they would not obey
the orders in the battlefield.
As it happened yesterday.
Then, Ertugrul Bey...
What? Tell me, what happened to Ertugrul?
You have not heard it from me
but he is up to something.
-What is he up to?
-With his Alps and Wild Demir.
I saw him entering
Abdurrahman's tent yesterday.
He sent everyone out while he was
talking to Abdurrahman.
He mauled the guard as well.
After he talked to Wild Demir, Wild Demir
got to work and flared up the furnace.
I would like to be alone.
Alps, come on, with the name of God.
Where did Ertugrul go?
He asked for Gundogdu and left.
What happened, mother?
I do not know, my daughter.
I have a strange feeling.
Anyway.
-How is your work, my daughter?
-Thank God, it is good.
We are trying to catch up with schedule.
-If you want, I can show you the goods.
-I would love to.
How are you with Aytolun?
We are staying away
from each other, mother.
Come on, sit down there.
Girls!
Bring the new drapes,
Mother Hayme wants to see them.
Come on.
What are you trying to do, Ertugrul?
Do not say our tribe and future.
Talk openly. What is your problem?
I want to talk you alone.
Did the dog of Tugtekin
who tails me told you those?
He tailed me all night and
talked to his owner then you, right?
Yes. Do you know why?
Because all the tribe is scared that
you are going to put us in danger!
Your mother, brother, wife!
Our tribe, my uncle's tribe
which we take shelter in!
Noyan will not hibernate
all through winter, like you.
He will not wait for
Ogeday's army, brother!
There are thousands of Mongols
on the frontiers of Seljuk!
What should we do?
Attack them with a handful of Alps?
There are so many people
aiding and abetting Noyan...
...and betraying to their people in
Seljuk lands that you would be surprised.
They are all helping to Noyan.
We have to stop them!
-So?
-We can make Noyan suffer!
We can leave him breadless all winter!
I saw how they live. If we cut the ways...
Then what?
They will attack the tribe again!
They will ruin everything!
Then we will suffer!
We only have one shot.
And we will use it all together
when Aleaddin's armies come!
You must understand and see the truth!
You will lose this war,
Tugtekin is just a boy!
He is brave yet arrogant and weak!
Do not concede to him!
Do not be with them
because you feel in debt...
...taking shelter in my uncle's tribe,
like my mother!
Open your eyes and look around!
Two tribes are waiting like
sacrificial sheep!
The butcher is coming!
He has spies everywhere!
You have lost your mind.
That is not possible.
It is possible.
We can do this, believe me.
How?
Let us talk to our mother.
She is old, now. You would be Bey.
Be the Bey.
We have to start this war.
Only you can do this, not my mother.
We cannot start resurrection of Kayis...
...by taking shelter
in our uncle's tribe.
You have the power to do this, brother.
You have to put yourself together
and look around, brother.
There is no war.
There is no war!
I do not want people to die.
You are a coward, brother.
A coward.
Yes, I am a coward!
I am a miserable man who accepts to be
a coward in order to...
...protect the unity of our tribe
which was entrusted to us by our father!
What about you?
You are a devil who does not think about
the lives that would be lost!
The tribe is messed up.
Sons of a Bey are
fighting with each other.
If I cannot save the Kayi tribe from you,
let my life become hell.
Hit me, brother.
Hit me until you knock me out.
If it would remind you who you are,
punch me until you knock me out.
where you came from...
...and that you are Suleyman Shah's son,
take my life, brother.
Do you remember, brother?