Episode 30 will start after 12:03 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
I brought your Alps, brave man.
With the name of God.
God, save us from evil jinn.
I told you Geyikli is wicked.
Did not you recognize your Bey?
Ertugrul Bey?
Is this really you?
Poke him.
Not me!
Bey, this is you.
-Yes, this is me.
Our Bey is alive!
Bey is alive! He is alive!
Bey is alive!
Turgut! Dogan!
-Bey, thank God, you are alive!
-Thank God!
Bey! Bey! Bey!
Easy! Easy!
You will make my Bey regret he is alive.
-Bey!
-My lions!
Bey!
Bey, thank God, you are alive!
I will make you pay for
what you did to me, Gundogdu.
If we kill him, Noyan may forgive us.
-Us?
-Yes.
You are the one who failed, Borklu.
Noyan will kill all the men
because of your awkwardness.
The long and the short of it, Tugtekin
is commander of two nomad tents' Alps.
Hamza could not stand to
Tugtekin's slanders and left.
I am talking about an army which is
vandalizing from Russia to Persian towns.
A wild herd that will make us
hanker for Crusader Army.
My brother and my mother
gave the right decision.
There was no other way.
We must be united.
About other problem, it is a mistake
that you are exiled.
Tugtekin is young, he made a mistake.
We will do what is necessary.
So, you talked about everyone.
How is Aykiz sister?
Aykiz...
...fell martyr.
They burned her alive...
...while she was fighting.
Seven Iron?
He dug Aykiz's grave by his own hands.
He only had Aykiz in this world.
And she has gone to another world.
His look, his talk and everything
he does have changed.
You prolonged my life, brother.
May God bless you.
Thank you, Bey.
From now on, Halime will stay
in my marquee.
Also, Gokce will sleep in my marquee.
As you wish, mother.
Are you worried for her baby, mother?
Do not worry,
I have eyes only for her, too.
Gokce and Halime, they are both my sister.
Her child is my child.
I will not let anything bad happen
to her and her baby.
It is a miracle that her baby
is still alive.
Come on, my daughter.
You shall go to your work.
They slaughtered even women and children.
They thought our women
would have been afraid and surrender.
Our women fought like Alps.
Bey.
Know that, if we do not make those
inglorious bastards pay for it
I will be ashamed of being a man.
Turgut Alp
we cannot drink or eat anything
until we make them
pay for bloodshed they did.
What happened to Kayi
will happen to all Turkmen tribes.
If we do not stop these tyrants
we will lose Anatolia.
How will we fight back to Mongols
who brought all world to their knees?
All the world groans bitterly
by the tyranny of Mongols and Crusaders.
If we are afraid of those tyrants
if we do not stop them
what shall oppressed people do?
If we do not stop tyranny,
we will not be Alps, Bey.
We could only be Turk,
if we do not knuckle under tyranny.
We could only be Turk
if we fight infidels.
We could be Turk if we are
a hope to the oppressed.
What are you thinking of, Bey?
We will fight until we perish,
until we die.
Gundogdu Bey!
Calm down Selcan, I am fine.
How could you say that, Bey?
You are wounded.
Mongols attacked him near the plain.
Now he is fine, Selcan Hatun.
If Kocabash had not been there,
you would be mourning for me now, Hatun.
From now on, he is my brother.
Know that.
Do you know why you are not
speared to these logs, Tankut?
It is not the things a man has
that makes him weak
but the things he wishes for.
You must learn to not give up
and sleep as Ertugrul does.
It was not possible to pass
all guards and escape.
But he escaped.
If you sleep or doze off
the fork will pierce
both your chin and chest.
If you survive you will regain my trust.
It will not be easy to catch him again.
-We will attract his attention.
-How?
I have a very powerful tool to do this.
I am grateful to you, brother.
You took my nomad tent under your wing.
You re-erected my husband's marquee.
May God bless you.
If God permits, both nomad tents
will grow together.
If God permits.
If God permits, that would happen.
But Mongols coming near our nomad tent
trying to kill my nephew
is not acceptable.
Is it, Tugtekin?
Uncle...
...if jackals attack the nest
the wolves, of course, lay an ambush.
Do not worry.
From now on, neither Dodurga
nor Kayi Alps will sleep.
I gave orders to Alps, father.
I punished the faulty ones.
From now on, we will keep a sharp lookout
in the nomad tent. Do not worry.
Mistakes are made once, son.
Repetition is foolish.
We have no right to be foolish, uncle.
I mean, going after head scarfed
was my fault.
A momentary inattention
can cost our lives.
Dodurga and Kayi Alps and
your nomad tents will be of
one heart under Tugtekin's command.
After late Ertugrul's unskillful Alps left
there is no one left in nomad tent
who has bad intentions.
They did not leave, Aytolun.
They will come back to their nomad tent
when they are done being a guest.
Moreover, they are my sons.
I raised all of them.
I have no pity on them
for my nomad tent's unity
but it does not mean I give up on them.
All the Alps are our sons, Mother Hayme.
But yours is not being a guest.
Oghuz tribes are welcomed
in each other's tribe.
Some of us treat our Alps
like they are step-children.
You and Gokce are step-children
of Mother Hayme, Selcan Hatun.
But she treats you like her own children.
Moreover, she married you
with her own son.
She loves you more than her daughter.
Know that, Kayi Alps are our own son, too.
Give me bread.
We need to learn Noyan's intention.
If we do not know what he is planning
he will cause us trouble sooner or later.
According to news coming from Konya,
Sultan Alaeddin was gathering an army.
Sultan Alaeddin's army cannot be here
before winter ends.
So we need to be cautious.
We need to prepare winter storage.
Mongol fear captured every soul
even before they fought with them.
That is why we need to keep
our eyes peeled.
We should not hasten.
What happens if we crack down on Noyan?
If we crack down on Noyan
we will be miserable
even in the very first battle.
Our mothers, daughters
and sisters will be miserable
in infidels' hands.
They will also destroy the nomad tents.
That is why, we will act smart.
We will wait for Sultan Alaeddin's armies.
When the enemy comes and takes his child
whom a man cannot take his eyes off
the spirit and the body he carries
will be a burden.
If God permits,
May god meet you in paradise.
Amen.
It condoles me that Aykiz is a martyr.
I always tell
I wish I had a thousand sons
and all of them would be martyr.
When are we going to
defeat Mongols, Wild Demir?
It is allowed to Oghuz to
get out of this in one piece?
We have an enemy worse
than Mongols, Artuk Bey.
-Who is that enemy, Wild Demir?
-The instigation among us.
Instigation and its fire.
It burns me out, Artuk Bey.
I also see that fire, Wild Demir.
I also see it.
But I cannot talk about it.
If we do not put out the fire
it will burn us all one day.
Artuk Bey, Halime Sultan!
We are here.
Noyan's army is at beginning of precipice
where Pasinler plain ends.
His other soldiers from Georgia to Kars,
from Kars to Ahlat
as two large springs are waiting for the
war to be made with Sultan Alaeddin.
Why are they waiting, Bey?
If they are so strong
why would not they finish us already?
Ogeday attacked China with the
largest army the world ever seen.
They are fighting in China
with all their powers.
They do not want to open another front.
So after Ogeday ruins China
he will come for us.
Break out! A big storm will break out!
Rivers will babble blood,
the mountains will bleed
there will be blood on roads, blood.
Even if they move mountains
and make dungeons in it
they shall not stop the light
of God, Geyikli.
Be at ease.
What are you thinking, Bey?
We would be hard on their trail in winter.
Noyan's wretched face
must not see the springs.
We would finish them off
before their soldiers help.
Bey, what about your brother, Sungurtekin?
What if what Noyan said is true?
What if he is at service of Ogeday?
These is a secret among us for now.
When we go back to nomad tent
I do not want my brother and my mother
to be sorry because of this news.
Is it understood?
It is understood.
What if what they said is true?
If what they said is true
if my brother knuckled under Ogeday
I will break his neck
otherwise my father shall not
find peace in his grave.
Ertugrul.
Bring water from the cold well.
We must bring down her fever.
What is the situation, Artuk?
I did my best, Hayme Hatun.
We will lose either the baby...
...or both.
All I wanted was peace.
God.
God, get us out of this trouble.
God, give us peace.
First, Sungurtekin was gone.
Then my husband, my man...
...my Suleyman was gone to the next world.
I bid farewell to my heart, Ertugrul.
From now on...
...my only hope is not to lose
my grandchild.
If I lose him...
Bey, you made your way out
of the that hell.
Death will not come to you, Bey.
Well, as I said, a man dies
when his time is right.
So, the time was not right for me.
Deer milk will heal your wounds.
Thank you, Geyikli. You saved my life.
I owe you a life.
He is the one who does it,
who sees, who makes us see
who makes things be,
who makes things die.
We are human beings, brave man.
Very nice, I will come back soon.
Good bye, Alps.
I heard that Kayi women are dexterous.
Now I can see it on your beautiful hands.
But seeing you worried
makes me sad, Gokce.
After all this pain, even living
becomes a burden, Aytolun Hatun.
You are my relative.
I cannot let you wear yourself
down to a shadow.
You are young and beautiful.
No man can take their eyes off you.
Because you are Suleyman Shah's daughter
no one draws near to you.
Do not wear yourself down to a shadow.
Tugtekin and Gundogdu
will go to Erzurum soon.
Go with them.
Go shopping, see new people.
Buy delightful clothes for yourself.
All right?
Word is that, even Byzantine women
wear our chintz and textile fabric.
Camel trains come to Konya
and Erzurum for trade.
We are no less than Byzantine women.
All right?
Tugtekin Bey wants to see
the mitts, Aytolun Hatun.
All right, leave. Gokce will bring them.
Come on, show these mitts to Tugtekin.
All right.
I told you, that woman is dangerous
and stay away from her.
Why do you not listen to me?
I have never seen a woman
who is more dangerous than you, sister.
But if she is as you said,
I got used to it because of you.
Do not worry, I will be on the safe side.
Mind your own business.
Bey, you wanted to see the mitts I made.
Thank you.
As I wanted.
But I do not understand how did
your delicate finger make these?
You need to make 500 pairs of this mitts
with women before winter ends.
I will do my best, Bey.
Nemrut, from now on
you are my private Alp.
I want to know the wind that blows,
the bird that flies and everything.
Yes, Bey.
Gundogdu Bey.
Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Bey, if you give permission,
I want to talk.
Of course, you have permission.
Tugtekin wants to talk to Alps.
Bad things reached my ears.
-What happened?
Kayi Alps do not want to obey Tugtekin.
They could not accept it.
What is that they could not accept?
What he did to Ertugrul's Alps.
And they could not accept
what he did to your Alp, Hamza.
They are offended because
they go by the board.
Wild Demir
do we have any mission other than
to protect unity of Kayi
and our nomad people?
No, we do not.
Otherwise, we cannot live on these lands.
Everybody must be aware of this.
Moreover, you wanted to come to these
lands before its time, not me.
Now, tell my words to those watering holes
who told you these.
Take my side.
Let Alps see you on Tugtekin's side.
They will calm down a little.
You know, they respect you.
No, Bey.
I have a more important business.
All right.
What happened, brother?
Is it something important?
No, Tugtekin. It is not.
-God is right!
-God gives life!
The time is right, Wild Demir.
I am by your side
until my last breath, Bey.
God is right!
Oh Bey.
Oh Suleyman Shah.
The union of two nomad tents
should not have been like this.
Our sons are fighting with each other.
How will it be? How?
Brave Alps of Kayi are
at your disposal, Tugtekin Bey.
Thank you.
Brave Alps of Kayi and Dodurga.
We have same blood and traditions.
Now we have same nomad tent and enemy.
Our Beys made a decision in headquarters.
The mission of commanding two nomad tents
were given to me.
Now, it is time to obey and be one.
All Alps must know that
smallest disobedience will be punished
and no mercy will be shown.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
My undying brother!
Ertugrul!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
My son!
He is not dead, he is alive!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
I heard that my Alps
were punished severely
because of various reasons
while I was not here.
I want headquarters to convene and
make a final decision about punishments.
Until the headquarters convene
my Alps will be under my command
in nomad tent.
If there is anyone who protests,
come to the forefront.
Until the headquarters convene
if anyone hurts my Alps
he will face me.
Everyone must know this.
Mother?
Do you have any word?
No, my son.
Uncle?
Do you have any word?
No.
If you say they are under your command
there is nothing I shall say.
You go and rest.
My brother.
My dying day has not come yet, mother.
May God give my life to you.
My son.
Thank God a thousand times.
Welcome, brave son.
Thank you, uncle.
Where is Halime Sultan, mother?
Where is she, mother?
In her marquee, son.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Thank God!
Thank God! Thank God!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Thank God.
Thank God, Bey is alive.
Halime.
My darling.
My beautiful doe.
We have a long way together.
Even though the end of the way is obvious,
it is still ours.
I do not know our fate
and the lifetime that God gave us.
However, as long as I am alive
I will not let neither you nor my child
worry about anything, Halime Sultan.
Come on, wake up.
I am pregnant, Ertugrul.
May God always keep you among us.
I will be a father! A father!
I am here to free you from your pain.
Come on, wake up.
May I come in, Ertugrul Bey?
Come in, Artuk Bey.
Now that you are here,
she will get better.
Thank God, you look very healthy.
When I see you, I feel like
I am seeing late Suleyman Shah.
What is Halime Sultan's situation?
She is in a bad condition.
She has survived till now,
she did not give up.
We will lose either the baby or both.
Son...
I need to see Wild Demir, mother.
Go, son.
Ertugrul.
My uncle will sacrifice an animal
in his marquee.
Every animal we sacrifice before
we get Noyan's head is dirty, brother.
Tugtekin.
Son, calm down.
Do you think he gets what he wants just
because he wanted Headquarters to convene?
He rides the high horse. He thinks
he can get everything he wants.
We fed them while they were hungry!
We dressed them!
He wanted Headquarters to convene
in spite of all we have done.
He asked why we exiled
his Alps at the nomad tent.
Son, calm down.
He is still your cousin.
First, you should be happy he is alive.
I threw my hat into the ring.
I will make him pay for this.
God, give me patience!
Are you going to shed blood?
If he does not obey me, I will.
Bey...
...with your permission...
Tugtekin speaks the truth.
We should nip it in the bud.
However, there is a certain way
to nip it in the bud, Tugtekin.
In any case, if you sow the wind
you will reap the whirlwind.
Do not forget that.
So, what shall I do?
Two nomad tents are united now,
there is no turning back from this.
We will invite him
to the Headquarters meeting.
But it will be Kayi Beys
who do not choose him. Not us.
And how is this going to happen?
We will find Ertugrul's weak point, Bey.
Wild Demir.
God, please let it be his voice
that I just heard.
Take my life.
Thank God.
Bey.
Animals being sacrificed,
the meal given to our people...
Are they doing this to give Ertugrul
what he deserves
or to convince him?
The verdict about Ertugrul
has been given.
From now on,
Tugtekin will command the Alps.
I know how much you love your brother.
If you are torn between
your love and nomad tent
I know you will choose your nomad tent.
Do not waste Ertugrul
just like that, Gundogdu.
Because my mother and you
were on the right track yesterday
but Ertugrul is back.
If you and Mother Hayme
will not take a step backward
you will go astray.
My mother and I know
what we are doing, woman.
You just mind your own business.
Have you ever seen
that Ertugrul has given up?
Especially if the mission was given
to him by his father.
Your verdict will have
no importance for him.
I said we should not have
gone to Aleppo, but they did!
come to Anatolia, but they did!
They should know better
and not do anything.
Otherwise, Gundogdu Bey
will make them understand!
God, please help.
God, please spare my wife and my child.
Do not let my descendants go astray.
Give us strength.
Help us, so that we can get out of
this blind hole we are in.
You will watch every step
Ertugrul and his Alps take.
What about the other Kayi Alps?
Try to get them on your side.
Cause a rift between them if necessary.
Do you understand?
Do not worry about it, Bey.
They will be in blind holes.
Son...
Your uncle hosts this dinner for you.
I cannot leave Halime, mother.
I want her to see me first
when she opens her eyes.
Are you upset with me...
...for taking your father's mission
back from you and giving it to Tugtekin?
Do you resent me?
You thought I was dead.
Under those circumstances,
your decision was right.
However, I am here now, hale and hearty.
So, your verdict is invalid to me.
I know, you do not want to go
against my uncle
after all the good things he has done.
I do not want to reverse your verdict
and put all the burden on your shoulders.
How is it going to be, son?
Let two nomad tent Beys
give the verdict in Headquarters.
I will tell everything
I know in Headquarters.
I will tell, so everyone will know
what happened
and how we are going to fight
with the enemy.
Then, Beys may vote for their own fate.
Dinner is ready, mother.
They are waiting for you.
Do you need anything?
No, my daughter.
Now that Ertugrul is back
from now on
they will stay on the right side
and you will stay with me on the left side
until you get married.
Who would marry me, Mother?
Why not? What do you lack?
You know what happened.
What happened?
When I was stabbed...
No one can know
whether you will have a baby or not.
It is the will of God.
Who would risk it and marry me, Mother?
My beautiful daughter, every man
who loves you will take that risk.
Alright?
You chose a warrior wife like yourself.
If you will be our enemy
she will be the victim of this war
sooner or later.
Your wife and all the people you love.
So you will resist.
This torture will not end
until you obey me.
Ertugrul.
I am back, Halime Sultan.
I am back.
You never left, anyway.
You have always been here.
How can I go
leaving you and my baby alone?
Your nephew you hosted dinner for
did not honor your dinner.
Where did this
Headquarters idea come from?
It is impudent to object Beys' verdict.
Ertugrul wanted Headquarters to convene
and Beys agreed.
You will ask this question to the
Beys of the Headquarters, not to me.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
My dear God
heaven only knows why
but you granted us such a beautiful day.
God, thank you.
Welcome home, son.
You made us happy by coming back.
Thank you, uncle.
You welcomed us, shared your food.
The Kayi Tent will not forget this.
This is the bravery of Dodurga.
We welcome, share our food
and be a comrade.
Very good for you, Tugtekin.
Not anyone in your position
will share his food as you do.
Sisters, bring the lamb.
Let us start now.
We must take care of
Ertugrul Bey and Halime Hatun.
Tugtekin, Tugtekin.
You are a good man
but you have a long way
to compete with Ertugrul.
Well, bard, play something
so we pull ourselves together.
Of course, Bey.
We will campaign to Georgia
Anybody can come to our province
But come only if you are brave
Only if you pass the bloody creek
We will campaign to Mongol
Anybody can come to our province
But come only if you are brave
Only if you pass the bloody creek
Listen to the words of the brave men
Let us get down to the arena
Come only if you can wear
The shirt of death
Listen to the words of the brave men
I pander to my beauty's whims
The real daughter of Georgia
Come if you can take her away
Blood flowing through the sword
Come if you can face it
If it were not for Geyikli
I could not have escaped
from those tyrants.
-What is Geyikli like?
-He is a Bayirbucak Turkmen.
He lives in mountains, plains and forests.
Let me unroll it. Give it to me.
I could come back here
thanks to you, gazelle-eyes.
To see you once more
to hear your voice once more.
My soul did not leave my body
because I believed that
you were alive, Ertugrul.
Ertugrul!
-Do not tell anyone.
-What did they do to you, my brave man?
How can you grab a sword with this hand?
You grab the sword with your heart,
not with your hand.
Ertugrul must accept
the situation, mother.
And only you can make him do that.
Otherwise, we cannot
keep the two nomad tents together.
How so, son?
I saw the rage in Ertugrul's eyes, mother.
I knew, yet the storm in his heart
is bigger than the Flood.
He will not rest until he kills Noyan.
He will go after Noyan like he did
for Petruchio and Titus.
We brought their castle down on them,
but that was luck.
However, it is not the same now.
After all this pain
we cannot face a new pain, Mother.
Alright, son.
Let us enjoy his return now.
Where are you going
with this wounded hand, Ertugrul?
Artuk Bey will heal my hand.
He is waiting for me.
I will be back in the evening.
I know you want to get your mission back
and seek your revenge.
Everytime you go to a mission
I bid farewell to you to be a martyr.
But this time
everything is different, Ertugrul.
What has changed, Halime Sultan?
I saw your hand.
You cannot even eat soup with this hand
let alone fight, Ertugrul.
I know...
...your motherly love
makes you say these words.
I am neither angry at you
nor will I tell anything bad to you.
You do not want to raise
our baby without his father.
However...
...I am not only your husband
and the father of our baby.
I am the commander of Kayi Alps.
I am entrusted with Kayi babies' lives
and their mothers' honor.
I failed that trust once.
Remember the lives we have lost.
We came to my uncle's tribe
like parasites.
Let the winter pass
and you get better, then...
There is no then, Halime Sultan.
We do not have a winter to wait.
We do not have even a day.
If I do not go out today,
there will be a lot of bloodshed.
Noyan will die.
He has to.
Kocabash won Gundogdu's favor.
Kocabash acted wisely.
Scarf headed had already deserved to die.
There is more.
What is it?
Gumushtekin and his daughter Goncagul.
They are returning from Konya
after meeting with Sultan Alaeddin.
They will be in the nomad tent soon.
Tugtekin and Gundogdu
will go to Harput to get them.
So?
So, they will fall into our trap.
Ertugrul? What about him?
If the Headquarters decide
against Ertugrul
we will not need to do anything.
They will fall out with each other
like all Turks.
You?
Welcome to my humble house, Hamza Alp.
Look at them!
Why are they grinning?
-Let me find out.
-Abdurrahman!
Mind your own business.
Ertugrul Bey does not want any problems
before the Headquarters convene.
What are you going to do with Ertugrul Bey
after the Headquarters, Dogan?
What are you going to do? Tell me.
You will herd animals together,
Dogan, right?
Dogan!
Alps!
Mind your own business, Alps!
I will...
-Give me that boy!
-Take him if you can!
Since when Tugtekin's Alps
show their bravery to boys?
We are trying to teach manners
to Ertugrul's Alps, Master Demir.
You...
I will smash that big head of yours!
Stop!
The dogs bark, yet the caravan goes on.
There will be no problems
before the Headquarters convene.
Mind your own business.
Let's go.
Who is this boy?
Son of Ilgordu Alp
who was martyred in ambush.
Turali.
After everyone in his family died,
he stopped talking.
Turali.
From now on, he is my bravest Alp.
Where is Ertugrul Bey?
He went to see Artuk Bey.
He will show his hand.
Until the Headquarters is over,
please behave yourselves.
Otherwise, we will be in trouble.
How is my hand, Artuk Bey?
I cannot lie to you, Ertugrul.
It is almost impossible
to use a sword with this hand.
Yet Geyikli did a good job.
God forbid, I may have had
to cut your hand.
Thank God, I have two hands.
I can fight with my right hand.
In the worst case
I will cut that bastard's heart out
with my teeth.
Halime Sultan must apply this cream
to your hand every night.
Then she will bandage it
with a clean cheesecloth.
Thank you.
What do you think about me
getting my mission back?
My heart is with you.
But I might have to obey Bey.
I do not know what verdict
I will give in Headquarters.
It depends on you, and your words.
Other Beys are confused as well.
Korkut Bey wants to see you, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank God, you are back, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Aytolun Hatun.
I wish you happiness with your baby.
May you bring him up in peace.
Halime Sultan suffered a lot
while you were gone.
Have som rest this winter.
Tugtekin will handle
your mission properly.
Also, you can help Halime Sultan
during her pregnancy.
When Mongols arrive,
your baby will be born.
Be with them.
Anyway, may God help us all.
Thank you, sister-in-law.
May God give you a baby, too.
Tell me Eymish Baci,
is Ertugrul Bey alright?
Speak!
What is wrong with our brave heart?
It was unpleasant for you to bring this
matter to the headquarters, nephew.
You disregarded me and your mother.
I handled this matter without
disregarding you and my mother.
I know that headquarters will give
the right judgement.
Headquarters' judgment will put neither me
nor you in an inconvenient position.
You show your cunning
as well as your strenght.
If your late father was alive,
he would be proud of you.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Mother Aytolun was right.
He will cause trouble, father.
He will give us a headache.
He wants the mission, his father gave him.
But there is nothing to worry about.
He will obey the headquarters' judgment.
What if their judgment is against us?
What if Kayi Beys kick up a fuss?
Even our Beys.
So, do not stop, son. Do your best.
What do you want from me, Noyan?
Why don't you kill me?
I need brave and strong warriors like you.
You want me to betray
my nomad tent, don't you?
No. I offer you an opportunity
to become a great commander of the Kayis.
How will this happen?
If Kayis serve to Ogeday, not Aleaddin
I will not have to kill your kind.
I promise you fame, glory
and gold in Ogeday's army.
Most beautiful women, fastest of horses
and the sharpest swords can be yours.
I offer you a chance to become a commander
in the largest army you've seen
which will conquer the world.
None of them wants to see
the danger Noyan possess.
What do Mother Hayme
and Gundogdu Bey think?
I will convince my mother and brother.
But we must take all the votes
in the headquarters.
What are we going to do, Bey?
Talk the Beys of every headquarters.
Tell everyone why I want to be
the commander of Alps.
Tell them I am not after position.
If we attack before Noyan attacks us,
victory can be ours.
Otherwise, Noyan will pillage our lands,
and kill everyone.
Talk with everyone.
-Yes, Bey.
-As you wish, Bey.
Abdurrahman, your mission is...
...to be my spy in Noyan's army.
We will ask Geyikli's help for this.
But we need to handle the business
in the headquarters.
Or all our plans will be in vain.
We must give hell to Noyan.
What if I do not accept?
Your horse is ready for you
with your weapons.
You are free to leave anytime you want.
You are useless to me when you are dead.
On the contrary, I would be sorry
if you would die.
You are smart enough to understand
the importance of my offer.
We both know you have nowhere else to go.
Moreover, your need for vengeance
consumes you.
You hate your Bey, whom you wasted
your life for.
I offer you opportunity of getting
revenge from Gundogdu.
Decision is yours.
You can be my guest tonight if you like.
Think. We will talk in the morning,
in the cold light of the day.
Canfeda, come here!
Yes, Bey.
Hamza Alp is my guest.
You will serve him until he leaves.
Turali!
Turali! Wait, son!
He is a brave boy.
Just like you.
When Ertugrul Bey brought you to me,
you were like him.
As wild and brave as he is.
And a handful I must say.
Tugtekin and Gundogdu are talking to Beys.
Is it strange that
they are not talking to you?
We know what are they saying.
They know I will not change my side.
Now, two of them together
will cause trouble for our Bey.
In the name of God.
Gokce is a skillful girl.
They suit you well.
I did not imagine that
she would be this good.
Tugtekin, you have feelings for Gokce.
I can talk to your father if you like.
Not now, mother.
We will talk after I handle Ertugrul.
Alright.
What did you do?
Did you talk to Beys?
What is their reaction?
Kayis are reluctant.
Alps want Ertugrul Bey.
Mother Hayme does not know what to do.
-Wild Demir is as usual.
-What about our Beys?
I have my doubts about Artuk Bey.
He does not breathe a word about it.
What about Horseless and Ayhan?
They think that it could cost us dearly
to waste Ertugrul Bey.
Ertugrul does not want to give up
being the commander of Alps.
Beys do not want to waste him.
So, there is only one thing to do.
What?
If we rob him of his position as an Alp...
...we solve our problem.
He will not stop until
he kills Noyan, mother.
But...
...there is something worse.
What?
His hand, mother.
It is impossible for him to grab a sword
with his hand.
What happened to his hand?
Bastard Noyan drove nails to his hand.
Good God!
What can a man do without his sword?
Oh, God.
Where did he go?
I do not know, mother.
He went to Artuk Bey to show his hand,
then he will see someone else.
He did not tell me where he was going.
Mother. I beg you, talk to him.
It does not make a difference, daughter.
Beys on the headquarters
will make their judgment.
But what about your judgment?
What are you doing, Gokce?
I was about to call Mother Hayme.
-Are they inside?
-Yes.
Bey.
You gave me life with your return.
May God give you strength.
Amen, Gokce.
Amen.
Mother.
Halime Sultan.
-Peace be with you.
-And peace be with you.
In the name of God.
With the 99 names of God Almighty,
creator of all existence,
For he filles our hearts with faith.
Beys.
Brave men.
Saints of our nomad tent.
Welcome to the headquarters.
We are here to talk about
the situation of exiled Alps
and the position of Ertugrul Bey,
as the commander of Alps.
With the permission of Korkut Bey,
I open this session.
No matter what the headquarters decides,
there will not be any peace
in our nomad tent, Halime.
At least you and my mother
do not go against Ertugrul Bey.
I told him bad things, Selcan.
I hurt him deeply.
My baby prevented me
from seeing the truth.
But it is too late now.
Why are saying this, Halime?
Mother Hayme...
...will never let her son
challenge death in his condition.
His condition, Halime?
What are you talking about?
Halime?
May it be easy.
Thank you.
Ertugrul Bey is prudent enough
to do everything for his nomad tent.
I know and believe it by heart.
But after all, he is a human being.
After headquarters' judgment,
take care of your man, Halime Sultan.
Do not let him be obsessed and
drag us into trouble.
You are trying to waste him
in his most difficult day.
What are you going to do
when you are in trouble?
Pray, Ertugrul Bey will be there for you.
It is a known fact that
a Mongol soldier...
...can go to a village and...
...behead all men, women and children...
...in a village all by himself.
People are scared.
First, we need to conquer this fear.
Waiting for war all winter long
is not different than
waiting to die in your own grave.
Tell us what you are thinking.
We must conquer the fear of people,
who are paying tribute to bastard Noyan.
We must be their hope...
...so those bastards dare not
ask for anything.
We must cut the flow of gold of merchants
who are supplying food to the Mongol army.
This way they will know,
we will cut their hands
if they accept their gold.
From now on, we do not have time to
be on the defensive.
We will attack that bastard Noyan
and give him hell...
...so that he will understand his army
cannot stay here.
And then?
That is why...
...I want my position back, which was
given me by my father Suleyman Shah...
...to attack that bastard Noyan
and give hell.
How much longer this headquarters last?
It drags on.
Our Bey must have opened their eyes.
Among us...
...Ertugrul Bey is the one who
knows Mongols best.
Because he went into their den.
Sooner or later the headquarters
will understand this.
Then Ertugrul Bey will be
the commander of Alps again.
Do not worry.
Ertugrul Bey's words are true
without a doubt.
But I do not know how would we do it?
Preventing merchants who feed
Noyan's army,
supporting nearby villages
and tracking spies is not an easy task.
But it is not impossible.
Ertugrul Bey's word impressed me,
he speaks the truth.
What if Bastard Noyan attacks us
again in a weak moment
and slaughter our women, children, Alps
and animals?
What are we going to do then?
We are at war, brother.
We must take necessary precautions.
What precautions are you
talking about, Ertugrul Bey?
An Alps life is his sword hand.
You already lost your hand to Noyan.
So your life belongs to him.
How could an Alp who cannot even grab a
sword, take command of all the Alps?
What are you talking about, Tugtekin?
Do you hear yourself?
Ask it Artuk Bey, not me, my Bey.
Artuk, is he right?
He is right, Bey.
They damaged his hand
when they drove nails in it.
I do not know if it will heal or not.
But it is certain that it will not heal
before the the war in spring.
Look.
-Will he fit in this, Selcan?
-Of course, he will.
When will headquarters end?
They cannot take away his right,
unless they play a trick on him.
I do not know which is better, Selcan.
We listened everyone.
Now, we must hear Beys' judgment,
Hayme Sister.
The time is up, Bey.
So, to prevent a conflict
among our Alps...
...until our nomad tents split up again...
...I put to vote that Tugtekin be the
commander of Alps...
...and take away Ertugrul
Bey's position of Alp...
...until he heals.
Ayes?