Episode 44 will start after 12:27 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
My dear mother.
My beautiful mother.
I am back, mother.
I am back.
Do not worry, mother.
I will recover with the help of God.
Mongol's blade may cut my flesh,
But it is not enough to kill me.
I will not...
...go anywhere before I eat your
bulgur pilaf with meat...
...and chickpeas tonight.
I would die for you, son.
Welcome, Sungur.
Thank you, brother. Well met.
No matter how far I was...
...my heart was always with you.
-Ishak, prepare here immediately.
-Yes, Artuk Bey.
My Bey, excuse me.
Hayme Hatun, excuse me.
Artuk Bey, I entrust my son's life to
God and your hands.
God willing.
Come along, mother.
My Bey.
In the name of God.
Let us begin with the name of God.
With the name of God.
Where did Ertugrul Bey find Sungur Tekin?
We don't know what happened too,
Aytolun Hatun.
Since he did not come here by himself
he went to battle with Alps
to find his brother.
Ertugrul Bey did as he pleased again.
Thanks to God, nothing worse
happened to them.
You would be happy, if it did I guess.
Sister, don't start
in a day like this please.
Sure Aytolun, our troubles doubled, right?
As you can see, our respected words are
bent and misunderstood intentionally.
There is nothing to do against this
wicked woman...
...except to leave her to God's will?
Selcan!
Mother!
Hayme?
How is my nephew?
He doesn't show...
...but his wound is very bad.
You made us very happy by bringing
Sungur Bey back. We believed
he was dead for years.
May God help him.
Thank you, Gumustekin Bey.
How did it happen? Who did you fight with?
We faced with Noyan and his soldiers.
How is this possible, Ertugrul Bey?
You sent us after Noyan.
Then you disappeared.
You did not come to the battle you asked,
now you say that you found Noyan.
Your secrets scare us all.
It is obvious that Sungurtekin
and Noyan got together somehow.
That's not what I want to know.
I want to know how did you find them,
my Bey?
Mere coincidence, Gumustekin Bey.
We dedicated our lives to
put an end to this Mongolian plague.
Thankfully, I was able to bring
Sungurtekin back to his nomad group.
What kind of coincidence is this
to make Ertugrul Bey fell into their lap?
I heard that you overcame
all of Noyan's traps
and turned back to nomad group victorious.
May God makes your victories everlasting.
This is not the case Ertugrul, we beli...
Shadows are becoming longer
each passing day...
...and our enemies are
breathing down our necks...
...what are you after really?
If it was not for you,
we wouldn't be celebrating victory
but suffer under Noyan's tyranny.
We will never forget what you did for us,
my Bey.
However, Tugtekin Bey is right.
Even though you have a pure heart,
it's doors are sealed shut against us.
Without breaking this seal,
how can we trust you?
Enough.
Enough, stop it.
It is not right to talk about such matters
while we have a patient inside.
My son, Sungurtekin returned home.
Don't take away my happiness.
Go and settle your scores in your marquee.
The blood Noyan had spilled
is finally avanged.
We are bathed in the glory of victory.
What else do you want?
Sigil of Oghuz Khan will go to Ogeday.
Ogeday will increase his power
with this sigil.
Emotions will flow among the Turks
in the army with this sigil.
Their eagerness will strengten
the position of the Khan of the World.
We all know the respect Turks show to
Oghuz Khan.
If Sungurtekin returns to his homeland
with this sigil...
...our army will split in two.
And Ogeday will make us pay for it.
We cannot let it happen.
We will not.
They will bring me
the sigil of Oghuz Khan.
How?
We shall begin, Ishak.
May God help us.
In deference to the name of Shafii.
Are you ready, Bey?
In the name of Allah!
Dear God!
Thankfully, you made me see my son
before he dies.
I am begging you, please have mercy on
him.
Please do not take him from me so soon.
-Amen.
Amen.
Mother. All our troubles
will come to an end, mother.
If God permits they will all be over,
do not worry.
-Ertugrul.
-Halime Sultan.
Come, Bey, you are tired.
We should sit here.
Ertugrul, what was Noyan doing there?
He was after Sungurtekin.
We killed all his soldiers
with Sungurtekin.
Noyan could escape wounded.
You dispossessed first his cave, then his
soldiers...
and now you Sungurtekin from his.
From now on you are
his only enemy, Ertugrul.
He will not stop
until he kills you.
I am also afraid of his
anger, Halime Sultan.
But not for myself.
He knows everything about both marquees
as much as we do.
Ambission of Tugtekin,...
...weaknesses of my uncle.
And even...
...our child you bear.
Speak for the sake of Ertugrul's child,
Halime Sultan.
If not, I will rip your bastard out,
with my own hands!
Ertugrul, there are also these things
that Selcan told.
I know everything, Halime Sultan.
Aytolun and Gumustekin both look
as if they respect to you.
They smile to your face but I see
how much they beware of you.
There are some things that are not pure.
Selcan is also not aware of that.
Do you think that Gundogdu can not accept
it because he will marry to Goncagul?
Whatever happens, do not leave
Selcan alone.
But respect to that girl
whom my brother will get married to.
When I am back, I would want to know
everything.
Ertugrul.
I am going on a long journey, Halime
Sultan.
I made you a promise, Ertugrul.
Whatever you do, you do it well.
Even if you set off the roads
that I have never seen before...
...my heart is always with you.
But this time is different.
Not knowing where you are planning to go,
really scares me.
I do not know what you are
going to encounter.
Crazy horses inside of me tell me
that it is time, Halime Sultan.
I hope that one day, those
crazy horses will tell you...
...not to leave Halime Hatun alone
anymore.
It is said that separation expands love,
Halime Sultan.
It is obvious that my heart will always
long for you, Ertugrul.
May separations not be in hearts.
I am always with you.
Our Beys showed the whole nomad group
what means being brave.
Everybody is talking about Gundogdu and
they have Tugtekin in their hearts.
An the bravery of my father.
People are speaking mostly about him.
He went to war with a wounded leg...
...but shedded so much
Mongolian blood, aunt.
While everybody was expecting
Gumustekin to return back...
...from palace of sultan fustily...
...thank God, he proved everybody
how brave he is.
Thank God.
I have not seen hide nor hair of Selcan,
Aunt.
She must have burried herself in her
widow woman tent, when she was snubbed.
You should know that, this black snake
will not remain calm.
She must be after something.
Until we get rid of her,
please do not dodge the column.
Non of us will have peace until that bitch
dies, you should know it.
-Selcan Hatun.
-Banu Cicek.
You are all grown up now. God bless you.
I have heard that you ride horse and
use weapon like a man, right?
I remember the first time you came to our
nomad group with Suleyman Shah.
You and Gokce taught me
how to ride a horse, Selcan Hatun.
So, you also remember
those beautiful days.
How can I ever forget? Your visits
were making me so happy.
We both grew up in the marquee of
Korkut Bey and Suleyman Shah.
We learned love and respect from them.
Now it is time to pay our debts
back to my martyr father...
...without embarrassing him, Banu Cicek.
What are you saying, Selcan Hatun?
Our nomad group has fallen into a
depravement like an endless swirl.
I want you to help me in order
to get rid of this malice.
But do not say the things
I told you to anyone else.
Selcan Hatun, your words are scaring me.
Tell me what you are trying to tell me
for God's sake.
I do not want anyone to see
us together.
I will wait for you in the meadow
out of the nomad tent.
I will tell you everything
there, alright?
May it be easy.
I came quickly right after
I heard what happened, Noyan.
I have always appreciated your
loyalty, Efrasiyab.
Now I will ask something from you
that is more important than...
...anything else.
What can I do for you, Noyan?
Sungurtekin has a seal.
You will help the sons of Suleyman Shah
to bring that seal to me.
I will do anyting you want from me
but entering to the...
You will kidnap a woman from the family...
...not the seal.
You will bring me the woman.
Then they will bring me the seal.
Whatever you say.
Is my loyal cur Hamza...
...still alive?
In the morning, he will be beheaded
by Gundogdu.
He will die honourably.
May spirits be with him.
Now listen to me carefully.
I will tell you how you are
going to do this.
Banu Cicek! Come here!
We are in a blind hole.
It is our duty to save our nomad groups
from this malice.
What are you saying, Selcan Hatun?
I do not understand. How?
There is a calamity that poisons both
nomad groups in the marquee of Korkut Bey.
You are the only one that can help me
to get rid of this calamity.
What calamity?
You understand who I am
talking about, right?
I am talking about the woman that
Korkut Bey assigned you even to risk...
...your life for if needed.
How can you tell me this?
Do not you have any conscience?
How can you talk about Great Korkut Bey
like this?
Right. He is The Great Korkut Bey!
But his wife is the curse of us all!
The whole Nomad group, The Dodurga marquee
of Korkut Bey... I am telling you.
She is going to poison us all!
We have to prevent it!
You have lost your mind. How can yo...
If you help me find what this Aytolun
bitch is hiding in the marquee...
Enough!
I can not betray neither my Bey
nor my Hanim.
Do not ever get close to me
or I will make you regret it.
What goes around comes around, Hamza Alp.
Dear God, I did so many bad things.
I seduced too many valiants.
My arrogance prevented me from seeing the
truth. Please forgive me.
Give me the opportunity to serve this
nomad group, for one last time.
-Selcan.
-Come in, Halime.
Welcome.
-Thank you, Selcan.
How is Sungurtekin?
Artuk Bey is still watching him, Selcan.
They are polluting the nomad group of
my father as they wish.
They poison us with their endless
ambitions, by laughing in our faces!
-Selcan.
-Halime!
I do not need consolation, I need
a sister to fight for our nomad group.
What does it mean?
That old woman, who killed her Halime?
Why did she get killed?
There are things both Aytolun and
Korkut Bey are hiding from us. I know it.
What do you think they are hiding from us,
Selcan?
As Aytolun could come to the marquee and
settled there...
...I say that Aytolun killed the first
wife of Korkut Bey.
Selcan, how are we going to prove it?
First we need to find the necklace.
Then we will prove it step by step.
Now tell me Halime,
are you with me in this?
Yes, I am, Selcan.
My dear sister!
Sungurtekin must have a connection
with Sultan Aleaddin.
And also with Halime and Wild Demir's
leaving the nomad group.
What are they after, father?
It will become clear soon.
That bitch Selcan was right.
Trouble became two, while it was only one.
Arrival of Sungurtekin will not be
good for us, brother.
We can not move before we hear from
Sadettin Kobek.
When there are no obstacles left
ahead of me being The Margrave...
...sons of Suleyman Shah won't mean
anything to me anymore.
They will only be details like an insect
to smash or a bone to spit.
As long as the news I am waiting for
arrives.
When Sungurtekin has been captured
by Mongolians, I was so small.
I do not remember neither him
nor what has happened.
Where has he been for all this time?
What is his issue with Noyan?
What kind of a relationship
he has with Ertugrul, Gokce?
I understand you, Bey.
Both Ertugrul and Gundogdu are tough men.
Now there is Sungurtekin too.
I want the best for both nomad groups.
You know it.
I know, my Bey.
If I do not know what is happening,
I can not take precautions.
Look Gokce, your home is my marquee now.
For the sake of both nomad groups,
tell me whatever you see or hear...
...so that I can take precautions.
Do not worry, Bey.
They are after spooky things again,
father.
I am afraid we will be in trouble again.
After everything that has happened, you
still do not trust Ertugrul, son.
How can I trust him, father?
He is lying us by smiling at our faces.
There are things he hides from you,
me, even his mother and his brother.
Ertugrul is not a coward and not a
betrayer at all. I know that.
If I do not know your loyalty
to nomad group...
...if I do not know that your heart is
as strong as your body...
...I would say that, you are jealous
of his achievements.
He established a marquee within a marquee,
a state within a state.
Without being aware of these, how come you
want to establish a seigniory, father?
While your brother is facing with death...
...where did this journey come from,
Ertugrul?
-It is necessary, brother.
-Is it necessary?
What do you mean it is necessary?
You do not explaim anything neither to me
nor my mother.
I will tell you when it is the right time.
What did you tell us on the right time now
you are claiming that you will tell this?
You said that you were going to meet
with Sungurtekin...
...instead, you fought with Noyan.
What kind of business is this, brother?
What kind of a world you are living in?
How did you learn Sungurtekin was there?
How did Noyan learn you were there?
I want to know it not only as
your brother...
...but also as The Head of Alps of this
nomad group. This is my duty.
But you do not say anything
neither to me nor my mother.
When you said you will obey me,
this was what you meant?
Is this obeying?
When you are in trouble, you tell me
that I am with you to death.
But when it comes to telling something,
you do not tell anything.
Every step you take is a secret.
Brother, one day I will tell you
everything as it is.
But today is not the day.
-Brother!
-Gundogdu.
Enough already. Enough, son.
Your brother is facing with death inside.
Mother.
When even I can not stand what Ertugrul
is doing, how The Dodurgans will?
What he does, with whom he competes with
is not clear!
Brother...
I will be back soon, mother.
Do not worry.
If you go and do not come back...
...you will make me suffer like
Sungurtekin did.
If something like that happens...
...you should know that you will cause
my death.
Because...
...I am not strong enough to lose
another son.
Wait outside.
Where is that cur Noyan?
I do not know, Bey.
Where is that cur called Noyan?
You are in his lodge for a long time.
Do not you know anything about him?
I do not know, Bey.
The only thing I know is that...
...I made a mistake.
I only know that I want you to forgive me.
Only God can forgive you.
But I will not!
What about Sungurtekin?
Your brother Sungurtekin?
Yes, my brother Sungurtekin!
I know that Noyan hates him, Bey.
I know that he used to trust him in the
past and...
...helped him to raise with Ogeday...
...and that later on, Sungurtekin became a
spy for Sultan Aleaddin.
Then... Then...
Then?
Then...
Did he speak?
Did you learn anything about Noyan?
No.
Who are you angry with, Gundogdu?
You should know that, you became
a son to me.
The world is not like it used to be
anymore, son.
The only thing cowards will do is to move
to the lands far from trouble.
But we do not have any other land
except this one.
Hundreds of people from thousands of
tents depend on our words.
It is our duty to make them live.
For the sake of both nomad groups,
be careful about Ertugrul.
It is uncertain wherever he goes,
whatever he does.
Undoubtfully he is a great valiant.
But If he stumbles one day...
...we will all be swallowed.
It is time to go to Georgia
Whoever wants to join, join now
Manfuls join, not cravens
Dogan Alp.
I am here to say May God be with you.
You brought victory and honor
to our nomad group.
Thank you.
Whatever our Bey ordered, we tried to do
our best. That is all.
Your bravery is far beyond
this, Dogan Alp.
You are our prides. May God
let you have many more victories.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Does not the lover burn for the sweet one?
Even If the sweet one started speaking.
-How can the lion sleep anymore?
-Leave me alone.
-Consider we are gone.
-Yes brother, let's say that we left.
Not that we will go anywhere.
Will the fire within fizzle out, brother?
You are right.
Her coming burns like bellow,
and her leaving is like coal.
Good.
Brother, finally you spoke.
He spoke finally.
Brother, the laundry is done already.
Make the meal as well. We are inside.
Thankfully, brother. God bless you.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in!
Sadettin Kobek sent you a letter, Bey.
What is written in it, father?
Sadettin Kobek says that...
...all obstacles ahead of me being the
margrave are gone.
Why are you like this, brother?
The thing you wanted for years
is about to come true.
But he also says that this will upset
all balances.
What does it mean?
It means that everything is in danger.
Is not there any solution?
Yes. There is.
Speak, brother. What is happening?
Solution is up to Sungurtekin.
On the seal he carries with him.
Sadettin Kobek wants that seal from me.
You were right when you said that Ertugrul
and Sungurtekin were after something.
Eventually, it even effected us.
What are we going to do then?
Until we came this far...
...we have destroyed many homes
and killed many men.
Now we are on a road with a dead end.
We will take this seal.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Hang on, brave man. Hang on.
Mother...
They are obviously cauterizing his wounds.
It is over now. Do not worry.
If God permits.
It is over, brave man. It is over.
We have been praying with your father for
years to see the three of you together.
The day is today.
Do not make me feel
the sorrow of separation again.
How does he flip that?
I hope nothing is wrong, sister?
We have a favor to ask you, Dogan.
I hope he gets better soon, Hayme Hatun.
-I hope he gets better soon, Mother Hayme.
-I hope he gets better soon.
Thank you. May God bless you
and the healers.
Thank  you.
With God's help
Sungurtekin Bey is as fit as a fiddle.
Those wounds are just like a wind for him.
Do not worry.
–He will be alright in three days.
-If God permits.
If God permits.
Artuk Bey.
Thank you.
-Yes, Bey.
-I would like to talk to you.
If it is possible, I want to know
the situation of Abdurrahman Alp.
Please.
Come in, mother.
They killed an old woman
and took the necklace.
And they are threatening me now.
Why do you not tell this
to Gundogdu Bey?
I cannot prove that I was telling the
truth without finding the necklace.
They will think that I lie because I do
not want him to marry another woman.
I cannot make them believe me.
I...
...went into Gumustekin's marquee.
I searched everywhere
but could not find the necklace.
If I find the necklace,
I can prove that they are the killers.
I need to go to Aytolun's marquee
and look for the necklace.
I got a feeling
that the necklace is there.
Okay, that is also understood.
But what do you want from me?
We want you to speak with Banu Cicek.
What?
Banu Cicek should find a way
to get me into the marquee.
While there is life, there is hope, Bey.
We will continue to pray every day.
Even if the mountains
turn into a sea of blood
Noyan will pay the price of
what he did, Artuk Bey.
I will not doubt that even for a moment
while you are alive.
Sungurtekin...
...knows about the
white bearded, Artuk Bey.
He asks our help to remove
the Oghuzs from Ogeday's army.
How will Sungurtekin do that, Bey?
With Oghuz Khan's seal.
Does he have the seal?
Yes.
He wants to remind our brothers
in Ogeday's army who they are.
If he can do that
if we can weaken Ogeday's army
before they enter Anatolia
then we can save our state
without spilling blood, he says.
I will do what is necessary, Bey.
Tomorrow morning, I will go to Sogut.
Lead the way for Sungurtekin
when he leaves.
Every new road
will start a new resurrection, Bey.
How will the fact that
you will be near Byzantine
change your and your nomad tent's destiny?
I also wonder that.
I went to many places
but I never got excited as much as now.
May God always keep you
on the right way, Bey.
Thank you.
–My brother is entrusted to you.
-Of course, Bey.
You wanted to see me, Efrasiyab?
Are the goods of the rug house
still loaded?
The camel train will leave
before it gets dark.
Save the last one for the morning.
We will take someone with us.
You wait outside.
I made you my Alp.
I entrusted you with my life.
And what did you do, Hamza?
You betrayed us.
I will take your head tomorrow
in front of everybody.
Whatever you do, you are right, Bey.
But I have a last wish from you.
Let my death serve you.
The dog that is about to die
speaks like you, Hamza.
Bey, listen to me.
What I will tell is very important.
Shut up, infidel. Shut up.
So, Mother Hayme wants to cheer
her table up with her children.
Yes.
Sons, daughters,
daughter–in–laws, son–in–laws...
You cannot get a better chance
to get the seal.
I will take that seal, aunt.
Do not worry.
I know very well what you are
capable of, Goncagul.
I have no doubt about that.
This ring is yours.
Aunt...
...this is very beautiful.
It suits a woman like you
who is young and beautiful.
Remember your aunt,
whenever you look at it.
Mother...
My brother Sungurtekin will come
to this table sooner or later.
And look, you cooked his favorite meal
with meat and bulghur.
Maybe he will feel the smell and come.
I am sorry.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Son...
Is Selcan not coming?
Do not forget the promise you gave me.
Sleep in her tent tonight.
Sungur?
Good appetite.
I said I would not leave without eating
the meal with meat and bulghur, mother.
Sungur...
This spoon has been waiting here
since the day you were captured.
My mother never lost hope
even when we did.
Mother...
My dear mother.
Sungurtekin Bey.
I want to get to know everybody here.
But I cannot see Sister Selcan, brother.
Selcan is fine.
But she will not be with us tonight.
Let me introduce you my fiance.
Goncagul Hatun.
My brother Sungurtekin.
Come on, girl.
Have a good night, Banu Cicek Hatun.
You too, Dogan Alp.
I could not sleep.
I was worried Karanfil would get cold.
You thought well.
Night frost is tough.
She is a nimble mare.
What is it?
Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun
also told me that she was a nimble mare.
-You like them, right?
-Yes.
Especially, Korkut Bey.
He made a great effort for me.
He made a great effort
for me and my sister.
You would do anything for Korkut Bey
and the nomad group, do not you?
Why did you come here, Dogan Alp?
Did Selcan Hatun send you here?
No one can ask me to betray
Bey and his wife.
If I see you again
I swear to God, I go and tell
everything to Bey.
Do you understand me?
As he said, if there is such a bad luck
in the nomad tent
the resolution of this issue comes
before everything, Banu Cicek.
It is your duty for Korkut Bey.
Dogan Alp, if you say another word...
Halime Sultan sent her greetings too.
She wanted you to find the necklace
of Selcan Hatun in the marquee.
You do what is necessary if you find
the necklace in the marquee
as Selcan Hatun said.
I said what I had to say.
Do not kill the messenger.
Sorry for that.
I thought
Mongolians did not take prisoners.
How did they take you
prisoner, Sungurtekin Bey?
Because I was very good with the horses.
I took care of the horses
of the family of Genghis Khan for years.
So, is that all?
It is not just that, of course.
If somebody would harm
even a hair on the horses' head
they would kill me.
Thank God, you left those hard days behind
and returned to us, brother.
-Thank God.
We eat my mother's meal together
with our loved ones in our nomad tent.
What more can we ask for?
I wish your father was here
and saw that.
This is God's will, mother.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Bey.
Still the same, Bey.
He went there knowing what Noyan will do.
-He sacrificed himself for us.
-Wait now.
Abdurrahman will wake up.
Neither we nor he has the right
to give up.
Bey.
Turali is entrusted to me now.
I will raise him as a brave Alp
like Abdurrahman, with God's help.
Turali proved us how a brave Alp
he will be, Wild Demir.
There is no doubt about it.
If you excuse us, Bey.
Come on.
Alps!
Prepare yourselves.
We will set off with the sunrise.
Where are we going, Bey?
To the lands where our destiny
will be determined, Turgut.
Selcan Hatun?
If you excuse me
I have something to tell you.
What is it at this hour, trader?
We have seen some flaws
with the carpets
when we were loading them
in the rug house.
What kind of flaws?
I checked them one by one.
Then I should tell that to Aytolun Hatun.
Sorry, I disturbed you.
Wait.
You go to the rug house,
I will come there soon.
I am waiting for you, sister.
I will wait next to the car.
Gundogdu Bey?
Gundogdu Bey.
You looked like you were worried.
It bothers me.
I asked for permission from my father
and came to talk to you.
I would like to talk to you, if you wish.
It is cold, do not get cold.
When I am with you,
every winter is like spring, Bey.
My problem is my nomad tent,
my Alps, Goncagul Hatun.
Is not that enough?
My problem is to not show you any other
troubles until my life is over.
Shall we take a walk?
Mister Trader?
I saw you were looking at
Selcan Hatun's marquee.
Is she your trouble that you could not
tell me about while we were walking?
My pain started the first day
I came to the nomad tent.
You were an unimaginable
dream for me, Gundogdu Bey.
You were Suleyman Shah's son.
You were married to his adopted daughter.
Do you know how much I struggled
to rip you off my heart?
That day you came and asked my hand
from my father
and now I do not care anything.
Neither Selcan Hatun remaining your wife
nor anything else.
What about now?
My heart is broken, Bey.
Since I saw you in front of her marquee...
I am sorry.
I crossed the line, again.
One who loves, gets jealous.
I am sorry, Bey. Have a good night.
Goncagul Hatun.
Do not forget my words.
Selcan Hatun promised that
she will be my wife until her death.
And I promised to be her man.
I know that.
And I know you are right.
It is just foolishness of a young girl.
I am sorry.
Have a good night.
I have been dreaming of this day
for years.
Sitting with my family in the
same table and same marquee.
I do not bother if I die now.
Get some rest.
We have so many things to talk about, son.
You returned to your nomad group.
Mother?
I want to set off in the morning.
Set off?
Where will you go?
You just came, son.
Besides, in this situation...
I need to go, mother.
Will you also seal your lips
against us like Ertugrul?
Secrets covered secrets, mother.
Every covered secret is a new pain.
And new pains are the
messengers of new secrets.
Which secret of mine
would be an ointment for your wound?
It will be salt for your wound.
Not an ointment.
Do not do this to me, mother.
Let me keep my secrets as secrets.
Just leave them with me.
You should know that
I did not dishonor my father
or my ancestor Oghuz.
Know that and pray for me, mother.
Get some rest now.
Give me your blessing, mother.
I hope I will return with good news.
May God speed you...
...on the way with Sungur.
You have my blessing.
Go fast, and come back fast.
You should know that, our way is
the way of fire and love, mother.
We are the slaves who want
to serve on this way.
Beyond that is illicit to us.
Give me your blessing.
May God be with you.
May God be with you, too.
Did you get it?
I got it, father.
We went in with Gokce at dinner.
I took the seal.
Look.
-Very beautiful.
-Yes.
Efrasiyab brought this from Tabriz.
-This is even better.
-Yes, it is very beautiful.
There are too many things.
Look what I will show you.
I am coming right away.
Okay.
It is time for being the margrave now.
There is no turning back.
May God let you succeed, brother.
But what is this seal?
It is the seal of Oghuz Khan, Aytolun.
What are you saying, father?
Will you give this seal
that all khans and sultans sought after
to Sadettin Kobek?
Everything has a price, daughter.
I paid the price.
Now it is Sadettin Kobek's turn.
Brother.
Since he is going to leave,
Dogan lost his mind completely.
As he will not be able to see Banu Cicek,
he's like hit by a ton of bricks.
I hope that you will also burn in
the fire of love one day, Bamsi.
You burn and understand
how cruel the world is.
Repentance, brother, repentance.
Did you lose your senses? Repentance.
Repentance.
Brother, you speak
as you do not know.
I am married to my sword. I
like my horse like my child.
If Bey orders me to die, I will.
I fight until an arrow lost its way,
a spear that is out of its range...
...says "stop brother,
your life ends here.”
Every fight of ours is our
bridal chamber, thank God.
Thank you, brother.
Tomorrow is the time to go, brother.
Let us see what kind of
fights are waiting for us.
Yes, brother.
Let us see what kind of
fights are waiting for us.
What is love? It is
word of wild human.
Brother, you know that I
keep Aykiz sister out of it.
I know.
Let us sleep, brother.
Thank God, we have Ertugrul Bey...
...and we do not have time
to think about our sufferings.
Did you say something, brother?
Have a good night.
You too, brother, you too.
Everything happened as Noyan wanted.
If God permits.
Calm down. It is me.
What are you doing here?
Noyan will never
leave a valiant behind.
So you find a way to get
me out of this nomad tent.
You find it, so I and Noyan
will always be grateful to you.
They do not understand that I
run away until the guards' shift.
You find a way to get
me out of nomad tent.
Welcome.
Welcome, brother.
Noyan wanted you to be with him and
what he wanted has just happened.
May God speed you, Ertugrul.
Amen.
May God speed you wherever you go.
I hope you go and come back quickly
and be back with your loved ones.
I do not want you to resent, brother.
I will explain you everything
as soon as I come back.
I hope so, brother, I hope so.
We are ready, Bey.
Stop.
Give your blessing, Bey.
If fate so decrees, we will do
business again, if God permits.
If God permits, trader. We will
do greater business together.
If there are honest Turks
who do business like you...
...everybody get the best of it, Bey.
Do not forgive me.
But do not pollute the land with
my worthless blood, as you said.
Let me take Abdurrahman's revenge.
How can I trust you after you
betrayed me and your brothers...
...so many times, Hamza?
I want to bring Noyan's
head to you, Bey.
If I die doing this, my blood
will be my offering for you and the land.
But I can give you more.
There is another traitor
in this nomad group, Bey.
I do not know why he came
here and what he is after.
But be sure that he will be the  one
who will take you and me to Noyan.
-Who is this?
-Trader Efrasiyab.
Till now, he brought
so much information...
...and so he hurt you
and the nomad tent.
If you want, catch him and
his men and make them talk.
You will see that I am right.
Whatever you decide,
I'm ready to die for it, my Bey.
Give your blessing.
Hamza, if what you said is a lie
I will not wait until tomorrow...
...and will take your head
here. Just you know that.
All I said is true, Bey.
I will get you out
of this tent tonight.
You will go to Efrasiyab right away.
You will finish the job that
Abdurrahman has left unfinished.
-Did you understand that?
-I understood, Bey.
Go away!
I am with you until
my last breathe, Bey.
God bless you.
Have a good journey.
Thank you, Bey.