Episode 38 will start after 12:19 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You killed her. You killed her.
You walk among others shamelessly
while you have blood on your hands.
You are looking into their
eyes impertinently. You rubbish!
You shut your filthy mouth, woman!
Do you know what you are saying?
That is enough. Stop shushing me!
I am saying that this rubbish killed
that old woman on that hillside.
This is disgrace! Could you not
hold your sick woman, Gundogdu?
What kind of a man are you?
I am sick of this
shameless woman's slanders!
If she says one more word...
...I swear to God I will
bring this to the headquarters.
You are talking about
headquarters unashamedly!
A creature like you do not have
any place in the headquarters.
-Quiet!
-Selcan!
Why are you so presumptuous?
Why are you so shameless?
How can you talk such baseless
to Hatun of Dodurga's Bey...
...in front of everyone?
She killed her, mother.
This cheap creature
killed that woman.
Do you not get it?
What does this mean, Aytolun?
I wish I knew, Hayme.
What are you doing here?
I am here to take revenge from
the man who killed Ertokus...
...and betrayed his state.
It is true that we
have a traitor among us.
But it's not me.
It has been your Alp
Kocash since the beginning.
He has been the dog of Noyan
since the very beginning.
Leave these lies aside.
You and your men are traitors.
And you shamelessly blame my Alp Kocash
who has saved your big brother's life.
You are so naive that
I just pity for you.
Enough!
Selcan.
Why do you think that she
killed that poor woman?
Because I know it, mother.
She is the murderer.
She killed that woman.
I saw the woman coming
to the carpet house.
She grew pale when she
saw her. She pulled her.
Pushed and shoved her. Then
expelled her from the nomad group.
After that they have found her body.
You cheap creature!
Okay but why do you think that I
killed that woman, Selcan Hatun?
If you cannot prove your allegation
it means that you are the snake...
...decrier, slanderous
of these two nomad groups.
I have expelled that woman from
the nomad group. That is true.
But since then I have neither left the
nomad group nor the carpet house today.
My man along with Dodurga and Kayi
women who works here are my witnesses.
Now.
You either prove your allegation
or I meet you in the headquarters.
This requires being at the headquarters. I
will be calling you to account over there.
Prove your allegation now.
I said prove it!
Tell me, Selcan.
What made you think so?
Tell me what did you
count on yourself?
Because I know it, mother.
I know that she killed that woman.
Believe me that she
killed her. I know it.
So she knows it.
We know what you did to the
nomad group with Kurdoglu.
We know that you had Aykiz whipped by
slandering her about she made you...
...had a miscarriage.
Now stand by your allegation
if you can, Selcan.
All scandals have been unfolded.
Gundogdu.
Take your wife away.
-Mother.
-Come with me.
-Come with me!
Selcan Hatun is really messed up in
the head. May God give your patience.
How do you know that
poor woman, Aytolun?
I know her from the nomad group.
She used to live on the
side of the nomad group once.
Whenever she had trouble, she'd
come to gain favor from me.
She crossed the line this time so
I expelled her from the nomad group.
That is all.
Forgive my daughter, Aytolun.
I would not be more embarrassed  if you
did not bring it to the headquarters.
Go back to your work,
sisters. Come on.
Don't get upset, Gokce.
You are the bride of our marquee
and joy of our family, girl.
Know this as it is.
So you want a festivity?
Let this festivity begin then.
If God permits you have learned
how to fight, uncle's son.
We learned a lot thanks to
your traitors, aunt's son.
That is really good.
I wish you had noticed that
the traitor cunt is next to you.
He brought you here.
Stop talking and surrender.
Gokce Hatun is the one who told
me that you will be here, Ertugrul.
Forget about these lies, be a
brave man, be a man, Ertugrul.
Let's say you want to lure me in,
why do you pull your woman Halime...
...into this, Ertugrul?
You look good in the
woman suit, Dogan.
You must understand it already.
This traitor scumbag has lured both of
us into a trap. They should be here soon.
Why are we still
waiting, Baycu Noyan?
It's nice to watch
the dogfight, Tangut.
Listen to me, Hatun.
I have warned you time after
time but that did not work.
I have thrown you away from
my bed but that did not work.
I did things that was not suitable
for a man and hit you with my hand...
...but that did not work, as well.
From now on, I do not want to
see your face, hear your voice...
...even pass through your shadow.
Get off of my back.
Get out of my life.
I was afraid of the dark
at the end of this path.
But I am not afraid of it anymore.
I know that there is light
at the end of the path.
Woman! You are still talking.
God damn you.
I will prove what kind
of a woman Aytolun is.
After that you will be ashamed.
But I will not be on your side.
That is enough.
Do not be upset, Halime Sultan.
Do not.
I am worried about
Ertugrul Bey, Wild Demir.
If God permits they will find out that
Kocash is a traitor so we would not...
...have to go to Konya.
If God permits, girl.
However one lives one's fate.
You have a lot to learn, uncle's son.
You have forgotten to use weapons
because of your disability.
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes and look around.
Where are they? Where are Mongols?
Attack!
Come on, Noyan. Come here.
Tugtekin is not so bad, Tangut.
We have made Turks kneel
down in lots of battles.
Turks are the best battle
soldiers on the earth.
But Turks without a leader would
equal to a flock without a shepherd.
They would become lions on the battlefield
if they find a leader who they believe in.
If we do not stop Ertugrul he
will reinvigorate this flock.
Then why don't we attack?
If you want to be a good hunter,
Tangut you should make the bait bigger.
I will throw such a bait
to Kayis and Dodurgas...
...they will fall apart
without using swords.
Open your eyes! Look around!
I would have killed
you if I wanted to.
Tell your soldiers
to drop their weapons.
Alps.
We are leaving.
Or brothers blood will be shed.
We will follow them.
Party is starting, Tangut.
Why are we running away, Bey?
We will not shed our
brothers blood, Turgut.
Kocash has pulled a trick on us.
Ertugrul!
Your voice is echoing
everywhere, Tugtekin.
Do not shout out so loud.
Your throat would get hurt.
Noyan.
Selcan.
Selcan. Selcan knows
everything, brother.
That you killed Duru, too?
I do not know but she
will not let it go.
There is Ertugrul outside of
the nomad group and Selcan is in.
We have challenging rivals.
Do not forget Halime and Wild Demir.
If God permits Tugtekin
will take Ertugrul's life.
I have no more endurance
left for him, brother.
He constantly blames
himself for his wife's death.
He always has a guilty conscience.
Crying every damn
day! And also groaning.
Day and night, he is putting me
through hell in his bed, marquee...
...everywhere, brother.
I am out of patience.
Be patient, Aytolun.
We should have my daughter
and Gundogdu get married first.
We should be in charge
first. Be patient.
Power syrup that I give him everyday
rules his heart and his breath.
One day I will add one more
drop of it and it will be over.
You  were impatient when
you were young as well.
We will take his marquee
first, then the nomad group.
Step by step.
Soon after that nobody will be able
to stand in front of us, brother.
You traitor scumbag!
It is correct that we
have a traitor among us.
But it's not me.
It has been your Alp
Kocash since the beginning.
This traitor scumbag has
lured both of us into a trap.
They should be here soon.
After the damage is done it has
a big price, right, Tugtekin?
I have buried too many like you.
Ulubilge.
So what did we do now, brother?
-Be silent, brother.
-I could not understand anything.
We have been waiting for infidel Mongols
but these scrubs came out.
Bamsi, can you still not understand?
What do you carry in your head
instead of a brain?
I am sorry Bey, forgive me.
It is just an empty head.
Sometimes, your words are
as empty as your head.
Come, Tugtekin.
Tugtekin.
Fiery Boy.
Now, go and tell the world
of Noyan's valor.
We have suffered many pains, fought
many battles from the fatherland to here
but we have never been down on our uppers
this much, daughter Halime.
If God permits, we will
overcome this, Wild Demir.
If God permits.
If Ertugrul Bey succeeds,
we will get rid of this pit.
Thank God, Bey.
What is it, Bey?
You are down in the mouth.
We could not triumph.
Why, Bey?
We were waiting for Mongols
Tugtekin stood against us.
But there was no sign of Mongols.
Bey, how did they know?
Gokce.
Satan is playing such a trick on us
that we forget in which land
we fool around.
-Bey, we shall set off then.
-Not now.
Mongols must be looking for us everywhere.
We are going to go to the cave, get ready.
Bey, the horses need to rest.
They must be exhausted
of fighting with us, too.
Turgut?
-Bamsi.
-Yes, Master.
What is the problem, son?
If someone sees you
they would think you never
cut a heathen's head.
That is true. I could not.
Is that why you are downcast?
No, Master.
Then why?
I upset Ertugrul Bey with this
billet-like empty head of mine
and this tuneless tongue of mine.
That is why I am mad.
Lions! Lions!
As long as you stand straight
behind our Bey like this
no one can bend us down,
no one can make us kneel.
With god's help.
God is greatest.
-God is greatest.
Each one would die for you, Bey.
I am glad I have them.
Yet I cannot give them the heathen's head.
The enemy is stronger than we thought.
I want to fight...
...but my hand is not ready.
I barely hold the sword.
Those days will come, too, Ertugrul.
Those days that you will shed
enemy's blood is near.
If I could not stop these tyrants
there will be nothing left
of my bravery or gallantness.
We are ready to go, Bey.
Devil can take him for all I care.
He thought being a Bey's son
was such prowess.
May your carrion fall prey.
Kocabash.
You will go to the nomad tent.
And say that Tugtekin died.
You will say, Ertugrul killed Tugtekin.
Let Kayi and Dodurga tribes
get up against each other.
Let them take each other's lives.
And I will come and take
the lives of the rest.
Take the road.
Kocabash!
You do not seem like you got out
of a battle at all.
Go on, goodbye!
Yes.
It is good like this.
Ulubilge, I feel a glow
of happiness today.
The sky is great.
The trees and birds are great, as well.
Ertugrul slipped through our fingers.
We could not kill them both.
Sometimes you are bulk headed, Tangut.
If you killed two people, then
you would have killed two people.
But now, Ertugrul is a living dead.
And the nomad tent is a fire ground.
They will get up against each other.
Each other.
Ertugrul was not the one who killed
Seljuk soldiers and abducted Ertokus.
What are you talking about, brother?
Unfortunately, that is the truth, Aytolun.
I have not a shadow of a doubt
that Ertugrul is guiltless.
But I am not sure whether
the truth or the lie...
...would serve our purpose.
I do not know how the matter
of Ertugrul will be solved
but Gundogdu and Goncagul must marry.
Then Gundogdu would always take your side.
We only need Hayme to allow this marriage.
We must seize Kayi, regardless
of the consequence.
First, I need to win Gundogdu's heart
then Hayme Hatun's heart for it.
Konya taught me the battles are won
in the hareem of the palace
not in the battlefield.
It seems that the nomad's marquee
and the Sultan's palace...
...are the real battlefield.
I pray every night, for you to die
so we could get rid of you, sister,
do you know?
Gokce, we both took the seeds of sin
inside us, from our father.
His greed, arrogance...
...grudge...
...and everlasting hatred.
My beautiful sister.
Thank God, I cleaned my soul
with the breath of his Ibn Arabi.
Now I am paying the price
for my sins, Gokce.
And you, sister...
...do not think that I do not know
what you are doing.
Your intention is not to marry
and build a happy family.
You have one care.
That is to vent your unrequited love
on Ertugrul and Halime.
Gokce, my beautiful sister.
Do not do that.
Remember your sister. You will burn
like a kindling in this sea of sin.
I am telling you for the last time.
Pull yourself together.
-Pull yourself together and...
-Enough!
Your heart has been defiled enough
to waste Tugtekin's love
for your sneaky vengeance.
You are cruel as my father
who wanted to kill Suleyman Shah.
Maybe every slap will remind you
who you are...
...who you are not and
who you can never be.
Maybe you will remember you grew up
with marquee's blessings.
And you need to be grateful.
Maybe you will remember
you reached the age of marriage
with the love of Suleyman Shah
and Mother Hayme
maybe you will repent and
get rid of this fiend inside you.
Get up!
Gokce.
Get out, daughter.
Selcan, what is this, daughter?
You are in a rage again.
I cannot stand, mother. I cannot stand.
No one sees what I see.
The devil called Aytolun
wants to ruin our marquee.
She wants to use Gundogdu and Gokce.
Selcan, that is enough. Enough.
You have troubles with Aytolun.
Gundogdu hates you.
You slapped Gokce.
Do you not come to heel, daughter?
That is enough.
Stop being apprehensive.
I want a tiny bit of peace.
Whatever a man sowed, he shall reap.
Selcan, know that I ran out of patience.
Aytolun, it is all over.
From now on, Aytolun
I will show what you are.
From now on
I have the right to be as sneaky as you
as vile as you as you.
Mother, I have no patience anymore.
She came to herself after she repented.
I was thrilled.
She slapped Gokce.
She completely lost herself.
It is not going to work, mother.
I will either be a killer or divorce her.
If you are tired that much...
...find another girl who can
give you a child, son.
But do not divorce Selcan.
A son of a Bey does not divorce
and turn his wife adrift.
It is not in accordance with our mores.
What if she does not consent me
having a second wife?
What if she brings bigger troubles to us?
We will think about it at that time.
If she does not behave herself, she can't
stay in my marquee and nomad tent.
Bey, apparently you wanted to see me.
I know you take a ride to collect grass
for your father every day.
But, I...
We shall sit down.
I witnessed what happened today.
I cannot look at my uncle's
and aunt's face.
Bey, Selcan is a troublesome a woman.
And it is obvious that you are merciful.
You have a heart so pure
to cast aside your wife
you have shared your bed with
for many years.
Your children had died one by one.
May God give you and her patience.
Apparently, all these pains
made her like this, Bey.
Not one, not two, five children
had joined the choir invisible
before they were born.
But you, Gundogdu Bey
you are the hope of Kayi.
I know that you have many burdens.
Being this sorrowful and alone
does not befit you, Bey.
Your words are as beautiful as your eyes.
Anyway, excuse me.
I shall go to headquarters.
Will you talk about Ertugrul?
I will.
Do you still believe that
Ertugrul is innocent?
Forever.
I want to you know, I believe your
brother is innocent, too, Gundogdu Bey.
Thank you.
I know Ertugrul Bey is innocent,
as much as you do, Hayme Hatun.
But that is not the point.
We must prove that Ertugrul is guiltless.
I know that you love my son
at least as much as Suleyman Shah.
I saw you were not pleased at all
when we took the head of Alps duty
from Ertugrul.
You only said okay with you hand shaking
just so there would not be duality.
Thank you.
But I want you to take my son's side
in this headquarters.
When we take a stand against
the rumors for him
we wish to see you with us.
Even if two nomad tents would burn,
I could not take the frame's side.
It would not befit me, our mores
and our religion.
You can rest assured, Hayme Hatun.
But the pitcher is full.
If one more drop falls...
...may God help us.
Kocabash slipped through the net again.
-Bey, what if he is not the betrayer?
-What if someone else is?
No, he is betrayer.
Even though his tongue says he is not,
his eyes represent Satan.
I am sure, he is the betrayer.
What will we do, Bey?
We shall to go to nomad tent and
make life unbearable for them.
There is no other way.
The dishes are ready.
I was going to eat my brain from hunger.
Brother, have you a brain to eat?
-Brother Dogan.
-Yes, brother?
Alright, I do not have brain.
You do, but you have not a mind.
-Are the brain and mind different?
-Yes, brother, they are.
You have not had your share of it.
Brother, we sent you off to train Alps
you became a leech, wonderful.
That is tutelage, brother.
The tutelage is something different.
Brother, the tutelage is
something different.
Ertugrul can never be in such a betrayal.
I want two nomad groups' Beys
to be one heart.
No one shall think my nephew is a traitor.
That is why I will join the headquarters.
Ertugrul is more dangerous
than we thought.
He has many fellow, including
Sultan in the palace.
Like he has his uncle in marquee.
He is calamity alive,
he is more calamity, dead.
It will be hard.
What happened, son?
I have no one left, Artuk Bey.
First, my mother and my father.
Then my brothers.
And now, Ertugrul Bey, Wild Demir,
Dogan and Brother Turgut.
Son, they will come back honorably.
Do not worry.
What if they do not come back?
What if I become an orphan again?
Do not worry about it, son.
God turns the evil to benevolence.
You will see Ertugrul Bey will come
to be relative for orphans.
Not just you, all oppressed migrants.
Mother, is there permission to come in?
Come in, son.
What is the matter, son?
Mother, you do not lie to me, I know.
Yet you do not tell the truth.
What are you talking about, son?
Halime and Wild Demir are not here.
You know where they are
but you do not tell me.
That offends me, mother.
They went to Sultan Aleaddin.
They left to take Sultan
the confidential papers of his state.
And they will tell the trap
which was set up for Ertugrul.
Mother, where did this paper come from?
I do not know where it came from
but I know who it came from.
From whom?
From the one I never believed he died...
...one I always said
would come back to us...
...from Sungurtekin.
Sungurtekin?
-My brother, Sungurtekin?
-Yes.
Mother, he is still alive?
He is alive and he will come back
here one day.
If God permits.
The drums are beating
for the headquarters.
We will talk later at length.
We need to go.
Wait a minute, mother.
Ertugrul.
Where does he get these news from, mother?
Erzurum is cold and deserted.
Which crane ends an urgent message
to him on these mountains?
Mother, what is my brother doing?
-Ertugrul Bey cannot be in a betrayal.
-How he could do this?
He cannot betray.
In God's name, the compassionate
and the merciful.
With 99 names of God Almighty.
Beys, dark clouds are upon us.
I wanted to talk the matter
with my headquarters' Beys
and find a solution.
Go ahead, have your say.
Our biggest matter is Ertugrul who
does not know custom and settle down.
He is still not found.
-Is that right, Beys?
-It is true.
I am scared that we will fall victim
to Sultan Aleaddin's wrath
who would save us from Mongols.
It seems that Ertugrul went to earth, Bey.
It is obvious that he is running away
from the mores and the justice of Sultan.
My brother fights by advancing on,
not by running away.
Gundogdu, he fights with whom?
First, he rioted against
Tugtekin Bey, then Seljuk's.
Is this his fight?
Right.
Are you talking about Ertugrul Bey
who took his life in his hands...
...and fought with Templars,
Mongols all this time?
These words are told with
courage of ignorance.
That is true. We acted foolishly
and did all we could
to unite two nomad groups.
We shared our daily bread.
Also, we shared our mattress.
We slept on land, cold and muddy.
So our brother, Kayis would not get hurt.
We shared everything
so their wounds would scab
and they can start over again.
-What did we get? Nothing.
-That is true.
Ertugrul is a traitor.
Do you not see that?
-What are you talking about?
-That is a lie.
We returned from war with Mongols...
...when Ertugrul was born.
Suleyman Shah was seriously wounded.
I commended him to Artuk.
He was unconscious.
I did not tell Hayme
so she would not be scattered.
I said he is healthy and
he is on the way, he is coming.
While Hayme was bringing
Ertugrul into the world
Suleyman Shah was facing death.
I took Ertugrul on my lap
after his mother.
I took him to Artuk Bey's tent of healing.
I laid him on his wounded father's bed.
I did so...
...he would know his father's scent
in case he died.
Ertugrul touched his father's face
with his tiny hands.
Suleyman Shah got refreshed.
He prayed and rendered thanks
to God Almighty, and said to his son
"May your tiny hands that enlivened your
father, be the cure for Oghuz's wound.
May your sharp eyes that looks like
Prophet Ali's sword, Zulfiqar
lead the way for Oghuz.
Even if all world comes down on you,
do not give up your path, son."
Ertugrul is a son, faithful
to his father's wish.
I have known it for ages.
Ertugrul is not a traitor!
And now, today, too, I know
even if all the world comes down on him
Ertugrul will do what is necessary.
He is right.
Thank you, Korkut Bey.
I wish to God Almighty,
that you are right.
And Ertugrul is innocent.
The soldier who got wounded in the battle
was wrong in his words.
If God permits.
Bey, Kocabash wants to attend
the headquarters.
He is wounded and he says
he has something to say to Beys.
-He asks for permission.
-Let him come in.
Kocabash?
Look at you, what happened?
Ertugrul Bey has attacked us
with his Alps, Bey.
-It is impossible!
-It is unbelievable!
Bastard's seed! Do you know
what you are saying?
I say what I saw. They did this to me.
Do you want an evidence?
That is the evidence.
-That is the evidence.
-Betrayers!
Well, what about Tugtekin? Where is he?
Bey, last time I saw him,
he fought like lions.
Then I saw that he was gravely wounded.
I lost my consciousness.
There were many dead bodies
when I opened my eyes.
But I could not find Tugtekin Bey
although I looked for him.
Lie! You are lying, are you not?
-Bey!
-Korkut Bey!
-Brother!
-Bey!
Bey! Are you alright?
Damned be the day you came
to my nomad tent.
Get out of here right now!
-Shame on you!
-You all are betrayers!
-You are betrayers!
-Get out of here!
-Betrayers!
-You all are betrayers!
Gather a search unit right now!
And they shall not return before
they find Tugtekin, alive or dead.
Traitors.
Where did they come from?
Why did they come?
He is right.
Now the pitcher is full. May God help us.
How could they do this?
They betrayed us.
Blood.
I am surrounded by blood.
Would it clean all this blood
covered in my hands
if I was washed in the river of Selenge?
Or the lustful water of Ulungur River?
Or Yenisey River?
If they come together
and pour to my hand...
...could they clean this much blood,
Ulubilge?
I claimed many brave men's lives today.
How it hurts me. How it burns me.
Tell me, Ulubilge.
How many more lives of brave Alps
will I take?
When will this pain end?
We gave them the universe.
That is true.
We wanted them to become one
with their brothers, Mongols
and reach the blessings of universe.
Certainly, brave men will come out
from them like Hamza and Abdurrahman.
They will be fellows for our way
and be wind for our swords.
We are going to conquer the universe
with Oghuz brothers.
But until that day,
they will follow their fool
insolent Bey and fight each other.
-Hamza, is that right?
-You are right, Baycu Noyan.
Neither our Alps nor people
will find peace
before those who sit on both
nomad groups' marquees go to hell.
What about you?
What do you think, Abdurrahman?
You are staying silent.
Ertugrul is the killer of
Tugtekin Bey and Alps...
...not just Ertokus and
Seljuk troops anymore.
Tell us, Abdurrahman.
What Kayi Alps are doing now?
Whom do they obey?
Mother Hayme or Korkut Bey?
Just as you wanted, Bancu Noyan.
Ertugrul's head will be cut.
From now on, Kayi and Dodurga tribes
will either drown in each other's blood
or they will submit to you.
There is no other way.
They will fight on your side,
while you conquer the universe.
Now, Tugtekin is painting in
glowing colors in the tent
how he chased us.
He should be thankful to Bey. Otherwise
we would bury them in the ground.
If our hands had their blood
we would not be able to return
to the nomad tent.
Bey, what will we do now?
Kocabash's treason will end.
This will end, one way or another.
Enjoy your supper.
-Bey, please, join us.
-I am short on time, Beys.
-I have news for you.
-I hope nothing is wrong, Artuk Bey.
Tugtekin Bey died.
How did that happen?
Kocabash told that you
and your Alps killed him.
Tugtekin.
Tugtekin. My son.
Duru.
Bey. Korkut Bey.
Please, pull yourself together. Bey.
Bey. It is me, Aytolun.
Look, I am with you.
Aytolun, we are paying
the price of our sins.
First my wife, then my son
paid the price...
...of our illicit relationship.
Now, it is my turn.
I know. It is my turn.
I believe Tugtekin did not die, Bey.
You will see, he will come back.
Do not do that. Dodurgas
want to see their Bey well.
Do not do that.
Kayi tribe will get out from
this nomad tent, tomorrow.
Kayi tribe is going to get out from
Now, I do not want them here.
After this, it is impossible.
It shall not be.
After this it is impossible.
I am here because I believe
you would not do it.
But no one else believes it, except me.
If you do not take action
within a short time
the nomad tent will turn into bloodbath.
-Did they find his body?
-No.
Mongols wanted to kill him
and calumniate me.
Satan will try to wangle.
Now every step you take
holds great importance.
-I shall go.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
-I will never forget your kindness.
-Thank you.
Do not get up.
Maybe he is alive.
We are going to look for him.
Get ready for it.
-All right, Bey.
-All right.
All our Alps are going to keep watch
with swords, all night long.
Mother, everything could happen
after this.
We cannot stay here.
If Alps of two nomad group
try to kill each other
it would be catastrophy.
We need to leave here
within a short time.
Otherwise, we could not answer
for it in afterlife.
I found out where Ertugrul is.
Go and bring him alive.
I will go and put pressure on
this ignoble Kocabash.
Mother? Where are you going at this hour?
-I am going to talk to Korkut Bey.
-Mother, what are you saying?
Alps are angry, one of them
might do something bad.
-You cannot go there alone.
-All Alps are my son.
They lost their Bey,
I know the pain they feel.
But do not worry about me.
Where have you been, Artuk Bey?
Alps are looking for you everywhere.
I am sorry, Aytolun Hatun.
There was a fevered patient
and I went to treat him.
I wish you have informed us.
Anyway, begin to treat right away.
Bey?
Aytolun, stop Korkut before
he does something crazy.
I do not care if he dies or not.
In fact, his death might serve
my purpose more.
A civil war would make me an unskilled man
in Aleaddin's eyes
-and everything will be over.
-I gave him medicine.
He will sleep all night long.
But these medicines would
harm him, brother.
If the need arises, put him to sleep
for keeps, just put him to sleep.
You know, I would do it. Be sure of it.
What does he say?
He will send off Kayi tribe
from his marquee.
Miserable! He will ruin the only
right thing he did in life.
Bey, Mother Hayme is here.
Invite her in.
Do not break ties with her.
-Talk to her carefully.
-Do not worry.
I want to see my brother.
He is not himself. He has a fever
and talks in his sleep.
We need to be thankful for it,
Hayme Hatun.
If he regains consciousness,
it would be catastrophe for all of us.
He lost his son, I am scared he will do
something crazy out of his pain.
You need to know that I hardly keep down
Korkut Bey, Alps and the people
in the absence of Tugtekin.
Thank you, Gumustekin.
You are doing the right thing.
The truth will show up itself
early or late.
Then we must be able to
look at each other's faces.
What does Artuk say about
my brother's condition?
He is concerned that Korkut Bey
will not make it to the morning.
If Ertugrul causes his death, too
and not just his son...
...we would all drown in the blood
that would be shed, Hayme.
Do not.
Tell them to go out.
Tell them!
Go out.
You saved my life.
But you believe your brother's words
instead of mine.
Ertugrul did this.
Turgut, Dogan, Bamsi and a looney man
called Wild Demir were with him.
They entrapped and hunted us one by one.
How did you run away from them?
It was difficult.
Well, how did Ertugrul...
...fight with Tugtekin
with a wounded hand?
Bey, first they shot arrows.
Then he fought with Ertugrul.
He took advantage from his wounded
hands and managed to run away.
I hope he is alive.
He would come and you can hear
everything from him.
I hope so.
We need to find Tugtekin, alive or dead.
I will take the road with Alps
who traces by far the best.
I shall come with you.
I shall come with you, Bey.
You stay here, you have no strength left.
Where did this happen?
Bey, what if they do something to you?
I would not even allow
their bodies to be buried
I would make them a prey for wolves.
Tell me, where were you?
In Kurtbogaz.
Gazelle eyed.
We are in the way of no return.
Be ready as if you can go to Konya
any moment.
Do not worry about me.
Now that I am on the road with you,
I would take if it is death or life.
If I do not return...
...if our baby is a boy,
raise him like an Alp.
He will undulate the flag I left.
Do not worry yourself, Bey.
Bey.
Take care of my wife and child, master.
Do not worry, Bey.
I would die than to give them.
May your path be bright, Bey.
Alps! Listen my words carefully.
None of us will sit here and
wait for Tugtekin Bey.
The truth will show itself.
There is no other way.
We will either eat each other
like hungry dogs
or slit our enemies' throat like wolves.
There is no other way. Now
if it comes to light that
my brother did it
I will not wait for the justice
of Seljuk or your rightful rage.
I will kill him with my own hands.
That is why we need to find Tugtekin,
right away.
Let us pray to God to find him alive.
And peace to come to our nomad tent.
-What is it, Bey?
-I am going to come with you.
I will not leave you alone at this hour.
Thank you, Bey.
Alps! In God's name.
Bey.
It is dawn but we had not
found a trace yet.
It seems like he went to earth.
You know, it saddens me
to tell you this
but you brother has become an
incorrigible highwayman, Gundogdu.
If you restrained him at the time
all these would not happen.
God give me pasions.
Bey, above all, we shall find Tugtekin.
Then we will talk about my brother.
I will look this way.
Go ahead.
Scatter around.
-Brother?
-Ertugrul, where have you been?
How could you kill Tugtekin?
I did not, brother.
Speak slowly. They are looking
for him everywhere.
I set a trap for Mongols through Kocabash.
But Tugtekin has learned it
from Gokce and came.
He wanted to fight.
When I did not want to fight,
he chased me.
Mongols killed him.
Ertugrul, what trouble you brought on us?
I believe you but how will you
convince others?
Brother, Kocabash is a traitor.
The trap was set up by him.
As long as you have this set of mind,
many trouble will come to us.
Return to the nomad tent.
-Let them adjudge you.
-Not now.
I will bring you to nomad tent
with my own hands.
Gundogdu!
Ertugrul, surrender.
You, go on.
Gundogdu!
Gundogdu?
There is no trace, Bey.
Do not tire yourself.
We shall return to nomad tent.
Wild Demir, we shall take the road
as soon as possible.
Our horses are brave, we will fly
like birds. Do not worry, daughter.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, welcome.
Welcome, Sheikh.
You are always ready to fight. God bless.
Thank you, Sheikh.
But the enemy does not get off our back.
So we cannot leave our swords.
Sheikh, please, sit down.
In God's name.
We sent off Ertugrul to fight with enemy.
But it has been a long time
and he did not come back yet.
Enemies are like Satan.
How?
Who helps the most
to make a man single hearted
to make a man one of
God's faithful servants?
It is the Satan.
The greatest helper to make a man
single-hearted is Satan.
Because if a man does not fight
with the devil and his desires
he cannot be single-hearted.
He cannot reach the true faith.
Satan, who believes himself
to be the wisest entity
trains his sight on a man and attacks.
He thinks he will mislead a man.
But actually, he is working day and night
so that man can be single-hearted.
Even if the Satan tries to mislead a man
a single-hearted man
would not buckle under him.
He would not yield to temptation.
And while he does not yield,
his faith gets stronger
his purity becomes more fertile.
The enemy is like Satan.
He keeps working to make a hero
of the man he thinks of killing
but does not realize that.
Daughter Halime, May God
ordain strong faith for us.
May he give us the will to fight
with enemy and Satan.
May he give us mind.
May he give us heart.
-Amen.
Well said, my Sheikh.
May God strengthen your heart.
-Amen.
Dervish, look after the vestry.
As you wish, Sheikh.
Brother, soon, you will sit there.
Aytolun, I do not care about
sitting on this stinky sheepskin...
...in this felt tent and ruling.
What do you say, brother?
All our effort, all the blood we shed...
What were they for?
I saw in Konya that a new world
is being formed...
...and nomads who follow their herds,
have no place in that new world.
We shall not shield Seljuk,
Seljuk should shield us.
It is time to find a home for ourselves
and take root on these fertile lands.
If we cannot do it by any means...
...this stinky sheepskin
would be our cerement...
...the grass would be our grave...
...and the winter quarters
would be our hell.
Our destiny is in seigniories
in the infidel towns...
...not in the tent of the nomad.
We will either keep up with this world
or become the whores of Mongols.
That is the matter.
Ertugrul says that he did not do it and
he does not say anything else, mother.
Kocabash!
So him saving your life...
...was a game to get closer to you.
And he managed that, mother.
I allowed Noyan's dog
to come into my tent.
Who knows what else he has done
behind my back.
While we are waiting for the war...
...Noyan had already won it
and we were not even aware.
So you finally came to
Ertugrul Bey's words.
You wanted to lock him in the tribe
like an old woman...
...using his wounded hand as an excuse,
from the beginning.
The more he told you about the storm,
the more you tried to crush him.
And when you could not do it,
you chased him out of the tribe.
But the storm is
in the middle of the tribe.
Tell me, what will you do now?
-What will you do now?
-Selcan!
Selcan is right.
Ertugrul was proven right again.
Mother, I do not know how we can solve it.
Kocabash. Traitor!
He is a traitor but how can we prove it?
How?
Mother.
I placed the Alps in the front
and back of the marquee.
What are you saying, son?
Mother, Dodurga Alps are angry.
This fire will burn both tribes.
What was I supposed to do?
We want the killer of our brain.
We want justice.
We want the killer of our Bey.
If something happens to me...
...take care of the tribe.
Bey, if something happens to you,
we would be eager to come to your side.
Then, come to my side after
I arrange the order there and all.
Bey.
Gundogdu Bey calls for you.
If I cannot solve it, I will inform you.
Wait around the tribe.
Are you ready to sacrifice yourself
for the future of the tribe?
I set my heart to die
for the tribe and people.
I am going to wait, today and tomorrow.
But I want Kocabash to be punished
as he deserves.
Do not worry about it,
he will be punished.
Give me your blessing.
We do.
We do, Bey.
Bey, allow us to come with you.
One Ismail who will put his head under
the knife is enough, Brother Turgut.
Do as I said.
Brothers, do not forget.
God is the biggest of the game breakers.
Take care of yourselves.
Allahuakhbar.