Episode 59 will start after 12:35 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
My Steel Mountain mightier than
the sun has heard my voice.
My Golden Mountain
mightier than the moon,
my Ethel Tree mightier than the axe,
they all answered my call.
Now, the time has come for bloodshed.
Now, the sacred trees adorned with
clothes are screaming for revenge.
Flames burn brighter with
the scent of your flesh.
You came here to meet
your end in my hands.
Did you think you would get away
with all the blood you shed, Noyan?
Now is the time to pay.
Let us see if Kobek, your partner
in all this will save you this time?
I wanted you, Ertugrul.
And Sadettin gave you to me.
I knew you would come
here to meet your own end.
Let's see who leaves
here as a corpse.
Since Kobek gave me to you,
come and get me then.
Holy spirits will become more
powerful with your blood, Ertugrul.
In the name of the spirits!
Attack, servants!
God!
What happened to you?
Ertugrul's Alps.
They were lying in ambush
on the road, his Ameer.
Bogac?
They killed everyone but
they took him, his Ameer.
So they captured him alive.
Ertugrul!
Welcome to Noyan's hell, Ertugrul.
Noyan!
Bamsi! Wait.
Ertugrul Bey should deal with Noyan.
The gallant man feeds on blood, Ertugrul.
You will drown in your own blood, Noyan.
Did you think it would be that easy?
It won't be easy.
You won't pay this easily
for what you did
to Gokce Hatun, Tugtekin Bey, Wild
Demir, Aykiz and the baby in her womb.
This is just the beginning, Ertugrul.
Do you think your little baby
will grow up and ride ponies?
I will not allow that,
for as long as I am alive.
Everyone in your nomad group and who
stands by you will all be dead.
Why aren't the spirits
on my side?
Why, Bey?
Why won't you kill that bastard?
Since when do you question
my orders and authority, Turgut?
This fire feeds with which carcass?
Dogan. Bamsi.
Take where the horses are.
-Tie them.
-As you wish, Bey.
As you wish, Bey.
You will regret you did not
kill me, Ertugrul.
They were beloved lieges of God.
He took their lives together.
May he not deny them his mercy.
Hatun...
...your pain is my pain.
The tears you shed are my tears.
We have been through
many calamities with you.
We will get through this, too,
if God permits.
Gokce was a piece of my heart.
She was more than my own heart,
one I raised myself...
...one I was with through her
every trouble.
I buried my three children
before I suckled them.
And now, my sister.
All we wanted was a sprinkle of peace.
A sweet smile.
We gave them all to black earth, Bey.
Get up.
Selcan.
The peace we are looking for
is here, in your belly.
We will see the peace we look for
and those sweet smiles on our
child's face, if God permits.
If God permits, Bey.
Come.
-May it be easy, Hatuns.
-Thank you.
-May it be easy.
-Thank you, Halime Sultan.
Your rags, your weaves are so beautiful,
Hatuns. May God bless your hands.
Thank you.
We have learned it from you to make
the blue in our rugs as the sky
and the yellow as the sun, Halime Sultan.
-Not at all.
-You have put so much effort in us.
Thank you, Hatuns.
If only the grass we fed
our animals were more lush
then our wools would be
more stuffed, Halime Sultan.
And the plants we dye
our rugs with are sparse.
If only we had more fertile lands
and we would cheer.
If God permits, we will have lands
like that, Hatuns.
Their pastures vast
their meadows full with plants
that will enliven our rugs.
One of a kind, earth's most fertile lands.
Where is it, Halime Sultan?
The lands in which we will feed our flocks
we will weave our rugs nicer
and sell are there.
Hatuns, I am talking about
Byzantine border.
The only place on earth, with wild
waters flowing from its springs
where we will get grace from its
ground and booty from our enemies
where we will be bigger,
stronger is there.
So you kidnapped Noyan, too, Ertugrul.
I will not let you reach Sultan.
Summon Sungurtekin Bey to me at once!
He will come to me immediately.
What is Bey doing, Dogan Brother?
Will he set Noyan free like Gundogdu Bey?
How could that be, mountains' bear?
What will he do, then?
How would I know?
Turgut Brother? Tell me, what will happen?
I have not seen Turgut like this before.
And the look he gives to Ertugrul Bey.
May God render our end well.
Why, Bey?
Why?
What will you do with these ignobles?
What is it you want to do?
How many more lives he must take
like Tugtekin Bey and Gokce Hatun
for you to kill him?
Is this how you will avenge Aykiz,
Wild Demir, all the lives we lost?
Do you think everyone is
as manly as you are, Turgut?
That is why I say, they must die, Bey.
That is why I say, take their lives.
If we kill them, it means we have lost
the battle we carried until now.
It means all that blood shed
will not be brought to books.
I do not his carrion, I need him alive.
Hold your rage, Turgut.
If we do not make him pay for
all this blood, then who will, Bey?
I want them to appear before
Sultan Aleaddin along with Yigit.
Do you still not see?
I do not, Bey. I do not.
I have had enough. I have had
enough of all these games.
Enough!
Turgut!
I do not want to see a weak,
desperate Alp before me.
What kept me standing all this time
was the vengeance within me, Bey.
You took it away from me.
Since you do not want to see
a desperate Alp before you
then I shall go on my way.
Bey.
Get on your horse, Bamsi.
You cannot even look out
for your Alps, Ertugrul.
Shut up, wounded boy.
We are leaving.
Halime.
Selcan.
What do you tell the nomad tent's women
with your silver tongue?
Please, tell me, too.
I say there are always better,
more fertile lands, Selcan.
Are you saying it for migration?
Gundogdu Bey, Sungur Bey...
...many Beys of Kayi tribe, Dodurga tribe
do you not know what they want?
Would not what you say
separate us from each other?
Would there ever be separation
between us, Selcan?
You are my sister.
Who else do I have in this world
other than you?
Halime.
I lost Gokce.
What would I do if I lose you, too?
I beg you, talk to Ertugrul Bey,
convince him.
I left Gunduz with Banu Cicek, Selcan.
I should go to the marquee.
Selcan.
What is happening, child?
Halime.
She tells about the fertile lands
she will migrate to
to the women, Hatuns of nomad group.
Mother. Please.
These mean separation.
Do not allow separation.
I beg you, mother.
Do not let them leave us.
Stop them.
Stop.
Ertugrul.
What are you after again?
Our Bey's and his wife's blood
is left unavenged.
And migration is at the door.
We do not know what to do, Bey.
Our duty is to not leave our
nomad group without a leader, first.
We can only find a solution
for migration like that.
And we will avenge Bey's and his wife's
blood, with God's allowance.
These ignobles will pay for what
they did, one by one, if God permits.
Artuk Bey is right.
Everything has its time.
As long as there is a wise Bey as
yourself, we will surmount this, too.
Thank you.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Akca Bey.
I see you do not leave
our marquee empty, Artuk Bey.
Our marquee is the heart of Dodurga,
Akca Bey.
It will always overflow with
fresh blood, with God's help.
I see the ardor for seignory
bestirs everyone's heart.
Seignory is not a position
of ambition, Akca Bey.
Seignory is a heavy burden God Almighty
bestowed upon mankind.
It is time to gather
the headquarters immediately
and choose the brave man that
will go under that burden.
It is time, Bey. It has come.
-It is true. It is time.
-Time has come.
Our headquarters is all our destiny,
Akca Bey.
Let the ones who seek to be Bey,
be clear tomorrow.
So we can solve this matter erewhile.
Our nomad group shall not be left
without a leader.
-May the best happen.
Beys, let us set off immediately.
Ameer Sadettin is waiting for us.
Selcan!
What is it, Hatun? Dark winds
are blowing inside you again.
When did dark winds ever
leave upon our heads, Bey?
However, as long as you are with me
no one can shatter the marquee
of my heart.
Do not worry.
Tell me, now. Who broke your heart?
I saw her as my sister.
I said, I have no other sister
after Gokce but her.
But she will leave me alone, too.
Who are you talking about, Hatun?
Were we not the branches
of the same tree, Bey?
Tell me, Hatun. Who are you talking about?
Halime Sultan.
She tells women about the fertile lands
she will migrate to, at the rug workshop.
I told my mother, too.
Stop it, Bey.
Do not allow it.
Did we not go through many
long winters and reach spring?
Do not let them separate us
from each other.
Wherever we will go,
let us go together, please.
Halime!
Is what Selcan said true?
It is, mother.
When our nomad group
is in all this trouble
when we are mourning for the ones we lost
when it is not certain what
will happen to your brother
when it is not certain how will your man,
Ertugrul get rid of Ameer Sadettin
are you attempting to do these?
Mother, I know what I said.
Yet as you know...
I know, of course.
I know. You do not act like a Bey's wife.
What does it mean to beguile women?
Mother, is my duty not going on
my husband's path?
If Suleyman Shah was alive
would you leave him alone
on the range he will reach?
Of course, I would not. I would not.
But you cannot meddle with
nomad group's matters.
I am a Bey's woman.
Even a leaf would not move
without me knowing it.
Look, Halime Sultan.
I will not allow anyone
to tear Suleyman Shah's
nomad group in pieces.
And you shall know it.
You did not fall prey to blind pharaohs'
cravings at this young age, Shahzada.
You proved you are as trustworthy as
your kin and as brave as your name.
You should know,
you not coveting to sedition
is one of greatest deeds
in the presence of God.
May God keep your path bright.
Ertugrul.
Yigit!
Yigit.
Would you believe? Look at little Sultan.
He does not fit oceans.
Dogan. Bamsi.
-Tie them up thoroughly.
-As you wish, Bey.
You have came to the end of another duty
drawn in your fate, Ertugrul Bey.
You will sow this cloth of mission
woven with many secrets, many pains
into a caftan of taintless hope.
You should know, in this twilight
we fell into
you will be the dawn of Islam.
If God permits.
The ones of your own blood
will oppose you.
Do not hesitate and sink into despair.
Do not forget...
...God would not leave the ones who
fights the holy wars on his path alone.
You have been a remedy in many dark times.
You have shared my trouble, and have
been the light on my path. Thank you.
Come on.
You shall know you will always be
in my prayers.
May God keep your path bright,
Ertugrul Bey.
What are the five conditions
of shooting arrows?
Bow, string, arrow, thumb ring, master.
What would a master know in a good arrow?
Wood, horn, glue, sinew.
Whether you pull the bow from your eyes
from your mustache or from your chest
you will never forget two things.
-What were they?
-Devotion and patience.
-Good.
-Why devotion, Sungurtekin Bey?
What is the most beautiful path
that makes mankind reach to
God Almighty, and attain his love?
-Devotion, Bey.
-Devotion.
Just as devotion is fearing God Almighty
and keeping our hands off and getting
away from the things he forbade
an archer's devotion is keeping
his hand, his eyes, his heart away
from whatever it is preventing him
from reaching his target.
What are these?
Wind, humidity, misgiving, apprehension.
Never forget. Devotion is patience.
Patience is the nature of the archer.
Bows on eye level!
-With the name of God!
-God, grant me!
What is it, brother?
Ertugrul is really out of his way,
brother.
He rebels against Sultan's edict outside
and against Bey's words inside.
What are you saying, brother?
Halime Sultan speaks with
Alp's women, with their sisters.
She calls them to be a martyr
on Ertugrul's way.
We need to find and stop him, brother.
Brother, you have been gone for long.
You do not know how stubborn Ertugrul is.
He would reach his destination with
his hands if you tie his feet
with his teeth if you tie his hands.
He will go. He will go to that
accursed Byzantine border.
And he will ruin this nomad tent
reminiscence of his father
when he leaves.
We must find where he hides.
There is no other way to stop him.
Is there something you know, brother?
I do not know, brother.
I do not know anything anymore.
Brother, tell me if you know.
I will go and settle this myself
without getting anyone involved.
After I surrender Shahzada to Sultan
no one can call neither my mother
nor Ertugrul to account.
Brother, if someone can solve this matter
without blood, that is me.
Tell me, if you know where he is,
for Ertugrul, for Halime Sultan
for their little baby in the cradle.
Look, Akca Bey.
Artuk Bey's closeness
with Ertugrul is apparent.
What worries me, he will stand
for seignory tomorrow
and be the head of Dodurga.
If Artuk Bey becomes the head of Dodurga
I am worried he will participate
in Ertugrul's adventures.
Do not worry, Ameer Sadettin.
We will not lose our nomad tent
as casualty of anyone's adventures.
You must do what is needed, Beys.
If you do not stop it
your nomad group will be in calamity.
Akca Bey, there is a matter I will speak
with you about. Beys are done here.
You are a brave Bey.
And you think about your nomad group.
I see it.
And you are worthy of being
the Bey of Dodurga. I know.
Like the late Korkut Bey,
like his son, brave Tugtekin
you will be an honorable Bey for Dodurga.
These gold will help you
open the sealed eyes of Beys
who lost their insight.
Thank you, his Ameer.
May God grant you to us.
They will learn, no one, no nomad group
can choose a Bey without my permission
nor migrate to wherever they like.
Who rebels against your might
will find us before him, his Ameer.
You will tell Sultan Aleaddin
everything when we reach him.
To save you from Kobek?
I would rather bite my tongue
and cut it off than to do that.
Bey, what will happen to Turgut Brother?
Was Turgut not the one who said,
your path is our path, Dogan?
When I said, this path
is the oath of ordeal
not everyone can reach the target...
...was he not the one who said, we
can die for you if necessary, Bamsi?
I ask you. It is time for him
to draw his path.
We will all see, if he will draw his path
with his anger that preys on his mind
that weakens him or with his Bey's words.
On this path that is thinner than hair,
sharper than sword, revenge is important.
Yet, mind is more important.
Noyan tormented me the most.
However, this is not a matter of revenge,
it is a matter of continuity of state.
If we cannot take this ignoble
to Sultan Aleaddin
Kobek will do the greatest harm to state.
-Did you understand?
-Yes, Bey. Understood clearly.
Look at me, Bogac.
You will keep your mouth shut, alright?
If you want to get rid of here,
you will wait for Kobek to come.
Do you understand?
I do.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-You have what you wanted, Bey.
-Not yet, Artuk Bey. Not yet.
How are things at the nomad tent?
Dodurgas will have the headquarters
tomorrow, Bey.
You will be Dodurga's Bey, Artuk Bey.
If you become Bey, we will be stronger
on the Byzantine border.
As you wish, Bey.
Go to nomad tent immediately.
Do not tell anyone what you saw here.
-I will come to nomad tent, too.
-Alright, Bey.
Yigit.
Yes, Bey.
We will set off with these
ignobles tomorrow.
We will reach to Sultan Aleaddin.
We will explain the situation.
-Halime Sultan will come with us, too.
-As you wish, Bey.
Aykiz.
She walked tall.
With long black hair
that fell to her feet.
With eyebrows tightened like a bow.
With a mouth too small for almond.
With red cheeks like the apple of autumn.
How will you arise and reach me
from where you went?
I am the one who fell to your infinity...
...and who waits for death on your path.
Forgive me, father.
I could not keep the promise I made.
I could not abide Bey's doings.
I could not make him pay...
...that ignoble who took you
and Aykiz from me.
Every breath I take is a burden,
Demir Father.
It would not befit me to walk on the paths
Aykiz's boot has not touched, father.
The anvil your hand does not touch
your shop that your hearth does not
fume is forbidden to me.
I cannot fit to these lands anymore.
My nomad tent is forbidden to me, father.
Forgive me, father.
Forgive me, father!
Forgive me!
Forgive me.
Tell me.
What did you do that makes you frown
like in your childhood?
My brother, Ertugrul preys on our mind.
They say, "Each tree creates
its own mite."
They were right, mother.
He slowly carves our marquee.
Ertugrul will shatter my father's trust
upon our heads, mother.
It is time to say stop.
Tell me what is on your tongue.
The path Ertugrul follows
is not right, mother.
And Halime Sultan, in his absence...
The range he will reach will divide
into two our nomad group.
I say, is it not the time to gather
the headquarters immediately?
Do you think this nomad group
does not have a head?
Who are you to dare to come
before me and say these?
How quickly you forgot
who is the head of Kayi.
Mother. If it continues like this
Ertugrul will not only
divide the nomad group
but he will also shed the blood
of someone from us.
If that happens, Ertugrul will not be
my son any longer.
And he will not find a place
in this nomad group.
You should get it through your heads.
Aykiz.
My mother has a weakness for Ertugrul.
It was like this yesterday,
and today, too.
I say, blood will be shed
if it continues like this
she keeps silent, still waits for
Ertugrul to do what he will.
Then, what is necessary will be done.
This marquee that is my father's trust
is too precious to hand in to
Ertugrul's blind fancies.
-I will tell him to stop no matter what.
-How will we do that, brother?
What is Turgut doing here?
Then where is Ertugrul?
Let us go and sound him out.
Once, when Wild Demir was making
this weapon you carry...
...he said, "This thing is forged
with love, not rage."
And again, he said
"If you will release your anger,
do not use the iron
do it by reaping the enemy
with what the iron forged."
It is not clear who is friend
and who is enemy, anymore, Bey.
Sometimes enemy is right
beside us, Turgut Alp.
And sometimes, right within us.
Our rage blinds us, deafens us. And
we do not hear the cries of the enemy.
Their obstinacy, their rage
blunts them so much
that they do not see they have become
enemies of their the most loved ones.
These are the times we are blind
to anyone but ourselves, Bey.
We wallow in our darkness
and then drown in it.
We hold the ignobles we took an oath
to avenge like pigeons in our hands
and wait for them to bite us like a snake.
The ones who killed Aykiz
Wild Demir, Gokce Hatun, Tugtekin Bey...
...have now became pigeons
in Ertugrul Bey's hands.
I cannot live in these lands anymore.
It is time everyone goes on their own way.
Apparently, some problem occurred
between him and Ertugrul.
Ertugrul is after some games again.
Each game of his games
turn around and hit us.
We must find Ertugrul hastily, brother.
Ertugrul must be
in the Geyikli cave, Sungur.
Go and tell him to stop, immediately.
And surrender Shahzada Yigit to Sultan.
And I will do all I can
to become the Bey here.
Where is this cave, brother?
On the east of Kirac Hill,
at the end of the valley.
Follow the pathway,
it will take you there.
Sungurtekin Bey, Ameer Sadettin
is expecting you at his place.
Go, at once. Let us find out what is
Ameer Sadettin's bother?
And do not trust him much,
do not tell him where Ertugrul is.
I do not care about
Ameer Sadettin, brother.
All I care about is there being
no fight for throne
between Sultan Aleaddin and Shahzada.
We can hardly find a ruler
like Sultan Aleaddin again.
Alright, go on.
Is there permission, Halime Sultan?
Come in, Banu Cicek.
Come.
What is it? Did something happen?
I saw one of Ameer Sadettin's soldiers
with Sungurtekin Bey.
The soldier said some things and left.
Then Sungurtekin Bey left in haste.
He left the nomad tent as soon as
he got on his horse.
Halime Sultan, apparently Sungurtekin Bey
is going to that ignoble.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
My horse's nail fell. I want you
to look at it, blacksmith.
I am not a blacksmith.
But I will still take a look.
Thank you.
It needs a new one.
Thank you, brother.
I could not know what to call you.
-Bestow your name.
-Turgut Alp.
I have always heard of Ertugrul Bey.
So you are his Alp.
You must have devoted yourself to this
labor out of boredom, after Mongols left.
My name is Doruk Bey.
My nomad group moved to Byzantine border.
So you are going to Byzantine borders?
Yes.
I came here to buy Arabian horses
for my nomad group.
And now I am returning.
Is Ertugrul Bey in the nomad tent?
A brave man like him surely would not
wander at the nomad tent.
He must be on duty with his Alps.
And you are here.
I will do its work, then you can come
and get your horse.
However you wish, Turgut Alp.
I will stay here tonight.
I will take my horse when I leave.
It is not necessary.
Thank you, Turgut Alp.
Give your blessings.
I do.
Gunduz.
Know, you will not live the life of
an exile like your mother and your uncle.
You will live under the shadow of
the sycamore your father will plant
with your head held high.
With people of your own blood and
at your own home, if God permits.
Mother.
Mother, if I said a wrong thing
and hurt you, forgive me.
Our children are such a beauty
God gives us...
...they are unique.
These are the best times of Gunduz,
savor it.
Yet, when Gunduz grows up
someday, you, too will carry the burden
my four lion hearted sons gave me.
You will struggle over
to keep them together
to see them happy, to always have them
with you on your meals.
Mother.
And once you have another child,
when there is discord among them
remember my words.
Then you will understand me.
A mother's toughest duty is to remove
the duality among her children.
Do you understand me?
Do not forget my words.
Even if Ertugrul wants separation,
you will tell him to stop.
Apparently, Turgut Brother
is in wrong, Bamsi.
Bey's intention is to unravel
Kobek's cunnings.
Yes.
Let us say, Turgut Brother made
a great blunder, did we not, brother?
Did we not repine to our Bey from within?
Did we not douse our insides
to mud with manifold misgivings?
Alright, but brother, what is leaving
your Bey and walking away?
Did we not resent our Bey
because he did not tell Turgut not to go
when he was leaving, brother?
What are you saying, brother?
Brother, I am saying, let us look for
mistakes and sins inside us, first.
Turgut Brother fell into negligence.
He did but what we did, brother?
Is there permission, Bey?
Bey.
Is there permission?
Sit.
Turgut Alp made a mistake, Bey.
And we made two mistakes, Bey.
He fell into negligence, too, Bey.
And we fell into negligence twice,
thinking about what our Bey did, Bey.
Forgive him, Bey.
Not only him, forgive us, too.
We resented your decision.
We made a mistake.
Did I not tell you this was a long path...
...before we set off on this path?
-You did, Bey.
This path is woven with many pains,
many troubles?
-You told, Bey.
-You told.
Did I not say, in the battle arena
you are only as gallant as your sword...
...where your swords cannot reach
you will be defeated by your weaknesses
and you lose the battle?
-You did, Bey.
Now, I am asking, are you sure
to walk on this path with me?
We were raw when we got on this path, Bey.
But now, we understood,
we are not experienced enough.
To be burnt like you, Bey,
has not been destined to us yet.
Forgive us, Bey.
We will set our hearts to burn as you
on this path, Bey, you should know.
And about Turgut...
He will get experienced on his own path
like all brave men.
May God keep his path bright.
Amen, Bey.
We will take Halime Sultan and
set off in the morning. Be ready.
-As you wish, Bey.
I believed in you. I trusted you.
And what happened?
Nothing. A big nothing.
You could not even bring news
from Shahzada or Ertugrul.
I did whatever I did for our state,
for Sultan Aleaddin.
I will solve this myself, Sungurtekin Bey.
You should know.
Will you confront my brother, Ertugrul
with your soldiers, his Ameer?
If need be, yes.
Tell me, Sungurtekin Bey, what would
you do if you were in my shoes?
Did Hayme Hatun come to my door say
"I will surrender my son
to Sultan Aleaddin, myself,
if necessary."? She did.
You!
Did you, yourself tell me you will
deal with this matter? You did.
Did I move a finger? No.
Why?
Out of my respect to Kayi Beys
whom I have no doubt
on their honor, their word.
I did not set my soldiers
on the nomad tent. Why?
For not to shed brother blood.
So Kayis, who fought like lions
against Mongols would not get hurt.
Do you not see it either? Tell me.
Do you not know what would happen to me
if I cannot solve this matter
before Sultan Aleaddin comes?
How would I answer him?
I know where Ertugrul is.
Is that so? How do you know it?
I found out.
Tell me, Sungurtekin Bey. Tell me
so this matter can be over now.
I was assigned by Sultan Aleaddin
to solve this matter.
And I will take care of it,
Ameer Almighty.
As you see, my brother is involved.
Perchance, your soldiers
get involved in this matter
what would the situation be like?
I cannot allow it.
You should understand me.
Then solve this matter, Sungurtekin Bey.
Or else, the state's iron fist
will go down on Ertugrul's
and Kayis' neck.
You should know it like this.
I have waited all these years
to reach Aykiz.
Do I not know, my bloody violet set
her eyes on the road in our tent
waiting for me. Do not I know?
How cannot I come running to you
when I know this, Aykiz?
Is there permission, Turgut Alp?
Come, Turali.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Are you going to quit me
like Wild Demir, too?
Come, sit down.
From now on, I confide the nomad tent
to you. Look after the nomad tent.
That is what Wild Demir said
before he left, too.
A brave man must be on his path.
Wild Demir attained martyrdom
on his path, too.
Our share is to say, may God
destine us the same.
-Be strong, my lad.
-Do not go, Bey.
-Is there permission, Turgut Alp?
-Yes, Bey.
Is your decision absolute?
It's time, Bey.
Is Ertugrul the reason?
Turgut Alp.
I have been thinking about what
you said at Wild Demir's shop.
Ertugrul and Noyan are at Geyikli cave,
is that so?
Look, Turgut Alp, brother.
Tell me the truth thoroughly.
Tell me, so I can stop Ertugrul
before he acts foolishly again.
There is one thing I know, and that is
I cannot stay here anymore, Bey.
Only his Bey can bend
a brave man like you.
Tell me, what is Ertugrul's intention?
He wishes to take Noyan and Yigit
to Sultan Aleaddin, Bey.
Noyan, too?
Do not ask more. I do not know
what is right or wrong anymore, Bey.
Sultan Aleaddin's loyal Alp, Ertugrul.
You are still loyal to Sultan even while
he is coming to take your head.
You do not see, if you go on like this,
you will lose your head.
You both will loosen your tongue
when you go to Sultan's presence.
You are right, Ertugrul.
Fear of death would make one do anything.
Gokce Hatun loosened her tongue
before I cut her throat, too.
Turgut Alp's woman, before
she burned furiously
she was the same.
She loosened her tongue, too.
She was begging, "Do not do it,
I am with a child."
Yet, I am not like them, Ertugrul.
Death is an honor for me.
What is the matter, Ertugrul?
Why are you silent?
Do you think you will scare me with death?
I said what I needed to.
Do your worst.
You should know, you will regret
not killing me. I will keep my oath.
Whoever is in your blood, I will
kill them all with my own hands.
Let us see if you will have the pleasure
I had, when you batten my hand.
Gundogdu, I do not see Sungurtekin.
Where is he?
Ameer Sadettin summoned him
to caravansary, mother.
What bother would Ameer Sadettin have,
he called my son?
I do not know, mother.
Whenever Ameer Sadettin calls Sungurtekin
you fall out with Ertugrul.
He wishes to sow discord among brothers.
Do you still not understand it?
You talk nice, you are right, mother.
But you always look outside for wrong.
However, the wrong is within us.
Turn around and look at
what your son, Ertugrul does.
Gundogdu.
What happens with your own blood
shall stay within your own blood.
Do not you know matters
about your brothers
about your marquee shall not be
let out of nomad tent?
My mother is right, brother.
Why do you not sit and talk
with my brother but do this?
Do not meddle in your elders' business.
Eat your food.
I am from this marquee, too, brother.
I have a right to say a few words
on my mother's dinner, too.
Ertugrul is done and now
will we deal with you?
I do not know what bother
you have with Ertugrul Brother.
Yet, it is quite clear who is in wrong.
Dundar!
Enough!
Dundar, he is your brother.
If it continues like this Ertugrul Brother
will not be by our side one day.
I hope you listen to his words carefully.
Or we will all suffer from it.
Dundar, you crossed well beyond your line.
Gundogdu! Dundar! Stop!
By your leave, mother.
Dundar, tell me, brother.
Did Ertugrul make your blood
boil against us, too?
May my blood be sacrificed for
Ertugrul Brother's path, brother.
But, you with this fury of yours,
who knows whose blood you will boil?
You come to my mother's marquee
and ask for a headquarters, brother.
You are not cut to become a Bey.
Shame on you.
Look at what state my sons are in
at Suleyman Shah's marquee.
Brothers cannot sit down to the same meal.
Either you pull yourselves together
and behave as it suits you
or I know what I will do.
We will rummage everywhere.
We will not return until we find them.
Child.
-Who is this brave Alp?
-Ertugrul Bey.
Do you know where Ertugrul Bey's Alps are?
I am one of his Alps.
I knew you were a brave young man.
Tell me. I saw Turgut Alp
entering the marquee.
He has prepared his horse and belongings.
Apparently, he will go far away.
He would not leave Ertugrul Bey.
He will return.
You are not telling me what happened.
But you are always welcome
to my marquee, son.
I have never seen you,
Ertugrul's other Alps
any different than my own sons.
I know, Mother Hayme.
If you want to return...
There is no return for me anymore,
Mother Hayme.
Give your blessings.
I give my blessings, son.
May God keep your path bright.
Turgut Alp.
You are a very precious Alp for us.
We have been to many battles together,
reached to many destinations.
Do not do it. This nomad group needs you.
Thank you, Bey. But this is it for me.
I cannot stay here any longer
when my heart is burning
for reunion with my beloved.
-Understand me.
-Alright.
-Let me kiss your hand, Bey.
-There is no need, brother. Come here.
Even your closest Alp cannot bear you.
Tell me, brother.
Why would you assign Halime Hatun to
talk to persuade people into migration...
...when everything is a mare's nest?
What are you trying to do?
I said what I needed to, brother.
Whoever wants to come with us on this
blessed path for holy war, to settle...
...my path is their path,
their life is my life.
I have nothing to say beyond this.
Shame, brother, shame.
You have really lost your way.
How quickly you forgot
what Suleyman Shah said...
...when he was breathing
his last on our hands!
Father! Father! Father!
I confide my nomad group to you.
Protect our nomad group
from every malice...
...as your wives, as your children.
Obey to our ancestor Oghuz's mores...
...and Seljukian, the state of these
mores.
Be one and alive.
Is this how you will protect our unity,
our amity?
Suleyman Shah is the one who
opened my path, brother.
Yet, your eyes have been so branded,
you keep wallowing beyond blindness.
-Ertugrul...
-Gundogdu!
Ertugrul!
What do you do besides talk about unity
and amity and do the opposite?
You are at one place, Gundogdu,
at another place.
Sungurtekin is at another.
Dundar is at another.
For how much longer this will continue?
It will, mother.
As long as you appeal to Ertugrul,
it will.
With rebel Shahzade and Halime Hatun
who provokes people...
...by your side and Sultan's furious army,
on other side.
When all these are clear, which Alp would
reach to ultimate reunion with you?
Tell me.
Brother, do not do this.
Let Sungurtekin perform
the mission he was assigned.
Let him kill my brother, is that
what you say, Gundogdu Bey?
Halime!
I will not let Sungur or you do something
you will regret later, brother.
Both Sungurtekin and you gave your
leash on Kopek's hands such a way...
Ertugrul!
Gundogdu, Ertugrul!
Ertugrul, what will you do?
Tell me, what will you do, son?
I will take the road with Halime, mother.
Yigit will come with us, too.
I will appear before Sultan.
I will explain all that happened.
Kopek's games...
...Gumustekin, Noyan.
What they did to Tugtekin and Gokce.
Do you think Sultan would believe you?
He will, brother.
That is all I will say.
I have always believed in you, son.
Even though every word coming
out of your mouth wounded us...
...I saw they were true.
Perhaps, you are right.
But what good would being right do?
After all these pains...
...do not put us through pain of
separation.
If Sultan believes my words
and lets us live...
...I will migrate to Byzantium border
with gallant men who believe in me.
That is all I will say, Mother.
Give your blessings.
I have nothing else to say.
He will not give up, Mother.
Is this how it would be, son?
Would Suleyman Shah's blessed marquee
witness to these, too?
May whatever is best for us happen,
Mother.
Come, Dodurga headquarters
is waiting for us.
I have been waiting for the moment
I will reach my brother for so long.
Thank God, I saw it, too. Thanks to you.
But there is a matter I want you to know,
Ertugrul.
Sungurtekin Bey went to Ameer Sadettin.
He was not at dinner either.
I fear Sungurtekin Bey will do something
bad to my brother.
We must take the road at once,
Halime Sultan.
We have not time to lose.
In the 99 names of God Almighty,
the merciful, the compassionate...
...who fills our heart
with divine light of faith.
Dodurga's gallant and glorious Beys...
May God let Tugtekin Bey rest in heaven...
...he who reached God's grace while he was
fighting for God against the tyrant.
Amen.
We gathered here to choose the new Bey
for Seigniory position...
...that is left empty after Tugtekin Bey.
May the new Bey who will be chosen
be fortunate for Dodurga tribe, already.
-Amen.
-May God be his helper and his friend.
Now, Hayme Hatun will have her
say to lead the headquarters.
Go ahead, Hayme Hatun.
Gallant and glorious Beys of
Dodurga nomad group...
...Dodurga nomad group
is my nomad group, too.
My late father and brother were a Bey...
...and served first to God, then to their
state and then to their nomad group.
It made me happy beyond measure...
...that you gave me the duty of
leading the headquarters.
I know, on this tough day...
...Dodurga's Bey will make the best
decision and choose their Bey.
-May God render your tribe everlasting.
-Amen.
Who wishes to become
Bey of Dodurga nomad group?
Akca Bey and Artuk Bey put themselves
in for the position of Bey of Dodurga.
Before we move on to choosing,
do you have anything to say?
I do, Hayme Hatun.
Go ahead.
Dodurga's Beys...
...if you choose me as Bey...
...by using all means and
with the support of the state...
...I will make our nomad group regain
peace and safety we long for...
...if God permits.
Thank you, Akca Bey.
Artuk Bey, do you have something to say?
-I do, Hayme Hatun.
-Go ahead.
Dodurga's Beys...
...it is time for Dodurga nomad group
to awaken its own will and mind.
The might we need to make our
nomad group regain peace is within us.
That is the purpose of me standing
for Seigniory.
Let us regain peace together.
If God permits, this choosing will
be fortunate for our nomad group.
Glorious Beys of Dodurga,
let us move on to choosing.
Who would like Akca Bey to be Bey?
Who would like Artuk Bey to be Bey?
The new Bey of Dodurga nomad group is
Akca Bey.
May it be the best.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Here.
May your Bey position be the best
for Dodurga nomad group, Akca Bey.
Thank you, Gundogdu Bey.
May your Bey position be the best
for our nomad group, Akca Bey.
Thank you, Bey.
May your Bey position be the best
for our nomad group, Bey.
Brother, I will come to Byzantium with you
like Yigit.
What about my Mother?
What if my Mother does not come?
My brothers would not leave my Mother
alone.
And I will not leave you alone.
Neither you, nor Halime Sultan, or Gunduz.
You are my marquee from now on, brother.
Thank you.
Once we return safely we will talk about
these.
If God permits, may your path be bright,
brother.
Thank you.
-Be under God's watch.
-Be under God's watch, brother.
We will be before Sultan's presence
before three days, Halime Sultan.
When he reads the letter Yigit sent...
...Sultan will believe Yigit is innocent,
Ertugrul.
If God permits, Halime.
If we cannot prove Kopek is in betrayal...
...not only us but also our state will be
under threat.
We must make both Noyan and
Bogach appear before Sultan.
Hasten, brother, I will die of starvation.
Take it, brother, here.
Brothers.
Give Shahzade to me.
Our hangman is here, Bogach.
-Do not raise difficulties.
-Do not, Bey.
We will not give him to you.
Ertugrul Bey trusted us with Yigit Alp.
We cannot give him to you, Bey.
I do not want to hurt you.
Lower your swords.
Do not, Bey.
We will protect him at the cost of
our lives.
Move aside.
You are dragging yourself, Ertugrul Bey...
...and our nomad group to disaster.
Do not, Bey.
Alps!
Attack!
Ertugrul, who are they?
My brother.
Yigit.
Wait here, Halime.
Forgive me, boy.
I must do this for the continuity
of the state, for Ertugrul.
Brother!
Enough, brother, enough!
Enough, Ertugrul! This will be over!
Brother.
Ertugrul, I will save you and our
nomad group from this trouble.
Do not stand in front of me.
Do not stop me.
Sultan's edict must be fulfilled for
the continuity of the state.
-Move aside, Ertugrul!
-Brother!
Yigit! Brother!
Bey. Sungurtekin.
Brother.
Brother! Brother!
Stay with me! You will heal, brother.