Episode 33 will start after 11:49 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
If it would remind you who you are,
where you came from...
...and that you are Suleyman Shah's son,
take my life, brother.
Do you remember, brother?
I did.
You reminded me who I am.
You tricked my father and
led all of us to danger.
You blamed me of being a coward.
But you are a coward
who betrays his mother.
If those did not remind you,
perhaps this will, brother.
Go to hell, Ertugrul.
Go! Go on!
The two brothers lead
Kayi towards a cliff.
I will not let them.
I will wait for the nightfall and
see what it will lead up to.
Very nice. God bless your hands.
These are marvelous patterns.
God bless your hands.
Selcan, you made a great color harmony.
We did it like Halime taught us.
Would you like to see
the armors Gokce made?
I do.
What did you put behind the armor?
I put wire and felt, mother.
Neither an arrow nor a spear
could pierce it.
Well done.
God bless your hands.
Dodurga and Kayi women
are getting along well.
Right, Selcan Hatun?
I hope that our Alps will be united like
our women, soon, Mother Hayme.
Do you doubt it, Aytolun?
If you and Bey are leading our tribes,
I have no doubts.
But Ertugrul's stubbornness
worries me just like everyone else.
My son stated that he would obey
the headquarters' judgment.
He would keep his promise.
Mother Hayme.
Ertugrul Bey and Gundogdu Bey are
fighting at the entrance of tribe.
This is what I was trying to tell to you,
Mother Hayme.
Control your son
or he will be the cause of our disaster.
What happened, Kocabash?
Ertugrul Bey.
He waited Gundogdu Bey
at entrance of tribe.
When we arrived, he walked up to Bey.
They fought with each other.
We could not break up the fight.
Is this your prudent nephew, father?
Why is he acting like this?
Everyone knows what happened.
Ertugrul will be a trouble not just
to his tribe but to us as well.
Bey, you must find a way
to bring him into line.
Dear God!
Ambition, Bey, ambition.
Ambition is the root of all evil.
And the demons around him.
For example, Selcan.
She always instigates Halime Sultan.
Father, if you do not stop him,
I will bring him into the line.
-Gundogdu!
-Don't ask anything, Selcan.
Mother, control your son
or I swear this will end ugly.
What are you saying, son?
Why are you so tactless?
What does a fight
between two brothers mean?
Did your father raise you for this?
Do not tell these to me
but to your impudent son.
I cannot handle you anymore.
You crossed the line!
From now on, if you do something
like this again...
...you will not have my blessing.
If Bey is not in tribe,
he must be at Geyikli's place.
This tribe is not a blessing  for us.
Tell your lame handed Bey that...
...if he causes any more trouble
in my tribe...
...I will nail his other hand.
Is Baycu Noyan awake?
Was he pleased with you?
If you want to live,
you must please Noyan.
Do you understand what I mean?
Good.
Go, now.
Baycu Noyan!
Have you decided what to do to
the merchant who dealt with Gundogdu?
What keeps parasite Kayis
and Dodurgas together, Tankut?
The fear they have for us.
What else?
Their brotherhood traditions.
How long will Dodurgas feed Kayis
on long winter days?
Brotherhood is up to some extent.
What happens if Kayis could not
sell their goods and herds?
They will go at it hammer and tongs.
That merchant will die.
Efrasiyab will fill his place.
We will take everything two nomad tents
have.
So, do Oghuz tribes bound up
to their traditions?
Oh, Ak Tolgali.
The sky cracked.
Two brothers fight will make people
miserable.
I wish I had not spoken and hit him.
I wish I had control my anger,
so it would not have been.
-Brother, are you alright?
-I am alright, Tugtekin.
Why did he attack you?
Look at this.
How could a man hit his brother?
Why do you care two brothers'
fight to much, Tugtekin?
Save it, Selcan.
Instead of scolding me,
mind the ones stoking the fire.
Shut up, woman!
Ertugrul Aga like a raging bull,
will put not only himself...
...but all of us all in danger.
Then, you will understand.
Ertugrul will obey headquarters' judgment.
He has to, aunt.
Or I make him obey me.
Bey.
Ertugrul is Bey.
He is hurt, he is in pain.
His wounds will not heal, Gokce.
You misunderstood me, Bey.
Ertugrul is hurt.
He twists the knife.
But he is making a huge mistake.
He must obey headquarters' judgments.
That is what I thought.
Will he obey them?
Perhaps, he must suffer to obey them.
Ertugrul is my dear...
...my only one.
But he is making a huge mistake.
I want to you know, you are right...
...I will be on your side in any case,
Bey.
Thank you, Gokce.
Thank you.
-Were you kicked by a horse?
-Sort of.
Sit down.
-Could you find Noyan's place?
-Yes.
So fast?
Birds tell their place, and their place
tells the truth.
-Bey, are you alright?
-Thank you, I am fine.
I have one more request.
My brother, Sungurtekin.
Did he really betray to his nomad people
and his ancestors as Noyan said?
Is he alive?
Will he go back to Urumqi?
I need to know these.
Whether my birds talk or not,
your trouble is our trouble, Bey.
If your brother is even in China,
my birds will not talk anymore.
From now on, we give hard times
to idolater Mongols!
Alright, Bey.
What happened, Wild Demir?
It will be alright, Bey.
I keep my promise to Ertugrul Bey
sooner or later.
-If God permits, you will.
-If God permits.
Two brothers' fists hurt two nomad tents
more than the brothers.
If the nomad tents get more damage,
there will be no nomad tents...
...and unity.
You speak the truth, Bey.
You speak the truth.
Ertugrul and his Alps are not around.
Do you know where they are?
At least tell me whether
this is going to end well or bad?
If Ertugrul Bey is here, there will be
nothing bad.
Do not worry, Bey.
-Let us hope for the best.
-Thank you, Bey.
Have a nice day, Halime Sultan.
You, too, Artuk Bey.
What happened, my daughter?
Did something bad happen?
I know you are on a though path
with Ertugrul Bey, Wild Demir.
I know you are standing by your man with
your baby and huge heart,...
...my daughter.
My mother is also offended to my man.
Like his uncle and Agha.
There is no one I can talk to.
Do not let anything happen to him,
Wild Demir.
I have no one other than him.
He loves you as his father and
minds your words.
Do not be afraid, Halime daughter.
I will not give those bastards
another child.
-Turali.
-You have a guest.
Yes.
Turali?
We could not imagine how it ends,
Mother Hayme.
If we had known,
would not you have been in it, brother?
Our judgment was not wrong, Mother Hayme.
It is not good in our religion
and traditions...
...not to help hard arduous people.
Moreover, we back up each other
against Mongols.
But Ertugrul came and ruined everything,
right?
He is my blood and family.
He is one of the best Alps Oghuz tribe
raised.
He is like my son.
But you know I will take necessary
precautions for my nomad tent's peace.
If he continues acting like this...
...I will have to exile him with his Alp,
Mother Hayme.
Brother...
...if necessary, I will do it for good of
two nomad tents.
But only I could do it.
Be aware of that.
Have you ever thought what a female lion
about to lose her whelp could do?
Now, think about it.
Mother Hayme.
You missed your work, right?
I do not have anything except for my work,
Mother Hayme.
Where are they?
Who, Mother Hayme?
Where are Ertugrul and his Alps?
I do not know, they rode their horse
and left.
Where did they go?
What are you hiding from me?
Wild Demir,...
...if you know and not telling me
you will not have my blessing.
We both know, they are up to something.
Know that I will keep an eye on you.
Turali.
Come here.
Come here, sit down.
Come on.
Turali, I am in trouble, right?
I lied to wife of Suleyman Shah
at this age.
May God forgive me.
Did Sadettin Kobek handle the business?
Tell me.
The number of pacifists who want...
...Sultan Aleaddin pay tribute to Ogeday
is raising, Noyan.
Sultan is also hesitant.
I do not want tribute of Aleaddin,...
...I want whole Anatolia.
Every inch of it, every horse on it.
What about Kobek?
He guarantees that he would do everything
you want, Noyan.
Sultan Aleaddin's army and Ogeday's army
which is under your command will wage...
...a battle in here, Erzurum, as you wish.
When winter ends and spring comes,
you will be victorious.
Sadettin Kobek will welcome you in Konya.
Tell him to kill pacifists one by one.
I want no obstacle about war.
When I entered Konya with my army,
I will carry Aleaddin's head on my spear.
If he does not want me spear his head,...
...he must do everything I said.
I need at least 40 camels to carry
the goods we bought from Kayis...
...from here to Konya then to Iznik.
At least 20 man to herd the animals.
Take care of it immediately.
Gundogdu Bey is about to come...
...and I do not want be embarrassed
when we go to the nomad tent.
If you excuse me.
Geyikli knows where Noyan is.
We will send Abdurrahman to there.
What then, Bey?
Then?
What if Abdurrahman fails?
What if Noyan wakes up to it?
We will do all we can to make him
successful.
If Abdurrahman fails...
...it means his blood will be
on our hands.
We walk on the earth.
Abdurrahman will infiltrate
and give us information from Noyan.
Only he can do this, now.
Then, we will cut Noyan's supply routes
one by one.
How will we do it?
Is it easy to do it?
Tomorrow is another day.
I set off.
He is crazy.
Where did he go?
Hamza?
My brother.
Brother.
Things got messed up while you were away.
I know all of them.
Ertugrul Bey's mission was taken away.
Even he is not an Alp now.
What happens if he is an Alp or not?
What are you saying, brother?
There is no good in this nomad tent
after Suleyman Shah.
Ertugrul made us to go this war.
We were ambushed because of him.
There were many martyrs because of him.
He is nothing, now.
He is a useless lame handed man.
You are saying this because of
what Gundogdu did to you.
I know you have a heart of gold.
We all had a heart of gold.
But they fooled us.
They did it for fame and money.
Gundogdu Bey betrayed to me.
This betrayal will trouble us in time.
All the nomad group.
What are we going to do, brother?
What do you want me to do?
There is only one way to save
both ourselves and the nomad group.
I am here to talk about it.
What is it?
Noyan gave us a way out.
Calm down. Listen to me.
You saw it.
Even Hayme show her teeth to you.
She is my sister.
But she is leader of Kayis.
And Ertugrul is her son.
So, it is not easy.
Her nomad tent and her son, right.
But Dodurga is your nomad group and
Tugtekin is your son.
You must think of your nomad group
and son first.
Two nomad groups merging is a dream
as long as Ertugrul is here.
There is only one move
that could merge two nomad groups.
What are you thinking, Hatun?
Trust neither Hayme nor Ertugrul
but trust only to Gundogdu.
If you act in unison, everyone wins.
How would we do it?
You must plant the idea of being Kayi Bey
to Gundogdu's mind.
So, he would be ambitious.
If you do not do this,...
...you will lose Kayi.
Mother, all the tents were erected
except for 13 of them.
We would provide the felt and
erect the rest of them.
Nobody will be outside
when the rain comes.
Thank you, my daughter.
If there is nothing to say,
I want to sleep, I am exhausted.
-Good night.
-Halime!
Yes, mother.
Where is Ertugrul?
I do not know, mother.
So, he rode his horse and left
without telling you anything, right?
Right.
Do you expect me to believe this?
I tell the truth, Mother.
I respect you so I do not talk
if I would lie.
We both know Ertugrul
is playing with fire, right?
So, I am right.
What if your silence will be our disaster?
Mother,...
...do you want me to rat on, my husband,
your son?
If necessary, yes.
This is not a game!
The gauntlet has been thrown.
Do not make me do things that
I do not want.
I have led this nomad group by trusting
Ertugrul for two years.
You know this, too.
So, where is he now?
He is gone.
Why did he go, Mother?
Because we both made a mistake.
We did not trust him.
We said he is lame-handed.
We wanted to merge the nomad groups.
We said he won't stay still, he'll want
revenge.
We turned our back to him.
We did it, Mother.
We left him alone.
Regretting losing him
does not help us now.
-If you excuse me.
-Halime!
I will follow every step you take.
Do not make me give decisions
that I do not want.
Mother.
Halime is not strong enough to see...
...Ertugrul's mistakes and show him
the right way.
You want too many things from a woman
who could not be wife to his Bey.
Gokce.
She is the women whom Ertugrul
fell in love with.
It will not change till doomsday.
Oh, Bey.
I wish you were alive and here with me.
I need you desperately.
Oh, Bey.
What happened, Dogan?
I could not sleep, Bey.
We could not talk while Geyikli
was around.
Your fight with Gundogdu...
How is the nomad groups?
Everyone heard what happened, Bey.
They are worried about future.
The gauntlet has been thrown, brothers.
There is no turning back.
But nothing will be same.
I know that.
Tugtekin is stoking the fire.
He bears a grudge.
He threatens us.
I let them be until I stop
Mongol tyranny...
...but I am at the end of my rope.
What would we do in short time?
Geyikli is chasing Mongols.
Tomorrow, maybe for the last time
we go to nomad tent and free Abdurrahman.
We take him and leave.
This nomad group has seen
so many destructions.
Think of it, brothers.
We challenged to Ayyubids, so what now?
Tell me, Clumsy.
Did not your two brothers die?
They did.
What about you, Yellow Hun?
Did not you bury your brave father
and brother?
I did.
So, why? Tell me.
So Gundogdu and Ertugrul Bey
will be more prosperous and braver.
Remember the wars
we went to let them marry Seljuk girls.
Why? So, they would have royal blood
and they could found a state.
Ertugrul Bey as Master Alp...
...made us fight in battlefields
countless times.
Is there anyone who did not hurt?
Is there anyone who did not lose someone?
He is right.
But he saved our goods and women
not just ours but all Muslim world's.
That is right.
He saved.
But why did we save?
What are doing now?
What do have against
the largest army in the world?
We have just fame.
But we do not have any food.
Other nomad tent is mocking with us.
Why? Because Gundogdu Bey wishes so.
Instead being together...
...two brothers are fighting
with each other in the nomad groups.
They disrespected to our traditions.
You are the greatest warriors of world.
Your name is heard even
by son of Genghis Khan, Ogeday.
He sent you gold
that you could not see in your life.
Now, think about it till tomorrow morning.
So, real Alps who want to come with me
could take their gold...
...and show the world a real warrior.
Is that right, Gunkut?
That is right, Hamza.
Do not say a word, woman.
Do truths hurt you this much?
Selcan.
You did not trust your brother
who you fought back to back...
...but you followed your uncle and
Tugtekin who are led by a bitch.
That is how it goes.
Your brother hit you for the first time,
do you know why, Gundogdu?
Because of you.
-If you say another word...
-You will hit me?
I will talk until you see what is right.
Even if I would die, I will talk.
You and your mother made a huge mistake
by turning your back to Ertugrul.
Enough, women, enough.
That ominous women will not rest
until she tricks my mother and Ertugrul.
Open your eyes.
We could not get out of the trouble
we are in by running and hiding.
Let go of me woman, let go.
Coward.
You are a coward.
You are scared of ambitions once we had!
But do not forget that Gundogdu,
they have worse ambition than us!
-Shut up, woman, shut up!
-Open your eyes!
Gundogdu Bey!
You are sick, women.
You are delusional.
You made me do this.
May god give your punishment.
Take your filthy hands!
Sooner or later, you will show the
cloven hoof!
May God not let me live one day
if I do not love you.
May God not separate us, my brave man.
Aykiz!
Drink some water, brother.
Bey.
I cannot breathe without Aykiz.
My life has turned into hell.
I missed her very much, Bey.
I missed her very much.
Aykiz Baci was a martyr.
She is not dead.
Know that she is alive.
If God permits, you will meet her.
If God permits.
God!
Please let me die a martyr in your path!
God, let me have the honor of martyrdom!
-Amen.
Amen.
I give you my word
that we will take our revenge
from bastard Noyan.
May God not let us live if we do not take
our revenge from bastard Noyan.
If God permits.
Wait for me bastard,
I will take your life.
Selcan!
Selcan, what happened?
My daughter, what happened?
-Gundogdu.
-What happened to Gundogdu?
Gundogdu hit me, Mother.
What are you saying, my daughter?
My son would never lay a hand on you.
I am an ominous, purulent wound
that he must carry, Mother.
I know.
When I pushed him, he stormed at me.
So, you deserved it, sister.
Gokce!
My dear daughter.
I will take care of Selcan, Mother.
Come on.
Alright. Come on, stand up my dear.
Come on, my dear.
Come on.
Your father is aware of everything.
Gundogdu will be the biggest supporter of
your newly founded seigniory.
Not Hayme or anyone else.
What are you thinking, Mother?
Gundogdu...
...is a lonely and unhappy man.
In his marquee, his bed is cold
the cradle is empty and he is daunted.
I see him grieving deeply every day.
He is a miserable man who is
under command of his step mother
in the shade of his father's
dear Ertugrul.
He cannot even confess it to himself.
What are you saying, Mother?
As I said to your father
if you act together with Gundogdu,
you would found the seigniory you want.
Then, we would have a home.
And if you send Goncagul to his bed...
What did you say?
If my brother Gumustekin's
daughter Goncagul
becomes Gundogdu's wife...
She is a real woman
who can warm Gundogdu's cold bed
and fill that empty cradle.
And when you take Gokce as your wife,
everyone will be delighted.
Can I come in, Bey?
Come in, Kocabash!
What happened?
Gundogdu Bey...
...beat Selcan Hatun.
What are you saying? How did this happen?
I do not know.
But I barely saved his wife.
Alright, you are dismissed.
I told you, do not leave him alone.
He is a lonely and grieving man.
Back him up, guide him.
My sins will not let me go.
I will pay for them till I die.
I will pay for what I did
both in this life and afterwards.
I pray to God everyday but...
Do not talk like that, Selcan.
What has passed is past.
You are more than a sister for me.
Do not talk like that, please.
But it is too late now, Halime.
Too late.
Selcan.
God!
Give me strength.
Give me patience.
I am freed from my ambitions
with your blessing.
I am freed from the soul-eating hubris.
But I carry the burden
of my father's marquee.
Give me strength to carry that burden.
Show the right way to Ertugrul.
Show me the right way.
I do not know what to do about Selcan.
Show me the right way about Selcan.
Your strength is enough for everything.
Save me from my vulnerabilities
and weaknesses.
Amen.
I heard what happened.
We are responsible for our nomad tents'
future, brother. There is no escape.
If we support each other, our nomad tents
would be out of the woods.
Alright.
But you must have peace in your tent.
If you are not at peace
you cannot find peace
when you are riding your horse.
And you need to have a baby.
Just like I need to find a woman
and get married.
Stop.
Duru.
Duru!
Bey!
Are you alright, Bey?
Bey.
-My wife.
-Does your late wife haunt your dreams?
Yes, every night, Aytolun.
Every night.
Neither I have ever slept well
nor I have woken up in peace
since the day I married you.
Whenever I close my eyes, I see Duru.
Whenever I open my eyes, I see Duru.
That night at dinner...
Bey!
Bey, smell. Smell.
Which night? What happened that night?
The night when Duru's heart stopped
and she died in my son's arms.
God, forgive my sins.
Bey, tell me what is troubling you,
so I can help you.
I could not tell you
all this time, Aytolun.
What, Bey?
We were at dinner on the night she died.
She looked at me and told me your name.
The last word she told me
before she died was your name.
She looked me in the eye
and said "Aytolun."
But why? Why would she say my name?
She knew, Aytolun.
She found out everything.
She knew I came to see you
and met you in caravanserais.
She knew everything.
It is not possible.
She told me, woman! Do you understand?
Then she looked at me with pity.
Do you know what she told me?
She said "I keep quiet for the sake of
our son and honor of our nomad tent.
But if you go to see that woman again
I will embarrass you more
than you have ever embarrassed me."
Then she said your name. Aytolun.
There was more pity in her eyes
than anger.
She did not hate me for sleeping with you.
She felt sorry for me.
Then, Tugtekin came in.
He sat at the table.
When she was about to have another bite
her heart stopped.
She died.
Do you understand?
She knew everything between you and me
while she was dying in my son's arms.
How long will this sleep last, Ertugrul?
When will you take up your mission?
Oh, God!
God, please help me.
Here.
You are real heroes!
You proved it by coming here!
You will save children and women
of Kayi tribe
from imprudent Beys!
As Kargin told you,
Konya will not be enough for Ogeday!
He will conquer Constantinople as well!
Then, he will advance on Central Europe!
Now, do you want to be the warriors
who get their share of wealth
or miserable men who challenge
the largest army of the world?
What about our family?
What about our children?
Noyan said that their lives will be saved.
He gave his word to you.
As I said...
...you proved that you are
true warriors by coming here.
These are yours.
But if you want to fight for much more...
...come with me!
I am in to show Kayi's strength to world!
-I am in!
-I am in too!
Gunkut, you?
I cannot!
I cannot betray Suleyman Shah,
his glorious nomad tent and traditions!
World's largest army is waiting for us!
Come on, Alps!
Baycu Noyan.
-Did you take care of it, Tankut?
-I did.
The merchant and all the men
he has business with are dead.
Good.
Gundogdu will not be able
to sell their rugs and herds.
We will see what his brothers will do
in nomad tent.
Will they share their food
on long winter nights?
When will Efrasiyab arrive?
I sent word, he will be here shortly.
My favorite thing in this
miserable life is fighting.
But do you know what I enjoy more, Tankut?
Conquering without a battle.
Kayis and Dodurgas
will fall into my trap one by one.
I admire your desires, Baycu Noyan.
He said "You grew up with us,
shared our food.
But one day, you made
my white-bearded father cry.
And the old, hoary mothers.
You killed my brothers! My brothers!
You trivialized white rugs.
You left beautiful orphaned babies behind.
When I catch you, do I let you go?
Unless I draw my sword
unless I cut your bloody head
unless your bloody head hits the ground
unless I avenge my brothers
would I let you go?"
Even monsters like Argus
and fire breathing dragons
will be served right
by brave Beys like Ertugrul Bey.
Even, devils like Noyan.
But the biggest monsters are among us,
my children, among us!
Do not ever forget this!
May God not let brothers and Muslims
fight among themselves.
The ones who choose
to be united and together
will have peace.
The ones who choose to be separated
will lose face.
May great God not make us need
the vile men.
We prayed to our God with good intentions,
may God accept.
The ones who say "amen" would be in peace.
May almighty God forgive our sins.
Oh my girl!
Oh my boy!
Oh my dear!
Oh my children!
Son.
Son!
-Mother?
-Get up.
-What happened?
-Go and get your wife from rug loom.
I cannot live with Selcan, Mother.
She blamed me for our fight with Ertugrul.
That is why you laid your hand
on your wife, right?
It was a mistake, you are right.
I know, a real man does not do it. But...
Son, you are a Bey's son.
If you behave like this,
what would people do?
You broke our traditions.
We do not lay hand on women
in our tradition.
Now go and get your wife, come on.
What about Ertugrul?
If necessary,
I will send him and his Alps into exile
until this dark war is over.
If God permits, I will not have to do it.
Keep your eyes open.
Do not let in the mistakes coming from
your uncle's marquee.
Do not worry, Mother.
Now get up, the girl is miserable
since last night.
And make up your mind about her.
You cannot solve anything by hurting her.
You are right, Mother.
Come on.
Bey, Geyikli is still not here.
I said he went to spy on Mongols.
How will he spy on them, Bey?
He knows these mountains like the palm
of his hand, do not worry.
Come on, get up, Turgut Alp.
I said, get up!
Come on then, Alp.
Bey, come on.
Come on, Bey.
There is no need, Turgut Alp.
My hand cannot grab a sword yet.
Come on, pack up.
Turali. You are here.
Welcome.
Are you going to stand there and watch me?
Or are you going to help me?
You wonder what am I doing, right?
I am making a steel glove
for Ertugrul Bey.
So, he can grab his sword as he used to.
So, he can avenge your parents and Aykiz.
We dug one grave for each.
This is why we are late.
I am sorry, Bey.
Mongols.
They have their finger on the pulse.
Otherwise, why would they
kill a miserable man?
They want us to starve in winter.
This is going to be harder
than we thought, brother.
It is but I have another question
in my mind.
What?
Apparently, Noyan will
cause trouble in winter.
If Ertugrul is right
will Dodurga share their food with us?
Selcan Hatun.
Apparently, you are not alright.
Your patterns are uneven.
You are not making it right.
Go to your tent and rest for a while.
I will do it again.
Leave it!
Apparently, Gundogdu Bey's anger
hurt you a lot.
Selcan! Selcan!
Go, pull yourself together
and then come back to rug loom.
Help!
Run, run!
Are you alright?
He is a Kayi.
Move! Move aside! Move!
Do not stand up, you are hurt!
Find Gundogdu Bey for me!
I have words for him!
Alright.
Run and get Gundogdu now!
Hold on! Hold on!
What are you looking at?
Go and get help, now! Now!
Hold on! Hold on, Bey!
So, you are going to help.
Call Artuk Bey.
Let me pass. Move aside. Let him breathe.
Gunkut?
-Bey.
-What happened?
Bey, Hamza...
Hamza?
Hamza did it, Bey.
He wanted to kill me.
Kargin and he left with 11 Alps.
-He left!
-Where did he go, Gunkut?
To Noyan, Bey.
They betrayed all of us.
No, Hamza could not have done this.
You got us into trouble, Gundogdu.
Kocabash, prepare the horses,
we go after traitors.
Yes, Bey.
Move aside! Move aside!
Come on, help.
With the name of God, slowly.
Slowly.
What is going on, brother?
You came in without permission.
Tugtekin was right.
Hamza is a traitor!
Probably, so is Abdurrahman!
What are you saying, brother?
Hamza and Kargin took Noyan's side
with 11 Kayi Alps!
He also wounded a Kayi Alp
who tried to stop the treason!
Sick bastard.
People will follow him, Hayme.
Kayi tribe is rotten to the core
but we have not seen it.
You must put a stop to other people's
possible betrayals now!
How?
Execute Abdurrahman.
If he confesses his crimes,
finish him off immediately.
If he does not
take his life slowly
and make an example of him!
This way. This way!
Something is wrong, Turgut.
Something happened in nomad tent
while we were away.
Bey.
Tugtekin was right.
Hamza is a traitor.
What happened?
He took 12 Alps to Noyan.
Bastard!
Because of him,
they think Abdurrahman is a traitor too.
They want to execute him.
They are in headquarters talking about it.
Beys...
...this is going to end badly.
We must take precautions.
It is not too late
to take precautions, Bey.
You still have a chance.
How could you enter the headquarters
without permission, Ertugrul?
How could you take revenge while you are
securing the justice, Uncle?
Oghuz traditions do not let a brave Alp
pay for other's treason.
Ertugrul...
...we are talking about what to do
in here.
We have not decided yet.
Beys will make someone pay for their rage.
They look for a scapegoat.
The scapegoat will be Abdurrahman.
I do not let this happen.
This is all because of your obstinacy.
Now you dogmatize!
After you came, Alps got confused
and did not know who is their commander.
Now, they turned their backs to Beys
and changed their side.
I told you, Noyan would not wait
for his army.
You did not hear my words.
While you were hiding your head
in the sand, Noyan started the war.
Do not force me into a corner, Ertugrul.
I will show no mercy even to you.
You disturbed the peace in nomad tents.
Do not get in our way.
You have no place in this headquarters.
Get out, now!
Stop it, Ertugrul Bey. Enough.
It is a pity for your mother and uncle.
Your uncle was always praising you
to the skies.
Whenever he said your name,
he would be happy.
Now, he cannot sleep and have anything.
Enough is enough.
Dodurga was united until you came back
from death.
Enough is enough.
Do not be stubborn, obey your Beys.
This is what a brave man like you must do.
Where did they go?
You are stubborn, right?
Where did they go, aunt-in-law?
To north.
Korkut Bey ordered us not to allow you
inside, Ertugrul Bey.
You cannot enter the tent.
Bey!
We will get you out of here, Abdurrahman.
Be ready.
Do not let me die
before I prove my innocence, Bey.
Do not worry.
Ertugrul Bey, do not make us do things
that we do not want to do.
Leave.
I will come back, Abdurrahman.
Bey, let us come with you.
Stay here. Keep an eye on Abdurrahman.
Yes, Bey.
There is something
I want you to know, Ertugrul Bey.
I am listening, Halime Sultan.
You mother is disappointed in you
as your brother.
And even angry.
But know that they are both feeling sorry.
I know.
I am not feeling resentful towards them.
They do what they think is right.
They think about sending you into exile
with Turgut and Dogan.
That is what I want, Halime Sultan.
I cannot do anything
in this nomad tent.
Do not worry.
Everyone will realize the truth
sooner or later.
So, what is my role, Bey?
Waiting patiently, Halime Sultan.
Waiting patiently.
Beys, headquarters will give a judgment
about Abdurrahman Alp.
Do you have anything to say?
Beys!
Wise men of our nomad tents!
You are making a mistake.
Headquarters will decide whether
it is right or wrong, Wild Demir.
The truth is obvious.
No treason goes unpunished.
Ayes for the execution of Abdurrahman Alp?
On a day that Kayi Beys see fit,
the execution will take place.
Shame on you!
They went this way.
They might have set a trap.
Maybe with Mongols.
Kocabash, go down and tell Alps
to follow us from up.
-Maintain eye contact.
-Yes, Bey.
Come on, to the horses!
Ertugrul Bey, I was not expecting you.
How could you betray them, Hamza?
Someone must put a stop
to Gundogdu Bey's mistakes.
That must have been you.
But you chose to die instead of obeying.
First, you lost your hand
then stopped being an Alp.
Noyan will not stop until he kills you.
What did bastard Noyan give you
to get you betray your nomad people?
I am not content with what I have
unlike your brother Gundogdu, Ertugrul!
Now, lower your sword.
Until the traitors are dead,
I will not sheathe my sword.
Alps!
I know your hand is crippled.
Take down this man
who is attacking your Bey!
I said take this man down! Take him down!
Treacherous dogs!
Treacherous bastards!
The new Bey of your nomad tent
is me, Ertugrul!
From now on, you will obey me.