Episode 57 will start after 12:22 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
Tugtekin Bey!
Tugtekin!
Tugtekin, brother!
I will make him regret he did not kill me.
Tugtekin!
How can I be calm when
he has Gokce, Ertugrul? Let me go.
-Tugtekin!
-Let me go!
It has been a plenteous hunt.
Your sons are with my servants in my den.
And since you came to my feet,
then I should play with you.
First Selcan, now Gokce.
You are only strong enough for women.
You will leave here as a carrion.
You bastard dog!
Do not, Selcan!
Kayi women are better than their men.
Everyone I wanted to see
is here except Ertugrul.
What more could I wish?
Dying before seeing your death
is a sin for us, Noyan.
A sturdy arm is more valuable than
inane courage in war, Maimed Boy.
Your maimed arm will cost you
your life, you do not see.
Be careful, mother.
Come here, dog's seed. Come.
It is not over.
Maimed Boy.
I see your arm made
your life miserable, Maimed Boy.
I cannot accept it.
I shall save you from this misery.
Gundogdu!
God!
Gundogdu, are you fine?
We will meet again.
Gokce!
Mother!
Son!
Son.
-Mother!
-Dundar.
We are fine, son. Leave us,
go after that Noyan bastard. Haste!
Come on!
Daughter.
They went this way, Bey.
Ride!
-I will rip his heart out!
-Tugtekin Bey!
Tugtekin Bey, do not worry.
We will catch him sooner or later.
I will pluck his heart out.
Do not worry. We will save her.
I will put his heart on his hand.
Alps! Follow Tugtekin Bey!
Do not leave Tugtekin alone
until he reaches to nomad tent.
Are you not coming with us?
No. I will not return
until I find Noyan and Yigit.
This must be over quickly.
-May God help you.
-Thank you.
If you find Yigit, bring him to
the nomad tent alive, brother.
We shall surrender him to Sultan Alaeddin.
Let him give his punishment.
Be under God's watch.
Ertugrul, do not silence
your justice when it comes to Yigit.
If he revolted, he will die.
Tomorrow will be the day
of your victory, his Ameer.
Shahzada Yigit will die along
with revolter Turkmen Beys.
And both Ertugrul and Tugtekin
will have their share of my rage.
I will be personally in command
in the battle tomorrow, if God permits.
Tomorrow will be a blessed day...
...that the ones who does not
submit to me will perish.
Order, my dear child.
Order.
The order of this state is above everyone.
Even our sultan.
And even myself.
What will Sungurtekin's
and Gundogdu's fate be, his Ameer?
They will do anything
for their nomad tent's future.
I have plans for Kayi Tribe.
It is time a new hero emerges from them.
And this hero's leash will be in my palms.
How will that happen, his Ameer?
What I actually wonder is,
who will that be?
Sungurtekin.
Sungurtekin will be a hero when he kills
Noyan and saves Gokce Hatun, thanks to me.
Watch the clutter then.
We will wait and see, my child.
Long live, Sultan!
My Beys.
You have took the brunt
for all the troubles of state.
You fought first against the enemy.
You died for your state.
You suffered
the grief of losing your child.
When need be, you left your home.
You were left
without grassland, summer pasture.
Where was Sultan Alaeddin
when you were suffering these pains?
Now I ask you,
would a Sultan ignore his subjects?
No!
Would a Sultan enjoy himself
while his people are suffering?
No!
Is it not the time to take
what is rightfully yours now?
Yes!
Has the time not come to subject
for a Sultan worthy of you?
Yes!
Now it is time to take what you deserve.
That is why I came.
I came to show you
the state's justice and benignity.
Long live, Sultan!
What will be my fate, his Ameer?
Do not worry, child.
After you take your revenge, you will
have the reward for the things you did.
You very much deserved
a noble and magnificent life.
I will take you to palace, by my side.
I will marry you to one of
my most worthful commanders.
Thus, you can continue
to serve me and the state.
When we avenge my aunt
and my father, this earth...
...will be heaven for me, his Ameer.
I will not forget
your favors for me all my life.
Noyan shall not know you came here.
Do not forget,
when Noyan takes off to kill Tugtekin...
...you will leave Gokce there
and leave immediately.
Now, leave.
If you allow me, I would like to kiss
your hand and ask for your blessing.
My dear sister.
On this happy day of mine
when I enter my man's tent...
...I wish to enter
with your benison, sister.
My prayers will always
be with you and your man.
You are a piece of my soul.
Your sister will always be with you...
...the same way you will be by
your husband's side for a life time.
The clouds that came between her
and Tugtekin Bey were lifting one by one.
The sun was about
to rise on their marquee.
Maybe my Gokce was
this happy for the first time in her life.
That bastard came and took my sister.
He vanished without a trace.
Gokce is gone. My sister is gone.
Noyan knew we were
going to raid his nomad tent.
He played with us.
He watched the Beys
leave the nomad tent for raid.
Then he abducted my child, Gokce.
They must have set a trap for Ertugrul.
We sent our brave men
to Noyan's trap with our own hands.
Then we need to take off
after our men at once, brother.
God, you protect our brave men.
Let them return to the nomad tent safely.
What will happen now?
Will we stand idle with our hands tied?
You keep your wits
about you first, brother.
Ertugrul will surely figure something out.
The real matter is...
...why Noyan wanted to abduct Gokce Hatun.
Goncagul Hatun!
Hatun!
Noyan!
I'm here.
You!
I will kill you!
So you entrapped
the wife of Dodurga, Noyan.
Come here.
Stop.
So you are Noyan's woman now, huh?
Sordid woman.
I will kill you!
Enough!
Be patient yet.
Do not forget, she will bring us Tugtekin.
No. No!
Noyan.
You are wounded.
Flare up the fire.
Ertugrul's brother Dundar
shot the arrow stalwartly.
What is the situation?
Could you find Yigit Bey?
We could not find Yigit, Banu Cicek Hatun.
And Turgut Alp? Where is he?
Turgut Brother is in Noyan's hands, too.
Where is Gokce Hatun, Mother Hayme?
Tell me that Gokche Hatun
is in the nomad tent.
Noyan...
...kidnapped Gokce Hatun, Tugtekin Bey.
What do you mean he kidnapped her?
Could not one man come out and
tell him to stop in this huge nomad tent?
Could he not die to stop it while a
Bey's wife was being kidnapped?
What do you mean "kidnapped"?
Tugtekin Bey.
We were near the graveyard, too.
But, forgive us, we could not stop it.
Were you trapped, too?
What was Gokce doing
in the graveyard, brother?
It seems someone
sent her there on purpose.
I will find that traitor.
I will tear his flesh from limb to limb
in the middle of the nomad tent.
I will feed his bones to hungry wolves.
Tugtekin Bey.
You should know...
...his deal is with you,
not with Gokce Hatun.
He will not kill her.
He wants to pull you
into a trap, Tugtekin Bey.
You dulled my pains by bringing this
ignoble woman to me, Noyan.
Your eyes make Noyan's heart rest.
It makes the gallant horses
inside him neigh.
You ignoble woman!
You will die like them,
Gokce Hatun, you know it, do you not?
Enough!
Goncagul Hatun, enough.
I know your anger, Goncagul Hatun.
However, Gokce is not
who we want. She is only a bait.
Ertugrul and Tugtekin are the ones
who took your beloveds from you.
Do not succumb
to your anger and ruin everything.
I know, Noyan. Do not worry.
I will keep my anger inside me.
Tomorrow, both Ertugrul
and Tugtekin will die.
Tomorrow will be our blessed day.
Then, we will have gotten
my revenge, Noyan.
Keep Gokce Hatun in sight tonight.
We need to hand her
to Sungurtekin safely.
Do you understand?
It is the same person who sent Gokce
Hatun to graveyard and put her dress...
...into the den.
A traitor from our nomad group.
They must not understand
that we know there is a traitor.
I will find that traitor.
If he convinced Gokce Hatun
to go well into the graveyard...
...then that traitor is
from my nomad group.
What does Ameer Sadettin want from me?
Ameer Sadettin stole Oghuz Khan seal...
...and gave it to Tangut
so he can get Noyan killed.
How come these two conspired
with each other? I cannot understand.
Our enemies have formed
an alliance against us, brother.
Sadettin Kobek wants us to
be hurt towards each other.
By kidnapping a Bey's wife,
he wants to erase your reputation.
He does not cover his hands in dirt
by making Noyan do all his dirty work.
What kind of a game is this, son?
How many more lives
will we give to this dog, huh?
This is such a game mother,
its one end reaches to Gokce Hatun...
...the other reaches to Sultan Alaeddin.
What we did not let him do with
Gumustekin, now he wants to do it himself.
He wants to be rid of Tugtekin Bey
and me without making both nomad groups...
...oppose him.
To bring Turkmen nomad groups to his heel.
My children.
Since he makes life unbearable to us...
...he torments us, for the lives
he took, for the families he destroyed...
...it is my will to you, do not
stop breathing down his neck.
Take revenge from him, for the lives
he took, for the blood he shed.
My children shall
get hurt rather than others.
What is it Bogac?
What is wrong with the animal?
The horse is foundering, Bey.
It obviously hurts. It cannot ride.
Bogac, return to nomad tent.
-Do not be a burden to us in the battle.
-As you wish.
I know who the traitor is.
It is Bogac.
Abdurrahman, where is Bogac?
He went with the Alps whom Mother
Hayme sent to search for Gokce Hatun
What is this crestfallenness?
It is the time of resurrection.
It is the time of dawn
after dark, brother.
Turgut did not have a good day, brother.
Our brother is taken prisoner again.
Brother, we will find him.
To find Turgut,
our horses' clops will merge...
...with the sparkles of our swords.
We will not leave our hope
or prayer lacking, brother.
Because where our weapons cannot
reach, brother, our prayers will.
You are right, Bamsi.
We came out many battles,
we took many wounds...
...we came back from
many deaths, did not crumble.
Would we crumble now?
Turgut Brother is alive.
I know it, brother.
I know, Turgut is alive.
Of course he is alive. He is alive.
Did you forget how Turgut
escaped from Templars' hands?
And brother, do you think
our Bey would leave Turgut Brother...
...in a Mongol dog's hands?
Would you, brother?
-Do you think I would leave him?
-We will not, brother.
We will save Turgut Brother and make these
lands the tombs of those Mongol dogs.
There is no woe as long as there is God.
It is the time for resurrection, brother.
God is almighty.
Yes, brother. God is almighty.
God bless!
He said his horse was floundering
when we were going to raid the den.
That bastard's intention was clear.
And it is clear where this gold came from.
Where is this bastard?
He went to search
for Gokce Hatun with Alps.
I will kill that bastard.
Your rage is grand Tugtekin Bey.
However Bogac is the one that
will lead you to Gokce Hatun.
I know, Ertugrul Bey.
That dog will lead me to Noyan.
And I will send them both to hell.
We cannot reach Noyan until he wants
us to. We should wait for a sign from him.
Noyan kidnapped Gokce Hatun from
nomad tent as you ordered, his Ameer.
Very well. Good, Bogac Alp.
Your place in my graces
is rising more and more.
I am always ready to give my
head for our state, his Ameer.
Now, it is Tugtekin's turn.
Go to Noyan at once.
-Do away with Tugtekin.
-As you wish, his Ameer.
Sungurtekin Bey is here, his Ameer.
Let him come in.
Leave from the backdoor.
Go to Noyan when sun rises
and do away with Tugtekin together.
As you wish. If you excuse me.
Welcome, Sungurtekin Bey.
Come, have a bite.
What is it? I see you are bothered.
We found Noyan's den.
We killed his soldiers.
We destroyed his den but...
But you neither could find
him nor Shahzada Yigit.
He knew we were going to raid his den.
He took advantage
of our absence in nomad tent...
...and wanted to kidnap
Gokce Hatun to entrap Tugtekin Bey.
I received news from
my Alp who I sent to nomad tent.
Noyan took what he wanted.
I am sorry, Sungurtekin.
I know you grew up with Gokce Hatun
in the same marquee, like siblings.
He is fulfilling the oath he took
to extinct our kin one by one.
There must be someone in
the nomad group who serves him.
It is apparent he is not alone.
Now it is time...
...to fulfill the promise I gave you.
I know that you think of the future of
your nomad group as much as the state.
You are right.
Noyan is not alone.
I came to know there is a woman
from your nomad tent with him.
And he sets all his games with her.
Who is that woman?
-I learnt Noyan's place, too.
-Where?
If he kidnapped Gokce Hatun, he
must have taken her to his secret place.
Shahzada Yigit must be there, too.
Perform the mission
Sultan Alaeddin gave you.
Kill Shahzada...
...save Gokce Hatun...
...and learn who the traitor is.
Ameer Sadettin,
where is this secret place?
Have a bite, first. Get a good rest.
Tomorrow is the day
of battle for both of us.
While you settle accounts with Noyan,
I will strike the headquarters...
...of the revolter Turkmen Beys.
Yes, I found out where they are, too.
Before the revolter Beys gather
raider Alps, against Sultan Alaeddin...
... I will do away with them.
Sungurtekin, it is time that
peace comes to these lands.
My business here is done.
I think of returning to Konya.
And I would like to put someone
I trust in my place when I return.
Sungurtekin. It is you.
Death is quite close to you.
If you are dreaming of escaping from me
as you did from the Templars, do not.
If you are dreaming of
scaring me with death, do not.
Death is reunion for me.
Your woman was burnt alive while
she was trying to show prowess, too.
You shall not burn, too.
What is happening there?
I came for the submittance letter
you would write to Ertugrul.
Ertugrul Bey will not
betray Sultan Alaeddin.
It is a loss of time.
We need to gather the army and take
stand against Sultan Alaeddin at once.
When you write the letter,
be sure that Ertugrul will come here.
He will make your Beys more powerful.
Your loyal Beys would like
to see Ertugrul submit to you.
And Turgut Alp's life depends on it.
Or else, they will take
their rage out on him.
Here, Sheikh.
Dervish enhanced his nomad dexterities.
Thanks to you, Sheikh.
-May God not taint our relish on earth.
-Amen.
How is the situation at nomad tent?
One trouble ends,
the other starts, Sheikh.
Ertugrul Bey cannot lift his head up...
...from striving with nuisances,
grappling with enemy.
Permission.
He must have been
able to, see, he visits us.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you, Bey.
I heard God was pouring grace down on you.
Grace?
Your troubles,
nuisances never came to an end.
We become astonished if a
day goes without trouble now.
-Give a drop of molasses to your Bey, too.
-Okay, Sheikh.
-Here, Bey.
-Thank you, Dervish.
Delicious, no?
-Bless your hands, Dervish.
-Enjoy, Bey.
Grape is different, molasses is different.
You have to be a grape to become molasses.
Yet, grape is not molasses.
And molasses is not grape.
Grape cures one ill but
molasses cures a thousand.
Grape becomes molasses
after long and grueling journeys.
To cure a thousand ill...
...you need to be snatched from your
home, to be crushed, to boil in flames.
There is a pain, a struggle,
a suffering in every pleasure.
You need to take on
this journey to cure a thousand ill.
Child, from the first day
you set off to Aleppo...
...by my God's allowance,
you faced many troubles...
...you brought
many enemies to their knees.
Who knows what troubles you will
encounter on this holy journey.
Many pharaohs,
many demons will set traps for you.
They will try to overcome you.
As long as they torment you...
...God willing, you and
your kin will make history.
If God permits.
It is as if I fell into a
different trouble this time.
As if there are abysses
between me and my brothers.
The mad horses within
me cannot dream with them...
...cannot battle by their side anymore.
Remember, son.
His brothers threw Joseph to the well.
And Joseph forgave them.
May God grant us a heart like Joseph's.
Amen.
Ertugrul Bey will come to you hastily
when he reads this letter from Sultan.
The day is the day for battle,
Sultan. May our path be blessed.
Konur Bey, have this letter delivered to
Ertugrul Bey with a messenger at once.
I wish to see him in my presence tomorrow.
As you wish, Sultan.
Sultan wrote the submittance letter.
Ertugrul will act valiantly
and come to these fools.
Do not be here when he arrives.
I do not want you
get hurt in that blood bath.
Neither Beys nor Alps want us here, Noyan.
We took many lives
of them shepherds at the time.
What will happen to Turgut Alp?
No one will be left alive here
when Sadettin comes.
Take good care of the boy. Do as I said.
Selcan, my wife.
Everybody knows how you gave Noyan hell.
Gokce is of your blood, too.
She will certainly give him
hell, too. Do not worry.
How will my sister do with
that Mongol dog, Gundogdu?
He will kill my sister.
God forbid, Hatun. Do not talk like that.
Keep your heart at ease.
She will surely return to her home.
Let us leave here.
Everyday a new trouble befalls us.
Let us leave.
Let us go to the lands
where we can raise our child in peace.
I have searched
for a woman to love  for years.
I lost her before I attained my wish.
Do not lose your hope.
You will retrieve her.
That savage has the woman
I could not dare to savor the scent of.
Who knows what pains she is suffering.
And I am waiting here.
I feel like I will go
insane the more I think.
What if they torture her?
What if they do something to her?
What if...
Brother!
Brother.
I will bring her back to her marquee.
If I cannot bring her
back to her marquee...
...this land becomes a grave for me.
Be patient for a while.
Be patient.
My God will unite you. Stay strong.
Halime.
I do not have a word to console you.
And it crushes me.
We have no one
but God to take shelter in...
...and we have nothing
to turn to but patience.
You know my brother would not betray.
You always protect him.
That is my consolation, Bey.
You, my mother, your brothers
did all you can for my brother.
I know that.
Is there permission, Bey?
Come in, Abdurrahman.
Bey, Konur Alp sent a messenger.
He brought a letter.
Do not let that revolter Alp in.
-I will come.
-As you wish, Bey.
Son, what is happening?
The news I waited for has come.
I have a letter for you from our Sultan.
I am given the duty of taking you to our
Sultan if you follow the letter's summons.
-Wait for me at the end of the nomad tent.
-As you wish, Bey.
We have news from Yigit.
Halime.
What does it say?
What does Yigit say, Halime?
Tugtekin Bey will not fall to your trap.
You will not kill him.
Why? Is it because my aunt
said you were in love with Ertugrul?
Tugtekin does not
want me as his wife anymore.
He will not come to Noyan's feet for me.
And when he comes,
he will come to wreck you.
You all will have your share
of Tugtekin Bey's sword.
Gokce Hatun!
Do you think I do not know
how Tugtekin is in love with you?
That fool lover
would risk everything for you.
I understood that when my aunt
told him you loved Ertugrul.
He would do everything for you.
He would even spurn death.
He will fall running into Noyan's trap.
He will give his head
to Noyan's sword.
You will see.
What does Yigit say, Halime?
He says he wants you to take the rein
of his armies, become his commander.
Thereupon, the Beys who revolted
want you to align yourself with them.
How could he do this? How?
When we trust him,
when we shed tears for him...
He saw what my father has gone through.
How much we suffered
in the hands of Templars?
How can he descend this much?
Halime.
Halime, look at me.
We both know Yigit is too
honorable to do such thing.
There is something wrong.
Then why does he pull you into a trap?
Why does he want you
to come with a messenger?
You cannot go with the messenger,
Ertugrul. Do not even think about it.
Ertugrul!
My brother wrote a secret
information inside the letter.
My father taught us that.
Use the first and last letter of the word.
And write a letter within a letter.
-What does Yigit say?
-Turgut is alive.
He will save him and stop the rebellion.
He wants you to go to him.
My God!
Look at Gokce Hatun.
Die, you scum!
You have nowhere to run to, Gokce.
I don't have a problem
with you. I want Fiery Boy.
Give one, take one.
Let us not sadden each other.
So he did it for his state,
for our brother Turgut, huh, Bey?
Yigit Alp is a gallant
Alp as his name suggests.
He did not let you down.
Yigit has done his part.
Now, it is our turn.
So, when are we taking off, Bey?
Yes, Bey, let us go and get
Yigit Alp and Turgut Brother at once.
They want me to go alone.
I will go by myself.
We must follow the rules of the game.
Bey, you are talking about going
in alone amongst the revolters.
And Noyan is there, too, Bey.
Apparently, he is waiting for you.
Kill us but do not say you will go alone.
What is destined will happen.
The only solution is, I go alone and
eloign Turkmen Beys from rebellion.
That is the only way I can bring
Yigit and Turgut to the nomad tent.
That is the only way to be rid
of Kopek who haunts our state...
...and Noyan who plagues our nomad groups.
If we do not cry out the right
by ourselves to the revolters...
...to hypocrites, to traitors when
needed, as Prophet Abraham did...
...Nimrods will not
refrain from shedding blood.
One needs to be afire to be Abraham.
Bey.
We live to burn like Abraham did for
God and to surrender like Ismail did.
Bey, why do you keep yourself distant
from us when our purpose is the same.
Kayi women are nimble.
I learnt that from Selcan Hatun.
You are like your sister.
I will build a harem of Kayi women
for myself, when the time comes.
I will not remove
my armor when I bed them.
Why would you lay here woman?
Your blood made your grave.
Your rosy face withered.
It became sorrowful as the Gobi desert.
I will offer you
to sacred lands with my own hands.
I will sacrifice you,
Ertugrul, Tugtekin and many more...
...for Heavenly Father.
I will drown all of you in your blood.
The sacred lands will
gush out your carrions.
You cannot untie this deadlock
without ceding from your life.
Our duty is to take lives
and give lives for God...
...without drawing away
from the path of God.
If I do not return, give your blessing.
And send my greetings to Wise Men.
Tell them that Ertugrul
died as a martyr on this blessed path.
May God help and protect you, Bey.
Amen.
Ertugrul is playing with fire again.
How would I leave him alone?
Gundogdu.
Ertugrul is going to his destiny.
We cannot do anything.
Do you not know he would
not return upon your word?
He is the half of my heart, mother.
How would I leave my heart without me?
Gundogdu.
You traitor scum!
Traitor!
Listen to me carefully.
Bring me Tugtekin.
The time has come.
I will wait for him at the narrow pass.
As you wish, Noyan.
The news I waited from Yigit has come.
I will go to the revolters' base.
While you are looking for Gokce...
...do not fall for
your anger and fall into his trap.
Both your lives depend on it.
You know who is the traitor.
And who is behind him.
Take measures.
They will pull you to a trap.
If getting entrapped like Prophet Huseyin
and to die longing for a drop of water...
...is in our share, we will take it.
Alright.
I will speak with the revolter Beys
and explain this is Kobek's ruse.
What if they don't believe you?
Our loved ones' lives depends on it.
Give your blessing.
Noyan will certainly send a sign to you.
Be nimble.
Do not worry.
Ertugrul Bey.
If God allows
and we get rid of this trouble...
...I will come to the
Byzantium border with you.
Me and my nomad group are at your service.
May God help us all, Tugtekin Bey.
Amen.
Soon, Gokce Hatun.
You will unite with your man
not to be separated again.
Do you think Tugtekin
would let you get away with these?
You are fiery like your man.
Fiery Boy must be
exhausted of your longing.
Do not keep him waiting.
If Aktolgali will take
you to your destiny...
...then may God help you.
May the sun not burn your skin.
May the rain not make your body perish.
May not a rock touch your feet.
Leave like water
and come back like water.
Call the ones who attempted
against our nomad group...
...my brother, our state
to account, then come Ertugrul.
Know that I am going to the ones
we love, the ones we would die for.
Aktolgali will take me
like a bird and bring me back at once.
As long as the ones left
behind are not destitute...
...and their hopes do not wane.
Sultan is waiting for you.
However, he also wants to be
sure we are not followed.
Other Alps will take you on the road,
they will escort you to Sultan.
But if anyone follows,
the meeting will not take place.
We will not be responsible for that.
Ertugrul!
He's gone, mother.
I left him alone because of my damned arm.
He took a part of our souls when he left.
But we need to be fortitude.
We will pray so where he went would
not become his grave but our hope...
...so he would not return from where he
reached with a funeral but with victory.
If God permits.
We found Shahzada Yigit's den...
...the one who threatened
the perpetuity of state...
...who disregarded Sultan who aggravated
and debauched Turkmen Beys.
Now, our duty is to ensure the welfare
of our Sultan and our state.
This home of rebellion will be razed
and whoever submitted to him will be
killed along with Shahzada Yigit.
Whoever participated in this negligence.
They will have their share of our swords'
cold and piercing side.
Traitors must die!
Long live, Sultan Aleaddin!
If you will try to persuade me to submit
to you, do not waste your breath.
I will not submit to you.
Turgut Alp, I am not worried
about becoming sultan.
I worry about saving you.
Do you think I have forgotten
the pains you have suffered
on Templars' hands because of me?
Noyan forced me into this.
He threatened me with killing Dundar.
I had to enter this game
to save Dundar's life.
And now I wish to release you from here
and stop this rebellion with
Ertugrul Bey's support.
What are you saying, Yigit?
I wrote a letter to Ertugrul Bey.
When my sister reads the letter
she will find out the truth.
You will return to nomad tent and
bring Ertugrul Bey here, Turgut Alp.
And I will do all I can to dissuade
Turkmen Beys from this rebellion.
When Ertugrul Bey comes
he will vanquish the traitor rebels
whom were not persuaded.
I will not leave you here alone, Yigit.
Do not ask this from me.
I ventured everything, Turgut Alp.
I will sacrifice my life on this path for
our state, for our loved ones, if need be.
You will be tied here like a dog
until you submit to me.
I am at the end of my tether.
Bey, Bogac was seen at the exit
of the nomad tent.
Get on the horses. We are setting forth.
Locate yourselves.
Bey. We located Alps to places you told.
What will we do now, Bey?
There is no horse around.
Apparently, there is no one around.
-They shall wait for Noyan.
-For Noyan, Bey?
Noyan will come here, sooner or later.
Everyone shall keep their eyes open.
Even if he is alone, he will not die
before taking many of us.
Do you understand me?
Alps.
-Ulubilge!
-Ulubilge, captive is escaping!
Captive is escaping!
Turgut is escaping! Catch him!
We will get off the horses here.
You will continue with your eyes
closed from here.
Hand your sword.
Ertugrul, son of Suleyman Shah,
never gives his weapon.
Walk ahead.
Bogac.
Bogac!
It looks awkward.
Give it to me so I can show you
how well hatchet suits me.
-Brother!
-Bey!
By God!
-By God!
Turgut!
Shut him up!
Thank God they did not touch
your life, brother.
If it was not Yigit, I would have been
dead by now, Bey.
I know it all.
He proved he is a brother
befitting Halime Sultan.
Thank you.
I lost my mind, brother.
I thought you were dead.
Would anything happen to my brother?
They tried to kill him many times
-...they could not do it.
-Thank you.
Brother, how did you severed his head?
It slashed like a watermelon.
Brother!
The day I learned about your betrayal...
...I offered your carrion to
holy spirits, Sungurtekin.
I will give both your carrions to spirits.
And Oghuz Khan's seal will be my reward.
I will return to extinct your kin,
Sungurtekin.
Tell Ertugrul to wait for me. I will
strike your nomad tent like lightning.
I will kill you this time, Noyan.
Be it my oath, I will kill you.
Bogac.
Gokce, where are you?
Ride! This way!
-Let go of me!
-Gokce!
Goncagul?
Come here, the boy with fire.
Tugtekin, I beg you, go away from here.
Go, he will kill you.
Tugtekin, I beg you, leave.
I beg you. He will kill you.
We had an unfinished business
left from last time.
Now, it is time to finish that business.
Since you came out of the hole I threw
you because I thought you died
then let us finish it.
Let Gokce Hatun go.
You have what you wanted.
See, I am in front of you.
I will free her suffering soul forever.
She took Goncagul from me.
And I will take her from you.
An eye for an eye, Fiery Boy.
Eye for an eye.
If your wife behaved well,
she would have lived.
Perhaps, she would be devastated
by your pain.
But she would still live.
My problem is with Ertugrul.
With the ones who share his blood.
Tugtekin, I beg you, leave here.
He will kill you. I beg you, go, Tugtekin.
No.
I free your suffering soul forever.
I am yours, Tugtekin.
I will be yours forever.
No.
No!
He cut his ropes with a dagger.
Who gave him that dagger?
Sultan, do you have
any information on this?
Ertugrul Bey arrived!
Ertugrul Bey.
Ertugrul Bey arrived.
I came here so neither you
nor Shahzada Yigit
or Sultan Aleaddin would become
an instrument in a traitorous game.
You should know, Ameer Sadettin
is behind your rebellion.
He was aware of every step
you took from the beginning.
Ameer Sadettin is the one
that coalesced with Noyan
and pulled you into this traitorous trap.
He resorted to such a game because
he knew you would not submit to him.
We will not give up on this path
as long as our Sultan is with us.
We hosted you because we wanted
to be the commander of our Alps
since we know you are gallant
and undefeatable.
Behave as a guest.
Do you still not understand, Konur Bey?
I tell you Ameer Sadettin will kill anyone
who does not submit to himself.
And you first.
Maybe he is coming onto us
with his soldiers right now.
You are ruining yourselves
your nomad groups, your Alps
as you persist.
The honorable Beys of Oghuz!
We have only one state wedged
inbetween Mongols and Crusaders
and that is Seljukian Empire.
This state Kinik Beys founded
is all of our state.
Neither ignobles like Kobek nor
the enemies of our state can inhibit it.
Now, I say, give up before it is too late.
Give up so our state will be everlasting
and our enemies be parried.
Catch Ertugrul Bey!
Stop!
Ertugrul Bey's words are right.
Know that I renounce from the throne
that is rightfully mine.
You do not have a Sultan anymore.
-Irruption!
-Yigit!