Episode 52 will start after 12:05 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
It has been hurting me for a long time.
But I did not take it seriously.
When I was getting ready to go
to caravansary, it started to ache.
This boil is hurting me.
Did you for your arm, Bey?
Not really, we trained
with our Alps just now.
I wish you did not.
You should rest immediately.
And I do not know whether this boil
is benign or not.
But if it is malignant,
it will show itself with fever.
I cannot rest now.
Amer Sadettin Kobek is waiting for me
in caravansary.
So let me know when you come back
to the nomad tent.
-Okay, I will, do not worry.
-Bey.
Do not underestimate this boil.
Thank you.
God is a benevolent ambusher,
Tugtekin Bey.
You saw the killer of your
mother and father.
But it is not enough.
Gumustekin is the one
behind these murders.
But not just him.
It is our duty to reveal the ones
who are undermining our Sultan and state.
Save yourself.
Will we not do anything, Ertugrul?
Be patient, Tugtekin Bey.
Selcan Hatun is not alone.
Both of you will die!
Aytolun will hurt Selcan, Ertugrul.
Do not worry, Tugtekin.
The bow of Sungur is on them.
He will shoot if something happens.
Selcan Hatun and Banu Cicek
would never give into this woman.
Knowing that you are in command of the
nomad groups which has
the most brave Alps gives me comfort,
Gumustekin.
As long as I have the leashes of Tugtekin
and Gundogdu in my hands,
It will be easier for me to control these
reckless Turkmen tribes.
When you go back to Konya, you will
be busy with more things.
Trust me, your highness.
If God permits, Gumustekin.
If God permits.
But what if Mother Hayme listens to
Ertugrul and decides to stop you?
I will never permit that to happen.
Gundogdu will be the Bey
of Kayi tribe soon.
And he is to be my son in law.
Do you think Gundogdu will disobey his
mother to become margrave?
Gundogdu is a decisive man
who is willing to do anything
for his nomad group.
He was not in the succession race
just because he did not want
any conflict with his brothers.
Everyone knows that.
But if Ertugrul dies,
the road to his succession will be open.
We will see.
Gundogdu Bey is here, his highness Ameer.
Invite him in.
Get well soon, Gundogdu Bey.
-Thank you, his highness Ameer.
-Come here.
I hope nothing is wrong, Gundogdu Bey.
Nothing important, Gumustekin Bey.
It is a boil.
I can send you a doctor from Konya
if you want.
Thank you.
A boil is nothing for Gundogdu Bey,
his highness Ameer.
Thank you, Bey.
For ten years, Sultan has been with us.
-God bless our Sultan.
-Amen.
Amen.
But in these ten years,
I feel at ease for the first time.
I am very happy to know that
these important lands
that are between the trade routes
are in safe hands.
My margrave on one side,
Gundogdu and Tugtekin Bey on the other.
You will have our state's
never ending gratitude.
-Thank you, his highness Ameer.
-Thank you.
It is time to share some state secrets
with you, Gundogdu Bey.
Banu Cicek, go away! You are wounded!
You have to give this evidence to
Ertugrul! Go away!
Give your sword to me!
Tell Ertugrul Bey to find me,
he will know where I am!
Come here, you wretch!
Come on Selcan Hatun, go away.
Not even hell will be your salvation!
Selcan, I swear that you will die!
Avshar tribe, Bayindir tribe,
Kargun tribe.
Karaevli tribe, Bayat tribe
and Kisik tribe.
And the others
live in a disorderly fashion from
Ayyubid border to Georgia border.
This disorder weakens the state
and nomad groups.
All of the tribes are fighting against the
Mongol plague, his highness.
Of course, their loses hurt all of us.
But we have to be like an unshakeable
castle inside and outside.
Gumustekin Bey is right.
The problem is not just Mongols.
Ayyubids also provoke Turkmen tribes to
rebel over and over again.
Those tribes fighting against
the Mongol plague right now
may become a serious threat to our state.
It is essential for us to take
precautions to protect our state.
I wish all nomad groups were loyal
as Dodurga and Kayi tribes.
Unfortunately they are not.
That is the main reason why I want to
gather Turkmen tribes under my banner.
The most important thing is
to make Kayi tribe get to know us better.
It will strengthen our state.
But the Beys of the two nomad group
that I trust the most
must be brave warriors.
This goes both for Dodurga
and Kayi tribes.
What I want to say is
we want to see the Bey of Kayi tribe
by our side
when our state needs him the most.
Thank you, his highness Ameer.
You can be sure of that.
Hayme Hatun is brave enough to
stand against most of the Turkmen Beys.
But she is a woman nevertheless.
Do you understand
where I am going with this?
Gundogdu Bey.
Alps are like wild horses.
If a Bey does not hold his horse's
reins tight
It doesn't matter how fast
or strong that horse is.
It's destination will be unknown.
Surely.
You must hold the reins of
Kayi Alps tightly.
The decision is yours, Gundogdu Bey.
But you should know that
his highness Ameer and I
will always be by your side.
Thank you.
Think about this carefully.
You will make the best decision
when the time comes.
Selcan!
Until Gumustekin falls into my trap
I want you to host the killer
of your mother and father
one more night in your tent.
You will smile upon that ominous woman
and call her mother.
You will put up with the lies
and slanders of Goncagul.
You will obey to Gumustekin.
Tonight, they will be so afraid
they can do everything.
All you have to do is put up with the lies
they will tell to set you against us.
Tonight, none of us will sleep.
We are obliged to the truth, Ertugrul Bey.
Selcan Hatun is returning to nomad tent
safe and sound, Ertugrul.
-Do not worry.
-Thank you, brother.
You saved my life once Ertugrul
and now you saved my nomad group.
Your help is priceless.
Our only aim is make Gumustekin
confess the truth.
When we achieve this
we will come up smelling like
a rose from our biggest war.
Come on.
Where is Selcan?
She is alone with that woman.
And also, Banu Cicek is wounded.
Oh God!
Do not worry. Relieve yourself.
Ertugrul Bey and Sungurtekin Bey
will not let anything happen to Selcan.
And If God permits, Tugtekin Bey
will see the truth with his eyes.
If God permits, daughter.
I want Selcan to come here safe and sound.
They get their deserts. We will see.
I want her here.
Where are you, aunt? Where are you?
-May it be easy, sister.
-Thank you.
May it be easy.
Goncagul.
The days that you jumped down
the nomad group's throat is over.
Your end has come.
You will get your deserts
within a short time.
What are you gabbing again, Selcan Hatun?
Do not rush. You will see sooner or later.
Aunt.
What did I do, aunt?
The people that split my father's bread
the people that we believe and
treat with great respect killed us.
How my eyes and heart sealed that much?
What did I do?
I do not have power to be mentioned
as Bey or even as humankind.
You cannot get anywhere by behaving
like that, Tugtekin Bey.
Come to yourself.
Carelessness sealed both
our hearts and our eyes, son.
Do not forget that I hosted them
in my table.
They stole the trust that
our Sultan gave to Sungurtekin.
I could not burst out my anger
to their faces.
I let my son Gundogdu to marry with
that centipede Goncagul.
If Ertugrul did not break
the seal of our hearts
we would be more miserable.
You fought with lots of enemies,
Tugtekin Bey.
You are always in the front
for your nomad group.
Everybody knows how you fought
with Mongols.
And how you risked your life.
Those beautiful days are so far now.
We all know that you have
a brave decisive heart.
Those days are here, son.
We will endure only one more day.
You saw the light within the utter
darkness with lots of pain.
Last ditch effort.
Tugtekin Bey, last ditch effort.
Now it is time to get out from this utter
darkness and arrange the justice train.
-Selcan!
-Mother!
How are you? Are you fine?
I am fine mother.
I know you were worried about me.
But fortunately, I am okay.
I stamped the mark of Kayi tribe
on Aytolun's arm.
If Tugtekin Bey did not have a claim
I would kill her.
I cannot remunerate you, Selcan Hatun.
Forgive me.
I will take care of Selcan, mother.
Do not worry.
Come, have a seat.
Aunt! Aunt!
What happened to you?
I could not capture the evidence.
Both of them managed to escape.
Banu Cicek will give the evidence
to Ertugrul.
We must avoid this.
Goncagul come to yourself!
Selcan will die, there's no other way.
The main point is Ertugrul.
Gumustekin Bey must kill him.
Aunt, is it easy? How will it be?
Do not forget that you are
the daughter of a mangrave, Goncagul.
Ertugrul or another person cannot
escape from the anger of Gumustekin Bey.
Now we must inform your father.
Alps are like wild horses.
If a Bey does not hold
his horse's halter tight
whether his horse is strong and speedy,
it is destination will be unbeknown.
You must hold both Alps'
and Kayi people's halter tight.
Did you see what the abscess
did to Bey in one day?
He will be miserable when
he learns the truth, Selcan.
He did not believe you and Ertugrul Bey.
He will learn everything now.
How is your arm, son?
It hurts a little, mother.
I got tired when riding the horse.
But I am fine.
Let us send word to Artuk Bey, brother.
No brother, thank you. I am fine.
Ameer Sadettin Kobek presented
his compliments to all of you.
Gumustekin Bey is just around the corner.
He is coming here soon.
He may come right in.
As you know, we have to meet
the margrave properly.
Have a seat, son.
We have things to tell you.
Look, Goncagul.
Your father and I trusted you
at the beginning.
You must maintain your composure.
Do not forget.
We survived lots of hardships until today.
We will overcome this as well.
We will aunt, we will.
They will all hang on to the sole of
our boots like bugs
and they will mix up with
the soil of the road we walk.
They will be pale in comparison.
Do you understand me?
Do not disregard your father.
I know aunt, do not worry.
I hope nothing is wrong.
You seem like our nomad group
fell into hands of Mongols.
I wish it did, brother.
What are you saying nephew?
I know the murderer of
my mother and father.
Now it is time for you to wake you up
from carelessness.
What are you saying?
Ertugrul?
What is happening brother?
What did you do again?
I threw together Banu Cicek
and Selcan Hatun
near the nomad tent, brother.
-What are you saying?
-Gundogdu.
Listen to him.
What should I listen, mother?
Do not you hear him?
He says that he threw together
the murderer of my uncle and my wife.
Aytolun was there, too.
Two brave women...
...Banu Cicek and Selcan Hatun
put their lives on the line...
...and showed me the truth,
Gundogdu Brother.
What is that truth?
Aytolun, who was deceived
by Ertugrul Bey, was there.
Her only aim was to kill them.
I heard that she killed
my mother and father.
That is all brother.
Banu Cicek and Selcan Hatun
took us to Aytolun
and Aytolun will take us to Gumustekin.
Tomorrow, it will be Gumustekin's turn
if God permits, brother.
I know you feel miserable, son. But...
...Goncagul is in this, too.
The light of moon brightens
the mountains before it rises.
We will not return to
this ominous darkness.
I did not believe you, brother...
....and I did not believe my wife.
I tried to take that sinister woman
to my bed.
We do not have time and power to think
and be grieved about these things.
It is time to take care
of this matter, son.
What should I do Ertugrul?
You cannot do anything
with your condition.
Let Tugtekin and I solve this.
So they deceived both Tugtekin Bey
and I, is that so?
They wanted me to be Bey just for this.
They entrapped both of us, brother.
We will not surrender, brother.
We will play a game just as they did.
So that our margrave will come
to our nomad tent...
...we will meet him properly.
Brother!
Son! Son!
-Brother.
-Inform Artuk Bey.
In the marriage of our master the prophet
and Almighty Mother Hatice
we can find the secrets of love
respect, fidelity and a happy family.
After the death of Mother Hatice
our master the prophet
memorialized her with love and respect
and he was always loyal to her.
The love between our master
and Hatice never decreased
and it increasingly went on for 25 years.
Our mother, Hatice was the biggest
supporter and friend of our master.
Our master told it to
Mother Hatice firstly
when he had the divine inspiration.
In those days, our blessed mother
supported him mostly.
When our master cloistered
in Hira mountain
Mother Hatice took his meal
regardless of her workers.
Our master was feeling that
his blessed wife would come
and he went to the foothills
of the mountain to meet her.
Because he knew that it was hard
to climb the Hira mountain
and he spared his precious wife.
One day, Mother Hatice
was waiting for our master
at the roof of their home.
Her relatives told her,
"Why are you doing this Hatice?
It is so hot, your old body
will get tired."
And our blessed mother told them
"When my master is under the sun,
I cannot wait in shade."
She showed her loyalty, respect
and the meaning of love by living.
When his biggest supporter friend
and wife Mother Hatice died
our master grieved so much and
they called that year the gloom year.
After the death of our blessed mother
our master memorialized her
with love and goodness.
Whenever someone talked about her
his eyes filled with tears.
Our master showed his fidelity and
dependence to Mother Hatice
in the conquest of Mecca one more time.
The Muslims that were expelled
from their country conquested Mecca.
Our master conquested Mecca
with ten thousand soldiers
and visited the grave of our mother
and cried for her.
When our master's companion asked him
where to set up his tent, he answered
"Set it up in front of Hatice's grave
I will watch her."
and he proved his loyalty.
Love is a gift for humankind from God.
Love, respect and fidelity
hold the partners together.
Fidelity is not forgetting.
Fidelity is loving in a good day
or in a bad day
no matter how great your trouble is.
Slowly, Bey.
Gundogdu Bey!
You have a fever, Bey.
You must rest completely.
Do not worry, Artuk Bey.
I will not leave him alone for a moment.
Artuk Bey.
As I understand, my brother's arm
is worse than we think.
What makes you anxious that much,
Artuk Bey?
Say it for God's sake.
Artuk Bey.
They are my family,
I have nothing to hide.
-This abscess is a big trouble, Bey.
-What trouble, Artuk Bey?
I have never seen an abscess that reached
to the bone in a night, Hayme Hatun.
If we cannot dry it, I am afraid
of the things that can happen.
Tell me, Artuk Bey.
I know this abscess well.
It was at the back of Suleyman Shah.
Tell us and let us take measures.
If we cannot dry the wound
it will mix with his blood.
And it may kill him, God forbid.
Is there another remedy for this illness?
I hope we will dry the wound Selcan Hatun.
-I hope so.
But I might have to cut his arm
to prevent it from mixing with blood.
Gundogdu Bey.
Never hinder the medicines I gave.
I will come and control your arm
frequently.
Thank you.
The rest is the volition of God.
Excuse me.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Selcan.
Take care of my son.
Do not worry, mother.
Oh Selcan!
After all the things I did...
...I cannot dare to look at you.
Wait. Listen to me.
I know you will forgive me.
You have always forgiven me.
But I do not know how I can forgive
myself this time Selcan.
After all the things I told you.
I cannot forget the things I told you.
They deceived you, Bey.
But I never gave up loving you
for one day.
I know, you always loved me.
You turned my world into heaven.
Everything will be the same, will it not?
If God permits, Bey.
I feel a little cold. Tuck me in.
God bless, Gumustekin Bey!
That corrupt man's day-old
sultanate started.
Do not forget, you will kiss his hand.
What are you saying, Ertugrul?
You must have great respect
for margrave without fail, brother.
Welcome, Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Tugtekin Bey.
It is a good welcome
befitting to our state.
Welcome, Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you.
God bless, Gumustekin Bey!
If you accept...
...I want to give you gold coins.
Of course, it would not recoup the things
you did for our state
for such a long time.
But you can consider it
as a little gift of our state.
Good luck with your margrave duty,
Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
May your margrave duty be blessed,
Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
Tonight, I want to host you
in my tent with Tugtekin Bey.
Your wish is my command, Hayme Hatun.
I will accept your invitation.
Thank you.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Gumustekin Bey.
May your margrave duty be blessed.
Thank you, Gundogdu Bey. Thank you.
Share it with your Alps.
Thank you.
Come, have a seat.
Congratulations, Bey.
Thank you, Sungurtekin Bey.
You proved your loyalty
to our state one more time.
Thank you.
Take it.
I will share them with
the children of martyrs.
We saw the kind face of our state.
Now we will see its justice.
Everyone will get their share
from its justice, Gumustekin Bey.
Whenever Ertugrul Bey talks about
justice he disturbs the peace.
May your margrave duty be blessed,
Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
I will be happy to share those golds
with the ones in need.
May your margrave duty be blessed, Bey.
May your margrave duty be blessed,
Gumustekin Bey.
Wait here!
There is a strict order,
no one can approach him.
Brother, we will give some water
and we will go.
Look, he is devastated.
No Bamsi, do not even bother.
What are they doing here?
Gumustekin Bey.
If you permit, we want to give
some water to Dogan.
How dare you?
Do you ask for permission
to give water to the convict?
-Remove them from here immediately.
-As you please, Bey.
Wait brother. Wait.
We are reasonable, brother.
Take this brother,
he must be very thirsty.
Thank you, brother.
What happened to your arm Aytolun?
I got wounded when I was fighting
with Selcan, brother.
What are you saying?
Banu Cicek.
She met with Selcan in Karakayalar.
How dare? How did you
let this happen, Aytolun?
-I was forced to.
-What does it mean?
Why did not you tell Alps? Why?
Banu Cicek was going to give
an evidence to Selcan
that will prove that we committed
the murders, father.
What are you saying, Goncagul?
What evidence?
We do not know.
I went there to kill both of them.
I could not say anything
to anyone, brother.
I was afraid that the evidence
would change hands.
It would be our end father. Our end.
And Banu Cicek? Where is she?
She escaped to give the evidence
to Ertugrul.
If Ertugrul lives, this would be
a disaster for all of us.
That corrupt man attained his desire.
We will collapse his sultanate around him.
He proved us that he won't be
a mangrave but a tyrant.
He is trying to buy his sins with
the gold coins he gives away.
The Beys that plead will pay
a heavy price for those golds.
But we will punish him first.
It is time to get even with him,
Mother Hayme.
From now on, things
will not be easy, son.
He will not stop until he kills you.
I have already given him an opportunity
to kill me, Mother.
He knows that I will go and get
the evidence from Banu Cicek.
He will come after me with his soldiers.
When he finds us together,
he will find the opportunity.
And all I have to do is
to give him that opportunity.
How will you cope with the soldiers, son?
And those soldiers will
carry out their missions.
If any one of them gets hurt,
it will be on us.
What if they kill you?
Do not worry, Mother Hayme.
We will keep sight of him all the time.
Nothing will happen
to our soldiers, mother.
If I can not get hold of Gumustekin,
everything will be over.
But, what scares me is not this.
What is it, son?
God knows what Gumustekin will
do before he starts following me.
This is going to be a long night.
They will not idle away the hours
doing nothing tonight.
I will not come to dinner tonight.
All of you will be my eyes and ears.
All the words he said,
all the things he did will be
a big threat for us.
Open your eyes and ears.
It is difficult for me to let you
go alone, brother.
I am sure you will be with me
with your prayers.
-You should rest, brother.
-Thank you.
Gundogdu Bey.
I worry about your arm, Bey.
I wanted to see you.
I am fine, it is not important.
If you need anything,
do not hesitate to ask for it.
You know, I am always with you.
Just as you are always with
my father's mangrave.
I wanted to express my gratitude
to you again.
I only want what is good
for our state, Goncagul Hatun.
You can not understand how happy I am.
The ones play off against us will not
prevent our marriage.
If God permits, our tent will be merry
with our marriage, Bey.
If God permits.
Our tent and our nomad group
will be merry very soon.
But you do not look good, Bey.
I do not know if it is because your arm.
I am thinking about the murderer
of my uncle, Goncagul Hatun.
I will not be eased until
they get their deserts.
They will, Bey. They will.
If God permits.
I will not be eased untill
I see them dying in pain.
All I want is this.
-Excuse me, Bey.
-Of course.
-Did you hear the words of that snake?
-Yes I did, Bey.
Oh God, she is telling lies in my face.
How did I believe that woman?
Selcan.
After all the things I did to you,
after all the things I told you,
how could you forgive me?
You are innocent, Bey.
You forgave an evil woman like me, right?
If you had not made room for my sins
in your big heart,
I would not be there today.
Selcan.
From now on, I want you by my side
until the last day of my life.
I do not want anything else from God.
Thank God.
I am so happy to see those
two nomad groups in unity.
From now on, Kayi tribe and Dodurga tribe
will collaborate and we will be stronger.
You are right, Gumustekin Bey.
Your mangrave strengthened us
in Turkmen Seigniories.
If God permits, this Seigniory will always
remain within your mangrave.
May God protect our unity and solidarity.
Amen.
What happened to your arm Aytolun?
It is not important,
just a little scratch.
What a pity!
I am so sorry, get well soon.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
As soon as the murderers of
Korkut Bey answer to me,
I will visit other neighboring
Turkmen nomad groups.
They provided enough support
for my mangrave
and they filled us with pride.
And then I want to see the marriage of
Gundogdu Bey and my daughter.
Let justice be done upon them
and then we can solemnize.
Thank you, Gundogdu Bey.
You talked about justice, Gumustekin Bey.
Justice will be done upon them of course.
We all know this.
The murders of my brother
will answer to us.
But when you said justice,
you seemed like thinking about something.
It is true. I will get my hands
on this matter as the mangrave.
You made a good decision, Bey.
It is time to solve this problem
and be in peace within nomad groups.
Your justice will impower us...
...Gumustekin Bey.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey. Thank you.
As the mangrave, first I will start with
taking Dogan Alp and learning
the place of Banu Cicek.
And then she will be executed erewhile.
Tomorrow morning, my soldiers
will take Dogan Alp.
And they will cut his body
until the sharp sword of justice
will loose his sealed tongue.
Quick justice is the best.
I will not let this sedition
to disturb our nomad group.
From now on, it is my duty
to find the killer of Korkut Bey
and take his revenge.
God bless our mangrave.
We do not want to be disturbed with
the obstinacy of Ertugrul Bey.
You saved us from another disaster,
Gumustekin Bey.
Well done, nephew.
As a child who grew in this lands,
I knew that you would make a good Bey
from the beginning.
Thank you.
The joy of oncoming Nawruz
and the wedding of my daughter
will coincide, if God permits.
Am I right, daughter?
If God permits, Gumustekin Bey.
If God permits.
It is the best time to remove
the rust and dirt of the past
and make a fresh start like a spray.
May God give you a long life, Bey.
Our people are exhausted, Bey.
They do not have enough stregth left
to move, let alone go to Kefere border.
And there are Alps, Bey.
All the Alps say,
"Sword is good with it's scabbard."
In conclusion, everybody
wants peace in his crew.
They want peace when
Bey throttle each other,
when those corrupt people
try to take hold of our state.
Right? Is this peace, Turgut?
No, it is not, Bey.
It is not, but there is no one
as gallant as you.
Under this blue sky, each mountain
is no different for them.
Neither their hearts nor their eyes
know something else.
Yes, Bey. Your heart is different.
It is big enough to embrace
the whole world.
If you were not here, we would not
know what to do, Bey.
Who knows, we may have been out
at grass on different mountains, Bey.
Bamsi is right, Bey.
It is time to set your heart on.
If you do,
the brave men that will follow you to
the Byzantine border can show themselves.
May your words be light
to the dark hearts, Bey.
Firstly, we should end this instigation
tomorrow, Turgut.
Then I will carry this matter
to headquarters.
We can interpret the condition then.
Thank you, Bey.
Just know that we are with you
until we die, Bey.
I have brought some ayran to you, Bey.
God bless you, brother!
But could not you find village bread?
Oh, you brave man!
Tell me brother, if Ertugrul Bey says
that we are going to China,
will you follow him?
If Ertugrul Bey says that
we are going to the stars,
I would wing and fly,
don't you know that, Bamsi?
How magnificent!
How great!
With this brave men, we can go everywhere
and we can conquest every country, Bey.
Make yourself comfortable.
Thank you, Turgurt.
Thank you.
Thank you, Bey.
Maybe we should finish this tonight
before Ertugrul meet with
Banu Cicek, brother.
Of course I can not get in his tent
and kill him.
Pull yourself together, Aytolun.
A wounded and abashed man can do this.
How?
Tugtekin.
What would he do
if he learns his wife Gokce
is in love with another man?
Am I wrong, Goncagul?
I will do my best, aunt.
-Ertugrul.
-Yes, brother?
You are right, brother.
What happened, brother?
Gumustekin will take Dogan Alp
to caravansary tomorrow.
It is obvious that he will torture him.
And of course he will kill him.
He knows that I will not give
Dogan Alp to him.
He invited me looking into your eyes.
Is his aim to kill you while you
take him from the soldiers?
No brother. He wants to prove
that I collaborate with killers.
He wants me to kill his soldiers
while I take Dogan Alp.
Thus, he will prove that
I raise against him.
So, he will have the right on his side
to kill me.
Neither you nor my mother
will have anything to say.
What will you do Ertugrul?
Tomorrow we will take Dogan Alp
from the soldiers without spilling blood.
And Gumustekin?
If I am right, he will send Dogan Alp
with soldiers in advance.
And then he will follow us.
Let's see who will come under ambush.
Look at the things we talk, brothers.
Ever since I could remember,
we have always been in trouble.
My late father took on with
Alp Tekin for his entire lifetime
and he wasted his life.
Then Kurdoglu and now Gumustekin.
When will this suffering end?
Maybe this is our destiny, brother.
We are obliged to these things
until we make our own justice
in our own country, brother.
These instigators discipline us
like a dervish.
The truth and the situation is this.
All we have to do is to fight against
these instigators till the end.
You are right brother, but
I do not have power any longer.
I miss the days that I herd sheep.
I want to grow old with Selcan Hatun
and die with her.
I do not want anything else.
-Brother.
-Gundogdu.
I am fine. I want to sleep.
I am okay.
I want to sleep.
What happened, Goncagul Hatun?
I am sorry Bey, I am...
Goncagul!
What happened?
Goncagul learnt something
that she shouldn't have.
The thing she heard was too heavy for her.
What is that?
She is scared that the dark shadow of
the past will descend upon us.
That is all. Excuse me, Bey.
They will be so scared tonight that
they can do everything.
You will smile at that sinister woman
and call her mother.
You will put up with the lies
and slanders of Goncagul.
You will obey Gumustekin.
You will grin and bear
their slanders that...
...they use to turn us to each other.
May I come in?
Come in, Tugtekin Bey.
I want to know what is happening
in my nomad group.
Don't you afraid of
the curse of knowing, Bey?
I would rather be broiled in the truth
than living with lies.
Bravery is for enemies, Bey.
Bravery is impossible for the people
that you love more than your life.
Have your say.
Talking in circles only disquiets
this nomad group, mother.
Neither my tongue nor my heart
accept to tell these things to you.
Say it. I have more power after
all those pains. Do not worry.
So, you should know what Goncagul heard.
What did she hear?
The one who is in Gokce's heart.
What are you saying, mother?
I am afraid of your anger, son.
I do not want to cause another pain.
Maybe everything's over and
daughter Gokce forgot him.
Maybe she wiped the wound in her heart.
I do not want to malign.
I reached the end of my ropes, Mother.
Have your say.
Ertugrul Bey.
Before he saved Halime Sultan from Kefere
Gokce was in love with him.
Do you hear yourself?
I would rather die than
telling you these things.
I would regard all these things as
childhood adventures but...
But what?
But, after he married Halime Sultan,
Gokce could not quench the fire in her,
but yet she wanted to marry you, son.
Enough!
May I come in, Mother?
Come in, daughter.
I came here to say goodnight, mother.
Goodnight, daughter.
What happened, mother?
Nothing. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
Do you want anything, Bey?
I am tired. I just want to sleep.
I know your pain is fresh, but tell me
the thing that you could not tell, Bey.
Is it right that you were in love
with Ertugrul once?
Is that right, Gokce?
It is right, Bey.
And...
And Ertugrul?
Etrugrul Bey always
considered me a sister.
And when I told him
the things in my heart,
he tried to deter me like a brother.
When Ertugrul Bey took
Halime Sultan to nomad group,
I twisted the knife.
No matter what.
Halime Sultan became his wife.
I fired my heart with brands.
But I could not make it.
I could not give up on this love.
And then you found me.
I learnt what being loved means from you.
I understood that you are the man I love.
And I will love you
till the end of my life.
I wanted to tell you tons of times...
...but I got scared.
I got scared that you would
fall out of love with me.
Is there anything else
that you did not mention?
This is not only about Goncagul
and Aytolun.
So that Gumustekin is in the loop,
there must be another person behind him.
What if things go wrong?
It is my duty to kill all of them
until the last betrayar, Halime Sultan.
Do not worry.
If God permits, Ertugrul.
Ertugrul.
By looking these stubborn kicks,
it will be a boy.
Our son will be the nightmare of Kefere
after his father.
I wish he will be a good child
and serve his nation.
If God permits, Ertugrul Bey.
Hold on, Bey.
I am with you, Bey.
I will reduce your fever.
Look I am here, I am with you.
Hold on, hold on.
Bey...
Let yourself go.
Hold on Gundogdu Bey, Artuk Bey will come.
We are here to take the convict.
Untie him.
What are you doing?
-Why are you untying me?
-Be quiet! We are leaving.
Why did you untie me?
Dogan Alp!
Do not worry, you will be saved soon.
Alright! That is enough.
Turali!
Come on brothers. May God help us.
Amen, Bey.
Mother Hayme.
-I have something to say.
-Tell me, daughter.
Tugtekin Bey.
He learnt that I was in love
with Ertugrul Bey before.
I know, Mother Hayme.
Aytolun poisoned Tugtekin Bey's mind.
So, she wants to turn Tugtekin against
Ertugrul and hide the truth.
But Ertugrul...
...uncovered the fact that Aytolun
killed my brother and brother's wife.
And Tugtekin knows this.
Mother Hayme,
Gundogdu Bey is ill.
Tugtekin Bey who boils with
rage over the smallest things...
...apparently doesn't take
her wife's old flame seriously.
I don't get it, brother.
Tugtekin's dagger should have slit
Ertugrul's throat already.
Tugtekin and Gundogdu
are aware of everything.
What are you saying, brother?
Last night when I said I would take
Dogan Alp with me to deliver justice,
no one said anything.
Not even Tugtekin.
What shall we do?
Selcan must die today, Aytolun.
If Tugtekin found out the truth,
his time has also come.
Do I have permission,
Gumustekin Bey?
Come in, Cagri Bey.
Ertugrul Bey left the nomad tent.
-Are the soldiers ready?
-They are, Bey.
Then let's go punish those killers.
Don't worry brother.
Today, this will all be over.
Let's go, Cagri Bey.
Goncagul, keep an eye on Gundogdu.
Bey!
Gundogdu Bey!
We are losing him!
He is getting away!
Come here!
Brother!
Your captivity is over,
brother Dogan.
Thank you, Bey.
You got lucky again, brother.
Where is Cicek Hatun, Bey?
Do not worry,
we'll go see her now.
How long will we turn a blind eye,
Gumustekin Bey?
We still have time, Cagri Bey.
We'll keep following him.
He saved a traitor,
but he will never stop.
He will go and see
the real traitor.
On your horses!
Let's finish this. Come on.
I drew it from the well.
It's ice cold.
We have to prevent the abscess
from contaminating his blood.
The only remedy is black knots.
I can go pick some, Bey!
I know those mushrooms very well.
I used to pick them
for Suleyman Shah.
Go pick some,
Selcan Hatun. Hurry!
Here you are, Bey.
Oh God!
God help us.
Don't take my son
away from me.
Amen.
Isak, we need to draw some
blood from Gundogdu Bey.
Grab some leeches from the
medical tent at once.
Yes, Bey.
What is the rush, dervish Isak?
Did something happen to
Gundogdu Bey?
He got worse, Goncagul Hatun.
Where is Selcan Hatun going?
Artuk Bey sent her to
pick black knots.
Excuse me.
Can I look at that one?
Selcan!
What happened?
Where are you going?
Gundogdu Bey's
getting worse, Halime.
Artuk Bey asked for black knots.
I am going to pick some.
-I'll come with you.
-Okay, sister.
Aunt!
What is wrong, Goncagul?
What is the rush?
Selcan went by herself to pick black
knots for Gundogdu Bey.
It is time, aunt.
It looks like Gundogdu's
troubles will be our remedy.
Let's go, Goncagul.
You know what to do.
We are splitting up here, brother.
We won't be far away.
But you better be careful, brother.
Don't you worry.
Bey.
Mother Hayme!
-Goncagul and Aytolun!
-What about them, Gokce?
They donned their swords
and left the marquee.
Goncagul Hatun had asked me
where Selcan Hatun was going.
Selcan!
One more thing, Mother Hayme.
Selcan Hatun wasn't alone.
Halime Sultan was with her.
Be careful!
They are somewhere around here.
-Cagri Bey!
-Yes, Gumustekin Bey.
Let's break up into two
groups and surround them.
We won't let anyone escape.
If need be, kill them all.
As you please, Gumustekin Bey.
-How is your wound, Cicek Hatun?
-Getting better Bey, thanks.
They will be here in a minute. But can
you fend yourself if they don't show up?
With God's help, Bey!
Great.
We don't want to
spill any blood!
What do you want then?
Gumustekin Bey whom you
have been serving...
-...is a traitor.
-What are you saying?
As a servant of the state and
Sultan Aleaddin, that's all have to say.
How dare you call the margrave
of our state a traitor?
Soldiers, attack!
Selcan.
Sister.
You're worrying yourself
over nothing.
Almighty God will spare
Gundogdu Bey to us. You'll see.
And if Gundogdu Bey saw you like this,
he'd be very upset.
We've overcome many troubles.
If God permits, this too shall pass.
Gundogdu Bey needs you, Selcan.
We all do.
If God permits, Halime.
If God permits.
Come on, let's find
some black knots.
Fine. I will check the backside.
Don't worry, we'll find some.
Okay.
You won't be getting away
this time, Selcan!
Selcan!
Kill them both!
It 's over, Gumustekin!
You did everything
just to be appointed margrave.
To take over the Dodurga tribe...
...you killed aunt Duru and
replaced her with sister Aytolun.
You wanted your daughter
to marry Gundogdu Bey
so that you could take
over the Kayi tribe.
It was all going
as you planned
until Selcan Hatun
confronted you.
I'll kill you all!
In the end, you killed Korkut Bey
just so you'd be the margrave.
I wish I could have killed him before.
No one will believe
what you have to say.
Halime!
Selcan!
Aytolun!
Mother Hayme!
Tugtekin Bey!
You are going to pay for
what you did to my parents.