Episode 33 will start after 11:58 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
You did a lot of things for us.
I spare your life.
But do not get in my way again, Ertugrul.
Or I will be your angel of death.
Treacherous dogs!
Kill me! Kill me!
I would not kill a one-handed man.
Tie him up!
If I do not put your heads on my spear
and walk around with them
I shall not be known
as the son of Suleyman Shah.
If God permits, you will not fall prey
to the wolves, Ertugrul.
These mountains are not safe.
Greetings to your brother Gundogdu.
I will take his life soon.
You time is running out, Noyan's dog.
We are leaving, Alps! Come on!
God, give me my sword hand back.
God, do not humiliate me
in front of my enemies.
Where are the tracks?
Tugtekin, we will find them. Do not worry.
This is happening because of Ertugrul!
We should have executed
Abdurrahman and Hamza!
We should have done it!
We will do what is necessary
for our nomad tent.
Calm down a little.
Come on, we are heading back
to nomad tent.
You are my Johnny-on-the-spot, Geyikli.
You are everywhere.
We must see who sends a Johnny
to those in need.
Thank you. May you live long.
Cranes brought news from bastard Noyan.
He is back from Ogeday's place.
He wants to cause trouble to nomad tent.
We will cause trouble to him first.
I need to free Abdurrahman. Good bye.
We wanted to be united
but they stabbed us in the back.
We shared our food
and tents but peace has left
our nomad tent.
Peace must be restored
in the nomad tent, Korkut Bey.
Or you will lose Dodurga because of Kayi.
Beys, you all knew there could be problems
when you accepted unity.
Despite all possible problems,
we decided to unite.
We cannot turn back.
You have nothing to worry about.
You filled your pockets
thanks to Kayi's casualties.
Impertinent! I will cut your tongue off!
Know your place!
This is my headquarters!
Kayis must pay for their treachery.
Or there will be a blood bath.
We want pound of flesh!
Beys in Korkut Bey's marquee
will want pound of flesh from us.
We paid the price before,
so we will pay this too.
We will pay the price
but how will we clear this traitor mark?
We fought many enemies
but none of them hurt me
as much as Hamza did.
What if he was the traitor since
the beginning and led us to slaughter?
Hamza became like this
because of his anger to Gundogdu.
What will we do, Mother?
What does Kayi tribe think
about remigration?
Migration for Kayi is like running
towards Azrael.
We have neither strength
nor goods to migrate.
God, please help us.
Tugtekin!
Every treachery has a price.
The price will be paid sooner or later.
Price?
You call this price?
We already paid a price by sharing
our food and nomad tent with you.
What is the situation, Tugtekin?
The situation is...
Kayi Alps now belong to Noyan.
Every Kayi in nomad tent
can take Noyan's side someday.
How can we live with all these traitors?
Dodurga Beys yielded to their anger.
They throw the baby out
with the bathwater.
I say that Kayis must resign
from their duties in headquarters...
...or their Alps must hand over
their swords
and Abdurrahman must be executed.
That means Kayis will be our equerries.
They cannot be even our equerries.
If they herd our animals,
that would be enough.
What do you think, Bey?
Bey?
-Oh God!
-Father!
-Bey!
Help!
Let him breathe!
Are you alright, Bey?
-Take off his caftan!
-Bring water!
-Bey!
Bey!
In conclusion,
Tugtekin lost his trust to us.
How could he not?
From now on, how could
we look at his face?
Stop there.
Having a treacher in a nomad tent does
not make whole nomad people treacher.
Who knows how many treachers
are there in their nomad tent?
I wish there was only a treacher.
We have disturbed peace
since the day we came.
I am surprised by
how could we did not see what they did?
I said we should not have migrated,
you did not listen.
If we herd our animals in wild lands
wolves and jackals
will lay an ambush for sure.
They would want pound of flesh.
They will make us pay for it.
We will pay whatever it is, Crazy Iron.
You are exhausted, Bey.
Your heart needs calmness.
Instead of living in peace at his age,
he is struggling with troubles.
Kayis cause him real troubles.
Permission, Bey?
Come in!
Ertugrul is here, Bey.
So he is here to die.
Get Alps ready quickly.
Do not you hear me?
Yes, Bey.
Do not cause trouble in nomad tent, Bey.
Do not break the traditions.
There is no tradition left, Artuk.
Tugtekin.
What you are going to do
will make enemy stronger.
First, cut them in pieces,
then you will eat them.
Son.
Father.
My dear father.
Does Bey drink this syrup?
This will cause his death at this age.
Leave me alone with sons of Suleyman Shah.
Come closer.
Look me in the eye both of you.
I did not raise you for this.
If your father my Suleyman Shah were alive
what would he have
said to your impertinence?
What would he have said?
We faced many troubles.
We defeated many evils.
We need unity and peace!
What did you do?
How could you face the community?
From now on
if you lay a hand on each other
you will have neither my love
nor my blessing!
Did you hear my words?
Hug and ask for blessing.
Give me your blessing, brother.
You have it.
Give me your blessing, too, brother.
-You have it.
Sit down.
Tell me about Hamza problem.
Strength is a desire erupting
from a man's veins.
But gold is a cheap
odalisque of that desire.
I know none of you wants this gold.
You are here to fight in the
strongest army of the world
and be a soldier of largest army
in the world.
To battle!
To take off heads!
But if you have desire for gold
come and get as much as you want.
I give all the gold I have if he wants.
You are not cheap men
who set off for gold.
You are the best warriors
this world ever seen.
You are Kayi Alps.
Now you are to serve Mongols
who are your brothers for thousands
of years and world's sultan Ogeday.
This is a holy meeting.
The meeting of world's best warriors
and biggest emperor of the world.
Welcome among us.
From now on, you are not my soldier
but my blood brother.
No permission.
I did not ask for permission. Move aside.
We will enter.
Turgut!
Obey Tugtekin Bey's words.
Obey so we will not have a problem.
We obey the Beys' words.
We brought food.
Let him eat something.
Go in.
But do it quick.
Brothers!
We brought you food, brother.
What is the situation?
They said Hamza is a treacher.
It is right.
He turned out a Mongol spy.
Maybe, he was the treacher
since the beginning.
He led the nomad people to slaughter.
They want to project their rage onto me.
As long as Ertugrul Bey is here
as long as we are here
they could not harm a hair on your head.
Do not worry.
Brother, you must
take care of your health.
If something happens to you,
people will be perished.
Hayme, people are already perished.
All Beys ask
is this the reward of helping Kayi
what if other Kayis are treachers?
What else they say?
They say, we have no peace
and order has been broken.
So, what are saying to all these?
My dear sister, I need to calm Beys down.
To do this you must pay a price.
Abdicate from headquarters
or let your Alps lay down their arms.
Brother!
Your Beys want to see us as shepherd
and Kayi as herd.
They want Kayi to serve them. Is it?
My Beys behaved themselves till now.
Your son Ertugrul and your nomad people
are the faulty ones.
Or this unity will break down.
You have gone...
...you are speechless.
No one knows what are you thinking.
If my tongue knows what my heart thinks
I cut my tongue
so no one will be in trouble.
We always have a rough ride, Ertugrul.
Tell me, I want to know
what is in your heart.
Just know this.
Mad horses are running wild in my heart.
Passing the seas.
Trebling the very ground.
They run without having had fill.
Away, far away.
These mad horses tell our nomad tent's
name will be known to world someday.
World will be on his knees before us.
Justice will flourish everywhere.
They say world will be ours.
We do not have a nomad tent yet, Ertugrul.
How could all world will be ours?
That is why, I do not tell
what is in my heart to anyone.
Look, even you do not believe
what mad horses told me.
How will we defeat all this evil
and trouble, Tugtekin?
Sow the wind and reap the
whirlwind, Gokce.
We Turks are here to make
these lands our homeland.
So, we will pay a price
till these lands will be ours.
What is on your mind?
We need to gather nomad people
and take treachers out.
How will it be, Tugtekin?
It will be good.
Do not worry about these.
Let us have a race.
Come on.
While your Alps being treachers
you are enjoying yourself here.
So, you are riding in wilderness
instead of being a Bey
and go after treachers.
Tugtekin.
Let us go.
Let us go, Gokce.
I scared too much that you hurt him.
Son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul,
does not deal with colt.
Kocabash?
You are a real cook. It is delicious.
We know that big head of yours is cunning
but your hands are skillful, too.
Am I cunning, Bohach brother?
Look at his eyes, they are astute.
Look at them, they never stop.
Turgut and Dogan...
...they came to see the Abdurrahman.
Did they see him?
Samsa let them see.
Samsa!
Brainless, stupid Samsa!
If you do not obey my orders once more,
I make dog food from your flesh.
I told you, do not let them see!
You will breathe down Ertugrul and
his Alps neck on smallest mistakes.
Understood?
Here, this will clean you up.
Stupid!
Korkut Bey wanted us to dismiss
from headquarters
or lay down Alps' arms.
Look at our condition!
I wish the ground would open up
and swallow me.
What is on your mind, Bey?
We will spoil the game with another game.
We will draw Tugtekin upon us.
He is already on our neck
waiting for a mistake.
So we will force him to make a mistake.
What will we do, Bey?
We will show everyone that
Tugtekin is an Alp
who is not bounded to traditions.
You are treachers
and you challenge us now!
You cannot wave a flag here!
My brother is waiting for an answer.
What will we say?
I want to talk to my uncle one last time.
What is happening outside?
Permission?
Come in.
Mother Hayme, Tugtekin Bey...
It is our flag!
Are you only strong enough
for Kayi Bey's legacy, Tugtekin?
Do not forget, this is not a simple cloth.
Raging on an ancestor legacy
does not suit an Alp like you.
So you can still talk without shame.
Did you forget, your Alps betrayed to
their nomad tent and be Noyan's dog!
Instead of being a brother and a father
you are betraying your Alps
who will die by your order.
Will you keep these nomad people united
by making others pay for your faults?
-Ertugrul!
-Tugtekin!
Enough!
Enough! Lay down your sword!
What are you trying to do? Lay it down!
What do we live for?
What do we fight for and be a martyr?
In this world which we could not control
why do we go to endless battles?
To trample on our ancestors' legacies...
...or keep that legacy over our heads!
Do not let our legacy
become forlorn, brother.
Tugtekin.
You behaved shamefully.
We trusted Tugtekin and gave him
commandership of Alps, but...
Tugtekin has crossed the line this time.
Ertugrul behaved Tugtekin as he deserved.
So he saved your,
my and your father honor.
You speak the truth, Mother.
Tugtekin has crossed the line.
But it is our Alps who stabbed Tugtekin
in the back Ertugrul's Alps.
Things would not have come this far.
If we do not keep unity in nomad tent
we will finish ourselves before Mongols.
Just like Cain and Abel.
How long will you let him crush me...
...father?
We need to handle this situation quietly.
He who gets up in anger,
sits down with a loss.
I could not believe you.
You are still favoring him.
He humiliated me in front of everyone.
You are still favoring him, father.
My aunt and him.
He is not just someone.
Do not you understand?
You always favored Ertugrul!
You always thought he is better than me!
You still do!
His Alps betrayed and followed Noyan!
You are still defending him!
Still!
Do you know why all these
have happened, father?
Because of you!
Because of you! You always favored him!
Now, answer me!
Do you favor Ertugrul
because you love him
or because you are afraid of him?
Tell me, father. Are you afraid of him?
Tell me, are you afraid of him?
Ertugrul would have never
humiliated himself
by hauling down the flag of a nomad tribe
and stepping on it!
But you are too weak
and stupid to see this!
Get out!
Out!
Now!
Bey.
Tugtekin's dignity is Dodurga's dignity.
So, it your dignity.
You must restore Tugtekin's dignity.
You must bring rebellious Kayi Alps
into the line.
Every move I made comes right back at me
in these rough times, Aytolun.
Do not see it?
-I see it, Bey.
But, we must teach Ertugrul a lesson.
Or he will fetter you
instead of obeying you.
How will do that, Aytolun? How?
On one side my dear sister Hayme.
On the other side cherry of
Oghuz's cheek, Ertugrul.
Is it easy?
Execute Abdurrahman.
You enjoy the best of both worlds.
So, Dodurga people will be happy
and Kayi people will pay a price.
What is happening?
-What are you doing?
-Move aside!
-What do you want from Abdurrahman?
-Move aside! Move aside!
-Take your hands off me!
Tell me who send you and
what you want from Abdurrahman?
Move aside, Korkut Bey's orders!
What do you want?
Your time is up, Abdurrahman.
Why are you grinning, treacher?
Neither your Bey nor you can tell me
my time is up.
But God can.
Will you talk like this while a horse
is dragging your carcass?
Move! Move!
Bey, it is as you wished.
It wraps around your hand and wrist.
I hope it will heal you.
My thanks to you.
Now I do not have a lame hand,
but a hand made of steel.
In the name of God.
Wonderful, Bey.
Wonderful.
Bey, you told me to tell you
if anything is wrong.
What happened?
They have come to take Abdurrahman, Bey.
Their intentions are bad.
-Let him go!
-You cannot take him!
We will not give up Abdurrahman!
-Let him go!
-Is it bad, brothers?
It is my Bey who will decide
whether away it is good or bad.
Don't do it, brother.
God will punish you.
He will smite you.
All good and all bad, come from God.
Move over!
Stop!
Lay down your swords.
You insolent men!
If you draw your sword
against your brother today
you will be kneeling
to the heathens tomorrow.
It is the Bey's order.
We will take him, Ertugrul Bey.
-Where will you take him?
-He will be executed in the training area.
-You cannot take him!
-We won’t let you.
Let him go!
Abdurrahman is innocent!
Enough! Enough.
We will abide by...
...the tribunal's judgment.
Bey.
We will respect the tribunal's judgment.
Take him!
He has been scheming with his Alps
day and night since he returned.
He meets with someone secretly outside the
nomad tent. I’m sure of it.
Who?
I will find out soon, Bey.
Is he in?
Yes, Aytolun Hatun.
-How is he?
-He would kill them all if we let him.
Mother?
Your father gave the order
to execute Abdurrahman.
So, he recognized his mistake.
After he humiliated me,
he came to his senses.
Perhaps, someone helped him
come to his senses.
You and your father have overcome every
obstacle to establish a great dominion.
The news we are expecting from
Sultan Aleaddin will come shortly.
We will build up strength in our lands.
Your only duty is to be patient, Tugtekin.
How will I do that
while Ertugrul is here?
Ertugrul's dignity will soon be damaged,
just like his hand, Tugtekin.
As your father always says,
we will handle matters quietly.
Now go and make Ertugrul's Alps
pay the price of betrayal.
Show them that a man with a lame hand
cannot alter your destiny.
Brother, how could you do this?
How could you give an execution order
without my knowledge?
I was just carrying out the decision taken
by the tribunal in two nomad tents
It’s the right time for the execution.
Or things will get out of control.
You cannot take my Alp's life
just for intimidating people.
I will decide when he will be executed.
That was before your Alps betrayed us,
do not forget that.
If my son or I suffer another blow,
this partnership of ours will end.
And everyone will have to fend
for themselves.
This is what it finally comes to.
To hell with him and his partnership!
Your father entrusted Abdurrahman to us.
How can I protect his legacy,
If I cannot even protect Abdurrahman?
Who knows...
...perhaps I am not worthy of his legacy.
Not at all, mother. That’s not true.
It is your presence
that holds us together.
We are torn asunder as never before.
How long?
How long will this last?
You know Abdurrahman is innocent, right?
We also thought Hamza would
never betray us, mother.
I don’t know who to trust
or what to believe anymore.
Go and bring me Ertugrul.
Yes, mother.
Uncle!
Are you here to call me
to account, Ertugrul?
I keep wondering what happened,
to the brave uncle I once knew?
Ertugrul, be careful with your words.
Do you want to execute my Alp
because you cannot execute me?
Will you cover up Tugtekin's stupidity
with the blood of my Alp?
Ertugrul!
The brave uncle I know and love
has enough honor to avoid this.
Be careful whose advice you are taking.
Understand that the rage in you
is leading us to the edge of a cliff!
Look what you have done to
two nomad groups!
Where is your conscience?
Stop this execution, uncle.
Abdurrahman is innocent.
Do not kill a brave Alp
because of your anger towards me.
Or you will be worthless to my Alps.
The tribunal's judgment will be obeyed.
Abdurrahman will be executed.
You did not give me any other
option, Ertugrul.
Maybe, from now on,
you will know your place.
When did you become so cruel
and thoughtless?
Or do you have a secret agenda?
If you have, I will bring that
secret agenda to light one day, uncle.
Stop this execution
while there is still time!
Ertugrul, get out!
Do not make me do things
we will both regret!
Get out! Right away!
-Traitor!
-Kill him!
-Kill that man!
Kill him!
Turgut, tell me Ertugrul Bey
will not let them do this.
Kill him!
We cannot let them execute
Abdurrahman.
They want their payment, mother.
Then let us pay the price.
What are you going to do?
Traitor!
Don't do that!
They can’t do that.
To hell with this brotherhood.
Uncle!
If you will delay the execution
our Alps are ready to lay down
their weapons.
But we have only one wish.
Let Mother Hayme give
the order to execute Abdurrahman.
If that is what you wish.
Father.
Don't do this. Give the execution order.
I am delaying the execution!
Thank God!
The execution has been postponed!
May God bless you.
Untie the prisoner and take him
to his cage.
Long live Korkut Bey!
May God bless you.
Well done! Well done!
-Have you brought news from Kayis?
-Yes.
Speak.
Everything went as planned.
So, they are in disarray, Tangut.
Abdurrahman will be executed
sooner or later.
And Kayi Alps will bear a grudge.
Ertugrul, too.
He will be mad with rage.
Then every bond that ties
the two nomad groups together will break.
I told you, Tankut.
You stir up the Turks
and then let them be.
Let them be
so that they will consume each other.
Sisters?
Do your work, instead of gossiping!
You girls go to the loom.
What do you think about
what happened, Gokce?
The price of treachery will be paid
sooner or later, Aytolun Hatun.
Or the price will be even greater.
So, explain this to Tugtekin
with your silver tongue.
He is still furious with
your brother, Ertugrul.
Go, I’m sure he will feel better
if you are with him.
You were right to be angry.
You were betrayed.
Bu you ended up being wrong
when you were right.
They insulted you.
You insulted Kayis, too.
I know, I made a mistake.
But Ertugrul insulted me
like no one else has ever done.
Not just you...
...he does it to everyone.
He breaks people's heart without thinking.
He doesn’t  care about
people's love and dignity.
Why are you so furious with your brother?
Because...
Because we do not deserve this.
Let's stop this bickering.
That’s all I want.
Don’t worry.
It will end.
Well done, my daughter-in-law.
You made it at last.
You are free to do as you please
in the nomad tent.
Selcan Hatun!
If it was not for your husband,
you all would be in pieces by now.
Thank God, you have a Bey like Gundogdu.
It’s a miracle that a brave
and honorable man like him
puts up with a woman like you,
even for one day!
The world's best warriors are among them.
I want all of them in my army, Hamza.
They all will fight for you
when the time comes.
Don’t worry.
Hamza is with us now.
Your secret is safe.
Right, Hamza?
I have good news for you.
Ertugrul will leave the nomad group
in order to preserve unity.
Ertugrul will never leave his nomad group.
What happens to a wounded wolf
when he leaves his pack?
If you make a sound,
I will cut your throat.
Rise.
Rise!
Did you think you could get away?
Step up on the log.
Step up on the log!
If you sleep, move, or try to escape,
you will die by hanging.
Do you understand?
No one will come in.
What happened, Bey?
You will go to Geyikli's cave with Dogan
tomorrow morning.
You will wait there for my news.
All right, Bey.
What about Abdurrahman?
You are leaving the nomad tent, too.
To leave him like this...
Don’t worry.
I will send him to Geyikli's cave.
What's on your mind, Bey?
Why aren't you telling us?
Don't you trust us?
You have not told us anything
for a long time.
If you know all my secrets
you can hurt me.
I know that the enemy could never
break your tongue or your heart.
But the ones who oppose us are
not our enemies.
They mean more to us than our own lives.
From now on, the less you know,
the better.
Understood?
Understood, Bey.
As you wish, Bey.
Now go and get ready.
I want you to set out
early in the morning.
Do you want anything from me, Bey?
-I do, Wild Demir.
-Yes, Bey.
You are the bride every mother in law
would want.
If God permits, we will see those days.
Gokce is about finish the armor
you requested.
But she needs more materials.
You will buy them when you
go to Erzurum together.
Right, Gokce?
I had better be off to bed.
You might have things to talk about.
Good night.
Wait a minute.
Let's talk for a little while.
You came to me and talked with me.
Thank you.
What happened, Bey?
You calmed me down.
You prevented my anger from hurting me.
From now on, I have someone
who understand my words and my heart.
Thank God.
Peace be upon God.
Who was that?
-Gokce.
-In the dead of night?
What does she want?
Young people cannot stand not
seeing each other.
I mean Tugtekin and Gokce.
They are well matched.
Tugtekin talked to me.
He respects and loves me
as his late mother.
He is in love with the girl.
-What about Gokce?
-They will go to Erzurum together.
When they return,
we’ll find out what she thinks.
So, what does Hayme think about this?
If the daughter of Suleyman Shah and
the son of Korkut Bey were to marry
that would mean two marriages, not one.
So Dodurgas and Kayis
would be solemnly married.
Where will all of this end?
We are suffering
because of our unborn babies.
If you run away
if you turn your back on me
where will this end up, Gundogdu?
I still feel the pain,
like burning cinder,
of my babies who died
before birth, like Selcan.
And there are the ones
you could not breastfeed.
I couldn’t bear to bury one more baby.
May god forgive my sins.
I could not bear such a pain.
So you say we will never hear
a baby’s voice in this tent, right?
Do you want to bury me alive in this tent?
Is this what you want?
Turali.
Are you ready, son?
-I am, Bey.
Come on.
God, help us.
What happened, Wild Demir?
I brought food to Abdurrahman.
Tugtekin Bey gave order.
He will not see anyone.
No one will go in.
If someone goes out
he will be killed.
Why I shall not see him?
Because he wishes so. Is it enough?
That is all right.
Go back!
Guards!
Come on!
Leave now!
Do not worry.
I give your kind regards to dead one.
Leave now!
Do not cause trouble in the dead of night.
All right. Okay.
You saw your Beys betrayed you
for who you gave your life.
Even Mother Hayme pays no mind to you.
Ertugrul Bey...
...does not come and ask how are you.
You are still being a dog for your Beys.
You will die here.
If you confess the truth
if you confess your coconspirators
I can stop your execution.
You will be exiled and have a good life.
Who do you want to burn along
with me, Kocabash?
I know your intention.
Get out!
Son, what are you doing here?
I brought Ertugrul Bey's greetings.
Be careful.
Keep a sharp lookout around the tent.
Control Dogan and Turgut.
We could not bear any more trouble.
And Abdurrahman...
Please, do not do anything for him.
-Fire!
-Run, fire!
-Tent is on fire!
-Come here! Fire!
Go and report to Tugtekin Bey!
Help, bring water!
Fire, bring water!
Hurry up!
Fire! Bring water!
Always smile like this.
When you are sad, I mumble.
I do not know what to talk.
-That bad?
-You could not imagine.
Bey?
Come in.
-Bey, the tent is on fire.
-Which tent?
Caged tent, Bey.
Damn it!
From now on, there is nothing we can do
about you and your Alps.
I will do my best to keep
Abdurrahman alive, Ertugrul.
I know, mother. I know.
But Abdurrahman's life
is not entrusted to us.
You already knew it.
Fire! Bring water!
Bring water!
-Abdurrahman was not inside, Bey.
-What do you mean he was not inside?
God damn it!
God damn it! God damn it!
Bring water!
Water!
Run! Run!
Run! Water!
When I get my grandchild to my lap
I will sit on top of the world.
I hope, but he could not be raised
by his parent.
May god forbid.
You vile! You let him escape, right?
You are impertinent, Tugtekin!
Who escaped? What are you talking about?
Caged tent burned!
Abdurrahman is not in it!
Is that right, Ertugrul?
I have no information about fire
and Abdurrahman, mother.
Tugtekin and his Alps could not protect
what is entrusted to them.
Lay down your sword.
Lay down your sword!
You are young! Really young!
You crossed the line!
Ertugrul, let him go.
Ertugrul!
Ertugrul, let him go!
If you did something to him,
I will take your life!
Let him go, you will kill him!
Tugtekin!
If you enter my marquee
like this once more
I will kill you!
And you, Ertugrul.
I am not sure whether you did this or not.
So, stay away from nomad tent for a while.
Set out when sun rises.
Mother!
Tugtekin.
Take your jackals and get out!
Out!
Do not worry.
I will be with you and our baby
wherever I am.
I know you want me to be patient.
You want me to grin and bear it.
I will do it, Ertugrul.
From now on, your heart will be
my and my baby's bed.
They are Ertugrul's Alps.
Turgut and Dogan.
I met them in Kervansaray.
We draw our sword to be a martyr.
But where is Ertugrul?
Shall I follow them, Noyan?
I need you here.
Tankut, send five men to follow them.
Yes, Baycu Noyan.
There is someone here!
Who are you, insane man?
What are you doing here?
Have you seen two Alps around?
You are insane but skillful.
I am not skillful but this stick
which run these infidels down.
Accept it, Ertugrul and his Alps did it!
Enough!
Stop blaming my son.
Your four Alps were guards at the tent.
What were they doing
while the tent was burning?
Abdurrahman did not fly from tent.
My mother speaks truth, Tugtekin.
Your Alps could not guard the tent.
You could not protect him.
At least, you fall into the
hands of me, Ertugrul.
-What are you doing here, Gokce?
-I could not let you go.
While there are enemies everywhere
what are you doing?
So why are you going, Ertugrul?
If there are Mongols everywhere,
where are you going with a wounded hand?
Who is that beautiful girl?
She is like Ertugrul's sister.
Suleyman Shah killed their father
and raised her sister and Gokce
as his own daughter.
So, her name is Gokce.
Go and prepare the horses.
Gokce.
Go!