Episode 41 will start after 12:31 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
Tell us, Ertugrul,
the son of Suleyman Shah.
What was the crimes of your state to
make you kill Ertokush?
What was the crimes of Dodurga Tribe to
make you kill two brave warriors?
We will consult the Fiqh book
regarding your case.
Now you may speak.
First you must know that...
...I have come before you by my own will.
Otherwise none of you
would be able to capture me.
I wanted to be here.
So that the elders of my tribe would know
who the real villains are.
Stop playing with words
and answer the question.
Your false justice
is created to be the end of Oghuz Tribe.
If you say another word,
our justice will fall on you right now.
Elders of my Tribe.
Ever since the first day I held a sword,
I have not spilled any innocent blood.
I have stood against the wicked.
Because I know very well that when a
single tyrant stops breathing...
...thousands of oppressed would rejoiced.
Considering this fact
how could I end the lives of
Atabey Ertokush and Tugtekin?
Eh?
How?
I beheaded the traitor Kocabash.
Fortunately.
Is it your duty to behead a traitor?
If you blindly host a traitor
under your nose, then yes, uncle.
-What are we going to do?
-How can this be?
-This is treachery.
-Impossible.
He cannot do such a thing.
Silence! This a trial, not a wedding!
Do you have evidence of
Kocabash's treachery?
We are with you, Ertugrul Bey!
Long live Ertugrul!
-Kill the murderer!
-We will not let you take our Bey!
Kill Ertugrul!
Death to Ertugrul!
Beginning from the lands of our fathers,
I have made our enemies
bow down to me.
-And defeated countless traitors.
-He is right.
My life has taught me the
nature of traitors.
Now, I say to you
Kocabash is personally responsible
from the death fo Atabey Ertokush.
Kocabash tracked and
fed him to the Mongols.
Just as he did with Tugtekin.
How did Kocabash manage
to get back to the nomad tent,
when countless Alps were
being slaughtered?
How did Noyan the Merciless, released him?
Noyan wanted to make me look guilty
by letting him live.
He wanted the Beys of the two tribes
to turn against each other.
He wanted to invade Anatolia
while Kayis and Dodurgas
were at each other's throats.
If only, our only traitor was Kocabash.
Karabek, who is sitting beside me
is the lapdog of that bastard Noyan!
-This is treachery.
-Foul play!
Insolence! Know your place!
-This is impossible!
-What treachery is this?
The dog who don't know how to bark
will surely bring enemies
to the nomad group, gentlemen.
This dog, allied with Noyan and
lay an ambush to the Oghuz tribe.
When Noyan was nailing my hand
he was watching with great pleasure.
-This is treachery.
-Unacceptable!
Is this true, Karabek?
This scoundrel is trying to
get away with murder.
This man has who has sold his
sword and tongue to the Devil...
...is a murderer! And a traitor!
He is trying to frame me
and provoke you against the State.
His words are empty.
I have a witness.
Do I have your permission, Gumustekin?
We will learn the truth today, Karabek.
Let him come.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
brave one?
I swear to tell the truth.
Sit.
Ibrahim Yuglu,
is the steward of the late Ertokush Bey.
He has been on the battlefield
constanly as a brave warrior.
His father is an elite guard
of our Sultan.
Now he will tell us
what has happended on the spot
where Ertokush Bey
and his warriors were massacred
-Traitors!
-It is I, Ertugrul Bey from Kayis.
You are all murderers.
Traitor! Traitors!
You are all traitors!
While my brothers were
being slaughtered one by one
this man, Ertugrul showed.
He was furious and I was alone.
It was impossible for me to
take on so many men by myself.
I had to flee with my horse.
I swear on my life that,
this is all I have seen.
You are right, my man. I also saw you.
I was there.
But everything was over
when I got there.
I went there because
Atabey Ertokush wanted me to be there.
You confessed.
You can no longer play with words to
save your skin, Ertugrul.
You were exiled, right?
There is no way you could have seen
Ertokush Bey.
Stop lying.
Go to your place.
I have never seen you like this, aunt.
You are on the edge, ready to explode.
I conquered this old mans bed,
for his marquee.
It was still not enough,
so I took his bride away.
I have been tolerating him for ages.
And for what?
For Oghuz's unity and strenght.
I have tolerated him
for the sake of tribes
living in Caspian and the Euphrates.
I stood with my brother.
For Gumustekin I would risk death.
Just as you would, Goncagul.
Tell me now.
Is it really strange,
that I am on the edge?
that my soul is on fire?
Maybe Gundogdu was the man I have been
searching this whole time, aunt.
Unlike you,
I would have laid with him happily.
Not for my father. Not for you.
Only because I loved him.
Unfortunately,
only a miracle can save us now, aunt.
Our sufferings are great.
But Gokce, my dear girl has a
deeper sorrow.
They took her man away
before their wedding.
We want justice for the dead Alps!
-We want justice!
-Justice will be ours!
-They are framing our Bey!
Everything is obvious.
What more do you want to talk about?
End this already!
Swift justice is the best justice.
The tribunal has come to a conclusion.
Ertugrul, son of Suleyman Shah.
For the crimes of laying an ambush
to the Ertokush Bey
and the massacre of his men...
...also laying an ambush to
the Tugtekin Bey of Dodurga Tribe
...and massacring him...
...and finally...
...beheading the Alp...
...as known as Kocabash...
...who has survived the ambush...
...you have been found guilty.
-Ertugrul Bey is innocent!
-He is innocent!
-What is the meaning of this!
He is innocent!
-Ertugrul Bey is innocent!
-Justice will be served!
Don't do it, Ertugrul Bey is innocent!
Silence! Enough!
We have given our decision.
Considering the two nomad groups'
deep sensibility
the execution of punishment
will take place immediately.
Sentence will be carried out
in front of the marquee.
Execution will take place
in front of the people.
As the custom dictates,
Korkut Bey will carry out the sentence
and rightfully decapitate Ertugrul
with his sword.
No!
Don't do this! Ertugrul Bey is innocent.
Ertugrul Bey is telling the truth!
You cannot do this.
My son is innocent.
My son is innocent!
Is there something you wish to say
son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul?
The truth belongs to God, Gumustekin.
And about this devil here...
Even if thousands of Husseins would perish
the ones who follow Ali's path
would never yield.
Take away the prisoner for execution.
Don't do this! He is innocent.
Our Bey is innocent.
Long live Ertugrul!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Gumustekin Bey.
Before the execution
I desire to say one last thing.
Here you go, Gundogdu Bey.
Have you informed Sultan Aleaddin
about this trial?
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
They are going to kill
Where are you Gundogdu?
-Our Bey is not a murderer!
-No!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Sultan Aleaddin...
...loves and respects Ertugrul deeply.
If he hears about this,
we all will pay the price.
We do not have time for this.
Do you want to start a civil war,
Gundogdu Bey?
As long as Ertugrul lives
blood of the tribes will spill.
Wild Demir and Halime Sultan
left for Konya
to inform the Sultan Aleaddin
about the matter.
You finally remembered that
your daughter in law is royalty.
Are you use this as leverage?
As long as you cannot provide justice,
I will do as I wish, Korkut Bey!
It is over!
Ertugrul is a murderer!
He will be killed. That is all.
You are blinded by hate and vengeance!
You all will pay the price! We all will!
Hayme Hatun.
Gundogdu Bey.
I am also deeply saddened by the events.
Kocabash's death is obvious.
After hearing the witness,
my hands are tied.
I will not wait any longer.
When Ertugrul was born,
you were the first to hold him.
When his father returned
from the war, injured
you took him to his father.
Ertugrul is innocent
as the day he was born.
Don't do this.
Long live Ertugrul!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
He murdered my son!
His death is my right!
And I will claim that right!
Korkut!
Mother.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
You are making a mistake, uncle.
Save your breath.
If you still have some faith
recite the Shadada.
I bear witness, there is no deity
worthy to be worshipped but God,
and I bear witness Mohammad is
his servant and his messenger.
I am well, son.
Go and do what is necessary.
Just go.
Do not worry Mother. Wait here.
-I will speak their language.
-Alright.
Halime.
Both Mother Hayme and
Gundogdu are not around.
It is obvious, they are
keeping them inside.
Help us God.
Dogan. Bamsi. Turgut.
It is time for battle.
Defend Ertugrul, my warriors.
Run!
Dumrul!
In the name of God!
Go, Alps!
For God!
-Mother.
-Go, save your brother. Run!
Go on, son.
Nobody move!
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Our Bey is alive!
This brave warrior has healed.
I have come to deliver him to his father.
Tugtekin! My son!
My son.
-My son.
-Father.
Lower your swords.
Father.
Who have done this to you, son?
Who did this?
The sole responsible...
...for all of this is...
Tell me.
What?
Ertugrul.
The sole responsible for this sorrow...
...is Ertugrul, father.
He has ruined...
...the nomad groups with
his vanity and stubbornness.
He gave Mongols...
...the chance to attack us...
...and defeat us from within.
Let everyone know that...
...the one who did this to me...
...the one who massacred our Alps...
...and Seljuk warriors...
...and the one who murdered
Ertokush Bey...
...is not Ertugrul.
Justice is served!
Our Bey is innocent!
Long live, Ertugrul Bey!
Thank God.
Ertugrul is a complete pain in the ass.
But he is no traitor, father.
Bey, Karabek is gone!
Horses! Get to the horses!
Thank you.
Bey!
We will take care of Karabek.
Please, stay with Mother Hayme.
Do not worry, Bey.
I will not, as long as you are by my side.
-May you conquer all.
-Thank you, Bey.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Brothers. Sisters.
Brave Alps of my nomad group.
Thank God, we are freed from
that bastard Noyan's treachery.
Thank God.
However, this malevolent...
...and treacherous war has just begun.
We have been betrayed
by our sons, brothers...
...as we have been for 1000 years.
The war will not be over
until wipe all of them out.
But, neither Noyan
nor the traitors within us
will be unpunished.
They will pay the price.
Allahu Akbar!
We are the glorious descendants of Oghuz.
Justice and liberty is in our blood!
We will live and die this way!
Justice, until the end!
Liberty, until the end!
Allahu Akbar!
Go on! Move you bloody animal.
Move!
Come here boy. Where will you go?
We will have a little chat.
Then I will beat you to a pulp.
Leave some for us, brother Bamsi.
We will have equal shares of this
Mongol bastard. Do not worry.
In the name of God!
Brother!
What happened?
Ertugrul...
...was saved from execution.
What do you mean he was saved?
Tugtekin returned to the nomad tent.
He told them everything, Noyan.
Everything.
Ertugrul!
Gather the men! We are leaving!
Take him.
Brother.
Are you alright, brother? Tell me.
A mosquito bite in the dead of winter.
What are the odds?
I wish there were more of them
for us to crush, brother.
I doubt we can finish them all like that.
Let's go after Karabek.
Come on.
My son.
Father.
What have I done to be
condemned to hell...
...while I was still drawing breath, God?
After all the children I have lost,
God made me suffer for you too.
I am back, father. Look, I am fine.
Do not worry.
If something had happened to you too...
...how would I endure your torment?
Death has claimed all of my children,
like a thirsty desert.
And now you.
Ertugrul was right about
everything he said, my son.
I despised his courage and intelligence.
May God forgive me.
Did my Alps...
...Bogac and Samsa come back?
We could not find any evidence
whether they were alive or not.
They are my blood brothers.
If Noyan...
...killed them...
...I will kill him with my own hands.
Get well, brave one.
Then you can slay that bastard.
Horseshoe tracks.
They took the carriage and left.
There is blood.
What should we tell our Bey?
I am glad it is over, son.
Thank you, mother.
It is over, brother.
Thank you, brother.
I am glad it is over, Ertugrul Bey.
Selcan Hatun, brother.
I am safe thanks to you.
May I come in, Sister Halime?
You may, Korkut Bey.
You honor our marquee.
Will you be able to forgive me, Ertugrul?
The war is at our doorstep, uncle.
Thousands of Turkmens are
being murdered every day.
Ogedai's army is getting closer to
Anatolia step by step.
We do not have the right
to be angry with each other
in this situation.
Know this, as long as you are just,
I will have your back
until my last breath.
Thank you, nephew.
What about you, Sister Hayme?
Will you be able to forgive me?
Everything is over, brother.
It was not us, but our enemy
who has put us in this state.
From now on we will not give
our enemy this chance.
Brother!
What is happening? What is wrong with you?
Ertugrul came in our way again when
we were getting close to our goal.
Did you think becoming a Bey
would be easy?
There will be countless traps and
ambushes waiting for you.
You will lose first so that victory
will be more sweet.
If Sultan Aleaddin hears
his accomplishments
my margrave will only be a dream.
I have to show my teeth.
Brother, it is time to act wisely.
Ertugrul became a hero
in Korkut and tribe's eyes.
You have to be a greater hero
than he is...
...or act against him.
Easy, Bey.
You take these.
Do not worry, Bey.
God will help you heal.
-May God bless you.
-Thank you.
Bey.
Do not move.
Your wounds are still fresh.
I am responsible for all of this.
I should not have told you
Ertugrul's location.
Do not blame yourself.
We both know that...
...Ertugrul is the only one responsible
for the things that happened to me...
...and this tribe.
You may seek revenge...
When you are healed and back on your duty.
I will not leave your side
until you recover.
We will all be fine when you get better.
Thank you.
Permission to enter, Bey?
Come in, Alps.
Bey.
Mongols caught us and
they took Karabek from our grasp.
Tell me what happened.
There were traces of blood
where they took him, Bey.
Noyan. He is the only one
who is capable of doing this.
I think he came close to the nomad tent
to watch my execution.
Then he took his dog and left.
-What are we going to do, Bey?
-It is time to attack, Alps.
Did you hear that, brother Dogan?
We will trample them!
As you command, Bey!
To those who raise and demolish states.
Greetings from Vazifeli Artuk.
Ertugrul Bey has overcome
all of the traps laid out for him.
He defeated all of his enemies.
With your permission, I would like to
bring him to Ahlat to see you.
What happened, Bamsi?
You look overjoyed.
That is true, Bey.
I would be like this all the time
if I could kill heretics every day.
May God make your joy everlasting,
brother.
Thank you, Bey.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Welcome.
-You honor our marquee.
-Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
How are you brave warriors?
-Thank you.
What advise will you give us tonight, sir?
The conquers that have been heralded
will come true one by one.
God's promise is near.
The world will get to know this conquest.
The joyous conquest we have been
waiting for is near.
God's loved one, our master
was exiled from Mecca where
he was born and loved very much.
In a midnight, Habibullah
ran away from Mecca in tears.
In the eight year of his hejira,
he returned to Mecca as a
commander of the conquest
that God promised him.
Our master left Mecca with only
one person beside him
but he returned there with thousands.
Not proudly as a conquerer
but with all his modesty.
He put his head against
his camel like he was groveling.
He was praying to God.
God's messenger did not attribute
this conquest to himself.
He walked in Mecca's streets modestly,
being thankful to God.
He ordered: "He who enters
Ebu Sufyan's home would be safe.
He who leaves their weapon and
enters his house, is safe.
He who takes refuge in Kaaba is safe."
Mecca was conquered once again
with people's morals and benediction.
Mecca was taken without bloodshed
and a bairam of forgiveness was declared.
Our master declared that he forgave
the savage who killed his uncle,
Ebu Sufyan's wife and all of his enemies.
He showed everyone the moral of
being victorious by his doings.
All conquerers must take guidance
from his actions.
Why he did not kill his enemies?
Son, he was sent to keep us alive,
not kill us.
He is the servant
and the messenger of God,
who is compassionate and merciful, my boy.
I agree.
May I come in, my Bey?
Come in, Gokce.
Good night.
I came to ask if you need something.
I want nothing now that you are here.
Despite everything I've been through...
...all my troubles fade away
when I see you.
That is enough for me.
Will you be able to say these
when Ertugrul is in nomad tent?
There is no peace where
Ertugrul is, Gokce.
Ertugrul is in good spirits because
he humiliated me in front of my Alps.
May I come in?
-Samsa?
-It is us, my Bey. May we come in?
-Yes, come in.
-Slowly.
You are alive.
Bey.
If I may.
-How did you survive?
-We were both gravely injured, Bey.
I passed out. When I opened my eyes,
I found myself in a village.
And there I saw Samsa.
He found me, and took me to the village.
We stayed in that village
until we were healed.
Then we found two horses and
came back to nomad tent.
We heard what happened to that
bastard Kocabash, Bey.
He got what he deserved.
Give me good news, Tangut.
You finally proved
you are my most trusted man.
You brought back what
Sungurtekin took from us.
However, Sungurtekin...
...is going to Konya, Noyan.
He is with Halime Sultan and that smith.
We gave Noyan's game away.
He will get more aggressive now.
We will not reprieve him anymore.
We will not stop until he plagues.
-We are with you with God's help, Bey.
-Thank you, Bey.
We can go right now. We can spend the day
by killing non-Muslims.
Alps!
For Ertugrul Bey! Be ready!
Bey, when will we take our seignior back?
Who can take our seignior, Dogan?
We born as Alp and will die as Alp also
with God's help.
Is there any other side of it?
When we will take our seignior
from that Tugtekin, Bey.
When will we take our seignior from,
Tugtekin Bey?
That is taken by legislature is also
given by legislature, Bamsi.
Beyond that it does not suit us.
Everything has a time, of course.
Thank you, Bey.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Long live you too, valiant men!
You never left me alone!
You believed me without hesitation
when all the traitors inside
and outside defamed me!
You long live!
Do not leave the laws of Oghuz
or our religion!
Long live.
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Do you understand me, fool man?
Sungurtekin and Halime Sultan
will never confront Alaeddin.
You will go to the palace
and prepare your game.
You will be on your way to Konya
early in the morning.
Tangut will come with you
so that nothing happens to you.
If you do not do what I said
I will come to Konya and kill you
with my own hands. Know it.
Get out of my sight now!
Noyan, should I take Abdurrahman
and Hamza with me?
They will stay here.
Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-May God be with you.
-Thank you.
It is time to get going for me, son.
I do not know how I could handle with
all these if you would not be with me.
When a man decided to be Moses,
God sends him a help.
Servants are only a reason.
You need to know who send them.
Thank you.
I go but I entrust my dervish to you.
It would be good if you gave him a task
in the mosque of nomad tent.
He educates the children.
-Do not worry.
Thank you.
Dervish, children are seeds.
If you feed them well and grow them well,
you get good harvest.
Do not forget that.
You gave this blessed task to me,
may God bless you.
I will protect my consignation.
If you excuse me.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey.
You destroyed the blessed army
of Ogeday in this land.
You killed your own soldiers.
Loss suits you now, not the victory.
Until you lose your commandership task
I will fight with you, Noyan.
Are you happy to be with Noyan
by selling out your marquee, Abdurrahman?
I did not sell out anyone.
I am here only to rise
in Ogeday's blessed army.
He sends us to death every day.
We live with death like it's our shadow.
It is good if we fail and die.
But if we return here,
we will regret why we are not dead.
You have so much suffering, Tangut.
He will send Karabek to Konya tomorrow.
He wants to kill Halime Sultan
before she fronts Alaeddin in the palace.
If things go wrong
he will kill me without showing mercy.
So put it this way, I am tired.
I am very tired.
Anyway.
Let us see how long you will resist
to this torture.
There is no other way than to die, Tangut.
And we are not afraid of it
with God's help.
You will give me Ertugrul, Abdurrahman.
I will take him one way or the other.
You are right but what if Tugtekin
do not accept this decision?
One way or another, this will be
the best for all of us, brother.
At least, we were stabbed in the back
to learn how to go in our own way.
You are right.
My brother is right, mother.
This should be end in this headquarter.
All right, son.
But how can you fight with Noyan alone?
There is Dogan. Turgut Bamsi.
There is Geyikli. Abdurrahman.
Meeting is starting.
I am sure that Ertugrul
will cause us trouble.
You are like captivated.
One of your words is Ertugrul.
If we do not take precaution
next will be us, brother.
Not so fast.
I have not played my game yet.
I trained people like Ertugrul
in the palace in Konya.
Let him live the happiness of his victory.
Ertugrul is much smarter
than you think, brother.
I will send Tugtekin to fight with him.
They will play like a child.
Then we will see his intelligence.
What if he learns what we did?
What if he reveals us like Kocabash?
He will not live so long.
Why did you want to see me here, Noyan?
Let us say that, it is safer.
Kayis and Dodurgians
had almost a civil war.
I know that, Noyan.
We have to ask the accounts for these
before winter ends and war begins.
We can handle this together, Noyan.
I know.
They will stand in front of the Mongolian
army as Tengri mountain.
They cannot defeat Ogeday's army.
But they will cause so much suffering.
They will harm us until our army
comes to Konya.
What do you want from me, Noyan?
Did you bring the gold that
Gundogdu asked for?
I brought.
Good.
When you go to take the herd and goods
you will not take the gold with you.
-Noyan, our deal is to give the golds...
-Do what I say.
You will say that golds are on the way
and come from Erzurum.
There is something I want you to do
while you are waiting for the golds
in the nomad tent.
-Goncagul Hatun.
-Gundogdu Bey.
-More power to you.
-Thank you.
What a lucky man your father is.
You get fresh herbs
for his foot every day.
Actually, I am lucky to have
a father, Gundogdu Bey.
The man who will marry you will be
at least as lucky as your father.
If I see a valiant man as you say
and if he can see the beauty inside
then it is my duty to marry him
and give him children, Gundogdu Bey.
Then it is time to say to you
what is in my heart.
Let your heart speak.
Goncagul Hatun.
I want to spend a lifetime with you
and hopefully with my children.
How beautiful your heart
speaks, Gundogdu Bey.
My Bey!
Your scars are not healed yet.
Where are you going in this condition?
Ertugrul will not stay not doing
anything in the headquarter.
If you go there so bad,
you will make Ertugrul's job easier.
Headquarter took the head of seignior
from Ertugrul because he was one-armed.
You are also in the same situation now.
If you join to headquarter,
Ertugrul will use this.
I will join to headquarter
whatever happens, Gokce.
If Ertugrul thinks that he can convince
the whole headquarter
including my father, he is wrong.
He will see that I am not alone.
I hope nothing is wrong
Abdurrahman brother?
There is no time to lose Geyikli brother.
You should immediately go to the
nomad tent, to Ertugrul.
Halime Sultan and Sungurtekin,
their lives are in danger.
What?
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
With the name of God.
In the 99 names of God most gracious,
most merciful.
Beys, we had hard times.
We were too close to our enemy.
We have overtaken the traps
thanks to Ertugrul Bey.
Now, we came together at the request of
Mother Hayme now.
I also wanted to see Ertugrul Bey
in headquarter.
He came, thankfully.
Thank you, Korkut Bey.
Here you go, Mother Hayme.
Precious Beys of Dodurga and Kayi.
After the invasion disaster we had
we gave Alps of two nomad group
to a single Alp.
I want you to know that
we still support our decision today.
If you still support that
what do you want then?
We have witnessed that
what Ertugrul Bey said
since he has been relieved
of duty is true.
Is there anybody who can disaffirm?
-That is true.
-It's right.
What Ertugrul Bey said was true.
Now you are saying that you regret.
No.
We are saying that
if Ertugrul Bey was here
none of these would have happened.
Enemy is wild.
Gravity of situation is obvious.
We are not looking for a scapegoat.
We want to take precautions
so that we will be harmed again.
You want to take head of Alps from me,
do not you?
We demand that the head of Alps duty
should be given to us again.
You want to gather strength
by using the opportunity you have.
Do you know what strength
and power mean, Tugtekin?
It means to follow the directions
by preventing your anger and nerve.
Now...
...the task of Tugtekin Bey was
to keep all Alps together and alive.
But you showed weakness on your duty.
Noyan used this and brought us
almost to shed blood of brother.
Finally, you showed your
intention, Ertugrul.
Now you want to use this opportunity.
Will you take the control of Alps
with your one-hand?
Is that what you want?
No.
I have no such a desire.
We want that
Gundogdu Bey will be head of Alps.
-He is right.
-Yes.
I also want that Gundogdu Bey
will be head of Alps.
If you excuse me
I would like to know
what you and your Beys think.
You want that Hayme Hatun but
we need to say stop for this matter.
What will we tell the Alps?
What will we say to people?
If the situation changes
in the headquarter
would not they say whay they do?
If you excuse me, Bey.
I also would like to say a few words.
Here you go, Artuk Bey.
Nomad tent is not peaceful
for a long time.
People suffer pain because lack of
unity in the headquarter.
If we fight inside and the enemy outside
we cannot prosper.
Bey, if we united with the Kayis
and headed the same way
then they should also have to judge.
Thank you.
Then let Bey of the headquarter decide it.
Now...
...those who want that Gundogdu Bey
will be head of Alps raise your hands.
It was a salutary decision.
Thank you, Gumustekin Bey.
If you excuse me, Bey?
There you go, son.
God bless the Beys of two nomad groups
who awarded me with this task.
-Thank you.
-Amen.
Feel comfortable.
Know that I will know the Alps of
both the nomad groups as my brothers.
I will prepare them for the war
just like the sons of the same father.
May God not embrace us for our decision.
-Amen.
-May God not embrace you.
-If God permits, mother.
May God not embrace you.
How could you do that, Gumustekin Bey?
How could you pass over me
in front of the Beys?
That is not true.
It was not me, it was your father.
Your father and the other Beys
had already made their decisions.
They were prepared to sacrifice you.
They were about to take the head of
Alps duty from you.
I wish I could do something, son.
I wish.
First, you pull yourself together
and enjoy your wedding.
Enjoy bridal chamber of our lovely bride.
Your real task and exam will start then.
What do you mean?
Oh, Tugtekin, oh!
You are a smart man.
Your father can no longer carry the load
of being head. Do not you see that?
He is sick.
He does not have so much time.
Now it is your time.
Know that, when it is the time
I will be with your side
whatever happens.
Mother.
I would like to have your permission
for asking for a girl's...
...hand in marriage tomorrow.
If Selcan agrees, I will not divorce her.
If she does not, she knows better.
If you will be happy and have children
and grow your family
I agree, Bey.
Who is this girl?
Goncagul Hatun.
Does Gumustekin know that?
I will be happy if you send someone
and let them now that
we will come for asking the girl's
hand in marriage, mother.
If that is what you want
and if Selcan
agrees
then you have my permission.
Good luck with that.
Thank you.
Good appetite. If you excuse me.
If you excuse me.
Everybody's destiny
is written differently.
May God give patience to both of them.
If you excuse me.
If God permits, mother.
Do you think that Goncagul Hatun
may be wife of my brother, mother?
I wanted to have Selcan.
Gundogdu was not peaceful.
Now he can choose for himself.
Thank you, mother.
When will Halime come back, son?
He went to give information about
Atabey Ertokus to Sultan Alaeddin.
He will report about us and return.
God.
Surely you are the best of those
who sets us a trap.
God, destroy the traps set up for us.
Do not leave me alone
do not leave me to my enemies.
Empower me so I can sacrifice my life
for the ummah that is scattered
as the pieces of a rosary.
Do not pull your hand off
so we do not fall prey to our enemies.
Help us so we can fulfill your wish.
We can carry your name with us
to where sun comes up and sinks.
Help us so the azan will be recited
all around the heaven.
God, do not let me separate
from the right way.
May I come in, Bey?
Come, Geyikli, come.
Ertugrul Bey.
Abdurrahman Alp brought news
from Noyan, Bey.
What does he say?
Halime Sultan...
...is in danger, Bey.
He sent Karabek after them
to kill them in the palace.
What will I do, mother?
How can I be willing that
he will sleep with that woman?
If you love your husband,
you will fight, daughter.
But know that
you are still in his heart.
He know what you have done for him.
He knows that you love him.
He knows your respect to him.
That is why he does not divorce you.
That is why he does not indulge.
I wish that he would kill me.
I wish that he could save me
dying like that every day.
It is time to leave for us, brother.
If I cannot stop Karabey
Halime Sultan and Wild Demir's lives
are in danger.
Ertugrul, it does not work
like that, brother.
Let me go with you.
The nomad group and mother
are entrusted you, brother.
It is so now.
If I have a trouble, you will
be the one who knows that.
No, brother. I hope that you will
not have any trouble.
But if you will, I will always
support you. Just you know that.
Thank you.
I will come to see how much difficulties
you will have in front of your
father-in-law, if I can catch.
You, rascal you.
Good.