Episode 37 will start after 11:58 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
You are here just in time again
Ertugrul Bey.
Thank God we met again.
-Are you alright, Ertokus Bey?
-Of course!
Noyan is more powerful than we thought.
Our enemy should be powerful
for us to show our might.
Alright, Ertugrul Bey.
-They issued a death warrant for me.
-Why?
I am accused of killing you.
Me?
Where did that arrow come from?
There!
Halime Sultan. Don't you understand?
My brother's life depends on it.
Tell me. Where is Ertugrul?
Don't you know that I would never tell you
even if I knew it, Gundogdu Bey?
Listen. If we cannot find him
Gumustekin will find him sooner or later.
After that point none of us can save
him from the gallows.
Everybody think that
he is a killer and traitor.
Halime. Tell us where Ertugrul is
before it is too late.
It is not just about you.
We all are in danger.
And this will crush all of us.
You will give him to Gumustekin,
the dog of Sadettin Kobek, right?
You cannot even deal with
Aytolun's tricks.
How will you deal with
the palace's tricks?
Can you not see the good intention of
Gundogdu Bey, Korkut Bey and me, Halime?
Tell us where he is while there is
still hope. Stop this nonsense!
Ertugrul Bey would prefer to die
because of my nonsense
rather than your good intention.
-Gundogdu.
-Yes, mother?
Gather all the Beys. Tell them to start
the preparations for tribe's migration.
What are you saying, mother?
Where does thiscome from?
Where could we go in this winter cold?
They want to start a conflict between
my son and Sultan Alaeddin
by smearing him.
It would have been okay if Noyan
was the person behind this.
But I know that Gumustekin is the one
who was fooled by this slander.
It is my duty to respond him.
-Mother.
-Gundogdu. Do as I say.
Hang on, Ertokus Bey.
You will be fine.
You will get better in the nomad tent.
It is too late. Listen to me, Ertugrul.
Listen to me.
The information your
brother Sungurtekin sent...
You must find it.
You must give it to Sultan Alaeddin.
That information...
There is a big birdcage
where Mongols captured me.
It is hidden in rock next that cage.
Find it, Ertugrul. Find it.
That information will also lead you
to your brother Sungurtekin.
I bear witness that
there is no god but Allah,
and I bear witness that Muhammad is the
servant and Messenger of Allah.
Where are you, filth!
-Where are you!
-This way.
My glorious Sultan.
It is my first letter since years.
I am writing this because...
...my man Ertugrul is being slandered.
Mother Hayme.
You must stop Halime and Ertugrul.
The peace we would get with my
marriage will also be in jeopardy.
As if we have any peace left.
Mother Hayme. Halime must speak now.
I think she knows where Ertugrul is.
I know how to make her speak.
What are you hiding?
Nothing, mother.
Do you think my eyes are blind?
Tell me.
Halime.
I am writing our current situation
to Sultan Alaeddin, mother.
Without my permission?
Only Sultan's command
can save Ertugrul, mother.
This will save us from the cruelty of
Aytolun and Gumustekin.
And also from the attacks
of that greenhorn Tugtekin.
Things will get ugly
if they hear about this.
They will kill my Ertugrul
if we do not send a messenger, mother.
Well! Look at Halime Sultan!
She is setting a trap to my man.
Gundogdu.
The real gift is
to see what the eye does not see
and hear what ear does not hear.
What are you up to again?
I see that you are walking into fire.
I wanted to reach out for one last time.
You should focus on your situation first.
Put out the fire in your wicked heart.
You have lost your mind.
As you say.
We would win the palace's favor
if we find Ertugrul first.
So you send your Alps around here
to scout.
We would keep a sharp lookout.
Do not worry, Bey.
-Bey.
-Gokce.
Let us talk privately, Bey.
What's going on?
-News from Ertugrul, Bey.
-What are you saying, my love?
Halime reports your actions
to Sultan Alaeddin.
Messenger will leave soon.
Halime is just like his man then.
What is she saying exactly?
Amen.
Rest in peace.
Bey. How did Tangut find here?
Abdurrahman...
Maybe they tailed Abdurrahman, Bey?
If they had tailed Abdurrahman,
Mongols would have never come here.
They would not have given
Atabey Ertokus to us.
Is there any chance that
they set up another ambush, Bey?
I doubt it. If they had set up
an ambush, they would have come after me
or you when you went after Tangut.
If you ask me
there is unrest among Noyan's army.
Noyan may have no idea
about what Tangut did.
So what will we do now, Bey?
First we find the information
Atabey Ertokus said, then we decide.
First of all we must find
that traitor in our nomad group.
We can never find peace or move forward
with this evil shadow looming over us.
Atabey Ertokus was the only person
who could tell the truth
to Sultan Alaeddin.
His death could be a problem for us, Bey.
Patience is the cure for every trouble,
brother Turgut.
-As you say, Bey.
My brave men! We have lived our lives
under the shadow of our swords
to reach martyrdom.
Come on then. It is time for batlle.
I wonder how you enjoy
playing with these, brother.
I cannot find peace if I do not clean
these rusty things, Aytolun.
I give them the value they deserve.
I polish what I like and darken
the shiny ones I do not like.
What about your destiny, brother?
Will it shine or darken?
Good question.
If Sultan Alaeddin accepts the offer
Sadettin Kobek made for me
I will shine as the margrave of this land.
You need to increase your power
in order to achieve that, brother.
Your next target should be Noyan
after you capture Ertugrul.
You must win one victory after another to
make people think you are the solution.
We were unable to find
any trace of Ertugrul yet.
What if you summon your
must trusted soldiers?
I do not want to attract attention
in the palace.
I ordered my trusted Alps to track him.
We must make powerful Alps
in this nomad group to bow to you.
We should make Gundogdu your son-in-law.
I also pull the strings of Tugtekin.
-Tugtekin? What is it?
-Halime Sultan is going to send
a messenger to Alaeddin to inform on us.
Son, you will be mute and
your eyes will be blind
until you deliver this.
Forfeit your life
before you hand this over.
Fly like a hidden wind.
Your command is my duty, Mother Hayme.
Godspeed.
So she hopes to get help
from Sultan Alaeddin.
We cannot hold back our people
if that messenger
leaves this nomad group to inform
Sultan Alaeddin.
You must stop him.
Let us say we stop it for now.
Then what? It means Halime has been
seeing Ertugrul secretly.
We must make Ertugrul's closest ones
in the tribe bow down to us.
-Who else?
-Wild Demir.
If things become complicated,
Gumustekin...
We will take care of it before that.
How so?
Don't we want to lure Ertugrul
into a trap?
Yes.
So we put Wild Demir and
Halime into a cage.
All hell would break loose
in the nomad group, brother.
My father would never allow it.
Your father left to check on our herds
in the outskirts.
It is not about taking them prisoners.
It is about showing Ertugrul
what would happen to his loved ones
if he does not surrender.
He is a murderer in the eyes of state.
We need to occupy Hayme and Gundogdu
while they are being taken
if we want to avoid causing trouble.
Like I said, it is not about
taking them prisoner.
It is about keeping them on edge.
We must make them seem like
they are collaborating
with a murderer who killed a statesman.
I will occupy Hayme and Gundogdu
with Goncagul.
What is this important matter, Artuk?
Bey, I have served you for years.
I think that I have done
nothing wrong against you.
Alright.
I know that what I am going to say
will not hurt you.
My job is to telling the truth.
Tell it, Artuk. What is it?
I am saying that you have
abandoned Seigniory.
They do not feel your power
in nomad group anymore.
You do not have your old eyes.
It seems that your word
has become obsolete.
If that continues, you will not only
be able to merge with Kayi
but also Dodurga nomad group
will fall apart.
Why do you think like that, Artuk?
Bey, Aytolun Hatun and Tugtekin
have a free hand in nomad tent.
They have right to rule
but they do not have any right
to be a Bey.
If they talk on behalf of you
neither their nor your rule
would have an influence.
What I mean is you must take the law
in your own hands immediately.
Immediately.
Do not commit a murder, Kocabash.
You do not worry.
I will do what is necessary, Bey.
When you came to nomad tent
to meet Ertokus Bey
that night Kocabash
stormed into our tent.
He has said that he saw
an uncanny shadow in nomad tent.
He supposedly came to our tent
to protect us.
We thought it is apprehensive
to be suspicious about Kocabash
until then but...
We have also rescued him from Mongols.
Is it possible that was him, Bey?
If you are after a big hunt,
you sacrifice little preys.
Maybe it was also a game
that you saved him.
It must be around here, right, Bey?
Yes, he was talking about here.
We must give our lives to protect it.
What do you mean I cannot find Tangut?
Where the hell did he go?
Find him!
He may have ashamed of himself
because he couldn't catch
a crippled man. He may have felt insulted.
Tangut will make you pay a heavy price
for your words, Turk.
Even death cannot take anyone's life
before get my permission.
You should know this!
Baycu Noyan.
Efrasiyab "The Merchant".
So you came back from nomad group.
Tell us. Did execution order of Ertugrul
set Turks against each other?
We are nearly there, sir.
Gundogdu will have the final strike soon.
Then maybe bravest warriors of world
will join your ranks.
Like Abdurrahman.
Like Hamza.
Bring wine for me and Efrasiyab.
We have a lot to talk.
Find Tangut and bring him here.
Our livestock would perish if we leave
immediately as Mother Hayme said.
Do the necessary.
I beg you, Bey. Do not force us
to migrate in the dead of winter.
Our wounds are still open.
You do not worry.
We will do what necessary.
Okay.
Migration?
So you heard it.
Bey...
...I know that Mother Hayme is mad
at my father.
And you have problems.
And you are right about it.
You and your mother are carrying a
large basket of eggs on your back.
However burden on my father's back
is completely different.
My father is responsible for lives and
goods of not only Dodurgas and Kayis
but also Bayats, Avsars, Karkins, Bey.
While they are talking about
Ertugrul Bey has kidnapped
the bravest commander of Seljuk
and killed his soldiers...
...what could my father have done?
I apologize, Bey. I have poured out
my heart to you suddenly.
It is no problem.
I was going to collect some herbs.
I should get back to it. Excuse me.
Of course.
If you want to pour out someday
I am a good listener.
You should know this.
Alright.
It is wonderful.
Thank you very much, girls.
They are so beautiful.
May it be easy, Hayme.
Thank you.
Daughter of the one of the women
is going to be a bride.
She wants you to go to her tent
and pray for them.
Let me check these first then we can go.
-Why do not we go now?
-Why so rush?
They will take her trousseau.
They are waiting for us.
Let's go then.
May it be easy.
Listen, son.
Community would fall apart on the day
when they do not embrace
their brave one.
Heads would be legs and legs would be
heads on the day when Beys
do not embrace their brave ones.
It is the day of devil that has no tongue
when those who see bad things
but do not say anything and when
those who do not fight for justice.
Yes, brave ones? What is it?
You will come with us, Wild Demir.
Gumustekin Bey will interrogate you.
-What interrogation?
-It is about helping murderer.
Listen to me, son.
Ertugrul Bey is the only alive son
that I have.
You are talking about him
as if he is a brutal killer
a traitor who betrayed his state.
I am just an aide, Bey. Come with me.
Turali. You wait here.
Let's see what does this
uncanny Gumus want.
Noyan. As if the ground swallowed him up.
So he has more time to live.
-What will we eat, Geyikli?
-I have made pastrami.
Bamsi would have died for pastrami
if he was here.
Especially Bamsi.
Bey, I swear to God I have never
thought that I would miss a bear.
Bey.
Could you solve it?
We must find someone
to read these immediately.
As I understand, Ertokus Bey
has specified the roads
that is going to be used before
the war against Mongols.
-Peace be upon you, brave ones.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you. Come please.
Any room for me in your table?
You are patron. We would not have table
without you. Come please.
Come, Dogan.
How did you find us?
Heart's voice of brave ones can be
heard from anywhere, Turgut Alp.
Thank you.
-Please.
-Thank you.
So you are Wild Demir!
You are the famous blacksmith
who makes irons come around.
Irons come around, Bey...
...but those hearts which went blind
will not be in same line.
Yes? What do you want from me?
Answer to justice.
Justice?
To whose justice?
Of course my justice!
Fine. Ask me so I answer.
Would you tell me Ertugrul's location
if I ask, Wild Demir?
I see. Your justice seeks Ertugrul Bey.
Listen, Bey.
If Ertugrul Bey would have
betrayed to his state
customs and marquee I would have
put his head on my anvil
and crush it with my own hammer.
I would not have cared.
I'd not have consulted you
or that worthless piece of order
that I do not respect at all.
Where is Ertugrul?
Your son-in-law Turgut Alp
and the other one, Dogan Alp.
12 traitors who fled from nomad group
and other Alps who joined them.
How did you manage to train
all those many traitors?
And you, Bey?
Which field's crop are you?
I am a really patient man, Wild Demir.
But patience and everything have an end.
You will sing like a bird anyway.
Okay?
Are you looking for me, Bey?
It seems you have problems as I do.
What is your problem, Goncagul Hatun?
My problem is my father, Bey.
I know how he risks his life for this
nomad group, for our Sultan.
I also know that how merciless
he is against people beside him
for the things he believes in.
Your father's duty is tough.
It is not about it, Bey.
What is it then?
Sometimes he is merciless against
people beside him.
Even against me.
Forgive me, Bey. I went too far
and spoke too much.
No worries.
He offended you and Mother Hayme
because of your brother Ertugrul Bey.
You forgive him, Bey.
He is a good man, believe me.
Everybody knows his respect and love
for your deceased father.
-You also know it.
-Thank you very much.
What is your problem?
I went too far again.
Who am I to ask your problem constantly?
As if I can find a solution for it.
What I can say is
"May God does not give any problem
and make us look for solutions."
No, Goncagul Hatun. No worries.
There is no way to solve my problem
with conversation.
You do not bother yourself.
I do not know your problem but you
never know who has the solution, Bey.
While life is so short, do not let
your problem become bigger inside you
and do not let the destiny burn you.
You have nice words.
What is it? What do you want?
You will come with us, Halime Sultan.
It is Gumustekin Bey's order.
Let's go.
Wonderful.
Welcome, Mother Hayme. It is an honour.
You are so beautiful.
May God bring you together
with your lover.
May God make you live happily
ever after if God permits.
Amen.
Mother Hayme.
-Mother Hayme.
-God damn it.
-What is it, Dumrul?
-It is Gumustekin Bey.
They took Wild Demir and Halime Sultan.
What do you mean they took them?
What is your brother up to?
That is so impertinence.
My brother does not do anything
without justice.
Do not go crazy before learning the truth.
I hope what you said is true.
If not everyone and everything
in this nomad group shall fall apart.
Dumrul. Tell Alps that
we are going to tent.
Yes, mother.
Stop!
Let her go!
Let Halime Sultan go.
I said let her go!
It is Gumustekin Bey's order.
We cannot let her go.
I said let her go!
Or my sword will drink
your blood like sherbet.
What is going on, Hayme Hatun?
Do you rebel against your state
like your son?
Rebelling against cruels
is in our blood, Gumustekin.
And making traitors kneel down
is in our blood, Hayme Hatun.
What is happening here?
Put down your swords.
Put them down!
Do not you ever think the results of
drawing swords to each other?
Put them down!
Hayme. What is going on here?
Gumustekin put Wild Demir into cage tent.
And I guess that was not enough
so he wants to put my daughter-in-law
Halime Sultan, too.
What does it mean, Gumustekin?
Every one of them is really
important information, Ertugrul.
What is it about?
Ertokus Bey kept tally of these lands.
"Which tribe has how many Alps?"
"Which tribe is ruled by who?"
"How many soldiers will be given
for war against Mongols?"
And he specified a route for
marching of Center Army.
Any news about my brother Sungurtekin?
Yes.
He wants to kill Ogeday and
want to rejoin you in a short while.
If God permits we come together again.
If God permits, son. If God permits.
What is your intention?
Everything we do is meaningless until
we find the traitor in nomad group.
I will go to nomad group
and take action tonight.
Thank God!
Ertugrul. There is not much time
to expected dawn.
There is not much time to resurrection.
Dark nights will be over
and world will have peace.
Be patient a little more.
Try hard a little more, son.
What did we say? Destiny loves endeavor.
Alps dismissed.
Go!
What is it, Gumustekin?
You are punishing others in nomad group
without my permission.
Why are you so nervous, Korkut Bey?
When did Gumustekin do something
injustice so you are roaring at me?
What crime did Hayme Hatun's
daughter-in-law Halime Sultan commit
so she was captured
in her own nomad group?
I would not care about my father
if my father acts as an accomplice
with murderer of statesmen.
Halime Sultan sees Ertugrul secretly.
Even it was, you cannot take anyone
without my permission.
Alright!
If Sultan Aladdin asks why did
you slip murderer through your fingers
I would say that Korkut Bey
did not give permission.
Gumustekin. I understand your anger.
Too many brave soldiers have died.
One of the most favorite commanders
of Sultan has been kidnapped.
However we need proof.
Halime Sultan and Hayme Hatun
is doing something
behind your back, too.
They have complaint about you and me
to Sultan Aladdin.
Their intention is to make him
meet with Ertugrul.
It means they know his location.
Right, Hayme Hatun?
Is he telling the truth, Hayme?
Since he is so sure he must prove it.
If I prove it...
...will you give Halime Sultan
and Ertugrul with your own hand?
I will.
But now you will release Wild Demir
and my daughter-in-law Halime.
As you wish, Hayme Hatun.
You are free. Gumustekin Bey
said you can go.
But you do not leave nomad group.
Your only intention is turning
nomad group into hell then.
My God!
Save us from this fire
as you have saved Abraham
from Nemrut.
Coward! He is still defending his niece
after everything I have done for him.
He is allied with Hayme. I told you so.
He is too weak against Ertugrul.
He may be afraid of him.
No matter what we must finish it.
Korkut...
...must die on short notice.
What? Are you afraid?
-No.
-What then?
We must bond two nomad groups
very tightly
so we would not fall apart
when Korkut died.
What are you thinking?
There is not much time for
Gokce and Tugtekin's wedding.
We may have a double wedding.
Then nobody can stand in front of us.
What if Korkut continues
to be a trouble for us?
I would not allow it.
He would not be
a trouble any longer...
...if I make him worse than dying.
How can you be so sure
about trusting Gokce?
She wants to use Tugtekin in order
to take love revenge on Ertugrul.
She is in love with Ertugrul then?
And where is Goncagul?
She is busy with stealing
Gundogdu's heart.
Bey.
-What is it, Dumrul?
-Wild Demir and Halime Sultan.
What about them?
It is Gumustekin, Bey.
He tried to take them into cage
to interrogate them.
Let me go!
Here I come!
In the name of God!
God damn it!
Noyan will lose his mind.
Bamsi! Brother!
-Brother!
-Is it you?
It is me, brother. It is me.
Brother, what is it?
I cannot tell you . Mother Hayme gave it
to me. I am taking it to Konya.
Brother, it is obvious that Mongols
set an ambush for you.
They will not let you go.
Come back to the nomad tent with me.
Talk to Mother Hayme first and go.
What do you think, brother?
I say aye.
My mighty brother!
These Mongols are fierce fighters,
brother.
They never end no matter
how much you kill.
How is my nomad group, brother?
Are they okay?
Why is that, brother?
Ertugrul Bey is exiled.
Ertugrul Bey?
Who exiled Ertugrul Bey, brother?
I will tell it on the way.
Tell me, brother.
Tell me about Ertugrul Bey, brother.
Your father has ruined our plans.
It is better this way.
When Kocabash finds the information
that messenger has
Mother Hayme will hand over Ertugrul
with her own hands.
Son, let's say we have dealt with
this situation, then what?
What do you mean?
Your father would not take action, son.
If a Bey would not take action
in a nomad group
there will not be any peace
in that nomad group.
We have not seen any comfort
since the Kayis arrived here.
Are they the only ones to blame?
Your father is guilty as much as they are.
Let me tell you son,
if this continues like that your father
will lose his Seigniory.
You must stake a claim on Seigniory.
What if they take it from the messenger?
What would we do then, mother?
We must be prepared for everything.
Wild Demir.
Can we take Halime out of nomad group?
It is too hard, Mother Hayme. Really hard.
They don't let anyone
out of the nomad group.
Mother.
What does everyone say?
I disappear for a little while
and look what happens.
It is really dangerous, son.
If they catch the messenger,
our relationship will be torned apart.
What messenger, mother?
Messenger we sent to Sultan Aleaddin.
God have mercy on us.
I wish you had shared these clever
plans of yours.
I sent it to my uncle.
You would know about it
if you were around, Gundogdu Bey.
No, Halime Hatun. No.
It is obvious that you want to
act like a sultan in this marquee.
As long as you keep acting like a sultan,
you will torment our tribe.
We want to learn my brother's location
from you but you keeep bringing us
more troubles.
What now?
How did they find out about
this messenger?
Only Sultan's order can save Ertugrul.
If anybody hears it,
things will get out of hand.
My God, protect our messenger.
Amen.
Peace be upon you.
-Bamsi.
And peace be upon you.
Mother Hayme.
Thank God you are here.
-Master!
-Welcome, son.
Bey!
-Welcome.
-Greetings.
Sister Halime.
Welcome, Bamsi.
Where have you been, you lunatic?
I battling in the mountains, master.
Mother Hayme. Dundar is fine.
Yigit Alp is fine.
They are being disciplined.
They are all like lions.
Mother Hayme, I have brought Gunkut, too.
Gunkut!
Brother Gunkut!
-What is going on?
-Mongols have attacked me, Mother Hayme.
I would have died,
if it was not for Bamsi.
They knew that I was the messenger.
We were lucky again.
Bamsi, I will talk to you later.
Alright.
Excuse me, I leave the decision making
to you.
As long as I don't learn them
from others.
I missed you, son.
My men are looking for him everywhere.
He cannot run forever.
He will show up sooner or later.
Bey!
It is like ground has swallowed
that messenger.
There are no trace of him.
Incompetent fool! Keep looking.
What now?
Relax.
My spies in the palace will deliver
another letter to Aleaddin
on behalf of Halime Sultan.
You scare me, Bey.
How are things in the palace?
Sultan Aleaddin? Sadettin Kopek?
Sultan Aladdin is the most gifted Sultan
I have ever seen.
And Sadettin Kobek is the most evil
vizier I have ever seen.
So the devil and the angel
are in the same palace?
I am also curious about the end of
this story.
But the real question is Tugtekin,
where will we end up in this story?
What do you think?
Right in the center of it.
I mean we must be the ones
who decide the end of this story.
Did Abdurrahman enter the nest of Noyan?
He did but I don't know
how will he get out.
I hope for the best.
We must think about saving Ertugrul Bey
from all this trouble.
One day the hand of God will touch it
and everything will go upside down.
That hand should reach out soon.
It is not the right time then.
Bey! Welcome.
Greetings.
Artuk Bey, you have done a lot for us.
Do not mention it, Bey. My pleasure.
As long as you seek justice,
there will always be someone
to help you and clear your path.
Thank you!
We don't have much time.
We must act quickly.
Peace be upon you.
-Bey!
-My Bamsi!
Bey, they told me you were on exile!
Bey!
They can exile us,
but we can come back from the sky, Bamsi.
I would die for you, Bey!
I would die for you!
Come, brother.
Bey!
Bey, your hand?
-This is just a mosquito bite, Bamsi.
-Bey, I would--
I would crush that mosquito, Bey.
Do not worry.
You fell in the middle of action,
Bamsi Beyrek.
Really, Bey?
Nice.
It has been a long time
since I decapitated some heathens.
I was drowning in sorrow, Bey.
We should tell Halime Sultan
that I am here.
I will take care of it.
-Excuse me.
-Thank you very much.
Do not stand up, please.
Master Demir, you know that
I am not good with words.
My condolences, master.
Our heart burns.
Thank you.
I want to hold you in my arms soon,
my child.
Why are you in a rush, Turali?
Ertugrul Bey wants to see you,
Halime Sultan.
I don't believe that
Ertugrul is a murderer
or he betrayed his state, Aytolun.
Then Ertugrul should come here to
face the trail himself, Bey.
And let the ones behind this plot
be revealed one by one.
Gumustekin is more than a brother to me.
I am breathing because of him.
He saved my life from the Mongols
with his sword without flinching.
His leg was crippled because of that.
However he is on a wrong path.
He is looking for the evil
in a wrong place.
Bey, you used to trust my brother's
intuition and experience a lot.
I did.
I always did.
But not this time.
His search for this evil
is giving birth to more evil among us.
Get ready, Halime Sultan.
We will go to Konya.
We?
Since our messenger was not able
to reach Konya
then we go there ourselves.
How is that going to happen, Bey?
By asking help from the traitor itself
to take us to Konya.
Gundogdu.
Our tribe is getting restless.
Decisions are being made
in your marquee without you.
Your Hatun burns down the nomad group.
And what are you doing, Gundogdu?
Pull yourself together quickly!
Gundogdu who is the son of Suleyman Shah.
Shape up or ship out.
Permission.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Yes, Master?
I have hot soup. Warm yourself.
Thank you, brother.
I want to talk to you
about something important.
I know that this will stay between us.
Turgut and Dogan used to hate you at first
but then you have proved your bravery
to all of us. Thank you.
Thank you, Master Demir.
I need your help to clear our names.
Turgut and Dogan have saved my life.
They are my brothers in this world and
the other.
I will do whatever you want, Wild Demir.
Thank you.
We must set off with Halime
before sunrise.
But we need get out of
the nomad group quietly.
The guardian Alps report to you.
What about Ertugrul Bey?
Will you meet him?
Yes.
Do not worry.
I will do my best, Master Demir.
Anything for you to clear your names.
Thank you.
So it is my turn to go and
leave you alone.
Godspeed.
May the sun never burn your skin.
May no rain make you cold.
May no stone get in your way.
Come back to your tribe
like a flowing river.
I want you to tell something to my mother
before you go, Halime Sultan.
Konya is too far, girl.
You will ride a horse for days.
And you are pregnant.
We also know what happened to that Alp
who I sent to Konya.
Ertugrul will come with us until we leave
dangerous lands, mother.
And if my baby is to become
a brave Alp like his father,
he must get used to challenging roads.
May God protect you.
Godspeed, my child.
I will ask you something, Halime.
Is Ertugrul still upset with me?
No, he is not upset, mother.
He misses you a lot.
He wants to kiss your hand and
embrace you as soon as possible.
I also feel suffocated.
May God never separate a mother
from her child.
Amen.
May the God protect you on your journey.
Mother.
Ertugrul Bey wanted me to give you
another news.
Another secret?
Another secret, mother.
What is it this time?
Sungurtekin.
Ertugrul Bey has learned that his brother
is alive.
How?
How can he know that?
"My mother has been patient
for a long time.
Tell her to be patient
without asking questions."
He will bring his brother
to the nomad group soon, mother.
My son!
My God, you made me hear this news,
so please allow me to see my child's face.
Let us be reunited, merciful God.
Amen.
My son!
Gokce.
I have learned his location.
Ertugrul's location.
Tugtekin, go and bring him here alive.
Bring him, so that he gets
what he deserves.
Brother.
I think you should talk to Hayme
before things get more complicated.
First we have asked Gokce, who he sees
as her daughter, for our son Tugtekin.
Now we want her son Ertugrul to send
to the gallows.
I think it is better to make Mother Hayme
happy, until we get rid of Korkut.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Enter.
Gumustekin Bey.
We need to talk right away.
Excuse us.
What is it, son?
I have learned Ertugrul's location.
Where is he?
He will meet with his wife
and Wild Demir tomorrow.
It seems that he wants to
bring the message himself
after their messenger to Sultan
was intercepted.
You did not tell it to your father, right?
No, he does not know it.
You know that your father
is really sensitive about his nephew.
I will take care of it myself, Bey.
That is the best way.
Go and take care of it yourself.
Do I have permission?
Yes.
You summoned me, Bey.
Gather our men.
We will set off before sunrise tomorrow.
I have learned Ertugrul's location.
I have news for Noyan.
So you are back.
Where were you, Tangut?
Where were you?
I want to talk privately.
What are you hiding from the men
I entrust my life?
I want to talk privately, Baycu Noyan.
Speak.
Ertokus. He's dead.
How?
Go away! Get lost!
Good job. Keep going like this.
-Aytolun Hatun!
-Move.
Move!
What are you doing here?
I have remembered
how generous of a woman you are.
You old hag!
I told you not to come here again.
Winter is ahead.
I am an old and lonely woman.
I need a place to stay
and something to eat.
You cannot stay in this nomad group.
Get out of here!
Wolfs would eat my body before
winter ends.
Maybe this is what you really want, eh?
Tell me is that what you want?
Wait me at that foothill.
I will bring the things you want tonight.
Thank you, Aytolun Hatun.
This will be the last time you see me.
I am so sick to survive this winter.
If you come here again I will not
let you die of sickness.
I will feed you to the wolves
with my own hands! Go now!
Aunt. Are you okay?
That old hag was here.
I told you that
she was not going to leave you alone.
Don't you worry, aunt.
I will take care of her.
I will whisper in her ear that
she should never bother you again.
I went for hunting in the woods.
I saw some tracks, trailed them
and found myself in some place.
Cut to the chase!
The tracks belonged to Kayis.
I traced them in hopes of
catching some of them.
Then I saw the Kayis attacking our
soldiers who were escorting Ertokus.
What are you saying, Tangut?
I killed Ertokus to prevent them from
recapturing him.
Man who I have been trying
to catch for years
have died before I delivered him to
Ogeday.
Get lost.
Get lost!
After I am done with you Ertugrul,
your world will be in ruins.
What is it, Tangut? What's going on?
May God help you.
As I said, Noyan will take prisoners away
in the morning.
Every news you bring from that
bastard Noyan, will lead us to salvation.
May God protect you.
Prepare the horses. Let's go.
Yes, Bey!
May the scourge of the earth and sky,
follow you wherever you go.
You are done now!
Noyan has lost one of his favorite man.
That is why he is angry.
Who are you?
Suleyman Shah's daughter, Selcan.
I used to know your father.
I mean your birth father.
That evil man who made brothers
kill each other.
I have heard that you are no different
than your father.
However an elder Dervish who came from
the west had tamed you.
You have repented.
Your old ears are not that deaf if seems.
I hear everything. I mean everything.
Now get out of here! Leave me alone.
What do you want from me?
Aytolun.
Why did she grow pale when she saw you?
Everything has a price, girl.
Price of the information you want to know
is not this worthless necklace.
I am not afraid to pay the price.
Then you hate Aytolun Hatun that much.
She is a miserable person,
not even worth my hate.
Tell me. What do you know?
Why is she so afraid of you?
She was warming the bed of Korkut Bey
long before his wife died.
Do we need to talk about this
wretched woman any longer?
Yes.
Then you must pay the price.
Pay it before nightfall to get
what you want.
You wait here. I will be back with gold.
Do not move away from this place!
Where can I go except hell?
It's you!
-What have you told her?
-Nothing.
What is this? What is this then?
I have not said anything.
You got what you deserved, old hag.
Why did you send Alps without
letting me know, mother?
Mother. Tell me.
Don't you trust me anymore?
Why?
Is it because I did not stand
up against you like Ertugrul?
Is it because I did not place more
burden on your shoulders like him?
It is because I placed
your burden on my shoulder?
-Tell me.
-Enough. That is enough.
I have thought that it would be
better if less people knew about it.
There is nothing to
feel upset about it.
How is this possible mother ?
You sent a brave one to death alone.
And you did it without telling me.
Do you trust Ertugrul who always causes
problems in nomad group more than...
...your step son?
Gundogdu.
Gundogdu! Son!
Where is she!
Women make homes,
right, Aytolun Hatun?
We have learned that
you destroyed it.
Let's hope for the
best for all of us.
Mother Hayme, Gumustekin Bey
wants to see you.
Let him come in.
Yes, Gumustekin? What is it?
Are you here to interrogate me?
I have acted impulsively
against you, Hayme Hatun.
When Sadettin Kobek gave me the
order about Ertugrul, and also...
...hearing words of that soldier who
escaped from war has made me blind.
All my life I have been in war against
Genghis Khan and Ogeday after he died,...
...and his ignoble sons now.
I maybe tired. I am sick of it.
However when I heard that I got another
stroke from Suleyman Shah's son...
...I was grieved by
that, Hayme Hatun.
Forgive me if I crossed the line
and broke your heart yesterday.
I know you and the importance of the
duty which Sultan Aleaddin entitled you.
My son will prove
that he is innocent.
If Ertugrul does not surrender,
state would not pardon him...
...even if I pardon him, Hayme Hatun.
And you should know that there
is nothing I can do from now on.
Mother Hayme. They found a body
of an old woman near nomad tents.
Selcan!
Neither Wild Demir nor Halime
Sultan, Bey. None of them is here.
Have you checked everywhere?
We have, Bey.
Keep searching.
Aytolun!
You killed her! You are
a murderer! Murderer!
Let me go! I am telling you, she is a
murderer. She killed that woman. Murderer!
I said she killed
that woman. Let me go!
You killed her. Killed her!
You were not expecting
me, right, my aunt's son?
Welcome, Tugtekin.
So you want to witness a festivity?