Episode 28 will start after 12:3 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
I want you to know that I'm very happy
to have met a noble warrior like yourself.
What do you want from me?
You can be sure that I want nothing
but your friendship, Turk.
Us Moguls are good at choosing our
enemies and friends.
We'd like Ertugrul to become
one of our friends.
You couldn't be my enemy,
let alone my friend.
Don't rush, Ertugrul. Keep calm.
Give him some water.
I was told that you wouldn't quit easily.
A cavalcade is coming towards here.
Your men are searching for you.
If only they could find you.
Victory will always be ours as long as
we fight against pikers like you.
Split up in different directions!
Don't leave any traces behind!
-This can't be happening! God, no, Aykiz!
-Turgut, my son.
Aykiz!
-My son.
-Aykiz
Turgut, pull yourself together, son.
No!
You should be proud now that
your wife has become a martyr.
-Let us lay her down.
-No. No.
Turgut
Slowly, gently. My poor daughter.
This glory and honor
would suffice you in both worlds.
Hopefully, God will help you
unite once more in his heaven.
Aykiz, Aykiz, no, Aykiz!
Turgut, son, it is alright.
Aykiz!
Henceforth, embrace Gokche
who grew up an orphan
as your daughter Aykiz.
Would you, Father Demir?
Help me, God or I'll lose my mind!
Bey!
Keep calm, Dogan Alp! Keep calm.
He's survived many hardships.
He will survive this one as well.
Do you hear me? Pull yourself together.
Infidel Noyan was here.
As long as that tyrant
who did this to people is alive,
we cannot be at peace.
Mongols has invade
everywhere with their tyranny.
The fear of the Mongols proceeds
their invasion.
They don't even have mercy
for the ones who surrender.
There are no traces here, Bey.
Water! Bring some water!
This is Bey's.
Bey!
They killed Bey! He is dead.
I have learned what the greatest
grace God grants to people is.
I've just found out it now, Mother Hayme.
I've just found out!
It is to be buried by his own children.
But it's my destiny
to bury my own children.
After my sons,
now I'm burying my own daughter.
We have traveled all these lands and we
lost a life on each land we stepped on.
My heart says,
these lands which we lost lives
and shed our blood on
will be the home to our future
generation.
We have seen winter, Master Demir.
Our generation will see the spring.
You are right, Mother Hayme.
You are right;
however I have buried
myself alive into a hole.
Unless death takes me,
I will not get out of this hole.
What other problems
can I have, Mother Hayme?
I buried my two sons and one daughter.
What about your problems?
What about your pain?
How will you save our tribe
from this darkness
which has fallen upon us,
Mother Hayme?
While many people
count on every word I say
how I can mourn after my children,
Master Demir?
I have buried my pain into my heart.
As long as our people thrive,
I don't mind suffering.
We have temporarily settled the
pregnant and elderly women in tents.
What about our martyrs?
The preparations for our martyrs' burial
place where the combat took place
are about to be over, Bey.
After funeral prayers,
we will bury our martyrs in the evening.
Artuk, how are the injured?
We've divided the prayer room
into two parts.
We are treating women and men
there with midwives.
Thank you. May you be blessed, Beys.
As you know, we embraced our brothers,
the Kayi tribe.
We have not abandoned them on the
mountains without food and water.
We have dressed their wounds.
What will we do, Bey?
How far will this continue?
Our duty is to stand behind them.
We will help them and share their pain.
The main issue is, what to do when the
Mongol dragon attack us with full force.
Let's think about that.
Sadettin Kobek
wanted you to know something, Bey.
When the spring comes, Sultan Aladdin
will gather all Oghuz tribes
and attack you.
Aladdin thinks he is cunning.
The new world is ours, Karabey.
After Genghis Khan's children
had brought China to its knees
they will come to these lands, too.
What happened, son?
Mother
Halime
Forgive me.
I was not able to bring
my brother back to you.
-Ertugrul has become a martyr.
-No!
Halime, Halime!
Halime!
How did this happen, son?
They burnt him, uncle.
They burnt all of them alive.
Mother!
Ertugrul will deal
the greatest blow to Sultan Aladdin.
-How?
-If Ertugrul chooses to obey me
he will become the ruler of Anatolia.
However, his leash will be in my hands.
And we will bring Aladdin to his knees.
Noyan, they brought Ertugrul.
Tie him up.
Get this girl ready for Noyan. Hurry up!
My condolences, Mother Hayme.
My condolences, Halime.
My condolences, Baci Hayme.
Before he embarked on his expedition,
I told my man that
may no stone touch his feet,
may no wind hurt his body.
However, I was told that even if
no stone touched him, no wind hurt him
they still burnt him alive.
None of us can be at peace
unless we avenge Ertuğrul.
Rest assured, daughter.
He is not only my sister Hayme's son.
Ertugrul was my son, too.
If I do not avenge him,
I cannot live with this shame.
Do not be scared.
Fear does not look good on
your beautiful eyes.
If you want that girl to live,
do not cause any trouble during dinner.
If Noyan vents his anger on her,
you will be sorry for that.
Welcome to my shrine, Ertugrul.
Enjoy your meal!
So you are the gallant man who
defeated the Templars,
became friends with
the Ameer of Aleppo, Al Aziz,
have bonds with Seljuk Empire
through marriage
and who spilled my brave warriors'
blood mercilessly.
So you are the ignoble man who rapes
women, kills babies in their cradle
and boasts about it.
You are right, Ertugrul.
We are the fire of the moor.
Once the moor catches fire,
it burns for days.
It throws the baby
out with the bathwater.
We are establishing the biggest state
the world has seen.
Genghis Khan conquered half of the
world.
We will conquer the rest.
What is a few corpses in such
a sacred cause?
Your empire is like a fruitless tree.
You will be chopped down.
The sun will blight you
and you will disappear.
People will only remember your cruelty.
And then the state you had founded
will attack here and there
and bite itself just like rabid dogs.
I hope that your Mother Hayme,
your bother Gundogdu
and your wife Halime
will not be amongst the ones those
rabid dogs attacked.
You have chosen a
warrior wife just like yourself.
We found out that she escaped us and
took shelter in Korkut's nomad tent.
But it does not matter.
Halime Sultan from the Seljuk Empire
will live just a few more days.
If she is lucky, a few more winters.
If you are our enemy, she'll be a victim
of this cruel war sooner or later.
Your wife and all your beloved ones.
-My condolences, Bey.
-My condolences.
Here.
This sword is your child's now.
God!
Halime!
Bring some water!
Dear daughter!
Halime!
If god permits, this sword will become
the voice and wrath of injustice
in your hands.
God bless.
Come to the point. Why did you not kill
me when you had the chance?
What do you want from me?
A strong warrior like yourself is more
valuable to me alive than dead, Ertugrul.
I can only be your angel of death,
Noyan.
For your mother, wife, and the children
in your nomad group
to be able to live at peace and serenity
I want you to see the truth and be
on our side, Ertuğrul.
Be with us, walk with us. Win with us.
Fighting dastardly and killing babies
is not something to be proud of.
But something to be ashamed of, Noyan.
We live for our honor.
We found out how you caused trouble
for the crusaders.
We know you well enough, Ertugrul.
Sultan Aladdin
will certainly die quite soon.
Then you all will be
left out in the cold.
I'm giving you a chance to protect
your nomad group and the loved ones.
You either take our ide and become
our friends
or perish just like all our enemies.
Do not rush to respond to my offer.
First, enjoy this food and wine,
then we will talk at length.
We have been fighting the armies of
Genghis Khan since I was born.
My beloved ones died one by one.
Including my brother, Sungur Tekin.
Now you are talking about friendship.
As long as I live, we will never
become friends.
Sungur Tekin...
He is one of the finest and
smartest warriors I have ever seen.
He proved that by becoming one of us.
Now he is fighting by Ogeday's side and
proving everyone how courageous he is.
You are both a vile warrior
and a vile liar.
You will see whether if
I am lying or not soon enough, Ertugrul.
Sungur Tekin will come here in spring
with the Mongol troops.
Now, go and think about
what I have said.
If you want me to believe that
you still have a hint of humanity
let the girl stay with me.
Enough! Stop beating him!
My heart tells me you did not die,
Ertugrul.
It tells me that you did not leave me
alone with our child in this world.
Please, be alive.
Please, do not leave me alone
with our child.
Cry, my daughter. Cry.
Mother, may Ertugrul be alive.
May he not have left us alone.
So, you still show resistance.
Let us see how persevering you are.
Ertuğrul wishes to have fun.
So let the fun begin.
The Kayi tribe without Ertugrul
is like a crippled person, Hatun.
I was the mind of this tribe.
And he was the heart.
He got into hot water.
However, he managed to overcome
all troubles.
I thought he would come back
this time, too.
I thought no trouble could come to him.
However, my brother is gone
for sure, this time.
For this reason,
his child is our child now, Hatun.
You shall take care of Halime.
Not to worry, Bey.
Bey Ertugrul has become a martyr.
He was bestowed the most
honorable of deaths.
The Kayi tribe should recover as soon as
possible.
Everyone is suffering in their tents.
If you do not exercise sovereignty,
everyone will be scattered.
We want two nomad tents to unite.
This way, we can find relief
for a few springs.
There is no other way for now.
However, being united has its
own problems.
Such as?
The Dudurga nomad group is without a Bey.
Bey Korkut is infatuated with Aytolun
in his old age.
Aytolun wants to reign the marquee.
Even if she's on bad terms with Tugtekin
she is sure to have him
under her spell soon, too.
God, Hatun while we are suffering,
how could you see all this?
I'm just saying, Bey.
You should know your allies well
so that they won't become your enemies
when it's time to break things off.
You are after the wrong man, Noyan.
You can never persuade him.
End this match!
Tie him up! I said tie him up!
Hayme Baci has been overwhelmed
by circumstances.
Moreover, the death of Ertugrul
has increased her pain.
Didn't you use to say that we
nomadic Turkmens carry
our pains on our horses
along with ourselves, Father?
I was ruined with the death of my mother.
And we still couldn't manage
to find her killer.
But if I do not kill her murderer
a thousand times I will live in shame.
God!
Come, Hatun, sit down.
I think you do not need to do these
things anymore.
-Find a helper for yourself.
-Thank you, Bey.
I have been thinking about it
for a long time.
Sewing workshop in the morning,
and marquee's work in the evening
I get exhausted.
Bismillah.
Please.
Father, what will your decision be
at the headquarters tomorrow?
I am thinking that two nomad tents
should be united.
-How will things proceed?
-The Kayi tribe can rule the Alps.
The Alps even fought with the Mongols.
And our Beys can take care of the rest.
Alright.
My deceased mother used to say that
if you need to make a decision always
consider the difficult days first.
It is not my business to
interfere with men's matters.
However, if there is unrest between
the two nomad tents
just keep in mind that
the one who holds the Alps' power,
will seize the power.
What do you mean?
I mean you should be the head of the Alps.
You should be the one ruling them.
So that when there is unrest,
we won't get into trouble.
I've brought you some milk, son.
Do drink it as you wish.
I am going to tell you
the story of Fil Surah, son.
It's the Surah that tells how little
birds defeated giant elephants.
Once upon a time, Abraha the Cruel
created an army made
of elephants to destroy Mecca.
When Abraha took to the road
all the people of Mecca ran
away for the mountains.
While Abraha was marching
towards Mecca with his huge troops
suddenly, swifts appeared in the sky.
It was actually a war
between birds and elephants.
It was a war between
heretics and believers.
The birds defeated Abraha's army
by dropping stones
from their beaks upon them.
Whenever you feel little and weak
like those birds remember this Surah.
It's not always
the big and the strong who win.
God's will decides who will be victorious.
May God be with you.
Thank God.
In which flames did they throw
my great-hearted man
and turn him to ashes?
Not even the sun was supposed to burn him.
Not even the wind
was supposed to make him cold.
He would go,
but he would always come back.
Did death do us part, Aktolgali?
Ertugrul became a martyr before
he could see his child.
It feels as if the blue sky has collapsed.
The brave earth is pierced.
The swords of the Kayi tribe
will rust in their sheaths.
Neither the hunting nor the headquarters
will have an owner.
He would not have left us, Aktolgali.
And it would not suit us to leave him.
From now on, breathing
is like living in hell to me.
Do not say that, Halime.
It's God's will.
We are mortal servants.
May God unite you in his heaven.
Will we unite in heaven, Selcan Hatun?
If God permits, Halime Sultan.
How is Halime?
Halime will never be able to find
happiness in her heart again, brother.
Hopefully, she will recover soon.
And how are you, Hayme?
Not a teardrop, nor a day of mourning.
Until my nomad tent finds peace,
I shall bury my sorrow in those mountains.
Fortunately, Yigit and Dundar
are not here to see our pain.
What do your Beys say?
I told them you invited them
to the headquarters.
-They said they will come gladly.
-Thank you.
What are you thinking, brother?
They attacked my nomad tent
last summer, Hayme.
We had many casualties.
They took half of the herd, too.
They broke our wings.
They broke our wings, too.
To hell with them!
This winter will be difficult for
both of us, Hayme.
Is this why you invited us to the
headquarters as a guest?
Not just as a guest.
I'd like to unite the two nomad tents.
If the Mongols do not eradicate us,
it will be our last winter on these lands.
I want two nomad tents to be one
so that we can survive
this winter even if it will be difficult
You will be a cure for the Kayi tribe
with these words, brother.
However, what would the poor and
the injured in your nomad tent say?
Winter is coming.
And we do not have anything else
except our pain to share with you.
You have the best Alps of the Oghuz tribe.
That is enough to help us.
I will talk about it at the headquarters.
I wanted you to know that.
Thank you, brother. If it was meant to be.
Incompetent man!
My horse became crippled because of you!
I am not a blacksmith, Bey.
I did my best. Forgive me, Bey.
Bey!
Poor man begged forgiveness.
And he was given
a task that is not his duty.
Know your place, Alp Dogan!
The ones who are in the wrong are
punished right away in this nomad group.
Otherwise problems will come
one after another.
We know our place from mores,
and get appreciation from our Bey.
Dogan?
What is it?
We are talking about Oghuz mores
with Bey Tugtekin.
Their deceased Bey Ertugrul
could not teach them manners.
We are in pain.
I don't want to be troubled with
your bickering.
You are right, Brother Gundogdu;
however, they do not know their place.
Anyway, we need to go
to get prepared for the headquarters.
You do not have your Bey now,
Brother Dogan.
Do not shit where you eat.
You will pay a heavy price.
We have no price left unpaid, Kocabash.
If the need arises,
we will pay for it, too.
Today I nailed the hand you swing
your sword with.
Tomorrow I will nail the other hand.
Then your feet.
Then finally, I will nail your eyes with
my own hands.
This torture will not end until you
decide to obey me.
What happened? What does Tugtekin
say about his father's speech?
He agrees with his father, mother.
He wants to be united.
-How about the other Beys?
-We will find out at the headquarters.
What do you think?
My words are not respected
in the Kayi tribe, mother.
Is that wrong?
I remember telling you not to go to
Aleppo, but you did not listen to me.
We got into hot water.
Right when we found peace,
we set off again. I did not approve it.
And we got into hot water again.
From now on, people
will learn to mind my words.
As for your question, I'd like the two
nomad groups to be united.
Otherwise we will fall prey to
our enemies this winter.
Also, we shall avenge
those infidel Mongols.
Or the pain of the people
will not be soothed.
And it is our duty to easy their pain.
Excuse me, mother.
Selcan, come, daughter.
Yes, mother?
Daughter, until the conditions
are clearer, our Hatuns who work
at the sewing workshop
will help Aytolun's women.
We've already placed a strain upon them.
It's best if we make ourselves useful.
Alright, mother. I will talk to our women
and do what is necessary.
Choose the best ones.
Leave whoever lost their beloved ones
at the battle alone.
Allow them to mourn.
We do not have
the right to do such a thing.
The best thing we can do is
let them mourn. Alright?
My condolences, Gokche Hatun.
May God give you a long life,
Bey Tugtekin.
I know well what it means to lose
a brother.
Two of my brothers died in my arms.
Ertugrul
he was more than a brother to me.
I do not know if it consoles you,
but whoever did this to Ertuğrul,
will pay for it, Gokche Hatun.
You must discourage the Turkmens
before winter comes, Noyan.
If Sultan Alaaddin takes this herd of
shepherds after him
and comes onto you before Ogeday
finishes his campaign to China,
you will be the ones crushed this time.
Not to worry, Karabek.
They will experience the most difficult
winter of their lives.
They will see that
they cannot take shelter in their tents
and live in peace as if
they were in their mothers' wombs.
When are you planning to set up a
meeting for me and Saadettin Kobek?
It depends on your generosity.
We Mongols are generous, Karabek.
Saadettin Kobek is ready to meet you.
The two of you will meet tomorrow.
-This quick?
-He's expecting you at the Sultan Inn.
So he's expecting me at the Sultan Inn?
Karabek, if you trick me
I will skin you alive.
Is that all? I was expecting more women.
Most of them lost their Beys or sons,
Aytolun, but they are the best.
Your work benches will be busy
night and day.
You can bring the goods to towns
and sell them before winter comes.
As long as they are not under
my women's feet...
I know that you are all suffering.
You have been through hard times.
However, we are all in a great war.
Our Beys are talking about
our future in the marquee.
And we need to satisfy
the needs of our nomad tent.
Before winter comes,
we must manufacture enough goods
for the markets
in Erzurum, Konya, Diyarbakir.
Our duty is as important as that of our
combating Alps.
We cannot stop.
We cannot regard it as a burden.
We will only do our duty.
Before winter comes,
we must complete our work.
Until your condition is clearer you will
help my women at the sewing workshop.
Am I right, Selcan Hatun?
You are right, Aytolun Hatun.
Our women will do their duty properly.
Not to worry.
If God permits.
Alright. Say "bismillah" and begin.
Go ahead, women.
Go there and help her.
Welcome, Hayme Baci. Welcome. Please.
In the 99 names of God
who created us with his one word
and who fills our heart with faith.
Bismillah.
Have your say, Hayme.
Mother?
Uncle asked you to be the first to talk
about the union of the two nomad groups.
First of all,
you opened your marquee
and your hearts to us.
May God bless you.
They say each day has a night.
Time flies. We know our enemy.
That is why being united is best.
I say, let us be one!
Be huge! Be strong!
Thank you, Hayme Baci.
If two nomad groups unite,
it will be easier for us
to stand against the Mogul invasions.
If God permits, Sultan Aladdin's army
will be here after this winter.
However, we need to survive
until that time.
Union is strength; however
how will this nomad group be governed?
How will we share the tasks?
What does the Kayi tribe promise us
provided that we are united?
Not to worry.
We do not intend to be
a burden on the Dodurga tribe.
As you know our sewing workshop
burned down.
But our dexterous women
will surely build new ones.
And as for the goods in our hands,
we intend to sell them to buy provisions.
The nomad group's governing
headquarters will gather at my marquee.
But both nomad groups will settle their
own matters at their own headquarters.
It is true, Bey. The alternative is
out of the question.
-It is true.
-Is that alright, Hayme?
It is, Bey.
I suggest that my son Tuğtekin takes
command of the Alps.
Is that alright?
It seems you've made all decisions
beforehand, Bey Korkut.
And we shall agree with them.
And it seems that Wild Demir
underestimates my Alp skills.
How can you command them if you
don't have any Alps amongst you?
Shall we start worrying about
the seigniory before we avenge
the blood shed for our brotherhood
to become stronger?
Let us not have a battle of words on the
first meeting at the headquarters.
Gundogdu is right.
Let us not squabble.
Let us not interpret
one another's intentions.
We approve of Tugtekin becoming
head of the Alps.
Gallant Gundogdu from the Kayi tribe
shall proceed with his duty for his nomad
group in our nomad group, too.
-Is that alright?
-It is.
Thank you.
Now, it is time to take our revenge.
It is time to show that herd of dogs
who we are.
Let us make the sun our spear,
and make the sky our tent
and attack the Mongols.
That will be the sign of our union.
Thank you, Bey.
-May God bless the Beys of Dodurga.
-Thank you.
If anyone of you has something to say,
speak now.
Because we are on a road of no return.
Keep that in mind.
-Anyone?
-No, Bey.
-No, Mother Hayme.
-May God bless the holy war of our Alps.
-Amen.
-May our union be blessed.
-May all evils clear away.
-Amen.
-May God bless us with luck.
Now it is time to take revenge.
Tugtekin, your duty awaits.
You never give up, do you?
Your brother Sungurtekin
was stubborn as you.
But he finally realized that I am right.
Now he is one of the
closest men to Ogeday.
You are lying.
I told you, if you obey me,
I will bring him to you.
You will hear yourself
if it is a lie or the truth.
I will not be your dog, Noyan.
It is a pity.
It will sadden me quite much to lose
a precious warrior like you.
My warriors are mad at me
for not killing you.
If you be on my side
the blood of Turks
will not be shed anymore.
You can be sure of it.
Noyan!
Turks would go running to drink
the sherbet of martyrdom.
My patience is running out.
If you do not obey me
I can surely find another traitor.
It is your decision.
I have a lot to do.
I want to smash Kocabash's face in but...
Anyway.
Brother Turgut.
It is said that you attended
the headquarters, is it true?
It is.
Mother Hayme wanted me to attend
instead of Ertugrul Bey.
What happened, brother?
What did you talk about there?
Why did they gather us?
You will find out now.
The headquarters decided to take
my brother Ertugrul's revenge
on that heathen Mongol.
Whoever volunteers for this duty,
step forward.
Thank you.
But first, we need to find
the trace of Mongols.
We are going to sent trackers
to all lands.
Abdurrahman and Hamza will scout from us.
And Bogac and Samsa from us.
Do not leave a stone unturned.
You will trace and return.
And here, we will prepare the Alps
who will take action.
Go ahead, trot along.
They are setting off to avenge Ertugrul.
Something tells me Ertugrul
did not die, mother.
As if he will come back to us, soon.
As if he would not leave
his child fatherless.
The two nomad tents decided
to take revenge.
They are preparing to scout.
We are going to cause them great distress.
Look sharp. Do not lay bare.
Do not worry about it.
What is the matter with you?
The nomad group talks about your bravery.
But you are waiting here,
your face and heart in shadows.
Tell me, what is wrong?
Nothing.
Come.
Sit there. Something bothers you,
it is obvious.
Tell me. There are two things which
bothers a gallant man like this.
Either he has an enemy he cannot defeat
or he is in love with
the most beautiful girl.
-Is it that obvious?
-Is this girl Gokce?
But how can you know?
I saw how you looked at her on the bridge.
By the grave of Aykiz.
At the funeral of Ertugrul.
A fire fall to my heart
when she came to nomad tent.
I could not stop thinking about her.
Do you want to me to do a kindness
for you, sad lover?
What?
I can find out if she has a lover
or not, for you.
Either you will move out
or my hand will stay there.
Tell me. Does Gokce has a lover?
Tell me, Ilgish.
Your mother brought me into the world.
She has many rights on me.
If you know something,
do not hide from me.
How could I, Aytolun Hatun?
How I can hide something from you?
Gokce is single.
And she does not love anyone.
Why no men has attended
to her all this time?
Hanim, she is the daughter
of Suleyman Shah.
It is not easy.
She has two brave brothers.
No man can dare to get near her.
It takes a lot of nerve.
And our daughter is a little coy.
We embraced Kayi tribe.
We did what would befit us, Aytolun Hatun.
I hope they do not attempt to bite
the hands we held out.
No.
Kayis would rather pluck out their teeth
than to bite the hands
reached out to them, Hanim.
Hopefully, it is so, blacksmith.
Hopefully, you are right.
-You had summoned me, Artuk Bey.
-I would not summon, Wild Demir.
Come with me, I will show you something.
What did you find out?
That she is a little coy.
That men are afraid to come near her
and that she does not love anyone.
She is in great sorrow.
Treat her tactfully.
And I will do what is necessary.
How could I remunerate you?
You can start by calling me mother.
Come. Go ahead.
Did you bring me here to show here?
I thought your heart may be willing
if you saw the hearth that does not burn
the hammer that does not meet the iron,
the steel that does not kiss the anvil.
We need you, Wild Demir.
Not only for you are a blacksmith.
But for you are a warrior.
For you are the finest warrior at that.
You will make the swords which will
pluck ignoble Mongols' livers.
I made many swords for many Alps, Bey.
But I saw their delight did not last long.
I saw my swords in their hands while
the light of their eyes were fading.
Last, I made a sword for my daughter
before we left Aleppo.
So she could protect her honor and life.
She fought like Alps.
She hit, cut and beat them.
But she could not survive
from burning, Bey.
Now while all these are on my mind
how do you expect me
to put a sword between this hammer
and this anvil?
How do you expect that, Artuk Bey?
There you are, jackal!
What will you tell us?
What are you?
Tell us, where is Noyan? Speak!
Let us make this dog talk!
Go ahead!
Uncle, we know that they are watching us.
But we wanted to make use
of this condition.
We placed our best Alps
to every corner of nomad tent.
They will lie in ambush and wait.
Surely, we will catch one.
Instead of looking for Noyan far away,
looking for him around the nomad tent?
If we catch only one,
we will find out a lot.
We sent news to four winds.
We did not want to pursue him
before we found a trace.
You thought right.
-The dinner is ready.
-Alright, daughter.
Please.
I hope you will like it.
I have tried all day
but this is all I could make.
What happened, Turgut?
-Bring water.
What happened, do you not like it?
Even those Templars did not
torture me like this.
The poison they gave me,
is tastier than this.
You think so? Go and drink
their poison then.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, sit down, I am kidding.
Turgut?
Brother?
In the name of God.
Welcome, daughter.
Please, sit there.
We are glad to see you among us.
You need to bury your pain inside
and be strong for your child, Halime.
This is the destiny
for the wife of and Alp.
We are glad to see you at our table.
Ertugrul did not die.
Ertugrul was the bravest Alp I knew.
It is hard to accept the loss of
an Alp like him for all of us.
But it is harder for you, daughter.
Brother.
We will put a plate for Ertugrul,
from now on as we do for Sungurtekin.
Tomorrow, the marquee of Kayi tribe
will be established.
Hopefully, we will see the owner
of those empty plates there.
Please, enjoy your supper.
Bey, is there permission?
Come in.
What happened, Abdurrahman?
As Gundogdu Bey said, we went to the field
and lied in ambush, Mother Hayme.
We saw a Mongol who was watching
the nomad tent.
-Did you catch him?
-We did, Mother Hayme.
-Did he speak?
-Before he died
he said Noyan will set off tomorrow.
Where he will go, too.
Tugtekin, make the preparations.
Halime!
I know you are alive, Ertugrul.
Until my breath drains away
I will pray for you to be saved
from your suffer.
For you to you reach your child.
Your father will return, son.
He will.
Do not worry.
May God keep your path bright.
Thank you, Selcan Hatun.
Gundogdu.
I have an ill feeling inside me.
God is almighty, Hatun.
We will go and return, if God permits.
Take care of yourself.
I am going to meet with Sadettin Kobek.
Watch Ertugrul carefully,
while I am not here.
Do not worry.
-Are you ready, Borklu?
-I am.
They say the hunter becomes the hunt.
Let them hunt.
Say my greetings to the hunters.
The Alps are ready, Bey.
They are waiting for you
outside of nomad tent.
Thank you, Kocabash.
We are ready, mother.
May God help you.
I hope that God will ordain us
to take our revenge.
Hopefully, uncle.
It will be a vengeance befitting
our ancestor, Oghuz's glory, father.
We will show the tyrants
what is bravery, if God permits.
Alps!
May our swords be sharp!
May our faith be strong!
May Khidr be our guide
and may God be our helper!
Allahu akbar!
I will return soon, Turk.
When I return, you will either die
or be my dog.
The captive is escaping!
Ertugrul!