Episode 43 will start after 12:18 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
What is happening, Hayme?
It is time to face with Noyan, brother.
I called you to listen to my sons.
As my mother said
it is time to take life of our enemy.
How is it going to happen, Ertugrul?
We are not talking about some bandits.
We are talking about the vanguard composed
of the most valiant Alps of Mongolians.
I hope you thought long and hard.
Ertugrul Bey I know,
would not call us here
without talking to our best Alp
and talk about it, Gumustekin Bey.
Noyan waits in Kurtbogazi
to make a trap to me.
How did you learn it, Ertugrul Bey?
The person you know
as betrayer Abdurrahman.
I was the one who kidnapped him
from fenced tent.
Ertugrul, every sing...
I exuded Abdurrahman from fenced tent
and placed him near to cur Noyan.
I have done the thing that our enemies
have made to us for a thousand of year.
Was Abdurrahman your spy?
While his brothers
try to make him executed
he did not consider of a dilemma not
to give his life for his brothers.
But, now life of Abdurrahman Alp
is in danger.
We want to take the action
before he loses his life.
Noyan will locate his man to valley
of Kurtbogazi in order to ambush me.
We will move to upper part
of valley on foot.
While they wait for me to come
we will attack from upward.
They could not even breathe.
Tangut will be with Noyan.
So while we attack
we need to move with our best Alps.
Me and my Alps will be with you...
...Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
Cantonment of Noyan is not an easy mark.
What our head Alp, Gundogdu Bey, says?
If my Beys agree
I want to make the Anatolian mountains
unbearable for them.
Now
this is the place where Noyan made
a trap to my brother.
They did all malice here.
They have three crucial unions here.
We will move from stream bed with our Alps
and then we will move from this stream bed
to the heart of their cantonment.
Mongolians know how to attack very well.
However, their defense is weak.
They are blind from the glory of
formerly gained victories
the thing I am trying to say is
if we success to enter to cantonment
of Noyan unexpectedly
they will not have any power
to fight against us.
If Korkut Bey let me,
I would like to join to this war.
God bless our holly war.
Thank you, my Bey.
Situation of your leg is obvious,
Gumustekin Bey.
It is better if you do not go.
Drowsing does not look good on me
while attacking to dishonest men
with our Alps, Artuk Bey.
Being martyr with my groom that I vestry
my daughter is an honor to me.
Thank you, Bey.
Now, things spoken here
will remain here.
If there is another betrayer shows up
then we will know that
he is from this marquee.
May God be with you.
-Amen.
What do you see, Ulubilge?
Tell me what you saw?
Tell me!
-Ertugrul!
-What about him?
Ertugrul...
Ertugrul was an eagle with broken wings.
Now he has wings stronger than each other.
With these wings
he will be flying over you.
He will be a trouble to you!
Until...
Until what?
Tell me!
Ertugrul...
Until Ertugrul dies
there is no victory to you, Noyan.
Peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Where are so many Alps going?
They must be up to something!
There is no pus left in your leg, Bey.
But you should rest, it is not wise...
...to go to war in this condition.
If I am not going, who will, Artuk Bey?
Even if death is the price...
...I will attack to those
Mongolian bastards.
Both as a Bey of the nomad group
and as a person authorized by the state...
...I will need to fight in this war.
May God help you, Bey.
What is going on?
Where are all these Alps going to?
We do not know, Bey.
Excuse me.
Good gracious!
What are they up to again?
Welcome, Halime Sultan,
welcome, Grandfather Demir.
-Thank you, beauty.
-Thank you.
God save you to your parents.
Has anything important
happened in the nomad group...
...while we were away?
Ertugrul Bey cleaned the nomad group
from betrayers, Bey.
-Is Ertugrul Bey in the nomad group?
-Yes he is.
Come on.
-Halime!
-Ertugrul!
Thanks God you are back home.
I was not away from my home
even for a single day.
I am at home,
and my home is inside me.
And you are on the seat of honor.
Separation awaits us again, Ertugrul.
We united with the Dodurgas.
We are going to war, Halime Sultan.
We will make Noyan fall into his own trap.
But I say Sungurtekin, Ertugrul.
Sungurtekin Bey sent you a message...
...he will wait for you
in the caravansary tonight.
He told you to come no matter what.
We are ready, Noyan.
Let us go, then.
Noyan!
Is it bad news, Noyan?
Sadettin Kobek
sent me news with Sungurtekin.
He will be in the caravansary tonight.
What about Ertugrul?
Sungurtekin is going to kill Ogeday
by the order of Aleaddin.
I need to stop him.
Ertugrul will die, Tangut.
This is your duty.
Do not ever disappoint me.
Yes, Noyan!
Prepare my horse.
Finally Ertugrul fell into my hands.
May God speed you and help you, my Bey.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
I want to contribute to this victory...
...with tear and blood.
I know that your dreams
are far beyond your father's marquee.
You will prove it in this war.
I hope nothing is wrong, son.
Halime Sultan and Wild Demir brought
you news from Sungurtekin, mother.
Thank God! Tell me, how is he?
You should have seen how
he cut the Mongolians up with the sword...
...I gave him when he was a child.
He was more than alright.
He came so fast and saved our lives.
Master, where is my brother now?
He is waiting in the caravansary
for Ertugrul Bey.
Why does Sungurtekin not come
to nomad tent and call Ertugrul instead?
I will find out when I go there, mother.
Ertugrul, the Alps are ready.
What should we say to the Beys?
Sungurtekin told me to come
no matter what.
You know he would not say that
if he did not need me.
As for Noyan...
...his blood is yours, brother.
May God help you.
Thank you.
Thank you, Bey.
May God be with you.
Amen.
We are ready, Gundogdu Bey.
Ertugrul is not coming with us.
-Why? He was the one who started this.
-He has a more important duty.
At least as important as the Noyan matter.
Let us go and take their carcasses.
They said you called us, Gundogdu Bey.
Ertugrul Bey is not coming with us.
You are coming with me.
We will meet with the Alps
at the bottom of the valley.
Dumrul will tell you
what you are going to do.
Yes, Bey.
-Thank you, Bey.
-Thank you.
Gundogdu Bey.
I just wanted to say, may God speed you.
May God give you strength, sharpness
to your sword and speed to your horse.
Thank you.
Whenever you see it
remember that I am waiting for you.
I do not need it to remember you.
But thank you anyway.
Goodbye.
Watch your behavior or I will kick you!
Be careful. Lovers kick so hard.
-Yes, brother.
-Damn it!
Brother, where is Ertugrul Bey?
I do not know, brother.
If he does not want us to know,
it is unlawful to us to know about it.
We will accept it as it is.
I know what is going on, brother Turgut.
The doors of the world of secrets
have opened to our Bey.
Only our Bey can enter through this door.
He will be out whenever he wants.
He is in another world now, brother.
He is from another world now.
-Another world?
-Yes, brother.
Oh, come on!
Turgut?
Yes, father.
Let us keep our promise we gave to Aykiz.
Alright, father.
Come on.
I could not make you comfortable since
the time I fell in love with you Halime.
You did not have peace ever.
I could not make you live a day
without grief and war.
You gave me your heart.
Is it not enough, Ertugrul?
Do you think I do not know
what you fight for in this short life?
Is your fight not for the peace and unity
of our children and family?
The honor of being with an Alp like you
is enough for me.
I am worried that you go
without healing completely, brother.
I cannot leave this victory
to Ertugrul, Aytolun.
The victory of a war he did not fight in
does not belong to him.
Do you know where he will go?
Then, we cannot be sure of anything.
I hope you will come back with victories.
Come on!
Selcan.
Halime!
Halime. My dear sister!
I missed you so much.
Come on, have a seat.
Are you alright?
I am alright, thank you.
I know about everything, Selcan.
What that bitch named Goncagul
is not Gundogdu Bey, Halime.
I know that.
What do you mean, Selcan?
All they want is just one thing.
They want
the consignation of Suleyman Shah.
Selcan, are you aware of
what you are saying?
They want to settle in Dodurga first,
and then in the Kayi marquee.
Nothing will be like before in this
nomad tent anymore, Halime.
Selcan for God's sake, level with me.
Gumustekin, Aytolun, Goncagul...
...they all want to drag us
towards a disaster.
Aytolun...
...that woman seduced my uncle
even before my aunt died.
The woman who told this to me was killed
the same night she talked to me.
I am telling you, Halime...
...they are hiding
much more things from us.
I will reveal all of them one by one.
Now tell me.
Are you with me on this?
Place the men behind the bushes there.
And over there. We cannot let
Ertugrul escape. Be quick.
Brother.
Brother!
Ertugrul is here, Noyan, he just went in.
So, I will witness
the meeting of Suleyman Shah's sons.
There cannot be a better day to kill.
Come on, have a seat.
Last time I saw you, you were
in the shores of Caspian Sea.
You ramped your horse.
You were holding this sword
which Wild Demir made.
You were going to war with my father
Suleyman Shah and my brother Gundogdu Bey.
And you were saying without considering
your age that you were going to...
...deal with the Mongolians.
You were turning the place upside down.
My mother was making Wild Demir hold
your arms in order to restrain you.
Gundogdu, there might be
other Mongolians around.
Now listen to me,
nobody moves from their positions.
I will go first in order to see whether
there are more Mongolians or not.
What are you saying, Bey?
For better or for worse!
We cannot be martyrs
before seeing Noyan die!
All together.
Our lives for are not
even a drop in the ocean for our nation.
You stay here so that
there is a commander for the Alps.
Do not move from your positions
until the last moment.
Where is this man?
Tekbir  in every mouth!
Allahu akbar!
Help me!
Who are you? I said who are you!
Inform Noyan, tell him that
Karabey's messenger has just arrived.
This is really important for Noyan.
What are you waiting for? Me to die?
Your longing turned into coal
inside of us.
Year after year,
that coal turned into fire.
However, we never lost
the hope of finding you.
Thanks to the One
who brought us together.
Come on!
I am going to make you regret
for not dying, Tugtekin!
You will curse
the day you were born, Tangut!
They say a brave man came
to replace my little brother.
He challenged and beat all men...
...from the lands that the Sun rises
to the lands that the Sun sets.
We cannot get even close to you
when it comes to being brave.
Come here.
You smell like my father, brother.
By the name of God!
Attack!
After Aleppo, we came to Erzurum
to fight against Mongolians...
...with our Sultan.
I know it all brother.
Things you did in Aleppo.
The Templars. Halime Sultan.
That I am going to be an uncle.
My mother, my father, you taking the
responsibility of being Bey, everything.
Other than the suffering
because of all the longing...
...it feels like I have never left.
And you, brother?
In the war I fought with my father and
brother Gundogdu, I was captured.
You thought I died.
My mother never believed that
you were dead.
And then?
I had a chance and escaped.
The only thing I thought was to
come back to my nomad group...
...to my family.
I a man's life on the way.
Then I learned that he was one of the
closest men of Genghis Khan.
He trusted me and took me to Genghis Khan.
I came into the presence of Khan...
...he rewarded me.
He welcomed me.
And then this man took me to son
of Genghis Khan, Ogeday.
From China to India, we ride our horses.
Who is this man?
Noyan.
I played this game to write and send
what I saw to our Sultan Aladdin.
I used Noyan.
Our Sultan Aladdin...
...managed the Mongolian politics
...with the information I sent,
for sake of state.
Many times we came back of wars.
We were saved from the war...
...with our Sultan's wisdom
and my information.
But...
...it is over now.
The target of cruel Ogeday is Anatolia.
If his arm arrives here...
...they do not leave any person alive.
I did not show concern for you for years.
Because it was the best
that you knew me as martyr.
I have one last duty, brother.
That is why I wanted to see you.
I can do anything for my state
and for you, brother.
You, brave as a lion!
Thank you.
Sultan Aladdin gave me a duty...
...to withdraw the Turks fighting...
...in Mongolian army, brother.
How will this work?
It is the seal of Oghuz Khan.
Our Sultan hopes that this seal...
...will harden the bonds of brotherhood
over the Oghuz's that we lost.
That is why I will go to the lands
of our ancestors.
What kind of power will this seal has?
The seal is what you see, brother.
The real issue is to remind our brothers
serving to Mongolians who they really are.
To save them from slavery and
to divide the Mongolian army.
If the Turks were not so supportive,
they could not get so strong.
Sultan Aladdin is right, brother.
But if we cannot bring the Islamic...
...world together and cannot get
any help from other Muslims.
Sultan Aladdin cannot do anything alone.
I hope these days are
very close, brother.
I hope so, too.
Now, the reason that I wanted you
to come no matter what is...
I wonder.
I want you to meet me
with the white-bearded.
I cannot do this without their help.
So you have the Oghuz Khan's seal.
Tell me about Sungurtekin.
Tell me so I can get my power back.
Did the sun of steppe blast his skin?
Did he have wrinkles on his face?
The last time I saw him,
he was a young man.
Now, tell me about him.
How did he grow up?
How did he become such a valiant man?
He never forgets about Suleyman Shah
or you, mother.
His brothers, his nomad tent.
Even if so many times passed he knows
every breath you took, mother.
How do you know my secret about
the white-bearded, brother?
Let us say that cranes flew and told me.
Now tell me, are you with me?
I am always with you, brother.
I wish that my mother and Gundogdu brother
could also see you.
If I do not die...
...I will return to my nomad tent
after I fulfilled my duty.
There is no time to lose.
Kiss both my mother's and
Gundogdu brother's hand for me.
There is no time to lose.
Then, let us go to Ahlat.
Noyan!
Attack them!
Allahu akbar!
Come along, my lads!
With God's help!
May God be with you!
The day I learned your betrayal...
...I dedicated your carrion to the
spiritual powers, Sungurtekin!
I will offer your carrions to the souls!
The seal of Oghuz Khan will be my award.
Allahu akbar!
Father!
Son!
Abdurrahman!
Son.
God, do not make me suffer for another
lose of child one more time.
Abdurrahman! Abdurrahman!
Open your eyes, brother.
Open your eyes!
Hamza!
Noyan!
I know the trap you set to me!
My Alps destroy your cantonment!
They also kill the soldiers!
Just like I do!
My Bey, wait. Wait.
I understood when I saw
Abdurrahman like this.
I made a mistake.
I am so poor to be defeated
to my anger for you.
My blood is halal to you.
Your blood is even illicit to this land!
Brother! Brother! Get up, brother!
Brother! Get up, brother!
Brother! Brother!
-How is the situation?
-We could not make it, Bey.
Abdurrahman is dying, Bey.
-Brother, get up!
-Abdurrahman, open your eyes.
Mother, are you alright?
I just...
...a cold wind covered my whole body.
I breathe in hopes that,
he will come back for years.
If I lose this hope now...
...I will not have power to live
or breathe.
I know that.
I am afraid not to see him.
Brother?
Brother? Brother? Brother?
-Did you take it?
-I took it brother, I took it.
My valiant brother.
Brother! Brother!
Open your eyes, for God's sake!
Brother!
Hang on, brother! Hang on! Hang on!
Hang on!
Get up, brother!
Open your eyes, brother! Open your eyes!
After I lost my two sons to Mongolians,
God saved you for me.
You win your chiefdom with your policy,
your Alp spirit with your sword...
...my daughter's heart with your bravery.
Thank you, Bey.
It is my happiest day.
They asked for mercy, Bey.
We cannot hit to people asked for mercy.
However, they are not human.
We make them prisoner and
take them to nomad group.
They might be useful. Who knows?
Maybe they will help to save
one of our valiants.
Is that cur escaped, Bey?
Yes, he escaped.
We will go back to nomad group
with victory, Bey.
And this victory is yours.
Victory is ours brother, ours.
Allahu akbar!
Did you bring golds?
-Is there any news from Noyan?
-No, sir.
Where are they?
What is happening?
We need to discover what they are into.
Wait for my news.
Seal of Oghuz Khan is consignation
to you, brother.
Do not worry, brother.
Please stay with me.
My mother waits for you.
Seljukian golds, they all are done
as I promised.
As you agreed with Gundogdu Bey,
you brought gold.
Herd and property of my nomad group
is yours.
My men will load properties until morning
we will place them to caravansary...
...and will be on the road,
with the help of God.
Thank you. May God help you.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
I have not seen Gundogdu Bey.
Nobody knows anything,
knowing ones say nothing.
What is happening?
He has a duty.
What duty, like state secret?
Right. Mongolian trouble,
it is good to be careful.
I say things for nothing,
classic trader words.
Before I count golds one by one...
...do not take properties out of
nomad group, Efrasiyab.
Thank you.
Deliver golds to Artuk Bey,
he will deal them to owners.
Beys are safely back to
nomad group, Mother Hayme.
Thanks to God.
Fortunately.
Excuse me.
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Stop!
Death to traitors!
Do not do it!
Stop! Stop!
Listen, everybody!
Do not do it!
Murderers!
Listen!
Hamza is my Alp!
As head of Alps, it is my duty
to give him punishment!
Understood?
Move on.
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Slowly.
You all are going to die!
Traitors!
Death to Mongolians!
Death to traitors!
May God help us.
With the name of El Shaphi,
I do whatever I can.
But do not raise your hopes.
Dervish, heat some water.
Alright.
Come along, you go and rest some.
With the name of God.
-Killers!
-Traitors!
Give us this traitor!
Death to Mongolians!
Traitors! Traitors!
Noyan, I am at your service.
Until Byzantine, all these lands
will belong to us, Efrasiyab.
Traitor!
Give him to us!
We will kill him!
Fall apart!
Murderers!
So, this time you attacked.
You will have your response.
Thanks to God that,
let us beat the enemy...
...and live glory of victory.
Thank you, Bey.
We came back with victory
but could not manage to find Noyan.
While you stand like lions...
...you will bring his body
with God's help.
Noyan cannot pull himself together
easily from now on.
We are grateful to our Beys, Alps
who made us live the glory of victory.
God bless them.
-Amen.
-Amen, Bey.
Dear God, accept our martyr
to your heaven.
-Amen.
-Thankfully, we have seen it.
-Fortunately.
Fortunately.
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Long live Gumustekin Bey!
-Long live Gumustekin Bey!
-Long live Tugtekin Bey!
Long live Gumustekin Bey!
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Long live Tugtekin Bey!
Now, I look at your face
without shame, father.
Thanks to God, we kept our promise, son.
We have avanged the blood of Aykiz.
Thank God.
Turgut, listen carefully
what I'm about to tell you.
These are the words of Aykiz.
Start a family for yourself.
Raise Alps that are proud of Kayi.
Both me and Aykiz want to see you happy.
Me and Ertugrul Bey want
the brave Alps to remember us...
...and pray in front of our gravestones...
...after we are long gone.
Only then...
... we can call this dark realm
our homeland.
Until we cast out the last Mongol
from this land...
...and my body is laid to rest...
...I cannot stop.
My home is...
...my gravestone, father.
My gravestone.
Find Noyan and tell him that
I am waiting for his orders.
I cared for you like my own son.
When your father became a martyr
right next to Suleyman Shah...
...I laid you down to sleep in the
same place with my sons...
...so that you won't feel lonely.
I cared for you like your mother.
Why?
Even these words...
...are a shame to my tongue.
You are not even worth...
...my spit.
How are you going to cross
the narrow bridge of Al-Sirat...
...with all the sins that you bear?
Shame.
Shame on you.
Shame on you!
You killed all of those brothers...
...yet you never gave them
the blessing of God.
You did not give them a chance to
recite shahada.
Was it worth it?
I wish you were brave enough to face me.
And get your answers with your sword.
I would respect you then.
If you could make me bleed,
I would thank you.
But what did you do?
Shame on you.
I will execute you in training field.
Just so you know.
Guard!
Give him a prayer rug.
Let him pray if there is an ounce of
fear of God left in him.
Dear God, what have I done?
What have I done?
Who is behind this, wise one?
You will find your peace...
...when you confess it to yourself.
Noyan lost, you know this too.
A one-armed shepherd defeated him.
Someone is coming.
You were also trapped, huh?
Yes, Noyan.
Ertugrul took his revenge.
He hit us with our own trap.
How did he know
that I laid a trap for him?
Tangut, how?
My soldiers...
Some soldiers ran away, Noyan.
They took Hamza to the nomad group.
Hamza.
Kill everyone who ran away.
Demand another vanguard from Ogeday.
From now on, we will set our camp
inside the cave of courage.
The real war begins now.
You go with Tangut.
And learn why the spirits are
upset with me.
What will you do all alone here, Noyan?
You are injured.
Help...
Efrasiyab waits for your order, Noyan.
Listen to me carefully.
Tell Efrasiyab that, Noyan wants to know
where Ertugrul went.
This important more than anything.
Do you understand?
If he learns anything...
...tell him to find me
in the place we always meet.
Go.
-Gundogdu Bey.
-Goncagul Hatun.
I used to have nightmares
whenever my father went to war.
But this time, I sent both my father
and husband to war.
This feels different, really different.
Thank God, you came back unharmed.
We die only once in battle...
...yet our women die thousands of times.
I know that from my mother.
While we do battle with our enemies,
our women battle against fate.
If you ask me which batlle is harder...
...my answer is obvious.
May God never take you away from us.
May God give you patience.
Is Korkut Bey inside?
They wait for you
with Tugtekin Bey, father.
Victory is ours but the jackal
we are looking for is nowhere to be found.
Noyan will seek revenge.
Cowards die many times
before their deaths.
We will take our precautions.
As Ertugrul Bey said, we need to
follow this jackal and show no quarter.
You are right, Tugtekin Bey.
We should not let Noyan and his soldiers
feel safe even for a moment.
Each breathe they take
may become our death.
This cloth will look good on my mother.
Why is Ertugrul not back yet?
He will come, if God permits.
Gokce, do you think these colors are fine?
Good. My mother's favorite colors.
How you can be so calm?
Every day something happens to Ertugrul.
Every day he causes trouble for us.
I cannot sleep thinking that...
...something bad will happen to him.
But you...
My Bey's troubles are always welcome,
Gokce.
I know that he always has the solution.
Gumustekin.
You represent the palace and
the nomad group at the same time.
Your advice is valuable to me.
What do you say these
brave warriors' words?
We are against a madman
crazy enought to...
...launch a suicide attack
to our nomad group at night.
As our firt Alp said,
he will not be our shadow, we will be his.
These mountains will be the death of
Noyan and his army.
-If God permits.
I hope nothing is wrong.
Kaya, what is happening?
My Bey, Ertugrul Bey came to nomad group
with an injured man.
Sungurtekin!
What is happening?
I hope nothing is wrong, Mother Hayme.
Ertugrul Bey returns, Mother Hayme.
He carries an injured man on his horse.
Sungurtekin!
I made you a promise, mother.
I said I would bring your son.
Mother.
My dear son.
My dear son!
My son, remedy of my sorrow!
Mother!
I am back, mother. I am back.