Episode 45 will start after 12:26 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
For my God, flag and sword.
Thank God, I am one of those
who are appointed for the duty.
If I go back from this journey...
...that I have for the
sons of my ancestor Oghuz...
...let me be harvested with my own
black steel sword as immature harvest.
Let the blue sky split off.
Let the dark ground be pierced.
Let my Oghuz father and blessed
pavilion to be sue me in afterlife.
Let Hizir Ata be my friend...
...and Prophet Ali my sage
in the way to the holy war.
Let the journey to be ours
and the victory to Gods.
It is time to shear these sheep.
Wool is needed in the carpet store.
Help with it, Shepherd Mustafa.
-With pleasure, Hanim.
-Thank you.
Let us see about what  Goncagul Hatun
takes responsibility again.
It is not easy to be a
Hanim to a Bey, Gundogdu Bey.
You will try to help in every work
so the pavilion may have peace.
What beautiful words
come from your mouth.
I say, at dinner time, let us
talk to speed up the wedding issue.
The girl's house is the coquetry
house. Pander to our whims a bit.
Thank you.
Bey!
There is an issue.
Alright, you can go.
Is there an important issue, Bey?
Hamza escaped from the trussed tent.
Oh My God!
-What will happen now? What will you do?
-Do not worry about it.
Of course, there is
something that I know.
Too much blood spilled for the
seal of Oghuz Kagan, Aytolun.
It seems that there
will be more blood.
What I really wonder is...
...where this seal
comes to Sungurtekin.
Sadettin Kobek knows
that he has the seal...
...the seal must
have come from Konya.
-From the palace?
-Yes, from the palace.
From the hand of Sultan Aleaddin.
Sultan Aleaddin must have given
the seal to Sungurtekin personally.
When Sadettin Kobek learned that
Sungurtekin returned to the nomad tent...
...he asked you to
take the seal from him.
If Sultan is on one side and
Sadettin Kobek is on the other...
...you should be
very careful, brother.
Hamza escaped from his trussed tent.
-How did he escape?
-I do not know.
His news just came to Gundogdu.
Bey.
You know that we will die for you.
You know that...
If you excuse me, Bey
we wonder where we go.
Yes, Bey, we wonder.
We cannot eat out of curiosity.
We are on the way from Otuken and we
travel from land to land, brothers.
Our only concern...
...is a homeland where our nomad
group, ancestry will find peace.
The journey is ours
and the victory is Gods.
There is no meal for those
who are not on the way...
...do not hunt and do
not look for the meal.
I hope we will find
what we are looking for.
If God permits, Bey, thank you.
-Thank you, Bey.
What are we looking for, Bey?
It is a homeland that we will
breathe justice and liberty, Turgut.
A homeland that we engrave
our tradition, soul and case.
The crazy little
horses inside me say...
...that this journey will not be like
the other journeys we had until now.
We will ride our horses for the
future of our nomad group and ancestry.
We will continue from the
lands where the sun rises and...
...to the lands where the sun sets.
Did you say the lands
where the sun sets, Bey?
The lands where the
Byzantines and Crusaders rule.
God is almighty.
Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Never again! Brother, where
did you come from again?
Do not care about who showed up
but care about who made him show up...
...do not care about who came
but care about who sent him, brother.
May God be with the one
who came and who sent.
I brought you food so you
would not be hungry on the way.
-Thank you.
Good appetite, brothers.
Eat slowly you bear, it
will stick in your throat.
Mind your own business!
You had a handful of brain and
you fell in love and lost it too.
Bey, if you excuse me I
would like to come with you.
The wedding day approached, mother.
Your marquee will have full of joy.
Your son, Tugtekin will make your
descend to continue, God willing.
Tugtekin Bey.
Tell me, Bogac.
Bey...
-...Hamza escaped.
-What are you saying, Bogac?
How could that happen?
I do not know, Bey.
Confound it!
Kayis made what they
wanted to do again.
They made nomad tent where
passengers frequently stop by. Walk.
Why did not you say that you will abduct
Hamza and send him to Noyan's place...
...as a spy to my brother Ertugrul?
Sungur. Ertugrul brother
has a secret duty...
...that he did not
tell me or my mother.
I did not want to prevent him.
That is why I decided
to paddle my own canoe.
And I send Wild Dumrul
to follow Efrasiyab.
-Does Korkut Bey know what happened?
-It is just around the corner.
-Korkut Bey came, Mother Hayme.
-Send him in.
How can Hamza escape, Gundogdu?
He betrayed you and put you
in a difficult situation.
But how could he escape
after we caught him?
I do not go to bed with
the snake twice, uncle.
Know that Hamza did not
escape. I let him to escape.
I will send Alps after Hamza now.
I want everybody, except those who
are here, to know that he escaped.
What is this situation,
Gundogdu brother?
Nomad tent became a place where
passengers frequently stop by.
-Let us have a seat.
-Is it time to sit, Mother?
We found and brought the traitor
who raised difficulties...
...for our nomad group
and now he escaped.
Have a seat, furious
man. Let us talk first.
Have a seat.
We are quite far away
from the nomad tent.
Let us get Hamza out.
You did a great job, Efrasiyab.
Noyan does not leave any
favor without giving an award.
-Thank you.
-It was not easy.
Stupid Gundogdu meddled with it.
He went round but...
...I got both of you out from
the nomad group as Noyan asked.
Traitor!
This cur was also a traitor like you.
How could you do this to your tribe,
nomad group, tradition? How could you?
You all will come to grief, you all!
Traitors!
Traitor!
You all will come
to grief as Kocabash.
Traitors!
Look who I brought.
Dumrul.
You hide your skills from us...
...you escaped from
the nomad tent, Hamza.
You talk like you do not know what
Noyan can do for his soldiers, Tangut.
The skill is not mine, it is Noyan's.
Tie them.
Devils. Demon!
Turali Alp.
I think it is time for to be a man.
What do you mean?
If I will be a man that way,
I would accept it with pleasure, master.
Well done, good for you.
Halime Sultan.
I hope nothing is wrong.
Ertugrul Bey left. I
feel bored, Wild Demir.
Do not worry about
Bey, Halime Sultan.
-He will come back, with God's help.
-If God permits!
Turali, what is this face?
-The issue is big, Halime Sultan.
-What is this issue?
It is a shame, I cannot tell.
Halime Sultan, you do your own
business and we have something to do.
All right, more power to you.
Selcan.
Gokce Hatun.
Did you come to this tent because
you remembered your sister?
Since when do you protect my sister?
What are you doing in
my sister's marquee?
We had something to
do with SelcanHatun.
-When I could not find her anywhere...
-Do not you know...
...that she is temperamental?
Who knows what she is after?
She is your sister, Gokce.
Do not turn your back on her
when she needs you the most.
-She needs her beloved ones behind her.
-Where was she when I needed her?
Do you know that?
Do you know that how
she walked over me...
...to became a wife of Bey
and sit in the tent, Halime?
You tell me first.
What were you supposed
to do with my sister?
Or do you want to do that
my sister could not do once?
Do you want to be the
wife of the marquee...
...and sway like you put on airs?
-Know your place, Gokce.
-What if I do not?
Do you think that I do not
know what you are doing?
You put a dagger on my throat in
my hardest, most desperate day.
You bandied about Ertugrul Bey's
words from one marquee to the other.
Mother Hayme was
like a mother to you.
She did not keep you separated
from her own children.
She put up with your bad manners
because of what happened to your father.
But I am neither your
mother nor your sister.
If you do one more mistake,
I will not forgive you.
Vanguard of Noyan was
dispersed by the raid we made.
It is possible that Noyan
asked for a reinforcing unit.
It is true that the bigger
attacks are waiting for us.
You are right, uncle.
After that he will
attack more harshly.
He will try to drive us from
these places by harassing us.
His reputation is shaken.
A person is defeated to his
own anger, not to a great army.
The weakness of such
man is their anger.
It is necessary to
excite his anger more.
Turkmen nomad groups
that he overrode...
...and also the non-Muslim
community of our Sultan...
...heard about the defeat
that we caused to Noyan.
The news about what we've done to Noyan's
curs has reached all the way to Konya.
People are very happy.
Fear of Mongolian left
its place for hope.
Thank God.
Noyan will do anything
to extinguish this hope.
You are right, Gumustekin Bey.
So; for this reason, while Noyan's
wound is still fresh...
...I want to beat him in his
den without we lose any more men.
Hamza gave me this opportunity. He will
learn where the cantonment of Noyan is.
He will complete Abdurrahman's
unfinished blessed job.
I agree with all of what you said.
But at least you could
tell this to us Gundogdu Bey.
Cousin, the Alp is my Alp.
And the duty is my duty.
I had to make an urgent
decision and I did it.
Both the sin and good dead are on me.
You thought right.
But I hope that Hamza
will not betray you again.
Uncle, let Hamza betray me again.
At least we know who the traitor is.
He will not stab us in
the back like Kocabash.
You attack to an injured man like a dog,
he must scare you a lot.
-What is your problem?
-This is not your business, Turkmen.
Kill him!
Tell me brother,
what do they want from you?
Do you not still trust us?
Help me.
They will kill them all.
My sheik, dervishes,
they will threat them all.
-For God's sake, please help.
-Who are they?
Why will they kill?
Tell me who are you?
They call me Ahi Evran.
I am a profession expert.
We were traveling with my master Kirmani.
I remained behind in order to deliver
a consignation to somebody.
My sheik is on the road.
Other part of these cruel
will kill him, too.
Who are they?
You know that they are cruel,
it is enough.
For God's sake! My sheik
is in shelter ahead.
We should catch him, brothers.
Come along Alps!
To the horses!
They say Sadettin Kopek
put someone on our tail.
Enemy never stops cheating,
we never stop being true.
Instead of speaking about cheating of
enemy, we should talk about truth, sons.
Now, immediately we should
get organized in each city.
If we do not improve lands
by science and economy...
...we cannot make this place our home.
We need men from all professions.
Each product we produce
will carry our stamp.
Each product is honor of his maker.
So, we need to raise a group of tradesmen
that are not doing any cheating.
This is the only way we can
get rid of dead soil on us.
We work hard and gain much,
we only use it for favor.
Do not forget sons, we will be
givers, not receivers.
Come along. Help yourself.
Nobody is here.
Be careful.
This way.
From now on, your tongue and body
will be useless.
Your eyes will work,
they will only see our victory.
Master!
Take care of wounded ones!
Master! Thanks to God.
We still have breathes to take, son.
Who are these valiants
that we owe our lives?
I am from Kayi tribe, Ertugrul,
son of Suleyman Shah.
-Who are you?
-I am from Kayseri region, Kirmani.
Tell me.
-Who is this?
-Selcan, wife of Gundogdu.
Are you trying to sell me the woman
that Gundogdu abandoned?
Noyan, Gundogdu will not leave her.
If Gundogdu will not come for her,
I will feed my dogs with you.
I hope your cave will collapse on you.
Are you Noyan, Mongolian cur?
This is not Kayi nomad group
that you rule.
Take this treacherous away!
Let me go!
Dishonest!
You were asking about Hamza, Noyan.
Look, I brought him too.
Come here my loyal Alp.
Hamza, how fool you, Turks, are?
Anyone can escape from your nomad group.
First Abdurrahman, now you.
Who will be tomorrow, we will see.
Why do you think I fight for you, Tangut?
Then escaping was not hard
for you at all, Hamza.
Tell me Hamza.
How you escaped, I wonder.
I sold out Efrasiyab.
I told Gundogdu that
Efrasiyab is a traitor.
I said I am ashamed of what I have done
to my nomad group, I feel guilty.
I said give me a last chance so that
I can bring head of Noyan to you.
Gundogdu believed me like a fool.
Now he waits for your head with all eyes.
Well done Hamza.
You did what was expected
from you. Well done.
Look at that woman. I would not
wish it on worst enemy.
Even devil may fear of her.
I also have a gift for you, Noyan.
Above all.
He is cur of Gundogdu.
He put him on tail of Efrasiyab.
So smart boy Gundogdu did not trust
you and put him on tail of Efrasiyab.
Dervish, give it to someone
to pick up fresh ones.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
-Go now.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Thank you, Artuk Bey.
How is your health? I hope you are good.
It is good Artuk Bey.
Thank to you I got over it.
-You saved my life.
-It does not matter, Bey.
We have not done anything.
It is God gave you health,
we just delivered it.
So you have more days to see, Bey.
Thank you, Artuk Bey.
Ertugrul told me about you
before he left.
He said you know all the conditions.
He said you can trust to Artuk Bey.
Thank you, Bey.
We lost enough time.
I want to be on road for my duty.
I informed white-bearded
about conditions, Bey.
After healing, we can be on road.
They wait for you with
seal of Oghuz Khan.
-Then, we go to road by tomorrow.
-As you wish, Bey.
Cur of Gundogdu!
You are a lucky man!
I would separate your head from
your body but you are auspicious.
What are you thinking, Noyan?
So Gundogdu declared war against us,
we will give response to him!
Now, listen to me carefully!
Listen, so that you go and
tell Gundogdu what I said!
Oh Selcan Hatun, oh!
Where are you again?
Who are the ones that ambushed you?
While human is in the right way
there are many devils after him, son.
Just a devil tried to trip us.
Like I might be afraid of death
as an old man.
Why did they want to kill you?
Because son, by killing us...
...they want to destroy Turkish-islamic
guild we formed in Anatolia.
I have never heard of
this organization before.
What is your duty?
Our purpose is to raise good tradesmen...
...that will bring halal income
to these lands.
I completed my duty. I have been
living in Kayseri for years.
Now, I am going back to Baghdad,
place I born.
I put my groom, Ahi Evran
to head of this organization.
From now on, it will be mentioned
with his name.
What is your purpose exactly?
Son, if you do not develop places...
...you gained with good tradesmen...
...it means this Turkish-Islamic guild
remains incomplete.
Unfortunately while we were kept away
from trade, occupational activities...
...cruel that got into it
had good profits.
They want to control people with lucre
that they cannot beat with sword.
How someone can beat someone with lucre
that cannot be beaten by sword, Bey?
My dear young sons.
They make it very well
and you cannot even notice it.
If a nation cannot raise its own traders
masters, they will always be lowly.
So, sons of this nation will work hard,
gain much and compete with each other.
But master, why does someone
fight for a lucre?
Eventually, this is an ephemeral world.
My dear son, is not it the idea
that makes us lowly?
We cannot say it is transitory life
and remain out of trading and be lazy.
Never!
First of all, was not our Prophet,
our guide a tradesman?
He raised within trading
since his childhood.
He worked for his halal food
in many caravans.
We will earn, yes, but we will not be
slave of what we earned!
We will give what we earned to the poor.
Well said.
You lightened us.
We travel everywhere...
...but we did not effort on
raising our masters...
...and trading as much as
we did in wars.
I memorized your words.
One day if I have a seignior...
...I will raise many masters and traders.
Thank you, valiant man.
We owe you a life.
Know that from now on
first my groom Ahi Evran...
...and all Turkish-Islamic guild
will be with you.
Know that from now on wherever son of
Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul Bey goes...
...they will always be with
Turkish-Islamic guild.
Thank you.
It should be a wedding, that looks
good on both Kayi and Dodurga.
Two marquees will have
two brides and two grooms.
We need to invite all Beys of
nomad groups that are around us.
Joy of double wedding should reach
to all tribes of Oghuz.
What do you say, brother?
We will do what Beys want
for my unique daughter.
This is my happiest day.
I have a valiant son like Gundogdu.
Thank you, Bey, thank you.
Halime Sultan, you pull a long face.
What is happening?
I have not seen Selcan Hatun
all day long, Bey.
I feel worried because of this.
When I came wounded, I know that
she was always watching me.
But I have not seen her
since the time I recovered.
Last time I saw her before dinner.
Then I have not seen her.
It bothers me, Bey.
What Tugtekin son and
Gokce daughter say to this?
How our beys want it,
alright for us Mother Hayme.
Mother Hayme, with your permission.
Dumrul Alp arrived.
He wants to see Gundogdu Bey.
Send him inside.
-Dumrul!
-Bey.
What happened?
Noyan.
What about Noyan?
Talk to me, man, what about Noyan?
Noyan kidnapped Selcan Hatun, bey.
Dumrul, what are you saying, son?
How can they kidnap my daughter,
wife of Bey from nomad group?
Tell me, how did it happen?
I was following caravan of Efrasiyab.
Tangut caught me.
They blindfolded me and took me to a cave.
Selcan Hatun was in caravan too, bey.
Noyan preferred to send a message
to you, instead of killing my, Bey.
Send what?
What message, tell me!
What does this Noyan centipede
wants from my daughter?
Noyan wanted me to deliver a message...
...but only to Gundogdu Bey,
Mother Hayme.
Come with me!
Mother.
Come mother.
Tell me what does cur Noyan want?
He will come to Gehenna Valley alone
only with Selcan Hatun.
What does he want from me
as return to Selcan?
He wants a consignation
that Sungurtekin has.
-What consignation?
-He did not tell me, Bey.
He only said that you should take it
and go to Gehenna Valley.
He told me that if you will not come
alone, he will kill Selcan Hatun.
Do not tell anyone about it, understood?
Go.
Son, what does this cur Noyan
want from you?
He wants a consignation
that Sungurtekin has, mother.
I have nothing to give to this dishonest
man, except my life, brother.
Your brother Sungurtekin?
I know Noyan hates him, bey.
He trusted him once, helped him
to raise with Ogeday...
...and then Sungurtekin became
spy of Sultan Aladdin.
I know Mongolians do not take prisoners.
How did they take you, Sungurtekin Bey?
Because I know a lot about horses.
I watched horses of Genghis Khan
for years.
Sungur!
You are like your brother Ertugrul,
Sungur.
You are like a tree that draws
a thunderbolt in a plain valley.
You did not terminate suffer
you cause on us on your returns...
...brought new ones instead.
-Brother...
-Do not say it!
Do not say it, Sungur!
Gundogdu!
Gundogdu. I was not able to
be a good wife for you again.
You were about to find peace
I caused trouble again.
I turned your world into black.
If God permits you give
your blessing to me, Bey.
However, death is the best for me.
A life without you is death to me.
Oh Selcan!
Such a bad fate you have.
You are woman of such great examinations.
Your existence is trouble,
your absence is grief.
If something happens to you...
Snake!
Do not get close to me.
I swear, I kill you.
My favorite two smells,
blood and woman.
Noyan!
If it is understood that
you got close to her...
...Gundogdu will not give you the seal.
I will not sacrifice you now.
You still have time.
Ulubilge!
Animal!
Brother.
Your fire of love just reappeared, right?
Look at me Bamsi,
if you say one more word!
What are you going to do brother,
are you going to kick me?
Brother, in the part you hit,
roses will grow.
Go on, if you feel
relieved brother, go on.
Dogan, sit down.
I said, sit!
Come.
Sit here.
You look like a rotor, fell in a bougie.
Yes, brother.
Neither rotor nor legs remained.
Bamsi!
If I talk again, I am a Mongolian cur.
Is the matter Banu Cicek?
-Is it a secret?
-Yes, it is.
Alright, then.
Keep your secret to yourself.
But, talk with us please.
Look brother, we have a long way.
But with condition of you,
road will never ends.
I am sorry brothers.
Tell us, what happened?
Banu Cicek have been saying it constantly.
Fate brought to nomad groups together.
Means it brought me to Banu Cicek.
But now...
What happened? Tell us.
When I went to see her...
...while my heart expects
a nice conversation...
Did Selcan Hatun send you here?
...my throat felt cold of
her dagger, brothers.
Come along!
Each route I go, each range I arrive
open me new doors.
Each opened door invites me
to new adventures.
Crazy horses, riding within my soul
big fires burn my heart...
...tell me, what is at the end
of this battle?
Why these pains will be obtunded?
Ibn-i Arabi, the white-bearded,
Kirmani and Ahi Evran.
Why these servants of you meet
with poor people?
There must be a reason for sure.
Dear God, do not leave me to my desire.
Meet me with your servants.
Have mercy on me.
There is no one left in this nomad group
that he has not threated.
My sons, daughter, myself.
I will not let it, as Gundogdu does.
Together we will take care
of this dishonest cur!
While your nomad group
marquee of your father...
...face with such a threat like that...
...you still want to go, Sungurtekin?
Mother, I want to...
If you go before head of Noyan
is sticked to pole...
...I will not give my blessing to you!
From now on...
...all people lives in this marquee...
...member of this nomad group
will dedicate...
...theirs to the war against Noyan!
Noyan will die!
Know it very well...
...before he dies...
...we are not foreseen as alive.
Mother Hayme, people of Dodurga
and Tugtekin will do anything...
...they can in order to save my sister.
If God permits you are right, Gokce.
What are you trying to say?
God's sake, if something
happens to Selcan...
I know so many people
that might be happy for it.
Especially in marquee of Korkut Bey.
Enough!
Such factiousness is this!
How can you say it in a day like this?
Mother!
Bring your bride into line.
Do it, if not I will cause an accident.
Enough, shut up now, both of you!
Shut up!
Sungurtekin obviously hides
what Noyan wants.
Even if Sungurtekin gives Noyan
what he wants...
...after Noyan gets what he wants...
...he will not let Selcan Hatun
and Gundogdu Bey live.
We cannot let Gundogdu Bey
come under ambush.
He should not risk his life
for Selcan Hatun.
He will go, Gundogdu I know would go.
We need to prevent it.
If he decides and do it...
...he will seek help from you.
Do not destroy you and Goncagul's home
before you have it, son.
Do not sacrifice yourself
for this ignoble woman.
Make him change his decision tomorrow.
Noyan will want to have his reputation
back that he lost with our attack.
This is the reason why he batted Selcan.
Do not come under ambush like good hearted
Gundogdu Bey does, Tugtekin.
I do not want to lose
my son Gundogdu and you.
This woman was the biggest obstacle
in front of your home, son.
Do not dare to go.
Let him drown in his own dirt.
Why Gundogdu has not come still?
Women, leave us alone.
I will talk with Sungurtekin and mother.
Give me consignation Noyan wants, Sungur.
I will bring you both your consignation
and Selcan sister.
I cannot do it, brother.
What does it mean, son?
Is this consignation more valuable
than your sister...
...is this the reason you say it?
I cannot do it, mother.
It is all.
If my brother orders,
I go and fight for my sister...
...give me life for her.
But do not want what I have.
Is there a contact with your unwilling...
...for giving consignation and being
spy of Sultan Aladdin, brother?
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
Is it true, Sungurtekin?
His eyes say it is true, mother.
So this is a matter of state,
secret of state.
Grooming horses of Genghis Khan
was not true also, right?
Where is Ertugrul in this matter?
Know that both me and Ertugrul...
...will not leave Oghuz Tribe
to Mongolian Curs and Crusader Army!
There is nothing beyond it!
Even if you give me this
consignation or not...
...I will go and save Selcan, Sungur.
Brother, let me come with you.
Give this consignation to your brother.
I cannot leave my daughter
to sword of Noyan.
Mother.
Suleyman Shah...
...never let anybody to death
while he was ruling this marquee.
I will not abandon as well.
Know it in this way, son.
Sungur, I swear, I will bring you back...
...your consignation and your sister.
Come along.
It is stolen, brother.
What are you saying, Sungur?
When I was wounded, Ertugrul took it
from hands of Noyan.
Brought it to me.
Seal was inside of carpetbag.
I hided carpetbeg under my pillow.
What is happening, mother?
Who can leak to marquee of Bey
and stole a secret of state?
Besides, who knows secret of this seal?
Someone connected with Noyan.
So have not eradicated
traitors yet, mother.
They can reach to our marquee even.
If I find who did this,
I will kill by my own hands.
As punish as a warning to others,
I will not take body down for months!
I know that I will go to place
Noyan wants...
...will take Selcan and kill him.
Without seal, you cannot
go there, brother.
Sungur, God's sake brother,
tell me what is this seal?
-Peace be with you.
-And peace be with you, Bey.
-Welcome, my Bey.
-Thanks.
-Is he still unconscious?
-He is unconscious, Bey.
But he will recover, if God permits.
If God permits.
Then we want to take your advice
about one thing, Bey.
Yes, my Bey.
We need a seal, can you do it?
Seal of Oghuz Khan.
I can do it, but before I do,
I need to see it Bey.
I cannot do anything without seeing it.
Artuk Bey, seal is missing.
I can draw the seal.
Great, my Bey.
Come along and draw the seal.
-Welcome, Gokce.
-Thank you, Bey.
Since last night I could not sleep.
If something happens to my sister
I will be grieved.
In spite of everything, she is my sister.
Tugtekin.
I am begging you, help saving my sister.
Do not leave my brother Gundogdu.
I am begging you.
We should hope for the best, Gokce.
We should hope for the best.
With God's help, I can prepare it
for tomorrow, Bey.
-If God permits.
Which one of you made this food?
This poor one, master.
You have potential of Ahi-order, son.
Everybody cannot make donut.
May God bless you.
I am good at eating meals, Bey.
Do I have potential of Ahi-order?
Bread is the staff of life, son.
Eating is also business of adults.
Our horses are ready, sheik.
We can be on the road anytime you want.
Have a good trip brothers.
-Have a good trip.
Come along. We need to be on the road.
Come on.
Do not forget to pray for us.
You got the pray of Ibn Arabi, son.
All we can do is just to say, amen.
In the region you go,
there is Mahmut Dervish.
Your routes will across with him.
He is a dervish with knowledge.
Share his food.
You have a long way to go,
always be prepared.
-Thank you.
Hayme.
As you also know,
Noyan will not let them live.
When we assigned Gundogdu Bey
as head of Alps, we trusted him.
Now, it is time to show it.
Mother Hayme.
Without wild one you cannot battle
or take a decision, Beys.
I came to say, whatever you do,
I contribute.
Welcome, master.
Hayme Hatun, we know that Selcan is
like your daughter, as Gokce Hatun.
Although betray of their father...
...you raised these two girls...
...innocent ones with mercy.
But the matter is not being a mother.
If something happens to our
head of Alps Gundogdu Bey...
...both nomad groups will be damaged.
What are we for, Gumustekin Bey?
Do you plan to leave him alone?
Of course we will not.
But I say, we should send other Alps
instead of Gundogdu Bey.
They should go with whatever
Noyan wants from Sungurtekin.
Why Noyan wants specifically Gundogdu Bey?
Obviously he is into something.
I will go and take Selcan Hatun
from Noyan.
I am not going to
leave my wife to a man...
...that is out of control to leak
him men...
...to our nomad group and
martyr our girls, women.
Of course he will pay for it.
Obviously, you took consignation
that Noyan wants from Sungurtekin.
Now I am asking...
...is he going to give you Selcan Hatun...
...when you give him
what he wants, Gundogdu?
I do not know if he does it
with his own wish or not.
But if he does not, I will rip it of
with my teeth if necessary.
Now, who is with me?
You also, do not go.
Noyan does not have his old power,
while we have weakened him...
...we should send our other Alps.
What do you say, son?
Who else is with me?
We will go and bring Selcan Hatun back,
brother Gundogdu.
Are you ready, woman?
Yes, Hamza.
You have proven that you are a loyal
and valiant warrior once again.
There were times,
I have doubted about you.
But you deceived me.
You did not back-stab me.
I was always with you, Noyan.
But your suspicion did not hurt me.
I would be like Abdurrahman.
I ask for another help from you, Hamza.
Even kids know that Gundogdu
will not come alone.
We should be prepared.
What are you thinking?
Take soldiers with you and position them
within Cehennem Valley.
When Gundogdu comes, wait for my cue.
Kill whoever is with or around him.
Do not worry, Noyan.
Do not worry.
-Did you manage to finish, Artuk Bey?
-Yes, I did, Bey.
-How it is?
-Praise be.
It works, good.
-Thank you, Bey.
I hope it helps.
Bring Selcan Hatun back with no harm.
If God permits.
With name of God.
With the name of God.
Greetings from assigned Artuk
to white-bearded...
...that forms and destroys states.
Seal of Oghuz Khan came to nomad tent
with Sungurtekin.
But it was lost in nomad tent.
They will go to take Selcan Hatun
with Tugtekin.
What are you saying, brother?
We just talked about it last night.
Fool Tugtekin still wants to be a hero.
Things we talked just passed
over his head.
He could not manage to say no to Gundogdu.
How is it going to happen?
We have the seal Noyan wants.
Does he go to die.
Maybe death of Gundogdu and Tugtekin
will suit our book.
Obviously they both are arrogant
and fool not to hear what we say.
If they die...
...only Ertugrul and Korkut left.
Maybe this will be better.
If Noyan is into this seal...
...it means that Sadettin Kopek
is in my hands.
Alps are ready, Bey. They wait for you
at the entrance of nomad tent.
We will go from stream bed, not to
let them notice us if they watch.
Yes, my Bey.
May God give you power, Bey.
May God send help to you.
You gave me top of world by
going to battle for my sister.
May God keep you blessed in both worlds.
Thank you, Gokce. Thank you.
Go and bring your wife, son.
Master Demir, stay here with my mother.
Bey, how can I leave you alone?
My mother needs you more than
we do, master.
Alright, Bey. Alright.
As you ordered,
we wait for bed stream, Bey.
You start to move, I will catch you later.
I have no right to say
you not to go Bey, I know.
But do not go.
I have no right to say you to be a coward.
But be brave and do not go, Bey.
If something happens to you,
I cannot stand.
Goncagul Hatun, breathe of Azrael
is always on us.
Either today or tomorrow.
May God speed you, Bey.
Thank you.
Gumustekin, Aytolun, Goncagul.
They all want to unite and
put us into a disaster.
The main purpose of this gorgon Goncagul
is not Gundogdu Bey, Halime.
They all want only one thing.
They want consignation of Suleyman Shah.
They want to settle to Dodurga marquee
first and then Kayi marquee.
Come, Banu Cicek.
I broke heart of Selcan Hatun.
What will I do if something
happens to her?
Do not worry.
Gundogdu Bey will bring Selcan Hatun
back to nomad tent with no harm.
-You say so, Halime Hatun?
-Of course.
Do not bother, you did not do
anything wrong.
If you think the thing you did was wrong
it is not nonrecoverable.
Look, Banu Cicek.
Go to marquee and find necklace.
You will see when you find all troubles
will be solved one by one.
First day on our road was
very plenteous, Alps.
In this moorland we come out
of each stone, Bey.
We will see which stone will be upon us.
Stones should remain solid, brother.
Bey, what have you put inside
of this carpetbag, stone?
He lost his mind because of love...
...now power and luster of these men
are also gone.
My Bey!
What happened, brother?
-My Bey.
-What is happening, Dogan?
So Master Kirmani meant this
by saying "be provident".
If they get into our marquee
and get what they want...
...it is our duty to find them.
If not, we all be destroyed.
Mother, if people hears about it
results will be worse.
We should consider people...
...we think they are suspect,
before they hear it.
What are you saying, daughter?
Do you know something?
Whoever did it...
...it is someone that can enter and leave
to our marquee without hesitation.
I am talking about Gokce, mother.
I know you raised her.
But Gokce bandy about things spoken
in this marquee.
She is the responsible of things
happened to Ertugrul Bey.
Besides, she is not alone, mother.
What are you saying?
Gokce is not aware that she is being
a part of tricks of Goncagul and Aytolun.
Halime, what do you know
and do not tell me?
Tell me!
Mother, Goncagul will become wife
of Gundogdu Bey. I respect to that.
But things I have seen and heard
keeps me away from being silent.
In the night we had dinner together
in marquee...
...I saw Goncagul and Gokce, entering
to marquee of Sungurtekin Bey.
Do you think that Gundogdu Bey
will let you get away with this?
will stay alive for another day?
It is obvious that you are offended
with what Ertugrul Bey did to you.
You seem to have no idea what you are
doing since you appeal to traitors.
But my Gundogdu will come.
He will feed hungry animals
with your dirty carrion
in this wild place.
Everybody's turn will come. Everybody's.
First Gundogdu and then Ertugrul will die.
But before them all, you will die!
Tangut.
You go and take care of Hamza.
Listen to me!
Everybody hide.
Do not move until I order you to.
Is that understood?
-When will Noyan come?
-You will see him when he comes.
While my brother Gundogdu is saving
Selcan Hatun, we should not idle.
We must find the seal.
Since Efrasiyab did not take it,
the seal is still in the nomad tent.
You are right, Bey.
But who else knows the secret
of the seal in the nomad group?
You know this nomad group better
than me, Artuk Bey.
Do you suspect someone, Bey?
Tell me, Bey, who do you suspect?
There is no such person.
But the person who stole the seal is
not the man of the Mongolians for sure.
Nobody knows the secret of the seal except
the inner circle of Sultan Alaeddin.
Dear God.
Protect our children and our nomad groups
from any kind of evil.
Do not withhold your help from us.
Do not give up on us, God.
We do not have anyone else but You.
No one else but You can protect us from
the betrayal in our marquee.
Help us, God.
What are you saying, Hayme?
The betrayal is not only
in our nomad group, brother.
It also entered our marquee.
We do not know who to trust.
Every day we are shaken by a new betrayal.
What is it that make you tell these?
We cleaned our nomad groups
from all traitors now.
I also thought like you when Ertugrul
beheaded Kocabash.
But I was wrong.
Traitors are still running wild
in our nomad group.
A very valuable thing that Noyan wants to
have so badly, but belongs to...
...Sungurtekin has been stolen from my
marquee, brother.
Who does that? How could this happen?
I do not know.
There are traitors...
...in our nomad group,
...among us, in our marquee and our
family, who are betraying us.
Come here the smart boy
of the nomad group.
Come here.
So Noyan?
In which den you have lived in
after your home demolished?
Mountains and stones are my dens,
you smart boy.
I heard that you have a second wife.
Thus I thought you would not come but
you turned out to be a man of honor.
You did not forget about your first wife.
Cut it short. Send the woman.
First I want to see the seal.
The time of fulfilling your longing is up.
Hamza!
Bray slowly, Noyan.
Be a little quiet.