Episode 49 will start after 12:27 min .
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
I will not let the ones who follow
Ameer Sadettin Kopek's way...
...to reach into my mother's marquee.
It is my duty to cut those hands.
I wanted you to know.
I am the representative of
Emir Saadettin here.
Every word that is been told about him,
is meant for me as well.
Then you are blaming me as well,
are you not?
Ertugrul!
What kind of training is this?
Your brother's tongue is as strong
as his wrist, Gundogdu Bey.
What are you getting at Gumustekin Bey?
Your brother blames both
Emir Saadettin and me.
Allegedly, I stole the seal from your
mother's tent with this command.
How can you behave like this, brother?
We have enough problems
in our marquee as it is...
...now you are bothering Emir's of state?
I say, somebody following
Ameer Sadettin stole the seal.
A servant of his,
living in our nomad tent.
Then, either my hand or your tongue
will be cut down.
So that this unrest between us
will soothe, Ertugrul Bey.
Gumustekin Bey?
What is this sinister woman going behind?
Get yourself together Selcan.
You did the right thing.
Whatever happens to you, let it happen
while walking on the right way.
Instead of letting the bushes
of the wrong way...
...let the stones of the right way
prick your feet.
Selcan Hatun.
I told everything to Korkut Bey.
Do not worry.
He does not know about you.
Even if he knows, do you think I care?
I am ready to do what you will ask of me.
Even as a kid, you were always so brave.
We will wait what Korkut Bey will do.
Now, go away.
Whatever happens, do not tell
anything to anyone.
It is high time, Banu Cicek.
The chain will brake at the weak point.
When that happens, I do not wish anyone
other than me to be harmed by it.
I will let nothing happen to you.
If anything happens to me,
you will carry the flag.
There is no need for all of us to get
the dirty end of the stick.
Now go. It will happen as the way
it is meant to be.
What do you think you are doing, Ertugrul?
How could you say such a thing
to Gumustekin?
How could you blame Gumustekin
for treason and theft?
Gundogdu, what is happening?
My brother Ertugrul sharpened his tongue.
He sharpened so that he can try and
cut Gumustekin's head when the time comes!
Ertugrul. Son, what is happening?
I know why the seal was stolen, mother.
Do you think Gumustekin did that?
My brother, at the training area,
in the presence of so many Alps
held his sword against Gumustekin's neck!
Mother, held his sword against his neck!
The night it was stolen...
...only you two knew that the Sungurtekin
has the seal.
How is it possible for Gumustekin
to know that there is a seal...
...so he came in and stole it
from our marquee?
Ameer Sadettin also knew that, mother.
Are you thinking the same thing, Sungur?
Do you agree with Ertugrul?
Gumustekin went his ways to stole the seal
and gave it to Ameer Sadettin Kopek...
...and then he gave it to Tankut!
Is that right?
Yes, it is.
My God! My Maker! Spare my mind!
My brother, do you have any proof,
any evidence?
You do not only accuse Gumustekin
but his Holliness Sadettin Kopek as well!
I do not have any evidence yet, brother.
But sooner or later,
I will get that as well.
You will! You will!
While we are scorching
in the desert of pain...
...I have found an oasis
like Goncagul for myself...
...and you ruined that as well!
My brother, are you aware that
the man you accuse is the father...
...of the woman who is to be my wife!
There are things that I know, brother.
Brother, what are those things you know?
Tell us! Tell us and make us aware!
Tell mother! Let mother know as well!
I am done talking.
Done talking?
Done talking!
The mysterious act that you have been
playing for so long...
...made me tired brother,
you should know that.
Not only yours, Sungur's as well.
I do not know who are those that
you consort with.
However, the ones you consort with...
...made you act like this,
you should know that.
From now on, no truth will hide itself
in nooks and crannies, brother.
-I will go to any lengths.
-Go brother.
Go wherever you wish to go.
Go to the uttermost end of hell, Ertugrul.
Gundogdu!
I repent! May God forgive.
Done talking! Look what he said!
Instead of coming and talking to me
at first, talking to his mother first!
Good God!
He held his sword against that man's neck
in the presence of the Alps, mother!
How can this be?
Shame on him! What a shame!
Brother, just be patient.
Ertugrul may be right.
My God, brother! What does it mean
he may be right?
What if he is not?
This is what we are fighting for!
Vandalizing is not the way to do it!
I have told him a thousand times!
What will I do?
I have just seen Selcan.
She left our marquee.
What does she want from you, Bey?
She spilled out the beans in her mouth.
Her evil reverberates on that
woman's tongue.
What else would we expect from her?
She told me that she knew what happened
between you and me before Duru died!
That vixen wants to hinder
Goncagul's marriage!
She can tell every possible lie.
Did she tell you anything else, Bey?
If what happened between us before,
my wife died reaches Tugtekin's ears...
...how can I look at my son's face
with this shame?
Father.
As Ertugrul was training, he held his
sword against Gumustekin's throat.
Then, Gundogdu separated them.
Can you understand what is happening?
We will see, Ertugrul is the one
behind this as well.
Know your enemies. Take your measures
or it will be too late.
What does my mother say, father?
What is happening?
What is it that related with Ertugrul?
Ertugrul will pay the price for this!
I will choke him on his own words!
Whoever comes at my way in this cause,
I will not stop without smashing them!
Brother!
Are you alright? I heard what happened.
I am not alright, Aytolun.
Ertugrul knows more than I thought.
He called me on the account for the seal!
Me!
There is more, brother.
Selcan came to talk to Korkut.
Aunt, what are you saying?
Your threats with the necklace will
not work anymore, Goncagul.
She will spit her poison slowly.
Who else did the sinister woman talk to?
I followed her after she left our marquee.
I saw Banu Cicek leaving her tent.
Apparently, she wants to use
Banu Cicek's love for Duru Hatun.
-What did she tell to Korkut Bey?
-I talked to Korkut.
Selcan told him that she knows...
...what happened between me and Korkut
before Duru Hatun died.
How could this happen?
What if she knows more?
It is impossible for her to know
how Duru died.
Korkut sent Selcan away.
What scares Korkut the most
is the possibility...
...of someone telling Tugtekin
about the matter.
This matter has gone too far.
How far will it strech like this?
There is no peace for any of us
until Korkut dies.
Instead of waiting for the wedding,
let us finish the job.
Tugtekin and Gokce must get married.
We cannot let this matter drag any longer.
-Did you tell him everything, Selcan?
-Everything.
What he say?
He dismissed me. People learning
his intimacy drove him crazy.
He is scared, thinking;
what if Tugtekin hears about this?
Because of this, his hands are tied.
What about Duru Hatun's death?
He will soothe himself for some time
thinking I made it up...
...as I am jealous of Goncagul.
However, I have sown the seeds of doubt
to him once. It will devour him.
Let us see when he will face Aytolun
and talk to her.
I did what I could do, Halime.
The rest is Korkut Bey's duty.
I will come back as a Margrave from Konya.
That time in marquee,
Tugtekin must be the one sitting...
...not the old man.
Ertugrul and Selcan.
What if they act together?
Even if it is not so right now,
sooner or later that will also happen.
Apparently, the tongue of that woman
will not stay silent.
The gauntlet has been thrown.
So what are we gonna do now, father?
Gundogdu's reins must be kept tightened.
He is worried about you.
He is afraid to lose you.
I will do my best fuel Gundogdu's anger
towards Ertugrul.
If I can succeed, I will send his mother
on him as well.
You sound out that girl called Banu Cicek.
Let us see what she keeps as a secret.
Selcan, look at me. Look, sister.
I have been there for you
and did what I could.
But I have to tell Ertugrul Bey
what happened.
I never kept anything from him, Selcan.
Please understand.
Halime, if you tell him now
Aytolun and Goncagul will come up
like a wood in water.
You know that I do not have anything
but my necklace to prove what I said.
I am begging you to wait a little longer.
Wait until Gokce's wedding.
I know if Korkut Bey has a little
bit of conscience
he will go after and take care
of this matter himself.
However, if Ertugrul Bey hears about it
no one can know who this filthy swamp
will devour.
Your services to the Bey are
worthy of esteem, Banu Cicek.
They befit to a Dodurga Hatun.
However, I think a girl as skillful as you
will provide more valuable services.
Comparing to what Korkut Bey
and Duru Hatun did for me
these are nothing, Aytolun Hatun.
You loved the deceased, did you not?
Of course, I did.
I did love her deeply.
However, she died without any sickness.
It still hurts my heart.
You can never know when will
death come for you, Banu Cicek.
Yesterday, Duru Hatun.
Tomorrow, us.
Like death, you can never know
whose hands will it come from!
May God protect us from
those sinister hands.
I will take my leave then, Hanim.
Your death will come from my hands.
This matter will go as
far as it can, Ertugrul.
If it will not, it will be a burden
to you, to my mother and our marquee.
However, this is not the issue.
The issue is Gundogdu Bey.
The man whose throat you shoved down,
will be Gundogdu Bey's father in law soon.
Goncagul and his wedding is soon.
When we bear this doubt inside
will we take her daughter
in our marquee Halime?
Goncagul can be innocent as she is.
As long as this doubt exists, the home
they will build will not be worthy.
Do not forget that this doubt
only belongs to the people
who believe in you, Ertugrul Bey.
My mother's marquee is not
a regular tent, Halime.
Those people who get inside of my mother's
marquee in secret yesterday
can do anything without us noticing it,
when they have the chance.
What about Goncagul and Gundogdu Bey's
wedding, Ertugrul Bey?
This is not a heart matter.
It is about Kayi's future.
It is my duty to stop this wedding,
if necessary.
That direful man.
Permisson, Gumustekin Bey?
Come in, Gundogdu Bey.
Thinking about what happened
brings me sadness, Bey.
He disobeyed the law and put me to shame.
He disgraced me by ignoring the rules
of the training in the presence
of the Alps.
Yet it did not satisfy him, he went ahead
and held his sword agains my throat
in the presence of everyone.
He still did not get satistied
then he cast aspersions on me
and disregarded my honor.
Not just you, even the whole
world feels sadness
does it make any difference, Gundogdu Bey?
Your mother interrogated my daughter
recently, for that ominous deposit.
And today, your brother.
Being so clever, he came at me
to test the water.
He thought he could wangle words
out of me by teasing me.
What a shame.
Please do not, Bey.
There must be a way to correct this.
To correct what, Gundogdu Bey?
Correct what?
From now on, there will be no wedding
for you with my daughter.
Do not come into my tent again, unless you
solve this matter between yourselves.
It is nothing, Dogan Alp.
I cut my hand.
It may be a deep wound,
you need to dress it.
Wait.
I will help.
You must press on it like this,
so that it will not bleed more.
Thank you.
It would not hurt this much
if it was my own hand.
A person bleeds to his lover, Dogan Alp.
Duru Hatun could not see Tugtekin Bey
come together with his lover.
I wish these would not happen.
If you will excuse me.
Who is the human, Efendi?
Human is the seal of God on earth.
Trees, birds, plants, oceans, rivers.
Why are they here?
Why does the moon beautify the night?
Why does the sun warm up the world?
Why does the ocean swing like a cradle?
Why the river flows?
Why does the sun rise?
Why does the risen sun set?
All for the human.
All the beauty in the universe,
all this show
all this preperation are
only for the humans.
For human to come alive.
For the human to have peace.
For the human to be grateful.
But the human is ungrateful.
He looks but he can not see.
He hears but he can not feel.
If this one breath was not here,
human would fall.
He falls but can not see the truth.
He will not remember God.
He thinks he owns the power.
May God make us of the grateful ones.
Amen.
-Peace be with you.
-And with you.
Beautiful person, brave person.
Tell me about the places you have been.
Gundogdu.
This is the end, mother.
What is happening my son?
My brother Ertugrul has returned from
his voyage with one more victory.
What voyage?
The voyage of overpowering Gumustekin Bey.
Did you speak with Gumustekin?
And his victory was to stain his brother's
honor and to break his wedding.
Gundogdu, every cloud has a silver lining.
You must be patient.
Selcan has made Banu Cicek's
head swim, brother.
You must see how she looks at me
with hatred.
How are we going to get through this?
Everyone will hear about it.
Korkut must die in the presence
of his Alps.
His killer must be executed right there.
His killer?
Banu Cicek.
If that poor girl who was confused
by Selcan's accusations
and slander to kill Korkut
we will kill three birds with one stone.
But, how are we going to convince people
to this sham?
Begin the preparation of
a poison right away.
As you wish.
I will ask for one more sacrifice, sister.
I set my mind on this blessed road
with you until death, brother.
Tell me what is it that you wish me to do.
You will drink that poison as well.
Do not worry, do not worry.
Artuk will save you from
the cold hands of death.
Just like he did to Korkut many times.
It will be seen as Banu Cicek has
both Korkut and you as her targets.
As you see Efendi, Byzantine has
became unfamiliar to his own public.
You have met with new people
and new places.
You have appealed to them with your heart.
You reminded them of their humanity.
And they reminded me that there are
a lot of opressed people
who need justice on the earth's surface.
-You are right.
Once upon a time, polytheists from Mecca
also forgot about their humanity
and buried their daughters alive.
Our prophet, with the God's grace
told them about the secrets of being human
so the world became peaceful.
What was that secret?
"God is one and only and Muhammed
is his messenger."
You can not reach the secret of being
human without knowing God first.
What about the people who say
they are Muslim but still cruel?
What about the ones
who fight over religion?
What about the ones who cooperate
with infidels and stab us in the back?
They are indeed the real cruels.
In our prophets last speech, he said,
"Arab is not better than Persian."
But they kill over religion.
They kill the Muslim.
How can a Muslim accuse another Muslim
of infidelity?
How can a Muslim kill a Muslim?
My God said in Fetih surah:
"Muhammad is the messenger of God.
Whoever is beside him
are strong against infidels
and are merciful among believers."
Son, if we want to serve the humanity,
we have to correct our home,
our nomad tent, our tribe, our city first.
You can not build anything on rotten soil.
We can not serve humanity
without cleaning our homes.
The hardest and toughest trial is coming
from our brothers, are they not?
Do not forget. The most cruel to our
prophet was his uncle, Ebu Leheb.
However, his pillar of support
was his cousin Ali.
May God give his followers
a fellow like Ali.
-Amen.
You son of Suleyman Shah, Ertugrul.
It is understood that you have
a new road coming up.
You must go to this road with the
most sincere and purest people.
So that you serve the best where you go.
Do not forget. Your site is your mirror.
When you look at them, see yourself
and when you look at yourself,
you see them.
This love is unbelievable.
He was like he got kicked by
a horse yesterday.
Now he is happy like a donkey
who found some hay.
It is love, brother.
It can make you a vizier or vile.
You are in love!
What did you say?
My brother. How did Bey get angry to shake
Gumustekin Bey like a pile of wool?
Whatever Ertugrul Bey did,
he did it on purpose.
Gumustekin Bey must have done something.
And Gundogdu Bey is in a hard situation.
On one side his brother
on the other side, his father-in-law.
What is going to happen
in the end, brother?
Whatever Ertugrul Bey wants
he will not stop until he gets it.
From now on, winds will bluster.
Gundogdu Bey will either give up
on his wife
or his brother.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
May happiness be with you.
-Thank you, Bey.
You brave child!
You will be an Alp just like
Wild Demir expected.
I see that you can even beat Dogan Alp.
All I want is to be an Alp
like you, Ertugrul Bey.
Grab us some ayran.
I have matters to discuss
with your big brothers.
Mother!
You suffered from each one of us
and you still do.
Even a stone would crack.
It comes after one another.
Son, it is not easy to be a mother.
A mother gives up on her own problems,
own pain.
But Ertugrul and Gundogdu
have problems between them.
It tears my heart out.
They share the same blood, they can
not be apart from one another, mother.
It is our duty to bring them back
together when the time comes.
However, if we can not take care of
Gumustekin matter, it will be difficult.
Are you sure about Gumustekin,
taking part in this matter?
Yes, mother.
Everyone knows about what happened
to Gumustekin on the training field, Bey.
Yes, Bey. God bless your hands.
The die has already been cast, Alps.
Gundogdu brother also supports him.
From now on, we are done with
Dodurgas and these soils.
We are going to Byzantine borders again.
However, we will not be alone this time.
We will go with whoever loves us,
believes in us, supports us.
They will force you. From today,
you must be strong.
You will be on good terms with people.
We will slowly try to convince them
for this blessed migration.
-Thank you, Bey.
Abdurrahman.
I demand one thing from you as well.
We know the situation about the tents.
Things are chaotic.
I do not wish something to happen
to my mother.
Just like my father. You are responsible
for my mother's safety.
I lay down my life for Mother Hayme, Bey.
Do I have your permission, mother?
Come, my son, come.
Korkut Bey invites us to
their marquee, mother.
Gumustekin is with him.
Mother.
Are they our enemies?
Look.
Gumustekin Bey has swallowed his pride
and Korkut Bey invited us.
We must go.
Surely, we can solve this matter
with conversation.
This matter can only be solved
with one way, son.
Whoever stole the seal must come out.
Or neither me, nor anyone else,
no one can stop Ertugrul.
Let us go then.
If my brother called us,
we can not make him wait.
Everyone knows about the rules and
I am not the one who writes them.
I am a witness to all that happened.
Is it appropriate to do it
in the presence of everyone?
I ask you. His tongue is
as sharp as his sword.
Nobody can say anything to his bravery.
However, impertinence and measurelessness
of Ertugrul has only one reason.
The ominous passion of his
that he can not quench.
Of course, he has achieved
important progresses.
His reputation increased day by day
in Turkmen tribes and in the palace.
However, his ambition that he can not
restrain is getting bigger and bigger.
He no longer wants anyone
to be ahead of him.
Not his brother, not his mother.
There. We can see what
he did to Tugtekin Bey.
After all, this is the matter.
Unless someone teaches Ertugrul his lesson
he will continue bringing trouble to us!
Bey. Mother Hayme and her sons are here.
Bring them in.
Be seated.
You bring me joy by coming
here, Hayme Hatun.
We all know about the unpleasant incident
between Gumustekin Bey and Ertugrul Bey.
I think that it is not applicable for
these two youngsters to keep suffering
because of the words that were
told tactlessly, even though
it is known that they love and
set their hearts on each other.
That is why, I say this to Gumustekin Bey.
Keep Gundogdu Bey and Ertugrul Bey
apart from each other.
Do not upset your daughter
and Gundogdu Bey
who you love like a son any longer.
I am also happy for Hayme Hatun
to come here with her grace.
It is the outcome of the respect
that she feels for us, apparently.
As for my child, Gundogdu.
He will always be a brave son for me.
I saw the essence of his heart
when we went to raid that
Mongolian dog Noyan's house.
Every father of a girl would like
to see him as a son in law.
And I told him this, at every turn.
Thank you, Bey.
We know how much you love and respect
my mother and me.
We feel honored for this.
However, this marriage is a matter
between two Bey families.
Unless Ertugrul Bey comes to apologise
to me in person
it is improper to give my daughter to him.
Maybe it is inappropriate for me
to speak in front of elders.
But I would like to say something.
Tomorrow is the blessed day that
we were waiting so long for with Gokce.
We would not want that day
to be a sad one.
Tomorrow is our wedding day.
Maybe there is something else
to do, Gumustekin Bey.
Our son Tugtekin is right, brother.
Maybe you will think once more tonight.
We have a wedding tomorrow.
We should not be estranged from
each other on a day like this.
I left my daughter Goncagul
at home, in tears.
Do you think this is easy
for me, Korkut Bey?
Ertugrul Bey's words are
impossible to swallow.
Are they not, Sungurtekin Bey?
It is not seen that my brother Ertugrul
has ever made a mistake.
However, I hope that
he was wrong this time.
So you think like your brother,
Sungurtekin Bey?
What I think is not important,
Gumustekin Bey.
As you know
when Ertugrul wants something
nobody can stop him until he is done.
Hopefully, this matter will be solved soon
so you may be in peace.
I will perform your wedding
ceremony tomorrow.
And you shall think and decide.
We will see in time if what Ertugrul said
was true or not.
Gumustekin Bey is right.
This wedding is between Bey families
of two nomad groups.
If one of those families are not at ease
this marriage will be a reason
for unpleasantless.
We all know about the love
between youngsters.
When the situation is like this
I also am not complying
with this marriage
until the truth comes out.
If Ertugrul Bey hears about it
no one can know who this filthy swamp
will devour.
Welcome, Bey.
Where is my mother, Halime?
Korkut Bey called her to the marquee.
She went there with your brothers.
Korkut Bey wants to secure the peace.
Gumustekin is playing
a new trick for sure.
We will see what comes out of it.
How can you do this, mother?
How can you say something like that when
Gumustekin is swallowing his honour?
This is better, Gundogdu.
This wedding will not bring joy to us
unless whoever stole the seal comes out.
Thank you, mother. Thank you.
Are you happy my brother?
Your wish has come true.
You saved our nomad tent from trouble.
Obviously, mother also agrees.
I hope you are right about
this decision you made.
-Brother.
-Ertugrul.
Until now, I never listened to you my son
and you were always right.
I will listen to you in this matter.
Until the person who stole
the seal comes out
I will not let Gundogdu and Goncagul
get married.
However, if you are wrong
I do not know how can we face them.
Gokce has her wedding tomorrow.
I do not want any more trouble.
Do you understand me?
I understand, mother.
Good.
Gundogdu Bey.
My father and Mother Hayme believes
in Ertugrul Bey's claim, Gundogdu Bey.
This may be our last conversation.
Goncagul.
I am begging you. I am begging you,
listen to me, Gundogdu Bey.
I ran down my honour and entered your tent
in secret like a vile woman.
Let me say what I want to say, at least.
As you know, truth will come out
sooner or later, Gundogdu Bey.
Ertugrul Bey will understand what
a big mistake this was to make.
Until that time arrives,
I will wait for you
even if it lasts a thousand years.
I want you to know that.
Until my body is mixed with the earth
you are the owner of my heart,
Gundogdu Bey.
You know this.
Goncagul, like you said,
truth will come out sooner or later.
You should know that, no one
can take you away from me.
-May it be easy, sister.
-Thank you.
Selcan Hatun!
I will not let you hurt my wife
and my son with your slander!
Obviously, you started to believe
what I said.
You believe me but you
cannot say, Korkut Bey.
You are afraid that your son Tugtekin
who is on a wedding eve
will hear about it, I know.
Be at ease.
I will not speak until the wedding,
for my sister's happiness.
If I hear that you speak your slander
with that poisonous tongue of yours
your death will come by my own
hands, Selcan. Do you understand me?
Stop right there.
God will make you pay for your
illicit relationship.
I know. You are not involved
in Duru Aunt's death.
I believe that.
But, you should believe this.
Both my hands will be upon Aytolun
in two worlds.
Sooner or later,
I will reveal every truth.
We are almost there Aytolun.
We are almost there.
Sister.
If you allow me
I would like to kiss your hand
and recieve your blessing.
My Gokce!
My dear sister!
My sister! I broke your heart.
Even when you were right,
I crossed the line.
You have always supported me. Forgive me.
I want to enter my man's tent
with your blessing
in my happy day.
Dear sister.
Thank God.
My prayers will always be with you
and your man.
You are a part of my life.
Just like you will always be with your man
your sister will always be with you.
Know this Gokce.
I will not let anyone break your heart.
No one.
Sister!
Goncagul, you should wait outside.
Do not let anybody in.
-Okay, aunt.
Do not worry.
Duru!
God, forgive my sins.
If what Selcan told is true,
how could I look at my son's face?
Take my life but do not make me
live this shame.
You are as helpless as this
scorpion, Korkut.
You are circling
in the middle of the fire.
But what you do not know is that the
fire of my anger will burn your body
take your breath away,
shred your heart to pieces.
Amen.
Now, it is time to bring your bride
to my marquee, mother.
I wish she will be a woman
of a Bey worthy of you.
She will always look after her man,
her nomad tent just as you.
I wish your mother would be with you
on your happy day.
She is always with us, father.
Always.
You will be vouchsafed to hold your
granddaughter, if God permits.
I hope so, son.
I hope we will be able to see those days.
If God permits.
With the name of God.
I wish you good hennas.
I wish you happy hennas.
I applied henna, for what?
To sacrifice myself to the tent
of the man I am married to.
For what else?
To know how to apply it to my Alp
when he is going to the battlefield
and to the back of my sacrificial.
What? What else for?
To not stop the sound of prayer calls
from our ears
to keep permanent of our ancestral morals.
May your happiness be
everlasting, Gokce Hatun.
everlasting, my daughter.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
My sister.
-Finished, Bey.
-Thank you.
This is a holy day, son of my uncle.
Love is always holly, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you.
Your happiness became our happiness
in this downturn.
Thank you.
Ertugrul Bey, you should know that
Gumustekin is my half father.
Aytolun is my half mother.
Every bad word you told
them burns our nomad tent.
You should know that this time you
are burning not only our nomad tent
but also Hayme Mother's tent, as well.
As soon as Gundogdu is hurt
two nomad tents would not find peace,
you should know.
If you will excuse me.
For all our sins, forgive us!
Forgive us!
-Forgive us!
There is no god but God
and Muhammad is the messenger of God.
Gokce, daughter of Alptekin
do you accept Tugtekin,
son of Korkut, to your wed
in return for him giving you
ten dirham gold and 20 sheep?
-I do.
-Do you accept?
I do.
Tugtekin, son of Korkut,
do you accept to marry Gokce
daughter of Alptekin with your promise?
-I do.
-Do you accept?
I do.
You, witnesses, do you testify?
-We do.
God blesses your marriage.
-Amen.
With the name of God.
God, we testified these
two people's marriage.
You testify, as well.
My Maker, bless their marriage.
-Amen.
Please give this couple love, harmony
and constancy in their marriage.
-Amen.
Do not let them have fights,
derangement and separation.
Amen!
My God!
Let this couple have the familiarity...
...and constancy
and conservation that...
...His Holiness Adam and Eve...
...and His Holiness Mohammed Mustapha
and Mother Hatice...
...and His Holiness Ali
and Fatima had.
Amen.
God! Endower our
beautiful two people...
...good sons,
long lives and plenty of food.
-Amen.
God, enlighten our wives
and children to us.
Amen.
And lead us to those who bewares
to defy the God.
-Amen.
-God!
Give us goodness, beauty
and blessings on earth.
Amen.
Give us goodness, beauty and blessings
in the afterlife, as well.
Protect us from the torment of fire.
-Amen.
Your God, with puissance and honor is away
and supreme then their qualification.
Greetings to Prophets.
All is pertained to the God of universe.
God blesses your marriage.
Amen.
With the name of God.
The only son of my tent
and family, Tugtekin
bring a worthy son and daughter
into the world.
May God make you happy and fortunate
in here and after.
Amen, father. Amen.
May you and your kin last long.
Have a long lasting Marriage,
if God permits.
Amen.
Be very happy, my daughter.
Congratulations, my uncle's son.
I hope you will give birth to beautiful
girls like you and brave sons like him.
Thank you, Aytolun Hanim.
-Congratulations to you, my uncle's son.
-Thank you.
I wish you a happy marriage.
-Be happy.
-Thank you, Bey.
May your lives be full of welfare.
May trouble be away from you, sister.
My sister!
Long live, Tugtekin Bey!
Long live, Gokce Hatun!
Long live! Long live!
May you and your kin last long!
Long live, Tugtekin Bey!
Long live, Gokce Hatun!
Long live! Long live!
May you and your kin last long!
Long live, Tugtekin Bey!
Long live, Gokce Hatun!
Long live! Long live!
May you and your kin last long!
-Come on!
You know what to do.
I know, aunt.
Do not worry.
However, I am worried about you, aunt.
Do not worry. I will be fine.
Let us end this.
Let us end.
What did Tugtekin Bey do?
He pitched a tent to Kok Alacimen!
What did he do for his beloved one?
He broke stud from horse,
wheat from camel, ram from sheep!
Did he break heart? Did he talk bad?
He neither broke heart nor talked bad!
He asked! He entered the bridal
chamber and attained his desire!
God blesses your marriage!
Amen!
Long live, Tugtekin Bey!
Long live, Gokce Hatun!
Thank God, we have seen
our son's marriage.
What bothers you in a blessed day
like this?
Selcan.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in, daughter.
I prepared wedding sherbet, Bey.
If you allow, I shall offer you.
Give me, daughter.
I prepared this for the two families
with Tugtekin Bey and Gokce Hatun.
Thank you, daughter.
Banu Cicek, you shall wait by the door.
We shall drink.
So that their lives will be sweet
like this sherbet.
The necklace that my deceased mother gave
to Hayme and Hayme gave to Selcan...
Why is it in our marquee, Aytolun?
What kind of lies did Selcan
poison you again with?
She says that Duru's sudden death is
not fate, you poisoned her.
Is this true?
You, Bey, you do not hear what you say.
Answer me!
Answer!
What did you put in this?
More than what I gave to Duru!
Why?
It fell to me and my brother to do
what is required when we understood
that a diffident and coward man
like you cannot rule the margrave.
Help, Banu Cicek! Run!
Korkut Bey!
Bey!
I shall let Artuk Bey know. Hurry!
Murderer! You poisoned my Bey!
Why did you do that?
Look at me, witch!
I do not know what you do,
but I will let Artuk Bey know.
Bey is dying!
Only your body can leave here.
Guards! Guards!
Murderer! She poisoned us!
Kill her!
Save our Bey!
Banu Cicek...
Bey? Let Artuk Bey know! Hurry! Hurry!
Bey? Bey? Aytolun Hatun?
I am thankful to God
for giving me a woman like you.
I am thankful to God for being the
woman of a man like you, Bey.
May you and your kin last long.
May my life be sacrificed for you.
Bey? Bey?
Slowly. With the name of God.
Slowly.
Bring the box with black herbs
from the Isakisfa tent. Now.
Okay, Bey.
Did you inform Mother Hayme
and Gumustekin?
We did, Bey.
Turn him over. Turn. Turn.
-Brother!
-Relax, Bey. Relax.
Aytolun!
My sister!
Aunt! Brother! Brother!
Aytolun!
Mother!
What happened to you, sister?
Aytolun, sister, what happened to you?
What happened here, Artuk Bey?
Stay away. They hardly breathe, obviously,
they are both poisoned.
What?
Who did this to you, sister, who?
Banu Cicek did it, Bey.
Both Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun
said it before they fainted.
Aunt! Uncle!
Bey! Bey, be a little patient
for God's sake!
First we should find out the truth!
What is there to find out, Bey?
Is not everything obvious?
-It is not, Bey! For God's sake!
-Let go of me!
-Ertugrul!
-Take her away.
-Sungur, Kaya, help me.
Ertugrul Bey, we shall inform Tugtekin
Bey as well. They are not good.
Of course, Artuk Bey.
I do not know if they will survive.
They must come and see them.
You are halal to me.
You are the hope for my tent
and margrave now.
I hope you will keep my kin alive.
This is the heritage of
my deceased mother, Gokce.
May you carry it your whole life.
Tugtekin Bey!
Bogac?
Bey! It is Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun!
Artuk Bey told you to come at once!
You will be fine brother,
you will be fine.
You will be fine.
Open, Bey. Open your mouth.
With the name of God.
Drink, aunt, drink.
Father!
Father.
Please tell me he will survive, Artuk Bey.
Please.
You should be prepared for anything, Bey.
Father!
Mother!
You will be okay, mother.
Mother, please open your eyes.
Mother!
Everybody, out. There is not enough
air inside. Out, now.
Come on, daughter. Come on. Come on.
Tugtekin, come here.
Come here son, let's go out.
Where is Banu Cicek?
She is held captive inside.
There is Ertugrul and Kaya Alp with her.
Come, my son, come.
Tugtekin!
Tugtekin, brother, do not!
-I will kill this woman, let me go!
-Do not do it, brother.
-Let me go!
-Do not.
After we learn why she did it,
she will pay for it eventually.
Do not worry.
Leave, brother, leave.
Bogac, Samsa, brother, take her to the
caged tent. It is not working here.
What did Dogan Alp do?
He pitched a tent to Kok Alacimen!
What did he do for his beloved Banu Cicek?
He broke stud from horse,
wheat from camel, ram from sheep!
-I hope we will see those days.
-If God permits.
If God permits, brother.
Banu Cicek?
What is it?
I did not do it, Dogan Alp. I am innocent.
She is still talking! She poisoned Bey
and his wife in front of our eyes!
She still says she is innocent!
Move, you prick, move!
Dogan, stop! Do not!
Leave me!
-Stop, Dogan.
-Stop, brother.
Dogan! Dogan!
-Where are you going, brother?
-Dogan!
What is happening, brother?
What should we do now?
Why this girl did something like this?
Is it not enough to know
the killer, Hayme Hatun?
It is not important
if Banu Cicek did this.
The important thing is why would
Banu Cicek do something like this?
We must find this out.
She loves Duru more than her mother
as well as she loves my brother.
So, why did she do something like this?
I cannot imagine.
As my mother said
we should find out
who is in interest of this.
You are quite right, Ertugrul Bey.
Who knows, what else they used her for?
Is that right, Sungurtekin Bey?
I shall go, check her tent.
Let us see what we will find.
My dear sister.
I hope you will be happy.
I hope you will give birth to many sons
worthy of Suleyman Shah.
What did you do, Selcan Hatun? What?
What kind of evil you have inside?
What are you saying, Dogan brother?
They say Banu Cicek poisoned
Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun.
How did you poison her mind?
How could you ruin her life, Selcan Hatun?
Brother Dogan, stop for a second!
Tell me over again, please!
Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun
are struggling with death.
What do you say? It is not possible!
Shame on you! Shame!
Dogan!
Bey.
Korkut Bey's condition is critical.
I drew too much blood out of his body.
If I draw a little more, I am afraid
he will die of blood loss.
I did everything I could.
Will my brother get better, Artuk Bey?
Unless I know what kind of a poison it is,
I can not say anything Gumustekin Bey.
I have found this in his tent.
Just as I guessed.
This is the most dangerous poison of all.
It shows its curse instantly, but
does not leave any trace behind.
If they were sleeping last night,
we would find both their corpses.
And there would be no trace left behind.
Go, you do not need to wait here.
Go back to your tents.
We can not do anything but to pray.
Korkut Bey.
Forgive me, Bey.
I wish I would die instead of you.
I could not protect you.
Are you going to say that you
did not do it?
It does not matter
what I say, Gundogdu Bey.
You poisoned Korkut Bey and Aytulun Hatun,
in the presence of the Alps.
These are lies, Bey.
What about the poison vial that
I have found in your tent?
Is that a lie too?
They used me, Gundogdu Bey.
If you want to find out the truth,
there is only one person who knows it.
Selcan Hatun.
Go to her, Bey. She will
tell you everything.
Brother?
Dogan?
Banu Cicek did not do this, my brothers.
Banu Cicek would sacrifice her life
for his Bey.
She would sacrifice her soul. But she
would never poison him.
Did you hear about what happened
to Banu Cicek?
Yes, I have heard of it, Bey.
Do you have anything to say?
I know that your heart belongs to her.
Yes, I have, Bey.
Despite all these slanders,
she still owns my heart.
Tell me then.
Tell me, so that there will be nothing
left uncovered.
Tomorrow morning she will be questioned.
This is her last chance.
I promised Selcan Hatun that
I would not say anything to anyone.
Selcan Hatun?
Yes, Bey.
Aytolun Hatun has been up to devilish
plans in Korkut Bey's marquee.
In order to reveal the truth,
Selcan Hatun has needed to...
...get back her necklace
that she left in the marquee.
She has asked Banu Cicek for help.
But after Banu Cicek has said that
she would not betray her Bey...
...she came to ask my help.
I also talked to her.
But again, she did not agree with it.
Afterwards, all these happened, Bey.
How? How? My God, how?
Selcan!
Tell me everything!
Tell me or I will cut you into pieces
like a sheep to the slaughter! Tell me!
Before Aunt Duru died, Aytolun was the
lover of Uncle Korkut, Bey!
Say your last prayer, woman!
Say your last prayer because
I will kill you right here!
Unless I kill you, there is no peace
neither for me nor for our nomad group!
Kill me! Slice my throat right now!
Slaughter me, and both of us will
be freed!
If you are going to search for peace
by hiding behind lies, go ahead!
Sacrifice me right here! Ease your heart!
But if you have a little courage in your
heart, listen to me, my Gundogdu.
Tell me then! Tell me!
-Brother, do not do it!
-Do not get close, Ertugrul.
I am so tired of this already.
Speak!
Reemember the corpse of that old woman
we found outside the nomad tent?
Her killer is Aytolun, Bey.
Aytolun, you killed her!
Murderer! Murderer!
Let me go! I am telling you she is
a murderer, she killed her! Murderer!
The old woman talked to me. She was going
to say more but asked for gold to speak.
She was not satisfied with the necklace
that Mother Hayme gave her.
Her greed was the cause of her death.
I came back to the tent to get her gold...
...so that she would tell us more, Bey...
...but when I went back, she was
already dead.
You are telling me these so that
I would not take Goncagul.
Somehow Goncagul has found the necklace,
and she threatened me.
She accused me of killing the old woman.
She said that she would not say anything
to protect the honour of Gundogdu Bey.
But she is lying, Bey.
Aytolun killed the old woman,
Goncagul knows that too!
Brother! Brother, please do not do this.
Brother, stop! Brother! Brother, stop!
That devil is the one who poisoned my
Uncle too.
I almost believed you.
Seeds of suspicion that you sow in me,
almost sprouted.
But the devil inside you is still alive.
Aytolun is also fighting for her life,
right beside Korkut Bey, Selcan.
God damn the day I took you in
my marquee, woman!
-Damn you! God damn!
-Brother!
Brother calm down, pull yourself together.
We will learn what happened
during the interrogation tomorrow.
Tomorrow, you will be questioned too!
Take this off my hand,
before I do anything bad.
Now tell me everything from the
very beginning, Selcan Hatun.
The one who poisoned them
was not Banu Cicek, Bey.
That girl is innocent.
I swear she did not do it.
Why do you think that Aytolun
killed Aunt Duru?
Did that old woman tell you this?
Then?
Nobody told me, I did not see it either.
But I know, Bey. I know.
A voice in my heart tells me so.
Aytolun is a murderer.
I know, I acted foolishly.
But you should not be angry
with me, mother.
You should know that both Selcan and I
tried for the justice to be served.
But we could not know that
this would happen.
Is this better now, Halime?
Did you think that you would solve
everything by acting on the sly?
How could you do this, by
ignoring me and your husbands?
I talked to Selcan.
She told me everything.
She said that you also knew it all.
Forgive me, Ertugrul Bey.
Selcan told me to wait until
the wedding for her to tell everything.
That is why I could not tell you.
How can you keep secrets
from your Bey, Halime Sultan?
How can this be?
If you have told me everything in the
beginning, things would not get this far.
Look at us!
Look at what I hear while my
brother is fighting for his life!
My God, I am about to lose my mind!
My nomad tent turned into a cesspool,
and my daughter is involved in it!
Mother!
Mother.
I never abandoned my Nasuh repentence...
...or the promise I made
to Ibnul Arabi, mother.
Whatever it is that you have heard, I am
standing behind my words.
I will tell everything I know, tomorrow.
If you tell a single lie...
...I will not let you live here
...or in any other Turkmen nomad group,
Selcan.
Dear God.
I have no one left to take refuge in
but You.
I beg you, please guide
to Ertugrul Bey.
Guide him so that...
...he can save us all from this malice.
I would like to see Banu Cicek.
Tugtekin Bey gave us order. He told us to
not to let anyone in, Bey.
I have some questions to ask this girl
who is said to have poisoned...
...-my uncle and my aunt.
-Bey.
Why did you do this to a man who has been
a father to you, Banu Cicek?
Bey, I did not make an attempt neither on
Korkut Bey's nor or Aytolun Hatun's life.
I am innocent. That is all I have to say.
What is Selcan Hatun's position in this?
She told me everything.
Selcan Hatun is not involved in this.
I believe everything she says.
Sooner or later, poetic justice will be
manifested.
Do you trust in the court that
will be set, Banu Cicek?
Never.
Bey, I trust in God first and then you.
The one who poisoned Korkut Bey
is Aytolun Hatun.
She put the blame on me.
So what, this woman poisoned
herself as well?
Anything may be expected from that demon.
Bey, I know that I will be executed
sooner or later.
You should take revenge not only for me...
...but for Korkut Bey and Duru Hatun
as well.
I do not have anything else to say.
What is their condition, Artuk Bey?
There is nothing else to do
except for praying and waiting.
But as for Aytolun Hatun...
...she obviously drank only a little
of that sirup.
If God permits, she will recover.
I did everything I could.
It seems
that you looked for the thief in your
marquee in the wrong place, Hayme Hatun.
The one who is responsible for all
of this is Banu Cicek.
Let us pray that everything will come to
light in the interrogation.
Without the need of the court.
What you should do is not to be biased.
Otherwise, when the court is set,
I will ask for a judge from Konya.
You should know that.
If you allow us, I would like to start
the questioning, Hayme Hatun.
Bring her.
We would like to solve this matter
before the trial starts.
Your crime seems obvious.
Confess and save us all from this trouble.
I am innocent.
I will tell everything I know at the
court.
What are you going to tell?
Will you tell how did you give them
the poison?
-Tugtekin Bey.
-Or how you attempted their lives?
-What are you going to tell?
-Tugtekin Bey.
We are all devastated.
But we are here in order to solve
this case.
Why are you waiting for the court?
Tell us now.
That night...
...after I gave the wedlock sherbet
to Korkut Bey and Aytolun Hatun...
...I left the marquee.
Sometime later, Aytolun Hatun,
cried out for me.
I went in and saw that Korkut Bey
was on the floor.
He was In the throes of death.
Aytolun Hatun attacked me with her dagger,
saying that I poisoned him.
So, I fought back for self defense.
Guardian Alps came in.
They hit my head and I had fainted.
When I opened my eyes, they were
taking me to the caged tent.
That is all I have to say.
I have committed no sins.
I am innocent.
Gundogdu Bey.
As the head of the Alps
who carries out this inqury...
...do you have anything to say
to this woman?
-Blend them together.
-Alright.
Bey?
Korkut Bey?
Slowly, Bey.
Do not tire yourself, Bey.
About the poison vial that I found
in your tent...
Artuk Bey says that the poison was used.
Tell us, why was that vial in your tent?
Whoever did this...
...put the vial in there as well.
After putting the poison in the
wedlock sherbet...
...why did you feel the need to take the
vial into your tent?
What is your problem, Ertugrul?
Is it your job to protect this women
who attempted on my father's life?
Also...
...while serving Bey and Hanim
in the marquee...
...when did you have the chance to go and
hide the vile in your tent?
Obviously, the ones who organized
this ruse...
is trying to make a fool of me and
everyone here.
God willing, after Korkut Bey recovers...
...he will surely be able to find them
and ask them to pay the price...
...for what they have done.
When Alps were taking Tugtekin and Gokce
to their tents with torches...
...you were there as well, were you not?
So you took that opportunity to take
the vial in your tent, did you not?
Lie.
That is completely a lie.
I do not know anything about the vial
or the poison.
God will punish those who ambushed me!
Do not worry.
I will punish you with my own sword.
Is there anyone else who has something
to say?
Yes, there is.
Go ahead, Gundogdu Bey.
That night, when I came to question you...
...you said that, there was another matter
needed to be solved, is that true?
True, Bey. I said that.
What are those matters?
Before the court, these matters
should be investigated.
That is why, I think that two more people
should be questioned as well.
Who are these people, Gundogdu Bey?
Selcan Hatun...
...and Goncagul Hatun.
Forgive me but Korkut Bey is gasping
his life out.
Brother!
Father.
No! Please do not do this, brother!
Do not leave us!
My God, please help us!
Father. Father. Father. Father.
Father. Father.
Father! Father!
Father!
Tugtekin!
Tugtekin, my brother!