Episode 27 will start after 12:24 min
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
WE HAVE BEEN ON THIS LAND
FOR A THOUSAND YEARS
AND WE WILL BE HERE
FOR A THOUSAND MORE YEARS.
MAY GOD BLESS OUR MARTYRS SOULS.
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Halime.
Halime!
What is it that you keep in your heart
but cannot say?
You have been in silence for days.
If I said a bad word,
may my tongue rot away.
If I broke your heart without noticing,
may my heart shatter.
If a bad word comes my way, I would rather
that it came from your sweet tongue.
You are my man, my hero for so long.
I never heard you say a bad word to me
and not even once you broke my heart.
Then, what is the reason of
your silence?
Since Suleyman Shah died, two winters
and three summers have passed Ertugrul.
We have never stopped.
We have never seen a peace of mind
in winter or summer hold.
It is said that a nomad realizes
their exhaustion when they get settled.
Spring is coming and bringing me
the worry of the road ahead.
However, neither I look for the light...
...nor the worry of migration
blackens my heart.
It is enough for me to be with you.
We have a few days
ahead of us to the new winter hold.
My uncle's nomad group is near.
A safe place a couple of days away.
If we can manage to get through
this winter, the rest will be easy.
There will be nothing left to worry.
If God permits, we will reach
the homeland we deserve.
I do not worry for myself, Ertugrul.
Who do you worry about?
We gave a promise to Suleyman Shah once.
If he had any boys as grandchildren
we promised we name them...
...Gunduz, Savci and Osman.
That will happen as well, if God permits.
Blessed boys and girls
will bring joy to our marquee.
As I said before, Bey.
I do not worry for myself.
Then, who do you worry about
my gazelle eyes?
For our baby, Gunduz.
I am pregnant, Ertugrul.
We are going to have a child.
If my dream was right,
I will give you a son.
Thank God!
Blue sky above and the black soil below,
bear witness to me!
I am going to be a father! Father!
Stop. Calm yourself. It is too early.
How can I be calm, my gazelle eyes?
Our people were looking forward for this.
I wish, Suleyman Shah was here as well.
He would have been so happy.
Neither in the winter hold that we are
about to reach, nor in many others...
...do not make your son cry while asking
his father's whereabouts, Ertugrul.
I cannot know the life that God
gave me or what lies in my destiny...
...however, as long as I am alive
I will not let you or my child...
...go through pain or hardship.
Rest assured about that, Halime Sultan.
May God keep you beside me.
It ends here, Turk.
If you wish your wife to live,
surrender yourself!
It is my last warning to you,
be sure of that, son of Bey!
Run to the horses
and don't look back, Halime.
Inform my brother Gundogdu
to change the caravan's path.
They need to come, help us.
Halime, run!
Do not let that whore escape, go!
Come to me, embarrassment of Kayi!
Neither you nor the ones left
from your nomad group will be able to...
...reach the winter hold, Ertugrul.
None of you will be spared!
Do not let him escape! Go!
Go!
I will kill you, whore!
Do not kill him!
Bey Noyan wants him alive.
Gunduz.
My Gunduz.
I will not let anything happen to you.
-Finally our paths have crossed, Ertugrul.
-Degenerate dogs!
All of your caravan tasted our weapons.
Kill me as well.
Otherwise, even death will not free you!
Alright.
Noyan wants you alive.
You should be thankful to him.
You were the dogs of my ancestor
Oghuz once.
Russia, China, India.
All the lands
that Euphrates and Tigris quench...
...are now property of
Genghis Khan's son Ogeday!
Anatolia is next.
You arrived at the last
point that you are able to go...
...with your few tents and little herds.
There is no way to run away from
Genghis Khan's army!
It is over. Do you understand me, Turk?
It is over.
These lands are the regions that
raise brave men.
We die with pleasure.
However, we do not give up
on even an inch of our land.
We will make you bleed in Anatolia,
bleed!
Then, you will understand
the might of the Mongols!
Get ready, you lazy men!
We are leaving!
Aktolga!
Ertugrul!
God, please give me strength.
What is happening, Kaya?
Aytolun Hatun asked us to move these.
Open the chests.
I do not repeat an order in this nomad
group, do you not understand that?
Open it!
Take them back inside. Now.
I am glad that you let me move your
deceased wife's belongings.
You should know that I respect her deeply.
However, I am the Hanim of this
marquee now.
If I am not accepted in this marquee,
how can I make people listen to me?
The woman who gave me life once again.
You are the Sultan of both my marquee
and my heart.
What is this impertinence of yours,
Tugtekin?
Impertinence is erasing my mother's
memory from this marquee, Bey.
On what terms, are you able
to advise me? Know your place!
Father...
...as long as I breathe, those cannot be
removed from this marquee.
Then, you should know this, even the one
who goes against my will is my child...
...I will stop them from breathing!
Bey. Let me.
If our son Tugtekin wishes his mother's
memory to linger in this marquee...
...we should respect his wish.
We should respect him
so our son Tugtekin...
...would respect his Mother Aytolun as well.
Is there any news from
your Aunt Hayme's nomad group?
They will arrive soon.
Tugtekin cannot accept me yet, Bey.
It is not easy.
However, do not worry.
He will accept me as a mother.
I will do everything I can.
Please, do not suffer for this as well.
You have the burden of your people on
your shoulders.
As long as you stand beside me
like this, Hatun...
...I will never bow to anyone,
be sure of that.
God is immortal. God is the one.
My dear Mother.
I wish I had died instead, Mother.
Without you, our nomad group...
...this homeland has become
a dungeon for me, Mother.
The nomad group once
you spread joy all over...
...is now the homeland of dreadful owls.
Death claimed you before
you could see me getting married.
I could not make you hold your grandchild.
That gives me too much pain.
But I miss you deeply, Mother.
Miss you deeply.
Even if my spear shatters hearts, even
if my sword makes my enemies kneel...
...even if I gain many victories and honor...
...when you do not witness them
what good is it, my dear Mother?
So, this is the syrup that
makes a man a raging bull?
If he hears that I have done this,
Artuk Bey would kill me, Hanim.
As long as I am here,
no one can touch you.
Korkut Bey gets joyful nights thanks to
you, is that wrong?
Artuk Bey.
God bless.
You trained Belkis Hatun well.
She became as skillful as you at her job.
If God permits, her heart will be as pure
as her hands, Aytolun Hatun.
I wish that I knew you were coming.
We would provide remedy
to your worries.
Thank God. I have no illness.
I was passing by.
I wanted to ask for womanly
advice from Belkis Hatun.
I hope that you have
found your cure then.
I hope everything is alright.
Kayis are coming!
Kaya? What is happening?
Kayis, Bey.
They are coming to our nomad group.
-What is wrong, Aytolun Hatun?
-Everything, Artuk Bey.
Tell them to start the preparations in
the healing tent.
I smell trouble in the air.
Hurry up and help the wounded. Hurry.
Hayme Hatun! My God!
-Brother.
-Sister, what happened to you?
We were raided. Mongols.
-We are in pieces, brother.
-Damn. Kaya!
-Yes, Bey.
-Inform Tugtekin Bey.
As you wish, Bey.
-Wild Demir.
-Artuk Bey.
Artuk Bey. Save my daughter. Cure her.
Hurry!
In God's name. Go.
Slowly.
-Ertugrul, Gundogdu, where are they?
-Ertugrul and Halime.
While we were
resting they went to the woods...
...and Gundogdu was gathering the caravan.
We did not understand what happened.
We were ruined.
I do not know who is dead
and who is alive.
Alright. Come. Let us go to the marquee.
-They will take care of them.
-Sister Hayme, come.
-Mother!
-Bring some water, Bacis.
-Hayme, where did they attack?
-At the Cortuk Bosporus, brother.
I had never seen them so crowded.
Some of them attacked the Alps...
...and the others attacked women and
children.
They were so blinded with anger.
They attacked like hungry wolves.
Kayi tent has battled many times.
However, we have never seen such
pillage and cruelty, brother.
Our women and children fought back
with weapons.
They battled courageous just like
their men, brothers and sons.
However, most people could not
escape death.
This means that the Moguls attacked
earlier than we expected.
Difficult days await us from now on.
Welcome, Mother. Aunt, I heard the
news. I am very sorry.
-What is the situation?
-Tugtekin, my swarthy nephew.
Thank you.
The Moguls.
I swear to God that I will make life a
living hell for those
who have done this to you.
Your Ertugrul brother and Gundogdu
brother will defeat them, if God permits.
Of course, Aunt. Of course.
What they said was true, father.
They did not send the best Ogeday of
Genghis Khan for nothing.
If they come, they will see, son.
Halime?
Ertugrul?
Daughter?
-Halime?
-Halime, what happened to you?
Halime, tell us what happened, daughter.
The Moguls...
Ertugrul and I were riding our horses,
mother.
We came across with them.
Ertugrul sent me to inform you.
-Where is Ertugrul?
-He was battling with them.
I fought with the Moguls while escaping.
I managed to kill them and escape.
Halime!
Bring some water! Give her some water!
Drink.
Drink, Halime. Drink, honey.
Not to worry. Ertugrul Bey is not
frightened off by those dogs.
Tell us, come on.
-Daughter...
I did not know what to do when I saw the
caravan burned and overthrown.
I went to the last place I saw Ertugrul.
Halime? What did you see?
Ertugrul had killed many of them.
Ertugrul?
I found his horse, not my man, mother.
I did not see Ertugrul either alive
or dead.
We did not stop anywhere.
We haven't seen the light of day either
during summer or in winter.
It will be easy after this winter.
There won't be anything to worry about
anymore.
-I don't worry about myself.
-Who are you worried about?
For our baby, Gunduz.
I am pregnant, Ertugrul.
I will give birth to your son.
You shall not make him cry
because of longing for his father
anywhere.
God! Do not let me die before
taking my revenge.
Dear God.
You are the one who granted
Ismail to Abraham.
You are the one who returns Joseph
to Jacob.
Please grant my daughter, my only
reason for living.
Do not make me live without her
in this world.
-God damn you! Blast you!
-Kill them all!
Stop! Stop my brothers.
Stop! Don't do it!
We need this dog alive.
Do not do it! We need him alive.
-Hamza, you're responsible for this dog.
-I will, Bey.
We must make him talk.
Mother!
My son!
Thank God, you are alive.
Thank God, Bey. You are here.
Welcome, son.
-Where is my brother?
-We do not know where Ertugrul is, son.
-Halime and Ertugrul were ambushed.
-Hamza! Prepare the Alps.
We will set off to look for my brother.
-Turgut, Dogan, where are they?
-No news from any of them, son.
Come, get in the marquee.
We shall regroup and act accordingly.
Gundogdu brother.
-How are you, brother?
-Get well soon, brother.
Thank you.
We can learn where they are from
this dog.
You shall rest at the marquee.
I will take care of him.
Come on, let's go.
I will break your fingers one by one
until you tell me where Noyan is.
Then, I'll break your feet and won't stop
you until fall to the ground.
Kocabash, inform me when he comes to.
As you command, Bey.
You will heal in a couple of days,
Halime Hatun.
Thank you, Aytolun Hanim.
He blacked out, I mean the snake.
We should make him talk before
taking the road, father.
It is obvious from his eyes that
he knows something.
What is the latest situation, Gundogdu?
We have a lot of martyrs, uncle. A lot.
The Ignoble! We can't find peace until
we find and kill that heretic Noyan.
We must make him pay for what
he has done.
Did your attacker have a shaved head
and braided hair?
Yes, he had, Korkut Bey.
This means Noyan wanted Ertugrul alive.
How do you know this, Bey?
Some of the army attacked the caravan.
Some of them chased Ertugrul.
So, they know him. Noyan sent his most
trustworthy man after him.
-So, they were after us for a long time.
-Yes.
The Moguls want to know their enemies
closely like jackals.
They set traps and attack accordingly.
And they never enter a war when they
know that they will lose.
So, what are we going to do, brother?
Try to get information from that Mogul.
Who knows where Noyan is...
However, we must find Ertugrul first.
Tugtekin, prepare the Alps and explore.
If they took my son like you said,
will they let him live, Brother?
-Brother.
-Thank you. I will be back after eating.
Do not think about it.
I will do what needs to be done.
Water? Give me some water.
Who are you?
Are you the father of that burn victim?
What did you want from women
and children?
Weren't the Alps enough?
We wanted to taste them all.
Old man, leave him.
You will get me into trouble.
Master!
-Father?
-My son! Thank God, you are alive.
Where is Aykiz, father?
Where is Aykiz?
Father, tell me, where is Aykiz?
Turgut Alp. Go to the healing tent.
-What is the situation, Dogan?
-It is bad, Bey.
We gathered the people.
However, we've lost many lives.
It was a blood bath.
What is wrong with Aykiz Baci?
They burned her, Dogan.
We must find Ertugrul immediately.
-Is Bey not here?
-He is not.
-Stop, you cannot enter. It is private.
-She is my wife.
It is still better if you do not enter.
My God!
Does one need a new country
for a good life?
A new country means a good life
for all of us. Mostly for us.
What have they done to you?
My God!
Almighty God!
We shouldn't have left them alone when
they went to find water for the animals.
Do not lose hope, Dogan.
Ertugrul Bey is not easily frightened off
by them.
Mother Hayme and Korkut Bey
are having a meeting.
With God's help, we will overcome
these troubles, too.
Haven't I told you not to leave that
Mogul alone?
You have, Bey. But Kocabas was with him.
-Are you still talking?
-Bey, please, forgive him.
He has made a mistake.
Prepare the horses. We will take
the road.
-Did you hear me?
-Of course, Bey.
Things like this happen.
I do not deserve this, brothers.
I do not.
Hamza!
You know he likes you.
Bey does not appreciate those who
likes him, Selcan Hatun.
He does not appreciate.
It is heavy, right Halime?
Must be very painful.
What do you want to say, Gokche?
I lost Ertugrul a thousand times.
Every time he was dead to me.
And he came back to life again.
I suffered a lot every time he died
and came back to life.
You still haven't given up on this love,
Gokce?
You only hoodwinked and kept quiet.
Halime...
It's been a long since I closed my eyes
and swallowed my tongue.
You should think about what you
are going to do now.
If he dies...
...I will not live. Not to worry.
I was told that you were tough.
But you fell into our hands rather easily.
Stay alert.
Don't choke on what you're eating.
I didn't choke on the likes of you while
I was burning Samarkand and Buhari.
You cannot even be a fish bone on
my throat.
If a Turk hasn't drawn his last breath,
the last words haven't been spoken yet.
I will not ask for mercy before the angel
of death comes to take my life.
-Save it for Noyan.
-Who is Noyan?
He is the one who wants you alive.
Come on! We are leaving!.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
Welcome Bey. Come on in.
-Do you have food?
-We have blanching and bread, Bey.
-Did you put zither and thyme, too?
-Of course, Bey.
-A little bit of garlic?
-You are a gourmet.
If you travel for years, you need to
become a gourmet.
So, Bey. What makes you travel like this?
The urge of possession, innkeeper.
The urge of possession.
What do you want to possess?
Everything you see.
They say the Mogul vanguards entered
our lands after Khwarazmshah's defeat.
They are led by a butcher called Noyan.
That ignoble dogs have not seen
soldiers for years.
They have become crueler in time.
Sultan Aladdin will teach them
how to battle.
The cruelty of that butcher Noyan is
well-known.
That bounder destroyed our brothers
in Khurasan, Samarkand and Bihari.
He burned and destroyed everything.
He raped our sisters.
We will battle him and take our revenge
one day.
What would you do if you saw him?
I'd love to rip his head off
with this knife.
-This will eventually happen one day.
-I hope very soon, with God's help.
-Do you want it to happen soon?
-I want to kill that ignoble the sooner.
Are you ready Ulubilge?
You asked for it and now you got it.
You are one of the beloved subjects of
Tengri.
You must be happy.
Good. Very good.
However, there is something else in this.
Turmeric.
Turmeric, Bey. It is turmeric.
Good. I'll give you that.
I do not like sleeping alone at nights,
innkeeper. You understand me, right?
Good.
So, you can find me a beautiful woman,
can't you?
-Do you have a daughter?
-I do not have a daughter.
This is too bad, old man.
Father! Father!
No, no! Father.
I'll make do with you for
a couple of days.
I will wait for the guest Ertugrul, here.
These Turks do not know their friends
from their enemies, soldier.
Take the bodies to the yard.
Close the doors of the caravansary
I will wait for Tangut, here.
Put guards on everywhere.
-Prepare her.
-As you command, Bey.
Kayis will see
how courageous you are.
You would seek danger without
batting an eye to find Ertugrul.
It is my duty to help anyone
who is in trouble.
It is so.
However, your altruism
becomes more valuable
if it's Ertugrul who is in trouble.
See? Ertugrul's reputation
has reached everywhere
from Genghis Khan's palace
to Konya, Damascus
and Constantine.
You are as courageous as he is
and even more intelligent.
Why are you telling me all this?
Because, mothers want their sons to
become famous and become Beys, son.
That's why.
If only I could come with you, brother.
Don't leave our sister alone.
We'll do whatever is necessary, brother.
Godspeed, sons.
Dogan?
Don't come back unless you find our Bey.
Godspeed you!
This is where Ertugrul and
Halime Sultan were attacked.
We'll take three different routes.
Gundogdu and I will be in the middle.
And mounted troops will follow us
from left and right.
In case of an attack, they'll support us
and provide our security.
Which tracker are you with?
The best ones, father.
Samca and Bogac.
And my Alp Kocabas.
I also took the best with me, uncle.
Not to worry.
Noyan has arrived with vanguards
from Tabriz.
He aims to gather information and to be
prepared for the real attack.
You must be very careful.
May God help you.
Blessed be our holy war!
Do your best, and with God's help
you'll achieve victory.
-Thank you, uncle. Excuse me.
-Thank you, my courageous son.
Give me your blessings, father.
I give you my blessings,
my courageous son.
Excuse me.
Why are you so late?
I am sorry, Bey.
-Who is this, brother?
-He is one of Ertugrul's Alps.
I'm risking the lives of my men
to find your Bey.
I won't accept any mistakes.
Keep that in mind.
Not to worry, Bey.
We'll do our best.
We have full confidence in him.
You can trust him, too.
If you vouch for him, brother...
I am very upset about what happened,
Selcan.
Thank you, Aytolun.
I've heard you lost three of
your children.
Your weak body
couldn't carry the babies.
The happiness and peace of
a woman stems from giving birth
to her husband's children.
-It hurts me to see you like this.
-It was God's will, Ayrolun.
Without any doubt.
You must never worry about others
You look very well.
You had no trouble taking your
predecessor's place.
God bless.
I was told that you'd become an angel.
However, the devil won't leave you alone
with that sharp tongue of yours, Selcan.
You should know that
your demons can't run wild here.
Mighty God who turns the night
into day, and day into night,
who controls fate and who
dominates time.
Save me from
this contempt soon enough.
Don't allow me to become desperate
and miserable in front of my enemies.
Don't let me surrender to the cruel.
Don't upset my wife, my mother and
my Alps, who are waiting for me, God.
Give me strength to endure
even if they shred me into pieces,
Almighty God.
I couldn't do it.
I couldn't protect my nomad tent.
Don't talk like that, Hayme.
You stood straight across these jackals.
They took one life from you,
but you took three.
The ones they killed were mostly
women and children.
You put up an excellent fight.
They'll pay for this eventually.
They burned down everything.
They destroyed our tents and goods.
They plundered everything we own.
We're homeless on the brink of winter.
What am I here for, Hayme?
What are Aytolun and Tugtekin here for?
This used to be your nomad tent once.
You are back at your nomad tent
where you were born
and where you became a bride.
Thank you, brother.
I'll never forget your kindness.
Aytolun had someone set up a tent
for you and your daughters.
Go and rest.
We'll take care of the wounded
and the orphans.
Aytolun will take care of this personally.
Thank you, Aytolun.
Bacis! Look here!
Take Mother Hayme to her tent.
I'll be right with you.
Hayme Baci, if God permits, everything
will be better soon.
Tugtekin will find Ertugrul
and bring him back safe and sound.
Thank you.
We're done and through with that
in short time.
Korkut Bey.
What do you mean, Hatun?
The Seigniory you wanted to establish.
The Seigniory that you'd collaborate with
the Kayis to establish.
Everything turned out in your favor.
How could you talk about these things
on this painful day, Aytolun?
On the contrary, it's just about time.
We'll end up worse than Kayis if
you don't take precautions
on this painful day.
The first time I took her into my arms
I felt as if I was the king of the world.
What property, what possession
could be more beautiful than that?
She looked just like her mother.
After her mother's death
I took strength from her
beautiful eyes
her soft words and her brave heart.
Come on, my daughter.
Come on, open your eyes.
Open them and bring us back to life.
If...
Aykiz becomes a martyr,
I swear on my life that
I will wipe them off the earth
and leave no man alive.
What's the situation, Artuk?
I've tried every medicine we have, Bey.
However, the condition of the wounded
is critical.
Most of them
won't even see tomorrow.
What happened to them today
might happen to us tomorrow.
What do you think, Bey?
I'll send a message to Sultan Aladdin.
There are no obstacles before the Moguls
after the defeat of Celaleddin
Khwarazmshah's.
We must get help from Konya.
Otherwise,
we can't stop those bandits.
Bey, Kayis should stay with us
for a while.
We'll consolidate our strength with them.
We can gather
the Kayi herd that fell apart
at the battle and sell them cheaper.
That way we can buy provisions.
Winter is coming. The men who
are alive can run our errands.
That's the right way, Artuk.
However, I'm not sure how to deal with
the troubles that will come our way.
If God permits, all the nomad group
will embrace them.
We'll become brothers just like
Muhacir and Ensar,
two of the companions of Prophet
Muhammad, who embraced each other.
Halt!
My brother is alive.
Ertugrul is alive.
He left traces for us.
Let's set off right away!
They can't be far. They're taking him
somewhere on foot. Come on.
It's a good thing that
we sent Dundar and Yigit away
to train to become Alps.
At least we're not
worrying about them, mother.
You should know that I'm very proud to
have daughters-in-law like you two.
They'll find Ertugrul and bring him back,
if God permits.
-If God permits.
We'll pray for it.
But, we shouldn't lag behind.
Our nomad tent needs us.
-We'll be there for you, mother.
-I know, my daughter.
As soon as they assemble at
headquarters we'll decide what to do.
The nomad group can gather further
down the valley.
We won't leave them leaderless
because of our sorrow.
Not to worry, mother.
-Mother.
-Tell me, daughter.
-I was going to tell you today,
-What?
after I told Ertugrul Bey.
I wanted you to hear this from him.
Tell me, daughter.
Is it bad news?
I'm expecting, mother.
My God! Thank you.
My God, you created us
and we will return to you.
You blessed us with a new life
on our rainy days.
Don't let him become an orphan,
my God.
Halime.
Let's split up here.
They can't be far away.
Look sharp. We won't go back to the
nomad tent unless we find Ertugrul.
What's going on?
Did you lose your way?
Don't you know that if you lose
your way, you can't become an Alp?
And if you're in over your head,
you're a lost case, Kocabas?
You should have protected
your Bey instead of talking.
There are no traces here.
Look to the other side of the hill.
Make yourself useful.
There are no traces
below the riverside, Bey.
It will be more difficult if we
continue tomorrow.
Bey?
Unfortunately, there are no traces.
We shall keep searching
until dark.
No!
Sir, your guest has arrived.
Make do with this for now.
You'll be mine tonight.
-I'm here, Aykiz.
-Aykiz, my daughter.
-I'm always with you.
-My daughter.
Aykiz?
My daughter.
Aykiz!
Aykiz! No!
Thankfully, Bamsi took Dundar and
Yigit to the Taurus Mountains
to be trained as Alps.
-If he were here...
-It would be a bloodbath, brother.
I'm tempted to act
as if there's no tomorrow
and rip off that big head of Kocabas's.
-Hush! He'll hear you.
-I don't care if he does.
You should know that the Kayis of
Suleiman Shah are losers.
They are hirelings and parasites.
We should talk
very carefully from now on.
Your Alps are very impatient,
Gundogdu Brother.
Do they not know we are searching
for a needle in a haystack?
They're all faithful companions
of Ertugrul.
Dogan, Bamsi, Turgut.
Ertugrul considers them as his
own brothers.
Ertugrul might as well be dead, brother.
You have no right
to fall into such despair.
If there's anyone who can help the
nomad tent survive this situation,
it's you, brother.
You should know that my father
and I are always here for you.
Thank you, my nephew. Thank you.
Like you said, it's time to team up.
The reason why this happened to us
is because we were no good at this.
Regarding my brother Ertugrul,
you don't know him well, my nephew.
He could get through anything.
He could even fool the devil.
If God permits, brother.
Ertugrul is a brave warrior.
-I hope we'll find him safe and sound.
-If God permits.
For all I care, we should spend the
winter on the same land.
We should unite. We have enough water
and we can share our food.
And we'll stick together against
the Moguls. Winters are harsh here.
When spring comes, there will be war.
We can team up with Aladdin's army
and kick the Moguls out of our land.
-We'll figure out the rest later.
-With God's help.
Move!
I caught this jackal in the bushes.
I guess he was eavesdropping.
-Tell me, are you one of Noyan's dogs?
-His name is Geyikli.
He's a harmless lunatic wanderer.
However, no one has ever
succeeded in catching him.
You have sharp ears even though
you're no good at tracing. Good job.
However, you should know that he's
faster than a deer, craftier than a fox
and stronger than a bear.
Don't mess with him anymore.
Excuse me, brother.
-I'll show you!
-Dogan.
Come on and eat.
As you command, Bey.
I was expecting you, my dear friend.
-Who the hell are you?
-Welcome to the hell of Noyan, Ertugrul.
-So, you are the vinedresser, Noyan.
-Yes. I am the hellhound of this hell.
Bey, smoke is rising from the caravansary.
I told you!
I did, but you didn't listen.
I'll make you pay for it
if something happens to my Bey
because of this bastard, Kocabas.
Dogan!
If you keep talking smack,
you'll be back at the nomad tent.
Mount your horses right away!
God give me patience!
Welcome to the world of the Moguls.