Episode 54 will start after 12:22 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
You had to put up with roads with me
from the Caspian Sea...
...to the border of Byzantine, Aktolgali.
Every land that you step
with your hooves...
...took us from lots of betrayers
and pain to another.
I understood that the secret of fortune is
to fight for justice.
The secret of fortune is hidden
in the lands that we found with justice.
Thanks to God who showed it to me.
They are ready to die for you Noyan.
I came here for revenge.
I came here to fight as a hero and die.
I came here to give your reputation
that Ogeday Khan took from you.
Those gold are yours, share them.
If there is anyone who afraid of this
happy road...
...he can take his share and leave.
I will fulfill the secret duty
that Ogeday gave to me...
...and I will cause Ertugrul's extinction.
When the time comes...
...I will give you the gold
that is in the palace of Sultan Aleaddin.
I can give you one promise.
You will all die as a honorable Mongol.
For the revenge.
For Genghis Khan.
For the revenge! For Genghis Khan!
Come on, sit next to me.
You went to various places,
from the Caspian Sea...
...to Ahlat, from Ahlat to Aleppo...
...from Aleppo to Erzurum.
In these places you go,
you became the honor of Kayi tribe...
...you became the pride of our tribe,
and you became the flag of Islam.
I just followed your way father...
...and I will do the same hereafter.
The roads that Kayi tribe...
...and Oghuz was on exile showed
its light to you son.
Be a follower of that light.
Thus you can be a new hope...
...and you can open the doors of
new world state for your descendants .
The ones with you and behind you...
...let them be happy with honor of this.
From north to south.
From east to west.
A big oak tree with exile branches...
...will be raised in this lands high
and low.
It is the time to make homeland the lands
that our plane oak tree roots, father.
May God not shame me.
I will not shame you.
Hayme Hatun and Gokce Hatun are coming!
May your work always be plentiful and
flourish like the first day of spring,...
...-happy Navruz.
-Thank you, thank you.
May that blesses us in our work
reflect too her goof fate on our tribe.
-Amen.
-If God permits.
Happy Nawruz, womans.
-May our nomad group blossom as sprays.
-Thank you.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun. May luck be with
The Dodurga nomad group.
Today is Nawruz.
Today is the first day of spring.
Let us clean our tents, make meals and
let the smoke rise from our chimneys.
May our nomad group cheer up
with your sons and daughters.
-If God permits.
Let us work, and may our rugs
be knitted as colorful as your hearts.
Amen. If God permits.
May your state tent lighten
with your children, Gokce Hatun.
If God permits, amen.
If God permits.
May our nomad group be cleaned
and purified from the evil...
...just as our tents.
Amen. Amen.
-May betrayers be away from us.
-Amen, amen.
May our nomad groups, our state tents
never wrack as black mountains.
Amen.
May our flag always flap.
Amen!
May our shady trees never be cut.
Amen.
May our water never dry up.
May God never make us dependent on vile,
never make us ungrateful.
Amen.
Happy spring!
Let us start with spinning the wool
of the sheeps that are sheared.
We commend our rug place to
Selcan Hatun and Halime Hatun.
We will never misappropriate your trust.
Your workplace is a mecca for us.
Amen.
Let us start working, in the name of God!
Come on.
Good luck with it, Turgut.
Thank you, Bey. You allowed me
to keep my father's work going.
May God bless you!
Thanks to you, the soul of Wild Demir
will rest in peace.
His soul will be rest in peace
in Byzantine border, Turgut.
It is time for everybody to
learn about it.
It is now the time, Ertugrul Bey.
Did you examine Alps, Turgut?
There are many Alps that will follow you
wherever you go Bey, with God's help.
Kayi Alps say that they would go
anywhere, even to the end of the world.
Yes, Bey. They say so.
But Beys want peace, Ertugrul.
And they fins peace in abbundance.
The real war is starting now, brother.
If necessary...
...we'll migrate with a handful of people,
just as our prohpet Mohammad.
Alright, brother.
With your permission, Ertugrul Bey...
...I have an important matter to tell you
and Sungurtekin Bey.
I will come to the healing tent,
you will tell me there.
Thank you, Bey. Good luck with it, Turgut.
-Thank you.
-Good luck with it, Turgut Alp.
Thank you.
How did you fire the oven, brother?
Just as my father did.
With the spark of The Nawruz fire, Bey.
Thank you.
May the iron thicken with the fire.
May the hammer and stithy shape up.
Amen.
Will not we forge in the fire of Nawruz?
-As you please, Bey.
-Come on, in the name of God.
In the name of God.
God bless!
May God discipline our enemies
in such a fire!
Amen.
Thus they can know their place with the
power of stithy.
Amen.
In the name of God!
-God!
-In the name of God!
What is the matter, Artuk Bey?
What is it that you want to tell us?
It is about Gundogdu Bey.
I prevented the abscess
to poison his blood.
But this abscess will give no quarter.
How much longer will my brother's
condition go on like this?
God knows that, Bey.
But the matter is much deeper.
What is the matter, Artuk Bey?
I do not know when Gundogdu Bey's arm will
recover and head up to Alps again, Bey.
In this condition, if he heads them,
he will harm both himself and the Alps.
What can we do, Artuk Bey?
Nothing, Bey.
But there is a very succesful doctor in
Erzurum whom I trust in his skills.
He better examine his harm
within a short time.
My brother should hear it
from my mother.
And when it comes to his duty...
...Alps cannot be left without a leader.
I know, the danger is close.
Stop!
Is this the man that you would like
to introduce me, Ameer Almighty?
Yes.
The head of Noyan
who martyrised many of our brothers,
is at your feet, thank God!
Noyan.
Do not be afraid of me, Goncagul Hatun.
I know that we both have the same goal.
Until the last drop of blood of
Ertugrul gets off his veins...
...you'll devote your life
to this case with this man, Goncagul.
It is obvious that the ominous seal
which caused the death of my father...
...did not touch you, Noyan.
Which war is as crueal as the politics,
Goncagul Hatun?
Politics is over now.
It is time for blood.
The hate that preys on your mind, was not
enough to leave your beautiful face...
...-in shade, Goncagul Hatun.
-What do you want from me?
We need to you spy on these two
nomad groups...
...which have clamped together thanks to
your father's headless corpse.
Thus we will be alleviated with the
help of the blood of our enemies.
My heart does not need to be refreshed.
Instead, it has the need to burn away both
those nomad groups.
I will give you what you want.
And what's more is, I will do it tonight.
If we are done here,
I would like to leave now.
Excuse me.
She is also brave aside of her beauty.
I wandered various lands but
I have never seen someone like her.
She is clever. If God permits,
after everything is over...
...I will take her to my palace
to take service with me.
I can not stand such a women to be wasted
in your palace, Kobek.
I think you are impressed by her.
Yes, very much.
So come on, steal her heart
But do not forget, you will not
come to my headquarters from now on.
If we will meet, here is our new
meeting place.
God bless you!
You look like fresh spring flowers
just like your name.
They are so beautiful.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
May God bless you and Tugtekin Bey.
You deserve everything, Banu Cicek.
I hope you will be happy with Dogan Alp
for the rest of your life.
May God give you beautiful children.
I hope so, Selcan Hatun.
I hope our children to grow old together.
Both Gokce Hatun's and Mother Hayme's
state tents may glow with children.
Gokce Hatun.
Are you alright?
I am fine.
I...
I have things to take care of.
If God is willing,
I will see you at diner.
Selcan Hatun, did I say something wrong?
No way.
I think it is because of joy.
When she saw you such happy...
Come on, let's try your bonnet.
It will also suit you well.
Hatuns, put the chest between the beds
of Yigit Alp and Dundar Bey.
And bring the chest of Sungurtekin Bey
from Mother Hayme's state tent...
...and put it right there.
But be careful, it is a little heavy.
God bless you.
May I come in?
Welcome, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Halime Sultan.
-It is obvious that you glamourized here.
-Do you like it?
Is it possible for you
to make something bad?
Ertugrul Bey, I do not know how I will
endure until tomorrow.
I have missed Yigit and Dundar so much.
Longing is over now, Halime Sultan.
When our child is born, it's uncle will be
here just as my brothers, if God permits.
-This is what makes me happy.
-If God permits.
Ertugrul Bey, I know that the
migration time is near.
I hope we will not need to be separated...
...from our beloved ones
when reach The Byzantium border.
In this holly journey, it's not separation
that falls to our share. Instead, it is...
...keeping our state tent and nomad group
together. And it is our duty to do...
...whatever it takes. We will see that,
when we migrate together, Halime Sultan.
Let's go now. It is Nawruz.
My mother waits for us.
Bey!
I could not succeed to get dressed
on my own.
I can help you.
No, Selcan! I do not need help.
It is nawruz, Bey. Your mother
wants you by her side.
Your Alps and your brothers too.
I do not want to appear before people
under these conditions, Selcan.
I do not know what I do anymore.
I tortured you and myself very much.
Do not talk like this.
No, Selcan, no.
I cannot appear before Alps
in this situation.
How long will it take for me to recover?
What will I do if something happens
to our nomad group?
Let me help you. It is Nawruz.
No, Selcan, no.
I do not want to appear before Alps
in this situation.
They should not see me like this.
May our sustenance overflow.
May our joy be permanent.
May our nomad groub be merry.
Come here child, take it.
Welcome, my dear.
Please.
Bring it to me. Bring it.
May all the evil burn with this
Nawruz fire!
May the grudge inside of us be cleaned up
with the Nawruz fire!
May the cruelty in the world
come to an end!
May our nomad group be filled with peace!
Happy nawruz!
-Amen!
Move! Turali Alp is coming!
He is coming to be circumcised!
He is coming to be a brave man!
He will be a real man!
Come on, my lad!
God!
Turali, it is time to be an Alp.
I will be an Alp like you, Ertugrul Bey.
-God bless you!
God bless you!
Turali, I have a present for you.
Take it.
It is exactly the gift that I
wanted to have.
It is bigger than the present
of Artuk Bey.
I wish Wild Demir could make my present.
Turali Alp, if you are ready, let's start.
Will I get hurt so much, Artuk Bey?
It is not much for a brave man like you.
Then, let's start.
Come on. Come on.
In the name of God!
Come on!
God bless!
Our nomad group already deserved
such a joviality.
Our people were longing for peace.
I hope this peace will be permanent.
-But...
-I also think what you think, brother.
Goncagul escaped.
It is not certain when will Noyan appear.
Sadettin Kobek is like a rabid dog.
Our nomad groups are under threat.
We need to be ready for war, brother.
This is exactly what I wanted to tell you,
brother.
This silence is not a good sign.
It seems that our nomad group will deal
with various troubles.
Our Alps do not have a leader.
If my brother quits The Head Alp
position...
...I want you to take over his duty.
Go on wrestlers!
Go on! Go on!
May God give you a long life,
Banu Cicek Hatun!
Long live, Banu Cicek Hatun!
Long live Banu Cicek! Long live!
-Banu Cicek won.
-Long live Banu Cicek!
-Long Live!
-God bless you! God bless!
God bless!
God bless you all.
Banu Cicek did not only win this
contest...
...but also risked her life to get
rid of the betrayers...
...that have beeen pestered to
our nomad group.
This is for you, Banu Cicek.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
We learned to risk our lives when
needed, from the best. From You.
If there is a hero, it is our elders like
you who tought us our morals.
May God bestow you to
your father and mother.
-May God give you children just like you.
-Amen.
God bless! God bless!
May God give everybody a child like you.
-God bless her!
-Look at her and see!
-God bless!
God bless! God bless!
Ertugrul Bey!
Yes, Tugtekin Bey.
Come on, pick an Alp
that you trust to his fists...
...thus we see whose Alp one is stronger.
As you please, Tugtekin Bey.
Pick your Alp.
I choose Bogac. Who do you choose?
Choose me, Bey, choose me!
Go out there, Bamsi!
Thank you, Bey!
Bogac! Bogac! Bogac!
Go Bogac!
Come on! Come on my lad!
Bogac! Bogac! Bogac!
Come on, Bogac!
Go on Bamsi, go on!
Come on!
God bless!
God!
Come on, brother!
Go on, Bogac!
Go on!
Bamsi! Bamsi! Bamsi!
Come on, Bamsi!
Come on!
-Surrender, brother!
-No!
-Give in, brother!
-Give in brother!
-No!
Brother!
I surrender!
Bamsi! Bamsi! Bamsi!
Where are you going, brother?
You will win the next time!
My lad!
Bamsi Alp.
You proved what a strong man
you are even in this ring.
This quiver is the prize of your success.
Thank you, Bey.
Bamsi Alp!
What is wrong with you In such a merry
day?
If you permit mother, my brother and I
want to talk to you about something.
What happened?
Hayme Hatun, Gundogdu Bey's illness
is beyond my knowledge.
What are you saying, Artuk Bey?
Gundogdu Bey needs to go to Erzurum
and recover there as soon as possible.
Under these conditions, for my brother
to continue being the Head Alp...
...will cause weakness
in the nomad group.
We need to solve this before
no one hears about it, mother.
Thank you.
Now leave me alone, Selcan.
-Bey!
-Selcan.
God!
Please do not test me more
with this pain.
Take my life and save me.
May God heal my Bey.
-Selcan Hatun.
-Yes.
Gokce Hatun wants to see
you in her state tent.
I am coming.
You’ve asked for me to come
to visit you, Gokce Hatun.
Sister!
Gokce!
What happened to you?
Tell me. What is this?
Aytolun!
What happened to that infernal woman?
She learnt everything, sister.
What did she learn?
Everything. She told to Tugtekin Bey.
Gokce, tell me. What did she tell?
She told, I was in love with
Ertugrul Bey once upon a time...
...how I got stabbed, she told
everything to Tugtekin Bey.
I told him I could not have a child.
Gokce!
Sister! He does not
look into my eyes!
He does not talk with
me anymore! -Well. Well.
Sister, he told me that I lied,
please! He told me that I tricked!
He told me that I slept with
him even I love Ertugrul!
He told me that I gave him hope
knowing that I cannot give him a child.
Sister!
Sister, what will I do?
Sister, please, I am
begging you, please help me!
Sister, please show me a
way! -Alright, Gokce. Alright!
Alright.
I will take your revenge, aunt.
No one can defeat me!
Do not even try!
I did not come here to kill you. I
came here to give you a lot of gold.
No one can buy me.
A woman can never buy me.
I know the service you
have provided to my father
for the less of this, Bogac Alp.
What do you want from me?
Ertugrul!
You cannot give me what
I want, Goncagul Hatun.
Do you want more gold? Or a position?
You cannot give me those
while Beys and Alps of
two nomad groups are following you.
They will find you and kill you.
I know a person that can give
more than you want, Bogac Alp.
It is not about gold or position.
It is about if you
have courage or not.
Can I come in, son?
Of course mom, come in.
How are you?
How can I be, mom?
I do not have power even to shoot
arrows to the enemy or to hold a quiver.
I feel like I am carrying the carrion
of an animal that I do not want.
Gondogdu.
This illness will take my life
just as it took my father's life.
Please do not talk like this, son.
For god's sake, do not talk like this.
Today I was embarrassed
In front of Alps, mom.
I wanted someone to
cut my arm and save me.
How will this end up?
Artuk Bey said that he
detoxicated the poison in my arm
but he is not
explaining the situation.
Artuk Bey wants us to go
Erzurum as soon as possible.
You have a troublesome thorn abscess that
is beyond his knowledge of medicine, son.
A wise doctor will
wait for us therein.
Why did he tell this
to you, not to me?
Because it is not
only about your arm.
What is it about?
It is about the duty that
two nomad groups gave to you.
You have to quit being
the head of the Alps, son.
Tomorrow I will ask for two nomad
groups to gather headquarters.
I do not want to debilitate Alps.
And you don't want it as well.
Of course I do not want, mom.
If you permit, I will tell my
decision in the headquarters tomorrow.
I wish to keep it among three of us.
Blood!
Everywhere will be blood!
Blood will clean up the
grunge inside you, Noyan!
Mountains will be blessed
with  the blood you
put under each tree!
Blood, blessed blood!
You will smell both scents
that you like the most.
The scent of blood and woman.
This woman will give you that blessed
blood that you will drink thirstily.
She will give it!
Noyan!
What happened, brother?
Brothers, I could not
decide what to wear tonight
while asking for the girl's hand in
marriage. Should I wear this or that one?
You’d better wear my armor!
Brother, you are not going to war.
Wear something clean, it is enough.
Thing called as love
is such a weird thing.
Take shelter, brother.
The big philosopher’s
started talking again.
Brother, when I look at Dogan brother
I think that love is
such a valuable thing.
Like the Luna Moth
flying around the Nawruz fire.
Brother, love is
such a valuable thing.
I swear, I saw it and understood it.
Brothers, look what
happened to brother Dogan.
Almighty God, you are so powerful.
Say what you want so say.
Say a word and let us listen.
Brother, the love of a
brave man to his woman
is like a Luna moth which does not flee
from fire although it knows it will burn.
It is like the love of God.
And I am asking you
if anyone who does not have love  for
any human being, can he love his God?
I swear, love is something valuable.
It even encouraged
Bamsi to talk. Well done.
Well brother Bamsi, tell us,
when will you fall in love?
Yes, come on, tell us.
No brothers, no.
Mine is Shahada love, my woman
is my sword, say it never again.
Say it never again. Never
say it again, brothers.
Say it never again.
Never say it again, brothers.
-Never again okay, never again.
Thank God who gave you to me.
From now on, there is only one
obstacle to hug you and our baby.
What are you saying, Gundogdu?
I need to get rid of
this trouble, right away.
-I hope, God will heal you.
-If God permits, Hatun.
Artuk Bey said that my
remedy is in Erzurum.
I will go to Erzurum with my
mother as soon as possible.
Do not leave me here alone,
Bey. Take me with you.
No way, Selcan.
You are pregnant, you cannot
come. I will go with my mother.
Please do not go without me.
How can I wait you therein? I will
be thinking about you all that time.
How can you travel all that
road on horseback, Selcan?
We do not want to
be sad one more time.
Let's not make my mother
and Tugtekin Bey wait more.
How long will it take, Bey?
Bey.
Take my life...
...or look at my face.
Please, tell me something.
Do not make me live with this shame.
I took you from Mother Hayme's nomad tent.
I took you to my tent.
I am responsible from your
life and your honor until I die.
Beyond is your problem.
Your shame, your destiny.
Mother Hayme is coming with
her sons and her brides, Bey.
Welcome, Mother Hayme.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
Welcome.
Thank you, Gokce Hatun.
Come inside.
-Welcome, Bey.
-Welcome, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
Tugtekin Bey.
Welcome.
Come in. -Thank you.
-Tugtekin Bey.
-Halime Sultan.
Gokce Hatun.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Almighty Ameer!
Goncagul Hatun wants to come to
your presence with a Dodurga Alp.
She may come.
Why are you here?
I learnt from Gumustekin Bey to stand by
the state on no account, Ameer Almighty.
And the slanders of Ertugrul Bey?
What do you think about them?
What I think is not
important, Hazrat Ameer.
The important thing
is how I’ll serve you.
I know that you are such a precious Ameer
that you will not let the people involve
in the fight of Beys, Ameer Almighty.
I am happy to see your
bond to your state, child.
Bogac Alp has precious news for you.
Really?
What is it?
Dundar Bey who is the
brother of Ertugrul Bey
and Shahzada Yigit who is
the brother of Halime Sultan
are about to come to the nomad group.
How did you learn this?
I know that Halime Sultan is making
preparations for a tent for two children.
My loyalty to you will not be
limited with this, Ameer Almighty.
You will understand this with
each news I brought to you.
I punish every infidelity...
...but I reward every loyalty.
Do you understand me?
I understand you, Ameer Almighty.
Good.
Now go and be my eyes and
ears in the nomad group.
Do you know the importance of the
news that he gave, Goncagul Hatun?
The sons of Sultan Aleaddin
Shazada Izzettin and Shazada Husrev.
These two children are the
only heir of Seljukian throne.
What can be more important
than this, Ameer Almighty?
You are as clever as your father.
But let me remind you something.
Do not forget that you’re
entering into the politics game.
To take your revenge and survive
you need my help, Goncagul Hatun.
I know, Ameer Almighty. I know.
My only aim is to take revenge
of my father and my aunt.
Ameer Almighty! Merchant
Abdullah wants to see you.
Make him wait.
Noyan came.
I told him not to come but
he did not listen to me.
Noyan?
What does he want?
-You.
-Me?
I know how you stole Gundogdu's
heart and how you trapped him.
Do you want me to behave that man
that Ogeday threw him out from his army
like I behaved to
Gundogdu, Ameer Almighty?
I know, Noyan is wild.
But he is not as smart as you.
My confidence in your
intelligence is absolute.
If you be his frailty, this
will  help both you and me.
I know after you took
the seal from my father
you gave it to Tangut to
kill Noyan, Hazrat Almighty.
After Noyan is done with Ertugrul
he will want to kill you immediately.
Neither his scarce mind nor power
is enough for this. Don’t worry.
Act to Noyan as you acted to
Gundogdu to indulge our wishes.
Do whatever you can to be his frailty
and even get into his den.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Good.
The Alps that I sent to look for
Goncagul came back to the nomad group.
Is there any news?
Unfortunately, they
could not chase her down.
She will get what she deserves soon.
Let's not foul this beautiful night
with the name of that ominous woman.
You are right, Ertugrul Bey.
How is your arm, Gundogdu Bey?
-If God permits, it will be better.
-If God permits.
If God permits.
Tugtekin Bey, Alps showed
their abilities in nawruz.
Bamsi Alp brought Bogac
Alp to his knees, Dogan Alp.
Which son of Adam can take a stand
against Bamsi Alp, Tugtekin Bey?
I hope, Bogac will
forget this defeat.
Of course he will,
what else can he do?
And our all Alps are one, right?
It is an honor to be
defeated by a Kayi Alp.
Am I wrong, Ertugrul Bey?
I told you not to
come here, right Noyan?
What else I can do if scent
of woman outweighed your words.
Goncagul Hatun is
stricken with grief.
I saw the Alp of Armed man Tugtekin.
Is it Goncagul Hatun's cunningness?
So you’ve smelled blood, right?
What did Armed man's Alp say?
Ertugrul's brother Dundar
and Halime Hatun's brother...
-Shazada Yigit?
-Yes.
They will come back to the nomad
group from Erzurum tomorrow.
I am sure you want to
welcome them kindly.
You can be sure that
I will show kindness.
But Shazada Yigit's blood is royal.
I do not want him to die. -I
think you want to kill him at last.
I want to talk about the main issue
which brought us together tonight.
If you let me, Tugtekin
Bey. -Yes, Mother Hayme.
Dogan grew up in my own arms
just like Bamsi and
Turgut and my own sons.
Just as Banu Cicek who grew up
with Korkut Bey and Duru Hatun.
Thank you.
These young people’ve lost
their heart to each other.
They want to get permission and set
up a home and raise good children.
With the permission of God
and the words of Prophet
we want Banu Cicek to Dogan Alp
who is the Alp of Ertugrul.
Banu Cicek and Dogan Alp are
honor of two nomad groups.
They both risked their lives
to protect the honor
of the two nomad groups.
They are both so precious for us.
If Ertugrul Bey also allows
we would be happy
for their happiness.
May God make them one and happy.
If you and my mother favor,
their happiness makes us happy.
Thank you, Ertugrul Bey. Thank you.
Cicek Hatun. -Yes, Bey.
You devoted your life to my
father and to our nomad group.
From now on you will devote your life
to your husband and to Kayi nomad group.
So you know all these and still
want this brave Alp, right?
I know, Tugtekin Bey.
I would die for Dodurga
nomad group and you.
But my destiny
and the path my heart follows
are drawn with Dogan Alp.
Alright.
Do have a word, Dogan Alp?
May God protect you, Tugtekin Bey.
Thanks God, you allowed us
in this happy nawruz day.
Thank you.
Then, may God make you happy.
Well Bamsi, Dogan is
also getting married.
It is your turn.
My woman is my sword.
Brothers, Tugtekin Bey
gave Banu Cicek to me!
God!
Congratulations, brother!
Brother! Congratulations, brother!
So that you are getting married, I
want to give your wedding gift early.
Here.
What is this?
Your new sword.
Banu Cicek will not
allow you to inculcate
so brother Turgut made it to
inculcate with brother Turali.
Congratulations, brother.
There are important matters that
we need to talk in headquarters.
We need to talk them
as soon as possible.
Is it about migration, Mother Hayme?
Yes, it is time to
talk about it, but...
...there are other important matters.
I will inform Beys and we can gather our
headquarters tomorrow, if God permits.
I want to talk about this
matter with you, as well.
But you should know that
this migration will not be
like removing our tents
and gathering our flocks.
Sadettin Kobek.
Ertugrul Bey is right.
He said he will call us to account
for the killer he protected.
We will see what kind of a
trouble he causes us, soon.
He cannot do anything as long as
these two nomad groups are together.
You are right, brother.
But he can do everything
because he has the seal of the state.
Forgive me, father.
Forgive me.
I have to do this.
Noyan.
You remind me the lands
that I was born in, woman.
Gobi desert's rain is
as salty as your tears.
It is as desolate as your eyes.
It's winds are as warm
as your breath in gloom during the day.
It's night is as cold as your heart.
While the sun blights the desert...
...I was finding solace
in the ice that hid behind the rocks.
What do you want from me, Noyan?
I want to get lost in the solitude
of your eyes...
...and I want melt in the warmth
of your breath.
I will come and take you after
I am done with Shahzada tomorrow.
Wait for me.
I have missed Yigit so much.
This is the first time
we remained separated that long.
The longing inside me
is growing with time.
If God permits, they will come safe
and sound soon.
If God permits, Bey.
But I will keep worrying until Yigit and
Dundar come back to nomad group.
Because he is a Shahzada, my brother
did not have a moment of peace.
We suffered a lot,
we survived many hardships.
I am afraid that something
will happen to him.
Thank you.
Please, Beys, please.
Hayme Hatun wanted to talk to Beys
about the matters of the nomad group.
If she permits, I want Mother Hayme
to manage the headquarters...
...because she is our elder.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
With the 99 names of Almighty God...
...the One who created us...
...and filled our hearts with faith.
In the name of God.
Beys! Brave men!
Nobles of my nomad group, welcome.
There are problems that we have to solve.
But first...
...I want to give the word to Gundogdu Bey
who is the Head of Alps.
He would like to tell us something.
Please, Gundogdu Bey.
If God permits, I will go to Erzurum
with Mother Hayme to see a doctor...
...which Artuk Bey advised us
after headquarters.
The situation of my arm is unknown.
While I am in this state...
...for the safety of Alps and the people...
...I am withdrawing from Head of Alps duty.
Your decision made us sad, Gundogdu Bey.
Thank you, Bey. This is our destiny.
If you permit...
...for the security of headquarters
I want to choose a Head of Alp.
It is obvious that Ameer Sadettin and
Noyan will not leave us in peace.
I want to see...
...Ertugrul Bey as the Head of Alp.
Of course, if he accepts.
Right, right.
Ertugrul Bey is the best choice.
We want him to be our Head of Alps.
-Yes, Ertugrul should be the Head of Alps.
-Yes.
That's true.
Thank you.
I am honored...
...because you deemed me worthy
of this important duty.
But...
...I have other things to arrange
before this duty.
If Ertugrul Bey has more important
matters than being Head of Alps...
...surely he will tell us
when the time comes.
Then, I want to declare my own candidate.
Sungurtekin Bey.
What do you think about this,
Sungurtekin Bey?
If you Beys permit...
...I want to officiate this holy duty
with honor.
Does anyone has a say about this?
We want Sungurtekin Bey as
the Head of Alps, Hayme Hatun.
He will bring strength to the nomad group,
Hayme Hatun.
Yes, we want to see Sungurtekin Bey
as the Head of Alps.
Tugtekin Bey?
We would be honored
to have him at this post.
Thank you.
Sungurtekin Bey.
-May your holy duty be beneficent.
-Thank you.
Good luck with it, brother.
No matter where trouble comes from...
...I will be leading our Alps
until I my last breath.
-Congratulations.
-Congratulations, Bey.
Congratulations.
It is the time, Ulubilge.
Ertugrul, his wife and his unborn child...
...will slowly fall into my trap.
Everyone who lives in Suleyman Shah's
marquee...
...will get their share from my sword.
And Kobek?
Let him think that he is
holding my halter.
He will understand that he cannot even be
the hoof of the horse that I ride...
...for revenge, when I cut his head.
No one can ever betray Noyan and survive.
When the time comes...
...Kobek will go beside Tangut.
He will suffer torment forever
with the underground souls.
He will get his share from
Erlik Khan's torment.
Prepare a big feast tonight.
There will be a precious guest
along with my captives.
As you please, Noyan.
May the lands that we fight, wander and
spill blood, be our home!
Our home!
My brave men who follow Genghis Khan,
it is time for revenge!
-For revenge!
-Revenge!
For blood!
We are ready to die for Noyan!
May you have your revenge!
For revenge! For blood!
We are ready to die for Noyan!
May you have your revenge!
For revenge! For blood!
We are ready to die for Noyan!
After all these sufferings, I understood...
...that unity made us powerful.
I hope the union of the two nomad groups,
this sharing of fate...
...will continue against the Mongols
and the betrayers inside us.
Tugtekin Bey is right.
Kayis and Dodurgas are partners in fate.
Everyone friend or foe knows this.
We are stronger now, you are right, Bey.
So it is time to talk about migration.
I think the most appropriate
place is Ahlat.
It's fertile mountains are suitable
to feed our flocks.
And our commerce with Ahlat will get
strong as our Sultan reclaimed.
-Right.
Ahlat is on the road of trade routes.
My heart's desire is this too.
We can depart soon if fate
so decrees, Bey.
It's road is smooth and safe.
We can arrive and settle
within the shortest time.
Elders and children can go slowly.
No one will fall in the ditch
on the road.
Does anybody wants to say anything?
If you permit,
I want to talk, Mother Hayme.
Yes, Ertugrul Bey, have your say.
Brave men of Oghuz!
The destiny that calls for the union of
the two nomad groups is praiseworthy.
I became aware of something while fighting
neck and neck with all troubles...
...and ominous enemies...
...it is time to migrate not to where
our herds will feed...
...but on the holy road of our destiny.
How is this a holy road, Bey?
Do not we migrate for our herds?
Tell us, Ertugrul Bey.
What is on your mind?
This blessed road is
a holy war road for us.
This blessed road is our road to
holy war for our nomad groups...
...which are stuck between two worlds.
If we continue to follow our herds...
...there will be no Oghuz's customs,
being an Alp or peace left.
As the wind blows, as the rain falls
they will take us from ourselves.
Your words inflames the lion inside
each brave man, Ertugrul Bey.
But if you want us to fight with the
Mongols who holds one part of the world...
...would we not put our nomad group
on a path that is unknown?
Wars or jihad are not with the Mongols...
...but in the lands where the sun sets.
In the Byzantine border of our state.
Are we going to war?
Permission! Ameer Sadettin Kobek!
Come in.
-Last night Noyan came.
-I know, yes.
He visited me last night.
He said he will take me
when he is done with the Shahzada.
So...
...will you go?
As a follower of our cause...
I would like to see
the fate of our Shahzada and Dundar.
Good.
But be careful.
Noyan should not learn that
you are under my command.
Otherwise, without a care of your tears...
...he would gouge your beautiful eyes out.
Do not worry, your highness Ameer.
I will do what is necessary.
Good. Good.
What are you saying, Ertugrul Bey?
Do you want to put us in a dangerous
position after all these trouble?
If someone asks me...
...to assign someone for
the pride of my nomad group...
...I would assign you without
hesitation, Ertugrul Bey.
Thank you, Tugtekin Bey.
But I am not only responsible of myself.
As Gundogdu Bey says...
...I disapprove the unknown path
for our two nomad groups.
Ertugrul Bey offered us
a different migration route.
I would like to discuss this
with the Beys of the two nomad groups.
I do not understand what
you want to discuss, Mother Hayme.
I don't want to understand either.
People want to migrate to Ahlat,
it is obvious.
-True.
-He is right.
Gundogdu Bey is right.
Gundogdu Bey,
headquarters is a consultation place.
Each Bey has a right to talk.
Of course.
But will we be migrating to the Byzantine
border because of Ertugrul Bey's request?
Ask to Beys...
...who will want something like that
after all those wars and exhaustion?
Gundogdu Bey, Noyan's unrest and
Sadettin Kobek's troubles are not over.
We cannot sacrifice our nomad groups'
destiny for sweet dreams.
Ertugrul Bey, your will is obvious
but ask to the Beys.
Who wants to fight with
the Byzantine again?
I think we should discuss this matter.
I think the same, as the Head of Alps,
Gundogdu Bey.
The ones who wants to discuss
Ertugrul Bey's idea...
...please put your hands up.
No. No. I do not accept.
Do you have anything to say, Ertugrul Bey?
Yes, Mother Hayme.
Here, the word is yours.
You should know that the lands
that will shape not only our fate...
...but also all Oghuz tribes' destiny...
...may be where the sun sets
but it will be where we shall rise.
The lands that will protect us from
powerless governors and ill ambitions...
...where our great people can take root
are near the Byzantine border.
We can only be united and in solidarity
with war, jihad and conquest.
These are my last words.
It is time to migrate for me.
The ones who believe in me
and has faith in his heart...
...will come with me without any doubt.
May God speed all of us.
With your permission.
I have never seen Ertugrul Bey like this.
Will we wait like this, brother?
Of course not.
Let's follow him, if he does not want,
we can turn back.
Come on, to the horses!
My mother and brothers,
I missed all of them a lot.
I am longing for my sister.
Mostly, I wonder about
my brother Sungurtekin.
Did you not see him before?
He left the nomad group when I was a baby.
I would not recognize if I saw him.
Our road is almost finished, Dundar Bey.
If God permits, you will meet
with your brother soon.
If God permits, brother. If God permits.
Tell Noyan that we found those two boys.
Sungur, look after Ertugrul.
The condition of
our nomad group is obvious.
We cannot go on a new adventure.
Halime, Selcan.
Take care of Dundar and Yigit
when we are not here.
-We will come back as soon as possible.
-If God permits, mother.
May God speed you. Do not think about us.
Do not worry, mother.
May Gundogdu Bey found his cure.
Daughter Gokce.
You are sad for a long time.
Is there something you do not tell?
No, Mother Hayme. Nothing.
May God speed you.
May God save you all.
May God speed you, Bey.
-Goodbye, daughter.
-May God speed you, Mother Hayme.
Mother.
-May God speed you.
-Goodbye, Gundogdu Bey.
Thank you, son.
May you find your cure
as soon as possible, Bey.
In the name of God!
Welcome, Selcan Hatun.
Thank you, Bey.
Did Gundogdu Bey go?
-Yes.
-May God unite you again.
Thank you.
-I hope that he finds a cure there.
-If God permits, Bey.
Yes, I am listening to you.
Gokce, Bey.
She has been sad for a long time.
She stopped eating, has gone all pale.
She is your woman. I cannot say anything
if you don't permit.
But I cannot stand to see
my sister like this.
Selcan Hatun.
You are precious to me because
of your mercy, courage, honesty.
I hold you dear in my marquee...
...but this is between me and Gokce Hatun.
What is the matter between you, Bey?
When I look at Gokce Hatun
I see a woman who would die for you...
...who can live for your life
if it is required, what is the matter?
Do not give me a hard time, Selcan Hatun.
I do not want to offend you.
You offended my sister,
you broke her to pieces.
Selcan Hatun!
Do you think that I will never resent
if you break me to pieces...
...if you break my heart, Bey?
I know, if you did not love her...
...you would not let her stay
in your state tent, in your bed.
Do not do this. I cannot stand a man and
a woman in love to be in this situation.
Please, Bey!
She lied to me.
She lied to me while her heart
was still in love with Ertugrul!
Did you want to hear this?
Is this the matter, Bey?
You are obsessing about the innocent
whim of an innocent child.
Innocent? Do you call this innocent?
Gokce told this to me, Selcan Hatun.
She said that she rubbed salt in her wound
when Ertugrul Bey took Halime Sultan...
...to the nomad group but
she still could not forget him.
She said that she branded her wound with
hot iron when he got married with Halime...
...but she still could not forget him,
she said that it did not work.
Did she not say the things
that happened later?
That she understood God's reason
when He brought you to her?
That her love for Ertugrul was not real.
Did she not say that she found real love
in your eyes and in your sweet words?
Did you not see her excitement...
...happiness and peace
the night you got married?
What about getting stabbed?
That she  cannot give a child to me!
And she hid this from me!
How can I share my marquee with a woman...
...who hides the truth from me?
It is not your duty to interfere with
the volition of God, Tugtekin Bey.
I lost my children before they were born.
Gundogdu Bey buried them in the ground
before I breastfed them.
God then blessed me with one more child.
My only wish is to hold him in
my arms and see him grow.
What is past is past.
The volition of God is the love
of Gokce for you.
Do not do this, Bey.
Do not torture the one who loves you
and the one who you love.
The matter in my marquee should stay
in my nomad tent, Selcan Hatun.
Just go your own way.
Let everyone suffer from their own pain.
-Are we ready?
-We are almost ready, Bey.
-Alps are getting ready.
-When shall we depart?
-Whenever you are ready.
-Well, alright.
If you are ready, let's go.
We are already quiet near.
We should not have stopped.
Dundar Bey, Yigit Bey, run!
Protect their path!
Inform the nomad group brother, hurry up!
Cutting your head will be pleasure for me!
Attack!
Why are we running away?
Why do we not fight?
It is not possible, Bey!
They are too many!
We cannot deal with them! It is our duty
to take you safe and sound!
You go on!
Come on! Come on, Yigit!
You cannot resist to Noyan!
You should surrender!
We shall not surrender, Yigit!
If we surrender, we will die!
I don't even think about
surrendering, Dundar Bey.
Surrender!
You cannot resist to Noyan!
My brave!
My Alp!
Help them, Ertugrul Bey!
Dundar Bey and Yigit Alp...
...are in danger.
They are in the slope below.
Who did this?
No...
Noyan!
Put them down.
I do not have a problem with you.
How can I have a problem
with two children?
My problem is with Ertugrul.
I said, put them down!
Take them.
Noyan!
Look at you!