Episode 40 will start after 12:35 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Is this the sherbet?
Now.
Listen to me carefully.
Those two have something
that belong to us.
We will take it and leave.
We do not want to hurt anyone.
Especially while we have
your wife and daughter.
Nice.
Take this sherbet pitcher to those two.
Take it to them so we take that
belongs to us and leave quietly.
You do not want a blood bath, right?
Help us under the name of El Safi, God.
My God!
Help us under the name of El Safi, God!
Help us my God for the salvation
of Suleyman Shah's son, Ertugrul
who has rebelled against cruelty for you.
-My God!
Thank God. Thank God we have saved him.
Thank God.
That is it.
Okay, girl. Thank you.
But, hide these well.
I will hide somewhere that even
evil cannot find. You do not worry.
I do not, girl.
You go sleep and I will keep watching.
Do I have permission, Bey?
Come in.
I came here to ask if you
need something, Bey.
No, thank you.
This sherbet is on the house.
You and your daughter drink it.
Thank you very much.
-Have a good evening, Bey.
-You, too.
Take it.
Good night.
Thank you, Father Demir, you, too.
Mother.
Mother!
Ertugrul.
Where is he?
-Ertugrul is safe.
You do not worry.
Mother. Get up.
Mother. Come on, drink it.
Drink it.
How are you feeling, mother?
I am fine.
I am better now.
Thank God.
Selcan.
Come with me.
I was rude...
...and rough to you.
I have disregarded your rights and
friendship in front of everyone.
I have hit you with my damn hand.
I apologize for every single of them.
Bey, you are getting too many burdens
on your shoulders every single day.
We all deserve happiness and peace.
And you mostly.
I know that, you will have it soon,
if God permits.
If God permits.
Selcan.
-Yes, Bey?
I want a child.
I want my bloodline to continue.
That is why
I need to marry with a new woman.
That is okay if you agree with that.
But if you do not accept a second wife
I will divorce you.
Think it thoroughly
and then make a quick decision.
Could you not sleep?
They will request to execution of
my brother in the headquarters tomorrow.
How can I sleep?
Forget about headquarters
and the execution.
Let's talk about you.
Sit down.
And also about my aunt.
Now, I want a child, Ertugrul.
And a peaceful home.
But I could not find both with Selcan.
I have told her. I have told clearly.
I have said that I will have another wife.
I said that stay with me if you agree
or I will divorce you.
What did she say?
Nothing.
Ertugrul, they will talk about your
execution in the headquarters tomorrow.
And see our topic here.
Whatever is the will of god,
it will happen, brother.
Correct. Correct.
Do you have anyone in your heart?
Who is she? Goncagul?
How could you know it?
I understood it while talking to aunt.
My God!
My wife and brother know the thing
that I cannot tell it to myself.
Do not stand against your heart, brother.
However, do not send aunt
to your mother's marquee.
She did not deserve it.
And she could not take it.
Actually, I do not know how she will
take another wife but
you do not divorce her anyway.
Sister.
Forgive me.
Brother.
Thank God you are fine.
How will we endure this pain, Hayme?
Today my child.
Tomorrow your child.
Where did we make a mistake, Hayme?
My son...
...is not a murderer.
He would...
...rather die thousand times...
...than killing a brave one
from his own blood.
Do you not know...
...your nephew who you fought
with against...
...enemy lots of times?
He has...
...put his life into danger...
...in order to kill...
...that traitor Kocabash.
He has...
...come to nomad group...
...and walked into so many angry Alps.
Have you ever think why?
Why?
I know that I have committed so many sins
so Mighty God punished me
with this pain, Hayme.
Karabek. Be careful with him, brother.
He was there when Noyan got me prisoner.
What are you saying, Ertugrul?
While my hand was being nailed
he was watching heartily.
My God! What kind of a hell this is?
Bey.
Korkut Bey has come to marquee
to see Mother Hayme.
You go, brother.
It will be a long night.
Do not leave mother alone.
Almighty God.
Forgive me.
Forgive my son. Spare my sister
and Hayme's life, too.
Do you feel guilty, uncle?
Do you not, son?
Which one of us is innocent
of these incidents?
Ertugrul? You? Hayme?
It is now too late to find
the answer, uncle.
Decision that will be made
in the headquarters tomorrow
will make two nomad groups
and state desperate.
See the truth and be on Ertugrul's side.
They will not be able
to kill Ertugrul, mother.
They will not be able to kill him.
I will not allow it.
Mother.
Mother. Do not move.
Mother. Stop.
Mother.
Mother!
Wait, mother!
Midwife!
Call Artuk Bey right now! Now!
Hold on, mother!
Mother, hold on!
Mother.
You have matched each other very well.
But the game is over now.
I do not know what you have
in that sinister head of yours
but from now on I will show everyone
how evil you are!
-Sister!
-Shut your mouth, Gokce.
You cannot see their spider webs
that they spined around you.
Get out!
Move! Come, Gokce!
Hanim!
Forgive me, Selcan Hatun.
-What?
Mother Hayme got worse.
You should know that I have
informed Artuk Bey.
What is this noise, Aytolun?
Is there any problem?
Mother Hayme.
Bey, Korkut Bey is here.
He wants to see you.
Let him in.
Did you kill my son, Ertugrul?
Mother.
Mother, I will sacrifice myself for you.
Please do not leave us.
Mother! Mother!
Mother.
What do you want to know, uncle?
Do you want to know the mystery of
Karabek who wants to take my head
by command of Saadettin Kobek
and who is also came from Noyan's table
and stay in your marquee?
My mother has paid the price of me
giving you Kocabash's head
who was trying to destroy nomad group.
So you also want me to ask
for your forgiveness?
Mother.
I will not give my brother to hands
of those infidels.
You stay with us, too, mother.
For the love of God!
I am ready.
I am ready, Bey.
We all are bound up with our death, Hayme.
However...
...those who live in this marquee
are bound up with more.
They are bound up with world's state.
Neither you nor someone in our blood
have right to give up.
Those battles which never stop
will be always in our marquee.
Neither you nor marquee's women
have any right to hesitate
and surrender for any moment.
Now get up
and embrace your blessed pain
which vouchsafed to every Oghuz woman.
Embrace it as if it is your child.
Embrace your pain with compassion.
You must know that I am with you
all the time, Hayme.
Suleyman.
You must lead our children and
nomad group until that blessed time
even world would go upside down, Hayme.
The darkness which will cover the world
will be enlightened by the light
that will rise from this marquee.
Bey.
Gundogdu Bey. Bey.
Gundogdu Bey.
Come on, Bey.
Come on.
Mother.
You go outside, too. Call the midwife.
In the name of God.
I have told you that cur Noyan
will not wait until summer
to battle with nomad group.
You have not believed me.
Your son has paid the price.
And now do you want to clear
your conscience by blaming me?
Tell me, uncle. What do you want?
We are under attack!
We are under attack! It is Mongols!
Wear your weapons!
Artuk Bey, do not leave mother!
Cover the tent!
Mongols have invaded the tent, Bey.
Open the door. Open it!
Die!
Mother!
Hatuns, are you alright?
Thank God.
Are you allright?
Mother Hayme!
Artuk Bey, is my mother alright?
Thank God.
May God never test anyone like this,
Selcan Hatun.
Hayme Hatun's life in one hand,
yours in the other.
Thank God,
I was able to stop the bleeding.
You got us into this trouble, Ertugrul.
You stubbornness caused this.
Uncle...
..can't you see the Mongols are after
something else?
Even if Tugtekin and Ertugrul is dead
they will never stop their attempts
against the life of
our mothers and sisters.
Enough Uncle.
Enough.
What is your agenda?
Don't you understand
what's going on?
You have done everything to
put me in that cage like a rat.
Look, I got out.
Now I will go to that cage myself.
Do you know why, Uncle?
To make you and all the other Beys
to see the truth.
We will settle our scores
tomorrow at the tribunal.
You will see how Noyan deceived you.
After the trial, I will see your
wretched head rolling on the ground!
Murderer!
We must bring Tugtekin
to the camp immediately.
He will not be able to save me from
execution in his condition, brother.
Everything will come to an end
if something happens to him.
I will leave with Artuk Bey, to see him.
May God help you.
May God help all of us.
This must come to an end
after the tribunal tomorrow.
Every breath Ertugrul takes,
gives birth to tears,
betrayal and more blood.
This sinister and bloody raid is the
ultimate proof of this.
Karabek, do you know
what you are trying to imply?
What does Ertugrul have to do
with this raid?
He was locked in a cage.
He may be executed tomorrow.
Karabek is right.
The nomad has been weakened.
You have gathered the Alps of two nomad
groups outside with Gundogdu, why?
In order to keep them from
fighting each other.
Gumustekin Bey, you will take the Alps of
Dodurga down the valley.
And I will take the Kaya Alps
down the river.
Only the scouting Alps will remain
in the square.
They will secure the both nomad groups
tents and the cage.
Noyan took advantage of this situation.
They attacked the nomad tent to die,
not to gain a victory.
Who would have thought
they would be this mad?
You are right.
The one who's responsible for this is the
murderer of my son Tugtekin, Ertugrul.
May God permit me to see
his beheading tomorrow.
Uncle...
...first Hamza, Abdurrahman
and then our 12 Alps have betrayed us.
You are right.
They were our nomad group's weakest link.
They could not resist the pressure.
They sided with Noyan.
However, neither of them has done
as much damage as Kocabash.
Or did the things he has done
single handedly.
Do you still refuse to see it?
Do not blame Kocabash, Gundogdu.
He was the Alp of my son!
He saved your life!
Ertugrul massacared him!
Choose your words carefully!
Your troubles will never end
if you keep recruiting traitors, Uncle.
What are you saying Gundogdu?
Who will you smear now?
I am talking about the one you hosted
in your late son's bed.
Karabek.
Insolence!
What are you saying?
Insolent!
Get out of my sight Gundogdu!
You should have chosen your words
carefully.
They say that when Ertugrul was
Noyan's captive,
this man was by his side.
I do not want anymore of your
insolence in my marquee.
Get out Gundogdu!
Get out!
Or I will send you.
They say that he was smiling
when that Mongol scum was
driving a nail through my brother's hand.
Enough!
Is this true, Karabek?
Do you believe that traitor
Ertugrul's words?
Is it true or not?
I will lead the tribunal tomorrow.
If you lie, I will cut off your head
before Ertugrul.
Gumustekin, enough.
I asked, is it true, Karabek?
Yes, it is true.
What are you saying Karabek?
Were you by Noyan's side?
Yes.
But on the orders of Sadettin Kobek.
I was sent to parley, to compromise.
However, that bastard did not listen to
any of our words.
That is all.
Lying wretch!
Mind your words.
Or else you will be worse than
your brother.
If you are still unsure,
ask Sadettin Kobek yourself.
You will defend yourselves
tomorrow at the tribunal.
I will not let this go, Karabek.
You can be sure of that.
You also fought against Mongols,
I am told.
They fought worthy of Kayi women, Bey.
Everyone did their best.
I used my weapon as my father taught me.
My Aunt and I supported
your Hatun and sister.
Are you alright?
We are alright as long as you are well,
my Bey.
We need your insight and
wisdom at this troubling times.
Thank you.
What were you doing with Noyan?
Tell me the truth.
Do not treat me like this, Gumustekin.
You are in need of us, such as everyone.
You will do as we say.
Ertugrul will be beheaded
with the decision of the tribunal.
No one can threaten me.
Now tell me, are you telling the truth?
Did you go to Noyan's dump
to strike a bargain?
Why have I not been noticed?
Why?
Because it was a secret mission
for the state.
If you are lying...
...I will carve your liver out.
What, have you decided to follow Ertugrul?
He is out of your reach,
you should know that.
Ertugrul must die.
Or you will be finished Gumustekin.
Sadettin Kobek will get what
he wants, not matter what.
Never forget this.
Bey, Tugtekin is alive.
Where is he?
-I could not hear, Bey.
-What?
Keep your eyes peeled.
Follow everyone, go!
Good job innkeeper, good job.
Thank you, my children.
Hatuns,
leave me alone with my mother.
What does Korkut say about this?
He is furious.
He blames Ertugrul for the Mongol raid.
My God.
What will happen at the tribunal tomorrow?
Son, tell me the truth.
Tell, so that we know what to do.
If Tugtekin does not heal and testify...
...it is not possible for us to
save my brother, Mother.
We cannot let Noyan to
make us suffer any longer.
We cannot let them kill Ertugrul.
If this devil Noyan achieves this...
...it will mean the end of our war...
...not just our beloved, Ertugrul.
I will not let them harm Ertugrul,
Mother. Do not worry.
I wonder, should be bring
Tugtekin to nomad tent?
Maybe they will stop and think.
Maybe they will stop trying to
get revenge on Ertugrul.
No Mother, Ertugrul does not approve to
move Tugtekin in his condition.
The only thing that will stop the
bloodshed is,
Tugtekin's recovery and testimony.
Then the only thing left for us
to do is...
...to pray to God for
Tugtekin's recovery...
...and hoping he will testify
at the tribunal.
My only consolation is
he is with Ibn'ul Arabi.
I will join them.
Ask for his blessing.
I hope you will return with good news.
God willing, mother.
At the edge of death...
...I saw your father.
Mother.
He said...
...do not give up.
I will not, son.
He said, whatever happens...
...do not leave your childrens' sight.
He said the light,
which will drown the darkness will rise...
...from that mountain and
engulf the world.
The whole world he said.
God willing, mother.
Rest now.
Oh, my Bey.
Finally, Halime Sultan woke up.
Wake that old man as well.
What do you want from us?
The documents of Sungurtekin
you are taking to Konya.
Who are you? What are you talking about?
Speak for the sake of Ertugrul's child,
Halime Sultan.
Or else I will cut that bastard
out out your womb with my bare hands.
Do as he says, Halime.
Do what is necessary
for your child's sake.
Documents are not in this chamber.
They are at the barn.
If this is a lie, you both will die!
Get up! I said get up!
Move!
In the name of God!
Where are they? Where?
I have put them in the saddlebag.
Come girl, quickly.
Hurry!
Run to the horses! Horses!
Brother seems to be dying.
Are you incapable of saying good words?
We should carry him to the
nomad tent before he dies.
He may be useful for once in his life.
He would die on the way
just to see my bey die.
Shitface.
Brother, he carries Mother Hayme's blood.
Why do you say that?
This devil has no blood.
Pure evil flows through in his veins.
Blasphemy.
It is the best thing to do.
Our only chance is to take him
to the nomad tent.
If our Bey went to the nomad tent
taking such a risk,
he must know something.
Use your head.
Brother, this is a stalemate.
I am going to the nomad tent.
I will not let my Bey to be beheaded.
If anyone tries,
I will rip their heads off like grass.
Enough is enough.
Wait, Brother.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
-We have a guest.
-Welcome.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
What is wrong Bamsi? Going to battle?
I wanted to get fresh air.
I got hot.
Sit down.
I have matters to discuss with you.
Ibn'ul Arabi, welcome.
Me and my mother are relieved
now that you are here.
We still remember your sacrifices
for our nomad group.
We are utterly grateful.
Thank you.
How is my Selcan girl?
How is he?
We have done all in our knowledge, Bey.
He is the one who brings
morning out of darkness.
He is the one who filled the night
with peace.
He is the one who created the sun
and the moon, moving around each other.
Science and prayer join together
like the branches of a river
lead to God's glory and will.
The rest is in his hands.
The tribunal will gather
in a short time.
It is obvious that the judgement of the
tribunal will be his execution.
Wait.
You are not the only ones in agony.
We have gathered here to
discuss what to do.
Noyan has gone more wild.
Yesterday he sent the men he bewitched
to the nomad tent to die.
What are you saying Bey?
What devilry is this?
Things got out of control.
Alps are ready, waiting for my orders.
And the people think that
Ertugrul is being framed.
We will each do our parts.
You will bring Tugtekin to the nomad
tent as soon as he opens his eyes.
Bey.
Do not leave us here, Bey
Do not take away the honor
of fighting for our Bey.
Gundogdu, let these brave warriors
come with you.
If the God will allow us to
venture through our enemis,
he will protect us
even with a spider's net.
Do not worry.
Okay.
Thank you, Bey.
Then wait for us before you
go into the nomad tent.
We will find a way to get
you into the chamber.
Thank you.
What is happening here?
They are mourning.
Mourning? What for?
He sent his men to Mother Hayme's
marquee yesterday for invasion.
Purely to show his power.
Purely to tease with
Ertugrul before he dies.
The men he bewitched have ran into the
arms of death without blinking an eye.
Where were you?
Noyan sent me on a mission.
I was saying farewell
to my brave warriors.
You did not even let me.
Tugtekin is alive, Noyan.
Where is he?
Ertugrul knows where he is.
Why are not you by my side?
Why?
If Tugtekin goes to the nomad tents
everything will come to an end.
Cover all the roads
which lead to the nomad tents.
Tugtekin or not
whoever is going to the nomad tents
will perish. And I mean everyone.
I will not let my victory day
turn into my mourning day.
Come with me.
Apparently, Hayme Mother's marquee
held against his men.
Thank God. You came back son.
Thank God.
If Ertugrul Bey dies, Noyan's bastards
who killed our brothers last night
would be victorious.
Do not forget it.
-Brothers, we will not allow it.
-We will not!
-Will we?
For our Ertugrul Bey.
For justice, if it is needed
we will be face to face with death!
We will run the risks
such as those Mogul heathens.
However they cannot bewitch us
and send us to die.
We would only die for God
justice and customs.
We would die for God and justice!
-We would die for God and justice!
We vow!
-We vow!
Yes, Turali?
They are everywhere Bey,
people cannot breathe.
May God help us.
Turali, do not wander around.
Go to the recovery tent
and do not leave until the evening.
Go now.
Mother Hayme, your injury is great.
Do not come to the tribunal like this.
We are here.
We will not leave Ertugrul Bey alone.
I will not leave alone
any of my warriors in my nomad group
let alone my son.
It does not befit me.
I have gathered you here...
...to get your approval on a matter.
Is there any of you
who believe Ertugrul Bey...
...had participated in such a treachery?
I am asking for the last time, is there?
Kayi Tribe exists because of
Ertugrul Bey, Gundogdu Bey
and your efforts Mother Hayme.
Suleyman Shah have a
special place in our hearts.
However you have honoured him adequately.
May God bless you and your children.
We would also pray for you.
Thank you.
If everyone agrees,
I want your full obedience
regarding the decisions
we would make about the accusations.
We are devoted to you
until we die, Mother Hayme.
-So do I.
Mother Hayme, do what is needed
in the name of justice.
We stand beside you until the end.
Everything is set, Bey.
We will not let them take
Ertugrul Bey from us.
-Beys?
-They approved.
Ertugrul's Alps are awaiting for you.
You will lead them to
the nomad tent secretly.
They are awaiting at the
skirts of Kusgozu Hill.
Yes, my Bey.
Gundogdu Bey.
There is an ominous gloom
in the air Gundogdu Bey, it awes me.
All people craves one thing.
Justice.
Merely justice will arise
from Korkut Bey's marquee today.
Have faith in me.
I will not surrender to neither
Korkut Bey's grief of his child
nor to the vengeful yelling of the folk.
Last night why did you come to my side?
I pray to God to let
Ertugrul's innocence would come to light.
However...
...I have my concerns about
what would happen to me...
...if I have to give him
the death penalty.
As I said my Bey.
All people crave one thing, justice.
Do not attempt to rebel, Gundogdu.
Everything will go downhill if you do.
If the tribunal you gathered
will act unjustly...
...Oghuz tribes will fall apart.
Seljuqs, who rely on Anatolia
will fall apart likewise.
Gundogdu Bey, we will bring
Ertugrul Bey to the tribunal.
I am coming.
There are tracks.
They must be taking Tugtekin
to the nomad tent.
We should send a word to Noyan.
They have found them.
Then, Tugtekin must be on his way
to the nomad tent.
We need to stop them.
To the horses!
Halime!
This horse cannot move
any step forward.
There is Ruzgar, Demir Usta.
He can carry us both.
Halime daughter, you go on.
I would slow you down.
Look, it is raining. Do not look back
and ride your horse, go on.
Accomplish Ertugrul Bey's mission.
Go, my child.
Do no ask of me to leave you
like this and go, Wild Demir.
I am begging you. Come with me.
I can stall them for a little more.
Think about your baby
if you do not think about yourself.
You must go my child.
-How can I leave you alone, Wild Demir?
-I told you to go, Halime!
Go! Your mission is more important!
Go on!
Stop!
Alright.
I will give you what you are after.
Halime!
No!
Here.
Kill the old man.
No! No!
As for Halime Sultan...
She will be the ornament of Noyan's bed.
Open the door.
Do you have good news, brother?
His condition is bad.
Let's hope for the best, brother.
We did the best we could.
Let's see what our destiny
has in store for us.
Don't.
His hands will not be tied.
You! This is impossible!
This is impossible!
The documents!
Do not worry. There is another copy.
Well done, my daughter.
You came just in time, brave man.
Tell us please.
Who are you with?
Dumrul.
-Welcome, brother.
-Thank you, brother.
How is the situation in nomad tent?
It is on fire.
We will put out the fire with
our spit brother, with God's help.
We will raze their tribunal to the ground.
Who do they think they are?
Wretched vultures.
-I will...
-Brother!
Enough.
Why would I stop?
What good would it do?
Keep him under control.
There is a tribunal in that nomad tent.
It is thinner than hair,
sharper than sword.
Do not ever act without thinking.
Gundogdu Bey has ordered.
His order is our command.
Thank you.
Let us go and save our Bey.
They found our track and they are coming.
The tracks are wiped away.
They know we are tracking them.
They are here.
Follow me.
Tribunal is ready, brother.
Beys are coming one by one.
What do they talk about?
They do not see anything but blood.
We wanted Ertugrul to die.
Now, we have his head.
Look what happened.
Our hands shake the most.
There is more Aytolun.
Ertugrul saw Karabek with Noyan.
What are you saying, brother?
He said it is the secret
of the state and kept quiet.
I am afraid of losing our way
in ominous forests, Aytulun.
There is something wrong about this.
What about Ertugrul?
Gundogdu is determined.
He will not give up his brother's head.
This means the Alps of two nomad
tents will fight, Aytolun.
I do not have any doubt.
We took necessary measures.
What will you do?
Gokce.
Yes, Hayme Mother.
I have to talk to Sercan.
Dumrul...
...is bringing Ertugrul's Alps...
...to nomad tent by carriage.
Thank God, Mother.
Gundogdu and I will be at the tribunal.
If something goes wrong...
...if something happens to us...
What are you talking about, Mother?
What can go wrong?
If a wild horse...
...loses a child...
...it will only stop when it's dead.
Only cliffs with no end will stop him.
You will fulfill marquee's decision.
Be at Dumrul's side.
Do not let those wretches hurt Ertugrul.
The mission is yours my daughter.
With great pleasure, mother.
Your wish is my command.
I am fine.
Ertugrul will get the end he deserves.
But, if you try to take
his head immediately...
...no one can be sure
how the things will end.
Fix this without anyone knowing.
Fix it so...
What are you saying woman?
Don't you know that Ertugrul is the
reason of what happened last night?
With his tenacity and ambition he is
putting us through hell that murderer!
He killed my child as well.
How can you come and
say these things to me?
-I am only--
-Enough!
He will get what he deserves,
from my hands.
His head belongs to me
according to talion law.
If I hesitate for a moment,
the civil war will break.
Do not ever forget
what I said, Aytolun.
Do you understand?
I understand, Bey.
May I, my Bey?
Come in, my Karabek, come.
What happened?
Gundogdu...
...is looking for trouble.
I say that you should arrest
him after the tribunal, Bey.
That wretch's head should
be in your hand until he dies.
Wait.
Sheikh, if they get inside,
they will kill us all.
Don't rush.
God, who protected his holiness prophet
from heretics with a spider web
will protect us as well.
Thank you.
There seems to be a way out.
You go look.
-Ertugrul Gazi!
-Traitor!
Traitor!
-Kill him!
-Traitor!
-Kill the traitor!
-Murderer!
-Kill him!
-Kill the traitor!
-Traitor!
-Murderer!
-Kill, Ertugrul!
-Show him!
Stop!
Where do you come from?
You also asked that
when I was leaving brother.
I am doing something for Hayme Mother.
Dumrul!
Where have you been?
Do you not know I want to get rid of
this ominous nomad tent at once.
I do not want to see
Aytulun's face ever again.
You are still standing there.
Selcan Hatun?
What?
Nothing.
You may pass.
Be quick!
What comes from God, returns to God.
Protect us with thy name, God.
Return to God.
Long live, Ertugrul Bey!
Murderer!
-Let me go!
-Stop it!
Long live, Ertugrul Bey!
What is happening to you?
The cave looks eerie, Noyan. Do not enter.
Geyikli drew them away from us,
my Sheikh. May God help him.
Thank you.
Who are you?
Where am I?
Where are you taking me?
If God permits, we are on a journey to
unseal hearts, son.
Are we going to make it in time,
my Sheikh?
-May Hizir help us.
-I hope.
Murderer!
-Shame on you!
-Murderer!
-Damn you!
You are nothing but a murderer!
Justice will be served!
Your judgement is near!
Murderer!
You will suffer!
-Murderer!
-Shame on you!
Long live Ertugrul Bey!
Murderer!
Justice will be served!
You will suffer, Ertugrul!
May God help us.
It seems Korkut Bey did not left
anything to chance.
Looks like they want my brother's head.
What do you think?
They say that Ertugrul is responsible for
what happened last night.
They are furious because Ertugrul's
situation weakened the two nomad groups.
Do I have your permission, Korkut Bey?
Permission belongs to justice.
Let there be justice.
Let God's justice be served.
Proceed.
Brave sons of Oghuz.
Mighty Beys of Kayi and Dodurga.
We are beginning the trial of
Suleyman Shah's son Ertugrul.
For our tradition compels us to be just
till the end of time.
He is guilty of murdering
Seljuk Atabey Ertokush...
...Dodurga Tribe's Alp leader
Tugtekin Bey...
...and massacring Kocabash,
the Dodurga Alp.