Episode 46 will start after 12:28 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORY AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED IN THIS
TV SERIES WERE INSPIRED BY TURKISH HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
You were a little bird...
and now you think that you entrapped me?
Is it so, smart boy?
Tugtekin!
Your wife is as brave as you.
She gave me a hard time in my headquarter.
Be proud of her.
And be proud of yourself.
But you both will die.
Your honour is trodden, Noyan.
I will teach you that...
you can not do anything by kidnapping
a woman from the nomad tent.
You are alone like an old dog
who got a kick, Noyan.
You came to take your revenge, you
furious boy? Is that so?
It is just like that day.
Like that day you did sic your mutts
on me.
My loyal cur, Hamza.
You decided to bite the hand
that gives you bones?
Come here, with pleasure. Come.
You come first so that your commanders'
turn comes quickly.
Ofcourse If they have the courage to fight
with me without their horses?
Hamza!
My loyal cur.
Stay out of this!
Be patient, Tugtekin.
Death of this cur will not be that easy.
I will give him another chance.
So the seal was an imitation,
you smart boy?
I appreciate you.
You tricked me twice.
But know that...
...if you do not kill me now...
...may the souls be my witness
I will torture to dead those...
... who are in your inner circle, in your
nomad group and in your bed.
-Long live, Gundogdu Bey!
Long live, Gundogdu Bey!
-Allahu akbar!
-Fetter this cur!
-Why do not you kill him now?
I want everybody to see how this cur
will die!
Hamza!
Forgive me.
Do not tire yourself.
Gundogdu Bey will rush you
to the nomad tent. Do not worry.
My mother gave me the name of that
great man who served our Prophet.
But I could not even be worthy of it, Bey.
I regret that too much. Too much.
May God bless you.
You gave me the opportunity to be a
martyr.
-Give your blessings.
-You have our blessings.
-You have our blessings, brother.
Eshedu en la ilahe illallah
ve eshedu enne Muhammeden abduhu
ve resuluhu.
It was so stupid of you to trust
both Abdurrahman and Hamza.
Now Ogeday will have a commander
that he deserves.
I know...
...that you are all ready to sacrifice
your lives for your ancestors,...
...your tribe and religion.
You are not scared.
Because you are the
brave sons of Oghuz.
But everyday...
...there happens to be a new betrayal
in our nomad group.
Traitors...
materialised like a poisonous
grass in our nomad tent.
Now they also entered our marquee.
I say that...
...if one of you knows anything...
...say it now.
Say it now...
...so that we can clean this poison
from our nomad tent and our marquee.
Mother Hayme, we grew up beside our
Suleyman Shah and in your hands.
We know only you and serve you.
We do not know anything other than that.
Sheik Ibni Arabi wanted me to stay...
...in your nomad tent to serve
Ertugrul Bey and you.
I immediately come and tell you whatever I
see, hear...
...and everything that you need to know.
But we do not know further than you.
I accept your marquee as
my marquee, Mother Hayme.
If I hear something,
it is my duty to tell you.
Do not tell anybody what I said.
Now you can go.
Thank you.
It is for nothing that
we have suspected them, mother.
Then who will we be suspicious of, Bey?
Who could have betrayed us?
From the person who knows
our smallest secret.
I will interrogate everybody one by one
until I find that traitor.
Until we find the traitor among us
neither we...
...nor the nomad tent may have peace.
No one else knows the secret of
the seal, except Konya.
The news came to the nomad group
from Konya.
Looking at the details it seems that...
a person who has relations
with the palace must have done it.
Then, there are also traitors
in the palace.
We are in a big game.
This place looks like no other place
we have ever seen before, Bey.
And we are not like any other men
who has ever been here, brother.
We are exactly on the border line.
Those hills belong to
The Byzantium Empire.
We will cross the border line.
-Be ready.
-Yes, Bey.
My great God, you let me see these days
thus I will never die in regret.
-God help us.
-Amen, my Bey.
-Amen.
Human means honour.
It means that we are the
most honorable creatures.
The most precious work of art of God.
No man is superior to the other.
We all are the children of Prophet Adam.
No one can change this truth.
Then what for this injustice?
Why are you drudging to those
who act claim to be superior to you?
You let them to steal your labor
and effort.
What else can we do?
Thou; Children of Prophet Adam!
My brothers and sisters!
What is it that makes them nobles
and you slaves
on these blessed lands of God?
They have been blessed.
And we are bare-legged poors.
God created us like this.
They are masters and we are
worthless villagers.
Children of Prophet Adam!
I invite you to a truth that a humanbeing
is not a superior to the other.
To a religion which people live
humanly.
To the path of a pure faith that
no Arab is superior to a Persian...
...or no Persian is superior to an Arab.
What is going on here?
We are working since the morning,
we are eating and taking a break.
There are Turks around here.
If you see one, let us know.
You? Do you want to say something?
The church...
When will the church let us be filled
up like our noble commanders?
How long will this torture continue?
You are nobody!
You are a worthless villager!
Leave aside being filled up...
...but if you want to even breathe
with your family...
...do not say these words again.
Is it clear?
Now everybody go back to work!
Tell me about this good faith
that no one is superior to the other, Bey.
I will tell, brother. I will.
You prepare some food,
I will go hunting and be back.
-Whatever your order, Bey.
-Whatever you say, Bey.
Come on, Dogan.
Our ancestors had said that the food made
by a man in love would be delicious.
I will groom horses
and you show your skills.
You, the bear of mountains.
You come closer when there is meal.
You run away when there is work to do.
Come on, brothers.
I will go and light a fire.
-Go along.
Mother Hayme does not know
what she is doing anymore.
I hope nothing is wrong, Gokce?
It is not good, Aytolun Hatun.
It is not good at all.
What I witnessed is just evil.
She queried the Alps...
...that she raised herself and
even the dervish of Ibn Arabi.
She is suspicious of everybody...
...because of the consignation
lost in the marquee.
What she is going through
is hard on Hayme.
She lost her mind now.
She make the people around her
to pay for...
...the shame of not being able to protect
her own marquee.
This is the thing that is bothering me
the most.
She plays with people's prides.
She thinks that they are thieves.
Then you are lucky, Gokce Hatun.
She has not thought of you as a thief
and query you.
I thought so too.
But I was wrong.
She said that she will question everyone
who comes and goes to the marquee.
All of us.
We just needed for her to think
that there are thieves in our marquee.
There is still no news from Gundogdu
and Selcan.
Where are they?
Everyday our suffering and anger
increases more and more.
Who has a hand in this, son?
Hatemongers of Seljukian palace
have a hand in this, mother.
The enemies of Sultan Alaeddin.
So why did Noyan kidnap Selcan
to have the seal, son?
Obviously, there are also some other
benefits in this.
Those benefits are right here in your
marquee, mother.
Who would have a benefit in my marquee?
What a horrible trouble is this!
It is obvious that someone in our
marquee...
...is under the command of our Sultan's
enemies.
What are you saying, son?
The only person who has a relation
with the palace is Gumustekin.
My son will marry with his daughter.
I do not say anything bad
about Gumustekin Bey, mother.
We saw how Gumustekin and Aytolun
fought when mutts of Noyan
attacked to the nomad tent.
Aytolun saved my life and Selcan's.
Whwn It is very difficult wvwn to think
about it, I can not imagine fighting...
...-with them, son.
-Mother, I will go nowhere...
without finding and cutting that hand
which reaches to your marquee.
El fatiha for the soul of the decedent.
You gave hard times to Noyan in his den.
He said it.
I am sure, he tells the truth.
I am the daughter of Suleyman Shah
and the wife of Gundogdu Bey.
It was too little what I did
to this ignoble, Bey.
I should take his eyes out with my nails
and take his kidney out with my hands.
Then I should not put you and
our Alps into this trouble.
Everybody talks about it, Selcan Hatun.
They say that what Beys and Alps
could not do
Selcan Hatun will do with her teeth.
She will take Noyan's kidney out.
Gundogdu.
You made the imitation of what this
Noyan dog wanted and saved me.
What else can I ask for in this world?
God bless you for thousand times.
God bless you too.
Selcan.
I would come and sleep in your bed
in your marquee that night.
But it was not in my destiny.
If it would none of them
would happen to us.
If you would come to my marquee that
night, you would not catch Noyan Bey.
They say, every cloud has a silver lining.
This is the good thing.
I say that thankfully I had this trouble.
Do not worry about it.
Are you looking for your trouble
with your demon eyes, Noyan?
Do you want to make me angry
and kill you here?
You hit it off because I degraded you
like a bug
and throw you to a well furious boy.
You are mad because Gundogdu
did not kill me here quickly.
You will die.
Your carcase will rot away
in the middle of the nomad tent.
I will listen how small worms nibble
the pieces of meat
sticking to the raven's nibs.
Hungry dogs will eat each other
to break up your bones.
And when your bones are broken
I will listen the sound of bones, Noyan.
Oh, furious boy, oh! Stop there.
Where there is life, there is hope.
This is such a war
that a shepherd that herds ox
like you may not understand.
It is not like to play with your
furious woman, Gokce like you.
Clever boy will take me to the nomad tent.
He will gain a reputation. What about you?
You will lose your honor, pride,
nomad tent and everything.
Very soon, they will take your
father's marquee from you.
You will only be putty in your
furious woman's hands.
Tugtekin!
It is enough.
Alps! Take him from here and
tie him up to my horseback.
We will be on the way soon.
I hope nothing is wrong?
Praise be!
Your foot is healed very well.
The medicine that Artuk Bey
gave me served its purpose.
Tell me which wild storm brought you here?
Hayme. She lost her mind.
She questioned everybody who comes and
goes to the marquee because of the seal.
Moreover, Korkut grants her sister right.
I said that this seal will
afflict with us, father.
If somebody knows that we had this seal
we lose our reputation.
Moreover, we will be accused by theft.
Your margrave remains as a dream
in the past, brother.
Now it is time to depart from this
life for Korkut, Aytolun.
But he should not die
without marrying off his son.
-I will make him quite weak.
-If he dies before the wedding
the work of margrave takes
longer than expected.
He will die when his son is
in the bridal chamber
so we can do the necessary for seigniory.
What will happen to the seal, father?
This seal will afflict with all of us.
Give it, father.
Give it and we can see our way now.
I will not give this seal to
Sadettin Kobek without taking what I want.
We are at the end now.
We have nothing to lose
other than our lives.
We will pay the price of it.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you, Turali.
Will Gundogdu Bey come back
to the nomad tent?
Will an Alp come back without bringing
to account for his brothers
and a man for her wife to the nomad tent?
He does not, Artuk Bey.
Good for you, valiant man.
Stop here, I will show you something.
Circumcision is the first condition
of being an Alp and a valiant man.
This dagger is left me from my ancestor.
From now on, it will be yours.
-Mine?
-Yes, yours.
But first you need to show
your valiantness.
How?
First the Beys need to come back
to the nomad tent.
You will wear this first.
Then this dagger will be yours.
Do not tell me that you are scared.
I cannot go to war
with this dagger, Artuk Bey.
What do you want then?
I want a sword as a gift
for the circumcision.
Praise be, my valiant man!
First you become an Alp, then I will
give you my own sword. Okay?
We are overwhelmed by circumstances
because of the traitors in our
nomad group for a very long time.
We sight for peace.
Before Kayis came to our nomad hroup
it was a nomad tent of distinction
between the Turkmen tribes.
Kayis came like an evil and caved in.
Aytolun!
Kayis are one of the most
valiant tribes of Oghuz.
The valiantness of Ertugrul is told
by Turkmens from mouth to mouth.
Hayme is my sister.
Kayis and Dodurgas do not have
anything separated.
You know everything better, Bey.
But do not forget what I said.
Are you better now, Bey?
I am fine.
Brother...
...since we came here
we could not see any non-Muslims.
Did we come to the wrong place?
It is the right place, brother.
They are everywhere.
You will benefit soon. Do not worry.
God is sole.
He is not born or gave birth.
So does God has no child?
No.
If he had a child
would he be different from us?
What about Jesus?
He is the Prophet of God.
And unfortunately, my brother,
when he has taken from the prophecy
and you make him son of God
you commit a big sin.
I have so many sins...
Do not forget. God is one who shows mercy.
But I do not show mercy.
Now may your great God come
and save you from me.
God! God forbid!
For God's sake!
We get the chance, brothers.
It is the sound of non-Muslims.
We are coming, my Bey!
-Who are you?
-Ertugrul, the son of Suleyman Shah.
Who are you?
Attack him!
-God forbid!
God sent you.
Who are you, valiant men?
-We are Kayis.
And who are you?
I am Abdullah Bin Mahmud.
Mahmud that Kirmani Master told me?
My Bey?
Hang on, my Bey.
Alps? Alps?
Help me.
Move his head.
Okay, my Bey. Hang on.
Go inform Artuk Bey now.
Immediately, run!
My Bey. Hang on, Bey.
I came, my Bey.
My Bey, Bey.
Do you see that what our nomad group
is tested with, Goncagul?
As it is not enough what these traitors
did to our nomad group
they have an eye on our marquee now.
These betrayals pushed me
from one suspicion to another.
You will be the wife of Gundogdu
and daughter of mine.
You have to fulfill your duty
until these dirt is cleaned.
You are right, Mother Hayme.
But I am the daughter of this marquee.
The misdeed made to this marquee
means that it happened to me.
But there is nothing that I saw or heard.
If there was, I would let you know of it.
You exert yourself, maybe there is
something that you do not remember?
I thought many times, Mother Hayme.
There is nothing that I saw or heard.
I hope nothing is wrong, Hayme Hatun?
Do you look for your enemies
between your children now?
Why are you so anxious, Gumustekin Bey?
Why does a person who have been
in the Seljukian Palace like you
rush that we do the necessary?
What is it that makes
you angry, Gumustekin Bey?
Everybody should perform
what is takes to clean this stain.
Mother Hayme! Korkut Bey got worse.
What are you saying?
Do not let me die until I see my son
get married, Artuk Bey.
It is time to go to Konya with you.
I want to consult with the scholars
who have more knowledge than me
about the evil circulating in your veins.
Where did it come from
to go to Konya, Artuk Bey?
Do not create works for me.
Bey, it is necessary to know what this
illness that makes you sick is.
I know many doctors in Konya.
Everyone is better than the other one.
First the wedding will be done.
And then I will do whatever you want.
I will commit myself to you.
Thank you, Bey.
Do you still drink
that syrup for power, Bey?
You told Aytolun Hatun
that I should not use it anymore.
And I do not use it.
Thank you, Bey.
Bey should use this medicine
until he gets better.
It will help to eliminate the poison
in his blood.
-Thank you.
-If you excuse me, Bey.
God.
How is my brother, Artuk Bey?
Korkut Bey is not seem good, Hayme Hatun.
Like there is a poison that he cannot
get away with it in his body.
That poison affected both the color of
his tongue and his eyes.
I see that for the first time.
Alright but what kind of poison is this?
I do not know if his body does that or
it is because of the food and beverage.
Only way to know that is
to take him and go to Konya.
But he does not let it.
Brother.
How are you?
I want to be grateful for living.
But I do not have power even for that.
Betrayal is everywhere
and dirty trick is everywhere.
Why do not you listen to Artuk Bey?
Association of two nomad tents is
important than anything.
I broke my son's heart
and took the head seigniory
away from him because of that.
Do I not know your good intention
and your good heart?
Hayme, maybe it is my last wish
from you as your brother.
Do not break someone's heart
with your suspects.
Do not destroy anything.
If we do not come together
against the Mongolians...
Brother?
Let him rest a little bit.
I heard that you are looking for those
who stole the consignation.
I hope you will find them sooner or later.
Be sure that it will not take
so long, Aytolun.
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Give him us and we will kill this traitor!
Kill him!
You will die, Noyan! Kill him!
-You will die, Noyan!
-Noyan, the killer!
Kill this dog!
Noyan, the killer!
Kill our sons' killer!
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
My Beys!
My brothers!
Valiant women of our nomad group!
Warrior Alps!
To be with God
to defend God is Oghuz' blessed duty
until this world is destroyed!
We did and will not let the Mongolians
that want to pass through
our land nomad tent
and religion for long time
with God's help!
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Today is our victory day!
It is the victory day that we broke
their hands that encroach to our flag!
It is the day that cur Noyan
who gave no chance to the poors
for a long time
in this land kneels down!
Do not think that this victory is mine!
This victory is ours!
God is greatest!
This victory
is the messenger of first light
that we expected!
The hope of God is very soon!
Our duty is to defend this hope!
This fight is the fight of God and evil!
Now I shout in front of you here!
The victory is God's!
God is greatest!
We live and become martyr
for this victory!
God is greatest!
You will not have graves in this land!
You will be destroyed in front
of the empire of the world!
We will sleep with your women!
We will water the land
with your horses' blood!
My brothers! Stop!
My Beys! Stop!
We will hopefully give the answer
to this non-Muslim tomorrow.
Take him to the trussed marquee.
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Killer of our sons'! Kill him!
Killer of our sons'!
Long live Gundogdu Bey!
Where is Noyan?
He should already came back.
Do not rush, Ulubilge.
Noyan will come back with the victory.
Why you are not with Noyan?
I was.
But he sent me back.
You go back to the den, he said.
He chose Hamza as a commander and
he took the control over the soldiers.
Chain him.
You talk very well, smart boy.
Your nomad group is proud of you.
But do not be so much proud.
You hold the aces but
last word is not spoken.
You love to talk nonsense, Noyan.
I do not know how you can talk so much
while you are struggle like a bird
in this marquee.
It would be better
if you kill me immediately.
You take your chance.
Otherwise, I will not leave anybody
alive from your family.
I will destroy your nomad tent.
You keep continue to dream, Noyan.
I will send another Mongolian cur
to the hell tomorrow.
Tangut!
Noyan was captured by Gundogdu.
-What did you say?
-How?
Hamza betrayed Noyan.
Now is not the time
to beat your chest, Ulubilge.
It is time to lead our army before
they fall apart with this news.
We should not leave the soldiers
without a leader.
Who can be the leader
to replace Noyan?
Will you be their leader?
I will do whatever is needed, Ulubilge.
It's up to us now.
You also need to do
what is required of you.
You need to back me up.
Servants!
Gather round!
Valiant Mongolian servants!
Noyan was captured by the Turks.
However...
...do not let this discourage you.
You have Genghis Khan's
warrior blood in your veins.
Do it some justice.
From now on, I am your leader.
Noyan's capture by the Turks
should not affect
our promise to Ogeday.
We don't need Noyan
to shed some Turkish blood.
Rescue Noyan...
...so that we can trust
your leadership.
These servants are
here to serve Ogeday...
...not Noyan.
TEKFUR PALACE
Great Creator!
Give me the power that you gave to
your son, Jesus.
Feed me with your son's soul.
Amen.
Kostas wants to see you,
Commander Valentin.
-It is very important.
-Send him in.
What is the important news
you have for me?
Your soldiers are dead, Sir Valentin.
What are you saying, you fool?
Who could dare to try
and kill my soldiers?
A Muslim dervish, Sir.
He was poisoning the people and
your soldiers came to bring him into line.
Several Turkish warriors came
out of God knows where
and they killed all your soldiers.
Turks?
Now listen to me carefully.
Father, father.
Come here, my boy.
Come here. Sit down.
Look, I brought you
the brave Alps from Kayi.
Welcome. It's great
to have you here.
Thank you.
What is your name, valiant man?
Ali, Bey. My father calls me
Edebali. Yours?
-Ertugrul.
-You are nimble like your name.
What is the meaning of my name?
It is written in the Divan-i Lugatit Turk.
'Tugrul' is a wild bird,
and when combined with 'er,'
it means a valiant warrior bird.
When combined with you,
it means valiant man.
Praise be on to you!
Brother Ali.
What's the meaning of my name?
My name is Bamsi.
I cannot answer every
question, Bamsi Alp.
If you stay for the night then
you will have your answer.
Of course they will be our guests, son.
How can we let these
valiant men leave us so soon?
Thank you.
Since his mother died,
it is just the two of us in this world.
I want to send him to Damascus
and have him study
in a madrasah but...
If God permits it will be
like you wish, Mahmud.
If God permits!
So, what brings you here?
We are looking for a new land
to herd our animals.
Then you found the right place.
This land will both fatten your animals
and make you comfortable.
I never came across more
prosperous land in my life.
When did you come here?
Why did you come?
Well, we came here to repair
broken hearts.
To spread the flame that Hodja
Ahmed Yesevi started in Khorasan.
Hodja Ahmed Yesevi
is someone to die for.
How do you communicate
with the poor people here?
The skill is to speak
the language of hearts.
But the people here are heartbroken.
They are injured.
You have a blessed duty, dervish.
God's word will be recited
everywhere from sunrise to sunset
thanks to you and people like you.
If God permits!
And thanks to valiant men like you,
the tyranny will come to an end.
If God permits!
With God's help.
Get better soon, daughter.
God spared your life for us.
Selcan stood against these scum.
and showed how noble
the women of Kayi are, brother.
Daughter, I want you to know
that I am proud of you.
Thank you, Mother Hayme.
But of course, my daughter's
being back in the tent
doesn't mean that
the trouble is over.
Betrayal is still in our marquee
as it once was.
My mother is right.
We all have to be investigating
this issue.
Our group will not find peace
until we know who stole
the consignation of Sungurtekin.
If we knew exactly what
the stolen item is...
and why it is so valuable...
maybe we could also help,
Sungurtekin Bey.
Our privacy has been
compromised, Gumustekin Bey.
Think about what the
person who did this is capable of.
Whoever stole this consignation...
...who knows which demon's
puppet he has become?
And even worse, he is
too stupid to know
which demon's puppet
he will become.
Now I understand what it means
to win many battles in the field
but to lose them in the marquee.
Then you understand that both
marquees have to keep quiet,
don't you, Tugtekin?
You made me enjoy victory
in this age, my sons.
May God bless you.
May God bless you too, uncle.
How's the Byzantine Empire doing?
How do the commanders treat people?
They do nothing other
than oppressing them, Bey.
They take everything the poor
have and call it tax.
They bully those
who cannot pay.
Byzantine landlords
oppress the people also.
People cannot find peace
due to taxes and sectarian fights.
There is a massive gap between
villagers and the nobles.
-Welcome, Kostas.
-Mahmud Efendi...
...we would like to listen
to you together with the villagers.
They are welcome.
You would be my guests of honor.
You are always welcome here.
It is dangerous to come here.
If you come tomorrow, other friends
want to listen to you.
All right. I will come.
Are you all right, father?
How can I feel bad after
seeing you two together, son?
Come here.
Sit next to me.
Sooner or later
the time of separation will come.
I know that you will be
the new leader, son.
The Beys want that, too.
First and foremost, Gumustekin.
Father, it is not the
time to talk about this.
It is the best time, son.
Now is the time.
Do not forget these words
when you become a Bey.
You should stand by
Gundogdu and Ertugrul.
This would not belittle you, son.
It would prove
how great you are.
This corruption did not end when
Ertugrul killed Kocabash.
It will not end either.
Never forget that betrayal around us
is getting bigger everyday.
Unite with your brothers
in Kayi marquee.
Stay alert.
Never let the betrayal destroy us.
Smart boy took his brother and came.
I never strayed from
the path of my ancestor, Oghuz.
I made you the best man of Ogeday.
I offered you the world.
And what did you do?
You betrayed me and Ogeday.
How did you know that
I was in the caravansary?
Tell me.
You are not the only traitor
turncoat, Sungurtekin.
Go easy on him, brother.
He's not worthy of getting
your hands any dirtier.
If you got these news, Noyan...
it is obvious that this person is
from Sultan Alaaddin's palace.
Maybe someone very close to him.
I didn't call you smart
for nothing, Gundogdu.
But if you were a bit smarter,
the two us could tear
that palace down on his head.
Instead of doing something like that
I'd prefer to be killed by
my son with a blunt knife.
Your offspring will curse you
for being spared that blunt knife.
Sooner or later, we will find
out who told you
about the seal and
where I was, Noyan.
And my only wish is to stick
his tongue to that traitor's throat
and watch him choke to death.
Come on, brother, come on.
I will kill everybody including
children and women in your marquee
or even those I see nearby.
I will disgrace you like
no Kayi was disgraced before.
There is no such thing, Noyan.
There is no such thing.
You won't be just drowning
in your own blood.
You will beg me to chop your
head off with my sword
while those people that you hurt
are watching you.
Your blood will be a disgrace
to the Mongolians.
Hell will be your shelter, Noyan. Hell!
Come along, brother, let's go.
Alps!
I will teach you a lesson
tomorrow, smart boy.
You will curse the day that you
did not kill me with that blunt knife.
Did you hear me, smart boy?
Did you hear me?
It has been a while since we ate
together in our marquee, Halime.
I haven't felt this peaceful
for a long time.
The troubles over our marquee
are slowly fading away, Selcan.
Bad days are almost over.
You were worried
for no reason, sister.
Look, Gundogdu Bey risked his life
to save you from that Mongolian.
You are right.
Gundogdu risked his life
and came to save me.
From now on it is my duty
to make him happy.
Wow!
Look at that table!
We cooked your favorites
together with Halime Sultan.
God bless your hands.
Did Noyan say anything?
No, mother.
We will kill him tomorrow
if God permits, mother.
Let his words stick in his throat.
Please have a seat.
Bismillah...
How long will you sit there
like you are angry with the world?
Their love was frozen like Lake Aral.
But now it gurgles like Amu Darya.
I felt so stupid, auntie.
When I saw them looking
and smiling at each other...
I was about to lose my mind.
I was about to lose my mind, auntie.
Patience. Patience.
When you are at the bridal chamber
he won't think of anything
other than you.
If he was happy in that
frigid woman's bed
he wouldn't have fallen for you.
Pull yourself together.
When you devote your youth and beauty
he will be the dust on your foot.
Now you go to the marquee.
Go and show them who you are.
I was not invited, auntie.
I was not invited.
You are a woman of that marquee now.
You don't need an invitation,
all you need is a little courage.
That is all.
The tree was too big.
I climbed it but couldn't jump down.
I began to cry.
Help me get down.
But she cried so much.
Migratory birds changed courses
because of her screams.
Then I saw my brother coming.
I asked him to help me
get down for God's sake.
He said 'No, I won't.'
If I helped you get down,
what will you do tomorrow?
You need to come down
the same way you climbed.
-Did he not take you down?
-No.
My brother is so stubborn.
But you learned how to get down
from the tree you climbed.
Yes, Mother Hayme is right.
I learned how to get down
from the tree I climbed
thanks to my brother.
I had two broken fingers
but never mind.
Enjoy.
I came to share the happiness
of your table.
Go ahead, daughter. Sit down.
Mother Hayme, it was a difficult day.
If you excuse me, I would like to rest.
Alright, daughter. Go and rest.
Gundogdu...
...take Selcan to her marquee.
Your wish is my command, mother.
Good night.
-Good night.
Goncagul Hatun,
there is some bulgur
at the bottom of the cauldron.
Do you want some?
Now, have a good night, Selcan Hatun.
Gundogdu Bey.
You came into this marquee,
your breath and smell
filled everywhere.
It is like the spring breeze.
You breath life into me.
When that evil Noyan caught me
I was not scared,
not even for a moment.
I knew that you would
come and rescue me.
Selcan.
Our marquees are separated.
But you are still my wife.
You know it.
You gave me the world.
What else can I ask from God?
I know that I neglected you a little.
But I will always be
with you from now on.
Don't you worry.
Will you stay with me tonight?
I will see the prisoner.
Get out of my way.
I will ask you only one thing, Noyan.
What was it that you wanted
to take from Sungurtekin?
And why you want it so much?
You ask this question
in the name of who?
In the name of yourself, Alaaddin
or in the name of Sadettin Kobek?
What are you trying to say?
I know you and
Sadettin Kobek very well.
I know there is no limits to
what you are capable of doing.
In order to be margrave
you run errands of Kobek.
And you can be more cruel
than I am if necessary.
I know everything.
Do you hear what you are saying,
you scumbag!
What happened? Are you surprised?
Who do you think I am, Gumustekin?
You despise me because I am a slave
here and will be executed tomorrow?
Besides, you are not even strong
enough to kill me!
You will face the fact
when the time comes!
What fact?
The fact that you lost the battle
before it even started!
The fact that whoever
helps the Mongolians
will grow and gain strength!
I am the only one that can give you
what you want, Gumustekin.
As you can see, I know everything.
This is the fact.
When you understand it,
come and find me.
You are a miserable, sordid
and despicable murderer!
Do you think that you can fool me
with empty words?
You will die tomorrow!
You know that too?
Tomorrow is another day!
Goncagul.
What is wrong with you?
What happened to you?
His mother sent Gundogdu to bed
with that whore right in front
of my eyes, auntie.
What are you saying, Gonca?
He took his wife and brought her
to his tent without saying a word.
I went after them.
In this cold, frosty weather
I waited for him to leave
Selcan's marquee.
But he did not leave.
Obviously, tonight he will seek
comfort in the arms of this whore.
Auntie, I will kill that woman!
I will kill Selcan!
As long as she is breathing,
this life is hell for me!
While you were sleeping at night
I was watching you.
I dozed off for a while...
...you were also in my dream.
I hope that's a good sign.
You were holding
a child firmly by the hand.
Blonde hair, deep blue eyes like yours.
You brought him
in front of me and said
"Take good care of him,
he is our son."
I hope that's a good sign.
Excuse me.
Dear God, please let me have a child.
Take my life but not my child this time.
Even if I die, let me do so
after giving birth.
Gundogdu Bey!
Yes, Goncagul Hatun.
I want you to forgive me, Bey.
What for?
I came to your table
without being invited.
Various things bothered me.
The only reason is that
I was jealous of you, Bey.
I was jealous of you and Selcan Hatun.
What are you saying, Goncagul Hatun?
I accepted to be your second
wife, I know.
Nevertheless, Selcan Hatun...
Goncagul Hatun!
Selcan has a place in my heart.
I cannot tear her apart easily.
But I also want you to enliven me.
To enliven you and give you children
is my duty now, Gundogdu Bey.
Thank you.
You wanted to see me, Halime Sultan.
You know why I called you.
I know.
I know but I said
what I had to say.
Do not ask me to betray Bey!
We only want you to learn the truth!
Is Selcan Hatun's necklace
in the marquee or not?
That is the only thing we want to learn.
I came here out of my respect
for Ertugrul Bey.
But this is enough!
Do not try my patience!
What if Selcan is right?
While Duru Hatun was alive,
Bey did not cheat on her.
While she was alive, he did not take
Aytolun Hatun to his bed.
We did not tell you this.
Where does it come from, Banu Cicek?
Stay away from me.
Noyan knows everything.
He knows about our alliance
with Sadettin Kobek.
He knows that I want to be
a margrave. Everything!
But how is that possible, brother?
Mongolians have settled
in the palace, auntie.
Who knows how many more
like Kocabash lives in the palace?
Mongolians have already laid
a siege to Anatolia!
Give this seal to Sadettin Kobek, father.
We are walking to the
edge of the cliff step by step.
We don't even know
what will happen after this.
Hide this seal where
nobody can find it, Aytolun.
After we punish that damned Noyan,
it will be time to talk to Sadettin Kobek.
Where will you hide the seal, auntie?
At the marquee!
Where I hid
Selcan's necklace.
How did Banu Cicek know everything we
talked about Ertugrul, Selcan?
Obviously, she knows something.
She knows but remains silent.
Maybe she knows even more than we do,
Halime.
But I know my necklace is in the marquee.
Aytolun is hiding it.
She knows perfectly that no one could
ever get in there...
...while there are guards
watching the cradle.
I wish I could find my necklace. Then they
will see what I am capable of doing!
I do not know what you will do
when you find your necklace, Selcan.
But I know what I will do.
I will enter the marquee
while Noyan is being executed.
We will see whether your necklace
is there or not.
If you allow us, we want to come with you
and see the circumstances of people.
Ofcourse, Bey, you will honor us.
Thank you.
Tell me Edebali,
did you read all these books?
I did, Bey.
Good for you. Well done.
Well done.
Sir Valentin?
-I have good news.
-Are they coming?
Everything turned out to be as you wished.
That fool believed it.
Those Turks will come with him.
Well done. Now go and do not play into
their hands.
If you make a mistake,
you will pay for it with your life.
-What did you tell her?
-I did not say anything!
What is this?
I did not say anything!
We should go.
You do not look good, Bey.
Do not worry, I can walk.
I want to see that mutt called Noyan dead.
-Tangut, there is a letter for you.
-Give me that.
Walk away.
Your life is in my hands, Noyan.
But I will not bat an eyelash.
You will pay for all the cruelty
you did to me.
You will also melt away like this letter.
Tangut!
You traitor!
So, you want to kill Noyan!
I swear, Noyan will scratch your eye out,
rip off your heart and eat it!
What is happening, Tugtekin?
I was told that you would do the execution
in front of The Kayi marquee.
It is true.
We attacked the den of that mutt
called Noyan all together.
May God bless you.
But you as are also aware that
Noyan attacked our migration caravan.
He tortured both my mother and her
children. It's her right...
...to spill his blood. I will see that his
head is hung high up in the gallows.
But cousin, this pride is
neither yours nor mine.
This honor belongs to the father
of all of us, Oghuz Khan.
Excuse us.
The time is up Noyan.
You still think that I will die,
you clever boy?
You will go down on your knees and beg me
when we flood into your land.
But Mongolians will attack on you in such
a wild way that you will not...
be able to breath. So that you will not
even have the chance to beg.
Untie him and follow me.
Byzantine community is tired, Bey.
They are voluptuous.
Neither man nor women
are the same anymore.
They are about to lose their homes and
society in the cause of pleasure.
So they are on the verge of the demise.
You can train a weaponless man
but a woman who has lost her womanhood
is like a knife stabbed
into the heart of a nation.
If a nation lost it's ability
of being a family
it means that it has lost everything.
You are right, Bey.
However, they are very wise especially
on fine arts.
There are many masters working
in their cities.
This is our greatest weakness.
Our traders and profession experts
are very weak.
Erewhile, we need to learn crafting
from non-Muslims.
When cruel Mongolians destroyed our
cities, many of our masters passed away.
They destroyed our memory, Bey.
The cruelty and tricks of the enemy
never ends.
What really matters is the things we can
or can not do.
We need to teach our children some crafts.
You are right, Bey.
Would you like to give a break hereabout?
Dogan, Bamsi, you pry around.
-Yes, Bey.
They will pay for our childrens' lives!
Let God's justice be upon us!
This man will have his punishment!
Kill him! Murderer!
Murderer!
Kill him!
Kill him! Murderer!
I wish Ertugrul was here and
witnessed this blessed moment.
Beys!
Brothers!
Sisters!
Thank God, the head of this traitor
Noyan...
...who martyrised many of our brothers...
...is at your feet!
Kill him! Kill him!
Kill him!
Bey, if you let me, I will take some
to Dogan and Bamsi.
This will not be enough
even only for Bamsi.
Then he will learn to be patient.
Good appetite.
Now...
...who commands this region?
Which feudal landlords own it?
And where are we exactly?
We are close to Verakoma.
Here is Prusa.
Here is Konstantinople;
Center of The Byzantine Empire.
The Emperor lives there.
Nikea; a holly city for Christians.
Bible has taken its final version upon the
council that gathered in this city.
Actually, the real Byzantium is there.
What does it mean?
Crusaders remained in Konstantiniye
instead of going to Jerusalem
in their last journey.
They invaded Konstantiniye.
They vandalized the city.
They slaughtered their own
coreligionists wildly.
Their own coreligionists?
Yes.
The ones witnessed the savagery say
that...
...Konstantiniye had gone through the
greatest savagery of it's history.
The Empire in Nikea was founded by The
Emperor who escaped from Byzantium.
Now Vatakis rules there.
They are at daggers drawn
with the emperor in Konstantiniye.
In the past, the namesake of my father
Suleyman Shah, from shahzades...
...of Seljukian, conquered this city.
Here is our first capital in Anatolia.
Meaning, it is a legacy
to us from our forefathers.
If God permits, people from your family...
...will make Muslims rule
these lands again.
If God permits.
I see that it is easy to conquer
these lands with weapon.
But we need to make
these regions prosperous.
We need to get welfare
for the local people here...
and find solutions to their problems.
We need to provide justice in
these lands again.
We need to keep the nation alive
in order to keep our state alive.
Do we have the chance entering these
cities you have mentioned?
It is too early. You will be recognized.
They must be seeking for you
everywhere anyway.
The next time you come,
we will try entering the city.
Next time, we will come to conquer
these cities, Turgut.
If God permits, Bey. If God permits.
If God permits.
Halime, let me go.
If you get caught, everything
will be ruined, Selcan.
You can not look at Gundogdu Bey's face
again.
You would lose and Aytolun will win.
I will enter the marquee, do not insist.
God bless you. Goodbye
Aytolun Hatun wanted to see me.
They brought Noyan!
Bey, are you alright?
I have no power left, Aytolun.
I told you not to come. You are not
feeling good.
You go.
Go and represent our marquee
while that dishonest is being executed.
I will rest a while, go along.
Kaya! Help me, son.
Dear God, please preserve my mind.
Why is he coming back?
In the midle of winter
these regions are too hot, Bey.
Oh that unique weather of
Pasinler Plateau.
-Bears do not like hot weather, Bey.
-May you freeze hopefully!
Come along with me,
I have things to tell you.
These regions are exactly like the lands
we are looking for.
Byzantium lost it's power.
If we succeed to move our nomad tent
to these lands...
...we will be able to found the homeland
we have been dreaming of.
We will have children
and keep our nation grow.
Our sons and daughters will be happy.
What if Beys in the nomad group
would not want to come here, Bey?
We will try to persuade them.
What if they still do not come, Bey?
Then we will come, Dogan.
We will come, Bey, we will.
We will go everywhere with you, Bey.
We will even go to death, Bey!
But, Bey, the next time we come here,
can we change the name of this region?
I am not able to pronounce it, Bey.
I thought he would say
something meaningful.
Sure, we can change the name, Bamsi.
Do you have any ideas?
For example, Bey,
this region Bega, Belagun...
Whatever it is. Tell what you want to
call it.
Bel, bel... Bel, bel...
Bilecuk.
Bilecuk! Bilecuk, Bey!
Can not we use Bilecuk?
Bilecuk!
Sure, Bamsi.
Can we say Bilecik instead of Bilecuk?
Sure, Bey. Sure, Bey, why not?
Bilecuk! Bilecuk!
We will come and conquer you! Bilecuk!
Shut up! Shut up you bear!
Kill him! Kill him!
Give his punishment!
I wanted you to witness this moment!
Witness that this cur of The Mongolians
is as mortal as we are!
Witness that this fear of Mongolians
within the hearts of all our brothers...
...from east to west will end now!
What shall I do?
Halime.
Daughter...
...what are you doing in here?
May God be with you.
I am Dervish Mahmut.
They came here to listen the things
you have already told me.
Help yourselves, sit please.
Thou, sons of Prophet Adam.
I invite you to a faith that people
do not transcend each other.
To a religion that keeps justice and
brotherhood above everything else.
How can a human be equal with another?
How will I be equal with a noble one?
If God, that created human
from a blood clot,
classified people,...
...is not that injustice?
If so, since the time we were born
we would be hard done by.
God is merciful. He forgives.
He shows mercy. He is fair.
Meaning that, he is the one to dispenses
the justice.
How can the creator
of justice do injustice
to people he created and oppress them?
If God would not oppress his servants
why do you oppress us
with your infidelity?
You are the betrayer that killed my men.
And you are the commander of
those cruel ones.
When it's time to battle,
may God be with us,...
...with the army of Sultan Alaeddin.
Allahu Akbar!
Dear Khan...
...Sadettin Kobek.