Episode 58 will start after 12:20 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
We believed in you. We were
going to make you commander.
You betrayed us, Ertugrul Bey! You brought
Ameer Sadettin's soldiers here!
Kill Shahzada Ertugrul!
It was good, brother.
We have not fought for a long time.
What is wrong, Turgut Brother?
What are you thinking?
We should not have left Bey alone.
We did wrong.
He told us not to go after him.
What should we have done, oppose him?
I told you so, brother. We are going.
An eye for an eye, Fiery Boy.
Eye for an eye.
A tooth for a tooth, a life for a life.
Blood for blood.
Come.
Did ember fall to your heart, Fiery Boy?
You were quite week last time.
Your woman's pain rendered you a man.
Now, you are my own size.
-Turgut!
-Your order, Bey.
Take Yigit. Yigit, come.
I see your eyes are on your woman.
You wish to go to her at once.
But it is not that easy.
While your flesh is getting colder
you will writhe with your woman's pain.
I have been waiting for this day
for so long, Fiery Boy.
for so long.
Die, Mongol cur!
Do not rival in the battles
you cannot win, Fiery Boy.
Now, you will die
bellowing with the pain of your woman,
in the short time you have left.
Noyan!
You taught me to love, Bey.
You taught me not to be
a foolish child but a real woman.
And you taught me to be a real man, Gokce.
That you do not become a Bey...
...with a weapon but with love.
Even though you hate me
even if I don't have as much worth
as the dust on your boot in your eyes
I will love you until my last breath.
I have loved you from
the first moment I saw you.
And I will always love you.
If it is in my destiny to love and not
to be loved, I will bow to my destiny.
From now on, we will be each other's
for eternity, Gokce.
From now on, our destinies are one.
Bey!
Bey.
He is alive!
Gokce Hatun is dead.
We must take them back to the tent.
Mount your horses! Now!
Ertugrul Bey was right.
It was all your dirty games.
Glory!
In these lands, both
power and glory is mine.
You failed to understand that.
Now you will pay the price
for disobeying me.
Damn you, Kobek!
Damn you!
Bring him to me.
Hold him.
His Ameer, Ertugrul
helped Shahzada escape.
Very well.
He is not a hero anymore.
He is a rebel now.
We created a rebel
out of a hero.
Go to the Kayi marquee at once,
Commander.
Take your soldiers with you,
ask for Ertugrul.
If they don't hand him over,
burn that marquee down.
As you wish, his Ameer.
Are you alright, Yigit?
Come here.
Are you alright?
I'm fine, Ertugrul Bey.
Don't worry.
It doesn't look so bad.
I want to get rid of these clothes
Noyan's woman gave me.
What woman are you
talking about, Yigit?
Her name was Goncagul.
She had eyes that looked
like a serpent's.
Do you know her, Bey?
She was at the heart of
the unrest in our tribe.
-Turgut?
-I couldn't say it during the battle.
It turns out that she's
Noyan's woman now.
Bey, how did they find each other?
Kobek.
Obviously, it is Kobek who
brought them together.
So they found each other
in the shithole, huh, Bey?
Must have been a
match made in heaven!
Are those two scumbags
worthy of mentioning like that?
You're right, brother.
I am sorry.
Apparently, it was that whore
who also pulled Bogac into this, Bey.
You are right, Turgut.
Bey, it is up to you make
something good of this evil.
The den of these scumbags
will lead us to goodness, Bamsi.
We'll keep an eye
on that den from now on.
There is no going back to the tent.
Kobek and his men
are looking for us everywhere.
It's all my fault.
You and my sister are
in danger because of me.
Ameer Sadettin will
label you a traitor
and he'll come after you.
It's all my fault.
You proved that you live
up to your name, Yigit Alp.
You sided with God
and the state.
None of this is your fault.
Don't you worry.
I don't deserve to live, Ertugrul Bey.
Every moment I am
alive causes new troubles,
and every breath I take brings
misery to my loved ones.
It must come to an end.
I'm tired of running away.
-Alps!
-Yes, Bey.
We are going
to the Geyikli den.
Go on.
Come, brother.
We've been going through
hard times for some time now.
We saw neither the sun
that warms us,
nor the rain that
feeds our crops.
The constant fear of the
next misfortune to fall upon us.
That's a neverending agony.
That is why we
have to stand together.
We'll be patient.
We will fight.
This our only hope
of salvation...
...for Gokce, for Yigit Alp,
for all of us.
I don't know when
this misery will come to an end.
However, I remember quite
well when it began.
It began the day my dad and I trusted
Ertugrul's word and came here.
The day we fought for the Sultan.
If we'd stayed in Aleppo
instead of coming here,
none of this would
have happened to us.
Yet, we are now in
endless pain and misery.
A peaceful life away from the Mongolians
is a distant dream for us now.
On top of all that,
my illness
taught me how painful it is to wait.
My brothers are at the
battlefield while I am here.
-God is testing us, son.
-Certainly.
This is such a test that
we have to be grateful for
the sorrow in the
highlands where we seek
peace and quiet in summer...
and for our quarters that provides
us with shelter in winter.
Whoever passes this test
will be honored
with God's mercy and grace.
That's what Ertugrul Bey
taught me in my darkest hour.
To confront our troubles
without hesitation...
no matter how big they are.
To be grateful for our suffering.
Suffering won't destroy us.
And we won't hesitate nor fear.
Yesterday, it was my brother,
today it was Gokce.
Tomorrow it could be me or my baby.
We will think of Ertugrul who fights
to keep this marquee standing,
and those who reached martyrdom,
and we will stand tall.
God help them.
-Give us the strength to endure.
-Amen.
-If you'll excuse me, mother.
-Sit down, son.
Sit down.
Us, our marquee, our home
can't be destroyed by any kind of pain.
Only we can destroy ourselves.
Suleyman Shah's blessed marquee
will be destroyed only when we give up.
Even though he is not here,
he lives in our hearts.
As long as he is there,
there is no sorrow.
Let's be grateful for what is
on our table
and the flame burning in our hearts.
Let us be grateful so we can
have the strength to endure.
In the name of God,
the compassionate and merciful.
Let's eat.
Goncagul is there.
They killed her.
What are you saying, Bey?
What could she be doing there?
Apparently, she conspired with
Noyan and tried to do something.
Now listen to me carefully.
You stay here and wait.
If I don't come back,
return to the tent at night.
And bury the body.
Sadettin, you think you are clever.
So you make Fiery Boy my prey,
and me Sungurtekin's.
I will make you pay for this.
There is no word from her.
I'm so worried about what
that scumbag could
do to my sister.
Selcan. Don't you worry.
Tugtekin Bey will save her
just like I saved you
from that heathen once.
If God permits.
Ameer Sadettin's commander
is here, Mother Hayme.
He wants to see you.
Send him in.
Let's see what he has
to tell me this time.
We are looking for Ertugrul Bey.
Where is he?
Why are you looking for Ertugrul Bey?
What does Ameer Sadettin
want from my son?
His Ameer has sentenced
Ertugrul Bey to death.
What are you saying, commander?
What's this all about?
How dare you come here
for Ertugrul? What did he do?
Halime Sultan!
Tell him that
I wouldn't even let you
touch my son's hair
let alone kill him while he
is in my marquee.
What does Ameer Sadettin
want from my brother?
We raided Turkmen Bey's
headquarters with His Ameer.
Ertugrul Bey sided with the rebels
and fought against us.
And not only that,
he also helped Shahzada escape,
whom Sultan had sentenced to death.
His Ameer wants them both dead
soon as they are found.
We were ordered to search
your marquee and the nomad tent.
If you resist, you will all receive
the same treatment.
As if it was not enough that you
threatened Ertugrul Bey,
now you threaten us too, is that so?
Halime Sultan, go back inside.
My son is not in the tent.
Go ahead and search it if you want to.
We'll keep quiet out of
respect for our state.
However, don't assume that
it will always be like this.
One day we will also have our say.
You two, look inside.
Ask for permission first.
Commander, put that sword back in.
Selcan, let him in.
Go ahead.
As you can see,
my brother is not here.
I only performed my duty.
If your duty is over, get the
hell out of our marquee.
Did you see what you had to,
commander?
We'll search the other tents, too.
Tell your Alps not to stand in our way.
-Thank God, Halime. They got away.
-Thank God.
If God permits, we'll also hear some
good news from Gokce, Selcan.
If God permits.
-Abdurrahman.
-Yes, Mother Hayme.
Let the Alps know. The commander
can look everywhere
to make sure that Ertugrul
isn't in the nomad tents.
As you wish, Mother Hayme.
So this is the man Sungur said was
innocent. That two-faced scum.
Brother Ertugrul was right.
He gained our trust only to betray us,
that Ameer Sadettin.
It is time to go and talk to him
face to face.
Gundogdu, get ready.
Let's go to Ameer Sadettin's quarters
and see what he is up to.
Mother.
We'll go to the Ameer for Ertugrul's sake.
Keep your calm while we're there.
You don't have to come with me, son.
I'll go by myself.
I have a right to say a few words to the
Ameer for whom our soldiers died.
They want my son dead.
Shouldn't I say something?
Of course you should, mother.
But I am talking about asking for what is
reasonable, and in a reasonable manner.
Please understand.
What news do you have
for me, Bogac Alp?
Noyan killed Tugtekin and his wife,
his Ameer.
Noyan.
Hopefully, Sungurtekin Bey
will deal with him soon.
However... Goncagul Hatun...
What about her?
Gokce Hatun killed her
as she was trying to get away.
Patience, my boy.
Pain is always temporary.
How could man appreciate joy
if there was no pain?
If he knew the taste of pain,
he would never want joy.
If pain wasn't the biggest blessing,
why would God give it
to his most beloved subjects,
the prophets?
Oh God, how mighty you are.
The arrow is lodged in the wound,
but it's not so deep in.
-Bring the cinder, son.
-Right away.
May the dagger be the cure for this
young boy in the name of Almighty God.
Bite this, son.
Bismillah.
-Geyikli.
-Yes, Bey.
Go to the nomad tent at once.
Let Artuk Bey know that Turgut Alp
and Yigit are both safe.
My mother and
Halime Sultan should know.
As you wish, Bey.
I've been fooling myself all this time.
I thought I was all forgotten.
I would live with the Kayis
and grow up to be an Alp.
I could reach martyrdom.
But it was not to be.
I saw it.
I can't stay here anymore,
Ertugrul Bey.
God who spared Abraham
from the flames,
do not let this young Alperen suffer.
With your name, The Healer.
In the name of God!
Oh God!
Thank God.
I can't return to the nomad group.
Everyone knows what I did.
Do not worry, Bogac Alp. I need you.
We will return to Konya together.
Stay with me until then.
I would die for you,
his Ameer.
His Ameer, Sungurtekin Bey
wants to see you.
Send him in.
Bogac, hide behind the wall now.
Wait there.
Let's see what news he has for me.
Those damned Kayis.
Their Alps are one problem,
and their women another.
Welcome, Sungurtekin Bey.
Have a seat.
I hope you came to tell me you
settled the score with that murderer.
I wish I could, his Ameer.
Don't you tell me you let him
slip through your fingers.
We waited for him where you told us to.
But he didn't come.
-He didn't?
-No.
That woman you said he was with.
I found out who she is.
-Who was it?
-That serpent called Goncagul.
You should agree that
my brother Ertugrul was not
mistaken about Gumustekin.
And apparently, Goncagul colluded with
Noyan to avenge her relatives.
Perhaps Ertugrul has destroyed
everything I could use as evidence,
while he was trying to take
justice into his own hands.
You don't find what I said about
Gumustekin credible?
I do.
But there is something else
I saw with my own eyes.
Your brother, Ertugrul
placed his own head under
the sword of justice today.
What does that mean, his Ameer?
We raided Turkmen Beys' headquarters.
Shahzada Yigit was there, too.
Guess who chose to side
with the rebels
and helped Shahzada escape.
Yes.
I personally witnessed what
Ertugrul has been up to.
Are you the ones who raided the
Turkmen headquarters, soldier?
-Tell me!
-Yes.
Ertugrul. What happened to him?
-He helped Shahzada get away.
-Sadettin couldn't do it.
Let me go. I am wounded.
Let go, please.
He destroyed all the
evidence I had.
That's impossible. My brother
would never turn against the state.
Stop defending Ertugrul,
Sungurtekin Bey!
If you can't complete the task
Sultan gave you, then resign now.
Resign, so that Shahzada Yigit
can be punished.
God forbid, if Sultan Aleaddin arrives
he and his army will be
punishing us all at once.
You shouldn't think of the grass
your ox steps on, Sungurtekin Bey.
I want you to know that I won't
abandon my task, his Ameer.
Shahzada Yigit will be punished
as our Sultan has ordered.
I don't doubt this at all.
And I will bring Ertugrul to the
Sultan with my own hands.
-You will see that he is innocent.
-To the Sultan?
It's obvious that my brother
doesn't trust you.
I cannot persuade him
to surrender to you.
But I can persuade him to trust
the Sultan's justice.
And what if he is not persuaded?
Then he will share
the same fate with Shahzada.
As you wish, Sungurtekin Bey.
I trust you just like
I do the Sultan's justice.
Ertugrul can go turn himself in
to the Sultan.
So long as this matter is dealt
with in peace and quiet.
And you perform the task that
the Sultan asked you to.
Put out these flames that
are burning our state down.
Find Shahzada and kill him.
Artuk Bey. There is word
from Ertugrul Bey.
Mother.
Don't you worry.
I have a few words to say
to that despicable man.
You tell me not to worry but
Noyan is still at large.
How could I not worry?
Do not worry. He'll get what
he deserves if we find him.
-Hayme Hatun, Halime Sultan.
-Artuk Bey.
There is news from Ertugrul Bey.
Shahzada Yigit and Bey
are both fine, thank God.
They are safe with their Alps.
He wanted you to know.
Thank God.
It is time to talk to
Ameer Sadettin, daughter.
-May you be under God's watch.
-You too, mother.
Selcan.
Ertugrul and Yigit are safe.
Thank God, Halime. Thank God.
Selcan, sister.
If God permits, Tugtekin Bey will
bring Gokce to the tent safely.
If God permits, Halime Sultan.
If God permits.
You are a fool, Sungurtekin. A fool.
You are too stupid to understand
Kobek is using you.
Gokce Hatun.
Oh my God!
Gokce Hatun, what happened to you?
Oh God, please help us.
Where are you going, Gokce Hatun?
Clear the way!
Let Mother Hayme get through.
Stand clear.
We couldn't save them, Bey.
-Gokce!
-God!
God, please don't make
us go through this pain.
Let me through.
My girl.
Is that my sister?
Is that Gokce?
Gokce. Sister.
Look at your face.
Your beautiful red cheeks
have turned snow white.
Gokce. Your sister is here.
Your sister. Gokce.
Gokce, please say something.
We celebrated newroz together,
just yesterday.
What did you do to yourself?
Selcan!
Tugtekin Bey, what happened to you?
Get up!
Get up! Wake your woman up!
Get up, Tugtekin Bey! Don't let them
take you away like this! Get up!
Gokce! Mother! Please say something.
I will die for the tear in your eyes.
Make her talk to me
and say something.
-Selcan.
-Gokce.
-Gokce, it is me, your sister.
-Stand back!
No!
Get up! No!
He is alive.
Let's lift him up.
My sister is alive, too.
Hold him steady.
-Don't shake him.
-Slow.
Take him to the marquee.
Be careful with him.
We will avenge your blood, Gokce.
Whoever did this to you
will have to pay for it!
Mother.
Halime Sultan, keep an eye on Selcan.
Mother!
Selcan.
Get back! Don't you touch my sister.
Go away.
My sister is not dead.
Open your eyes for me,
my beautiful gazelle-eyed sister.
-Open your eyes for me.
-Selcan, please.
Gokce!
I trust you as much as
I trust Sultan's justice.
Let Ertugrul go and surrender to Sultan.
As long as this matter is dealt
in peace and quiet.
And you perform the mission Sultan gave.
Quench the fire our state fell in.
Find Shahzada and kill him.
Father.
My gallant father.
It was not in my fate to see
your face for the last time.
I wish you would be alive.
I wish you would show us the right way.
On the one hand stands our nomad
group you entrusted us with
and Ertugrul on the other.
Our nomad group's future on the one hand
and Ertugrul's dreams on the other.
Know this, I will not allow Ertugrul
shatter your trust.
We could not find peace, Gokce.
We could not see the light of day.
We could not be happy
and raise our children.
Now you wish to leave.
Do not. Please. Get up.
Let your breath be mine. Get up.
Selcan.
Sister, do not.
Gokce reached the rank closest to God,
the martyrdom rank.
You are a martyr's sister.
Crying does not suit you. Stay strong.
Halime.
Look.
Would one die so beautifully?
Who would believe she is dead? Just look.
Look, would one die like this? Look.
Would one die like this?
She does not look dead, does she?
Get up.
-Get up, say something to your sister.
-Selcan, get up.
-Selcan, hold on.
-Please, do not.
-Selcan, sister, get up.
-I beg you.
Do not bury my sister on black earth.
-Selcan, sister, get up.
-Please, do not.
Alps, take Gokce Hatun. Go on.
-Selcan.
Gokce.
Do not let them bury my sister
deep in black earth.
Say something, do not let them bury her.
Do not let them take away my sister.
Say something.
-Come, sister.
-Halime.
Please Halime, say something.
-It is in bad condition, Artuk Bey.
-We will do all we can and pray, Ishak.
Give me hot water.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim ,
the compassionate and the merciful.
Gokce.
How could they kill you, Gokce?
How could they?
How could they do it!
How could they kill you? Gokce.
What will I do without you? Get up!
Selcan.
Get up, please, get up.
Get up. How could they kill you?
How could they do it?
Selcan. Please, get up.
-Gokce.
-Get up.
How could they kill my sister?
Selcan, sister, come, do not do this.
-How could they kill my sister?
-Come.
Come, you will stay strong. Come.
What will I do without my sister?
What will I do without Gokce?
You stay strong, sister.
Come, Merchant Abdullah. Sit beside me.
Let us talk a little with you.
We could not meet for quite a while.
I have good news for you, Sadettin.
Tugtekin is dead.
And Gokce Hatun, what happened to her?
Yet Goncagul Hatun died, too.
And I laid his wife's body next to
Tugtekin, like a Turkmen rug.
Gokce was supposed to live. I was
going to give her to Sungurtekin.
It's bygone, Sadettin.
There is nothing to do.
Did you not pamper that
fool Sungurtekin enough?
As I heard, you let Ertugrul and
Shahzada slip through your fingers.
If Ertugrul is still alive,
then it means we still need each other.
Where are you going?
Inform Ameer Sadettin, Mother Hayme
and Gundogdu Bey came.
I will send supplies and fighters
for you and your men.
I heard you do not have much men
left around you.
I will send you my best men.
But finish this business.
Ertugrul's time has come.
Apparently, you are afraid of Ertugrul
appearing before Sultan Aleaddin.
He will not be able to appear before
Sultan Aleaddin, thanks to you.
Is it not so?
Mother Hayme and Gundogdu Bey
are here, his Ameer.
Let them come in.
-Hide now.
-A shrewd woman.
She is trying to rip her son out
of your hands with her teeth.
Welcome, Hayme Hatun.
Here, sit down.
Your soldiers came to my nomad tent
and searched for my son.
I heard you are attempting
against my son's life.
It is my duty to do
what justice behooves.
Who tries to save him will have
the same treatment.
We have no doubt you are
performing your duty, his Ameer.
Yet I would like you to know this
my brother, Ertugrul has no such
matter as revolting against state.
Both he and Shahzada Yigit are innocent.
Then they shall come and surrender to me.
They are not meant to be thrown in
front of the jackal, Ameer Sadettin.
Know your place, Hayme Hatun.
When time comes...
...I will surrender my son to Sultan
with my own hands.
When time comes, huh? What time is this?
Ertugrul would never surrender
before he is done with Noyan.
The greed for throne, rank, position
brought many heroes to their knees
and perverted them
yet this boy did not yield to his desire.
May God destine a child like him to all.
And may he keep Muslims distant
from the ambition of being mighty.
May he destine us to regard all
our doings only by God's approval.
Amen.
Just as Kobek is the one who brought
Goncagul and Noyan together
Goncagul is the one who brought
Bogac and Kobek together.
With this, the only place she would
take shelter in is Kobek's lair.
Until the time comes and
Kobek finishes her off.
It is apparent where Bogac will go, Bey.
It is, Dogan, it is.
It is, Bey.
And it is apparent where
we will walk all over them.
Reach caravansary before sun rises,
keep your eyes open.
Even if we cannot get in, Bogac
will come out, sooner or later.
He will, Bey. And we will
swoop him when he does.
Bring Bogac alive to me.
Do it so there is no one left
that does not know Kobek
and Noyan work together.
Only this can save Yigit
and us from Kobek's game.
You came to life, mountains' bear.
I did, brother. I came to life.
I get in a good mood only when
I chop heathens and beat traitors.
Brother, we will down on their throat.
Noyan killed Gokce Hatun.
And Tugtekin is in the throes of death.
In throes of death?
How could that be?
Noyan kidnapped Gokce Hatun.
To entrap Tugtekin Bey.
You should know I am sorry.
Two young people.
Tugtekin Bey will get his health
back soon, if God permits.
If God permits.
You should know this
my son will not be the only one to be
weighed in Sultan's justice scale
you will, too.
As our duty necessitates, we are always
weighed on that scale, Hayme Hatun.
Sungurtekin Bey came before you.
He, too, said he will persuade Ertugrul
to surrender to Sultan Aleaddin.
I told him, too, whether me
or Sultan Aleaddin.
As long as this matter is dealt in peace
and justice is served.
Sultan assigned you to ensure
order in these lands
we fought on for the love of God,
we gave many martyrs for.
So be it. As he pleases.
However since you came,
neither my nomad group
nor others are in order or in peace.
Sultan will surely know about this.
Mother.
From now on,
do not let your soldiers
come and disturb us again.
I will keep my promise.
I will surrender my son to Sultan
with my own hands.
And you should know it as it is.
What a woman.
He brought the mighty Ameer to his knees.
Time will show that.
Besides, Tugtekin was alive.
What is this, Noyan?
Do not worry. I carved him so well,
he will not make it to morning.
You can go and weep at his funeral.
You can even mourn for him if you like.
As I said, if Ertugrul
appears before Sultan
you will not get a wink of sleep
at nights.
I will wait for Bogac and your men.
Then I will go and kill Ertugrul.
Do not pull something on me, Sadettin.
If you pull something on me,
no matter where you go,
I will find you.
Goodbye.
Your shaman.
Ulubilge.
Ertugrul and his men killed him
while they were escaping.
May God heal you.
What arrow could hurt a lion like you?
Even a scar would not be left soon.
I will check your wound again tomorrow,
before I leave to Ahlat.
Thank you, Hazrat Arabi.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
And peace be upon you.
Bey.
The situation is no good.
Speak, Geyikli.
-I do not know how to tell, Bey.
-Geyikli.
Are you testing my patience?
Gokce Hatun.
She is dead, Bey.
Noyan killed her.
And Tugtekin Bey had been
struggling to survive.
He is badly wounded.
Gokce.
Innocent Gokce.
Before they even get enough of
each other with Tugtekin.
And my brother Tugtekin.
Gallant Tugtekin.
I told him, "Noyan will pull you
to his cobweb, hold your rage."
Noyan.
Sadettin.
I will send you to hell.
I will not stop until tyrants
kneel down before aggrieved ones.
Be strong, child.
Be strong even if you are
tyrannized a thousand times.
Do not think it will go on this way.
As Prophet Ali said
"The day the aggrieved avenges
the tyrant will surely be more arduous
than the day tyrant tormented."
God is by faithful's side.
-I am going to nomad tent quickly.
-Bey.
Ameer Sadettin would not have
left out the nomad tent.
-His soldiers must be in the nomad tent.
-Do not worry.
I will go and return quickly.
Rosebuds before her marquee
The food inside, bleeding
Gokce lies, sleeping
Her neck, soaked in scarlet blood
Could this child be buried
Came the dark news
Turned its face
The ill fate
Both tribes weep together
What would Gokce Hatun do
Could one die this beautifully
Could one bury such a beauty
Two graves on the path
The wind blows into dust
And there you lay, Bey
Your flesh bleeds, eyes weep
Could this woman be buried
Tugtekin.
-What state is he in, Artuk Bey?
-Unfortunately, it is not good, Bey.
That Noyan dog thrust the sword
to his stomach so dexterously
he wanted him not to die,
to suffer, on purpose.
And Gokce Sister?
How did he kill her?
He killed Gokce Hatun
by cutting her throat.
I do not know if it is a consolation
yet it is apparent she died
without suffering.
Where is my mother, Artuk Bey?
News on Ertugrul Bey came first but
then on Tugtekin Bey and Gokce Hatun.
She went to see Ameer Sadettin
with Gundogdu Bey.
-What is it you say, Artuk Bey?
-She was so furious, Bey.
My God.
Selcan. What about Selcan Hatun?
How is she?
Selcan Hatun was quite shattered. I hope
it will not damage her pregnancy again.
Gokce Sister. I am wretched by our loss.
May God give us all patience, son.
May God give us the chance
to avenge their blood.
Amen.
How is Tugtekin?
He is not good, mother.
Gokce...
She killed Goncagul before she died.
How do you know this?
I learned Noyan's place
from Ameer Sadettin.
We lied in wait.
But he did not come.
When I went and looked I saw the body
of that serpent named Goncagul.
Obviously, she conspired with Noyan.
Since Noyan would not kill the woman
he alined himself with
Gokce must have found a chance while
she was trying to escape
and killed Goncagul.
And Noyan must have caught Gokce
while she was escaping.
Sungur.
My mother and I are coming from
Ameer Sadettin's place.
He told us what you talked about Ertugrul.
There is no other way than
to surrender Ertugrul
to Sultan Aleaddin's justice, mother.
Halime Sultan, I know my brother
Ertugrul is not a revolter.
Sultan will know and understand this, too.
We cannot let Ertugrul dies out of
his fury towards Ameer Sadettin.
We must convince Ertugrul into this.
And we shall surrender
Shahzada Yigit to Sultan, too.
Do you understand me?
Ertugrul Bey would not surrender.
What will he do if not surrender?
Should he live as a refugee on a mountain
with Shahzada Yigit for all his life?
Should they be entrapped and die some day?
Is this what you want?
You have been apart from
your brother for years.
It is obvious you do not know him well.
Ertugrul would not surrender to Sultan
before he brings us Noyan
and Ameer Sadettin, who
holds Noyan's leash in his hands.
Do you not know these words of yours
will cause Ertugrul's death,
Halime Sultan?
And you?
Do you not know that you trail
along after Ameer Sadettin
and put your brother's life in danger?
Enough!
Enough, what are you doing?
Is it time to talk these, now?
Will you go through these
hard times like this?
Is this how you will secure our unity?
Dodurga Beys wish to see you,
Mother Hayme.
Let them come in.
I am sorry for your loss, Mother Hayme.
It is all our loss.
What do you want to talk to me about?
We want you to know we will gather
the headquarters tomorrow, Mother Hayme.
We do not want to leave
the nomad group without a leader.
Look at yourselves.
You are fighting with each other like
carrion crows to get in the marquee.
You set your eyes on your Bey's
position before he even died!
Shame on you!
Get out of my sight!
I said, get out!
Did I not extend you the hand of mercy?
Did I not say the rebellion...
...would be in calamity?
I, mighty Ameer Sadettin Kobek...
...did I not show mercy to you?
What happened?
Your Beys perished along
with many of your Alps.
What good did it do?
Nothing.
A big nothing.
If it happened and Sultan Aleaddin
came, what would happen?
He would not let any of you live!
Forgive us, his Ameer.
We could not stop our nomad groups' Beys.
We told them not to revolt but
we could not make them listen.
They were blinded by anger, his Ameer.
We could not stop it, his Ameer.
Grant us to our children.
Forgive us, his Ameer.
Why are you silent, Karacabey?
We could not stop the Beys
in our headquarters, his Ameer.
You are right to say what you will.
We surrender our heads to your might.
Was it necessary for this many
ones to die, Karacabey?
It was not, his Ameer.
You should know, me and our nomad
group will always be at your service.
I will choose your nomad
groups' Beys henceforth.
And your part will be to respect
my decisions at the headquarters.
Who does not respect will pay its price
along with his nomad group.
Now, is there anyone
to talk after my words?
No, his Ameer.
As you please.
Karacabey?
Whoever does not obey your order...
...will find me before him first,
his Ameer.
Very well.
We have to convince Ertugrul
to surrender when he comes, brother.
He and Shahzada, both must surrender.
I will take them to Sultan myself.
I will talk to Sultan and convince
him that Ertugrul did not revolt.
I know there is no other
solution, too, brother.
Yet, what if Sultan would not be
convinced and kill Ertugrul?
We know he set off from
Konya with his armies.
He is obviously angry.
As I think what one wrong word coming
out of Ertugrul's mouth would cost
I feel like I will go insane.
Ertugrul.
How is Tugtekin Bey?
Brother, he is not good at all.
My mother is with him.
Ertugrul. We need to talk.
We know you took Shahzada
from Seljuq soldiers'.
Sultan will soon learn about this, too.
You need to surrender to Sultan's
justice with Shahzada, brother.
I will do what is necessary, brother.
No one should have a doubt on it.
What is necessary, Ertugrul?
I will find Noyan, brother.
I will prove they are working
together with Kobek.
If you ask what is necessary, it is this.
Then I will go to Sultan Aleaddin
and surrender.
I will bow down to his verdict.
You still keep saying, Ameer Sadettin.
Stop being stubborn.
Brother, see the truth.
Kobek was the one who put
Noyan and Goncagul on our tail.
And that woman was the one who
made Bogac a trouble to us
who led Gokce Hatun to death.
Do you not see how Kobek has blindfolded
you, how he holds your leash?
Ertugrul! Sungur!
You are the one who talks about going to
Byzantium, opposing all the nomad group.
You are the one who does not hesitate
even a little to divide the nomad group.
You are the one who deceived
even me with your words.
Now, with all the troubles on our
plate, you rise against Ameer
and make everything difficult for us.
I have had enough of you!
Sungur!
What are you doing?
Tugtekin is grappling with death inside.
On the other side Gokce is
laying dead in this young age.
It is enough. Do you understand? Enough!
It is not. It is not, mother.
What Ertugrul does is stubbornness,
pure stubbornness.
When will you get tired of
digging your own grave, Ertugrul?
Sultan is coming with his army.
Do you not understand?
If you continue like this,
he will bludgeon you and us.
Sungurtekin.
Are you not aware of what
a fire you are in, Ertugrul?
Damn it! I am struggling over
for you to live
for you to make your dreams
come true. Do you not see?
I do not dream, brother.
I do what needs to be done.
I do not rush to save my life when Kobek's
hands are covered in many of ours blood.
Both Noyan and Kobek
will have what they deserve.
Tugtekin Bey is dying.
My brother.
I will reunite with my love.
Don't you give up, Ertugrul.
You should make us expand
beyond the Byzantine border.
Be under God's watch.
Give me your blessings.
I do.
There is no god but Allah...
...and Mohammad is
his messenger.
Gokce.
Tugtekin.
See you in heaven, Gokce.
Dodurga Beys had their eyes on
Tugtekin's seat even before his death.
I will talk to them tomorrow
at the funeral.
I will try to stop those
who shamelessly wanted to take
Tugtekin's place even before he died.
If I don't do this, they too will be
under Ameer Sadettin's control.
When Ertugrul goes after
Noyan and Kobek,
it is our duty to look after
both nomad groups.
Hayme Hatun.
I'm very concerned about Gundogdu
and Sungurtekin Beys.
It is certain they will leave
Ertugrul Bey alone.
May God be on our side.
Amen.
Apparently, there is no place for
Ertugrul among us, brother.
He has already chosen the path he will
take, and a different destination.
It was obvious this would
happen someday.
Our nomad group will be divided.
There is no doubting that.
However, Ertugrul will not go alone.
That is what I am worried about.
Many of our Alps, many people
will follow his lead.
Then our duty is to prevent that.
But it is necessary for us
to solve Ertugrul's
Shahzada problem first.
We could save him but how
will Ertugrul save himself from his greed?
We're all set.
It's time to hit the road.
Let's go.
I am tired of waiting, brothers.
True, brother. No one is coming.
I can't wait any longer.
Look at yourself.
I thought you were more patient.
This is totally not like you, Bamsi.
You are right, brothers.
One can make mistakes
even if he is enlightened.
One can't tell right from wrong.
Someone is coming.
That is Bogac.
You see, Bamsi?
Good things await those
who are patient.
It was worth waiting for, brothers.
That moment has arrived.
Then why are we here, brothers?
Let's get on with it.
Do not worry, Halime Sultan.
Yigit is getting better.
What I fear is what will happen
to Yigit now, Ertugrul.
Yigit is my brother, Halime.
He means the world to me.
He can choose my path if he wishes.
You know he would go to the
end of the earth with you,
let alone the Byzantine border.
It is time for an exodus, Halime.
I'm going to make them pay
for the lives they took.
If God allows my safe return,
you should know that
the real battle will begin then.
If need be...
...we will take to the road
with a handful of people who
believe in us, like our prophet did.
I know that I will part with my
brothers, my loved ones on this path.
You should be prepared for this, too.
I am prepared to die for this, Ertugrul.
I'm ready to do whatever you say.
Talk to the gallant women
in the nomad group.
Explain that this is our only choice.
I will. Do not worry.
I hope you go there and
come back like the wind, Ertugrul.
Where have you been, Bogac?
We miss you at the nomad tent.
Attack!
Bamsi.
It is time to pay, Bogac.
Ertugrul Bey is waiting for you.
Al Fathehah, for the
souls of the deceased.
Gallant and honorable people of
Dodurga,
don't be sad that you
lost your Bey and his wife.
He, Tugtekin Bey strived
for his nomad tent
and his people all his life.
He risked his own life to
always protect us.
And we could never forget
how gallant our Bey was.
You should know that
those who think Bey's death left us
without a leader are very mistaken.
Whoever has their eyes on
our Bey's position should know
that Dodurga tribe has the might
to choose a Bey for themselves
as they have done
for a thousand years.
Dodurga tribe will soon have
a Bey worthy of them.
May God bless the souls of those
who died for this nomad group.
Amen.
The hunt is over, Bey.
You let Tugtekin Bey and Gokce Hatun
die for how many gold coins?
What did your master promise you?
How can you do this to your Bey,
who let you in his marquee,
who trusted you with his life,
who relied on you?
You will tell us everything that
your master is up to,
just like you told him about
everything said at the marquee.
Stop!
Stop.
Don't.
I will tell you everything.
My condolences, Hayme Hatun.
Gokce Hatun and Tugtekin Bey's deaths
saddened me beyond measure.
You've made us well aware of your
presence by attending the funeral.
You saved that Mongol dog
and he killed Tugtekin Bey and Gokce.
They would have been alive
if you had killed him.
His Ameer. Selcan is in great sorrow.
Excuse her.
I know about mourning.
And sorrow, too.
It's her sorrow talking.
I understand. It's okay.
It's painful for me to see
a glorious tribe like Dodurga
losing a gallant fighter
like Tugtekin Bey.
While Artuk Bey claims the opposite,
I am worried about Dodurga being
weakened without a leader.
I will do all I can, for a gallant Bey
who will make up for
Tugtekin Bey's absence,
to be appointed
as soon as possible.
You can rest assured of that.
As long as we are alive,
the Dodurga tribe will never be
weakened, God willing.
I don't doubt that, Hayme Hatun.
Yet, my duty is to do
whatever I can to help.
We wouldn't want our Ameer
to be preoccupied with our troubles.
Again, my condolences.
I only have one wish: Ertugrul
to turn himself to the Sultan
before he causes more
suffering and funerals.
I pray for that.
Sungurtekin Bey.
I managed to suppress the
rebellion with much difficulty.
I restored order.
And did this despite your
brother Ertugrul's efforts.
However, these lands are
always prone to rebellion.
Beys who ask for forgiveness today,
could stab us in the back
when they get the chance tomorrow.
That is why, when all this is over
in order for you to make
the order everlasting,
you will be appointed margrave,
Sungurtekin.
I am ready to do anything to
restore order in these lands.
But I need to deal with
the Shahzada matter first.
Alright, Sungurtekin Bey.
Stop Ertugrul from ruining
his tribe like he ruined himself.
It is time to meet
the holy spirits, Ulubilge.
May Ulubilge's soul
reach our Heavenly Father.
May your Steel Mountain, mightier than
the sun, light up with his soul.
May your Golden Mountain,
mightier than the moon...
your Ethel Tree, mightier than the axe
become mightier with his soul.
Ayaz Khan with moon and sun!
The sacred trees adorned with cloths!
Beech tree with the sacred leaves!
Owner of the flaming fire, Ak Yayik!
Oh, Heavenly Father!
Ground waters with a thousand ears!
Bugra Khan with eyes of cloud!
Brave man with the feet of ice!
Bulut! Tay! Bugra!
Take him to the world of souls!
May these lands we fought
and travelled on,
where we killed and died,
become our land of glory!
We came here for vengeance!
For vengeance!
Noyan!
Ertugrul.
I'm here to deliver you
to the demons of hell!