Episode 47 will start after 12:24 min.
RESURRECTION ERTUGRUL
THE STORIES AND CHARACTERS DEPICTED
HERE WERE INSPIRED BY OUR HISTORY
NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION.
Kill this Turk!
Were you saying something, commander?
If you take one more step, I will kill
the girl.
Take me! My daughter!
Please let my daughter go!
Leave your sword.
I said throw it!
Now we will go away from here
with the girl.
You should know that the girl will die
If you come after us.
Let her go and take me! My daughter!
Let my daughter go, I am begging you!
Take me!
Move!
Do not come, or else she will die!
Take me!
My daughter!
It is written in the letter that they made
peace and you hid it from us.
This is an opportunity to save Noyan.
If they do not give him even in the name
of peace, go and battle with them.
Save Noyan from those Turks, Tangut!
Ertugrul was brave enough to save
Abdurrahman.
Noyan will die.
He will pay the price for his foolishness!
You better accept it. Noyan is dead!
Your are not following the way
of holly spirits, Tangut.
The way you took, already awaken
all those underground spirits.
First, the voice of death will come.
Then death itself.
Enough.
Enough, shut up!
Listen to me carefully.
In China, I went to war with Genghis Khan
against Ziya Dynasty.
Genghis Khan was sick.
He was about to die.
He hid his sickness from everyone.
He risked himself to death for victory.
And he died.
What falls to our share is an honorable
death just like Genghis Khan himself.
Noyan will also die.
He will die honoredly.
He will pay the price for his mistake.
Valiant Alps of Kayi and Dodurga.
Their virtuous people!
Peace be with you!
-And peace be with you!
-And peace be with you.
Dear Khan, Sadettin Kobek,
you honored our nomad group.
We made Noyan; the archenemy of our
Sultan and our state,
bend on his knees in front of us.
You honored us while we were about to make
this blood shedder murderer pay for...
...what he has done. Welcome.
Thank you, Hayme Hatun.
I am very glad to be here,
in front of you.
When I heard that you captured
this dishonest man...
...I praised God.
This struggle you are going through
between these vast mountains...
...is worthy of admiration.
I want to present my gratitude
to all those valiants who captured him.
In the name of our Sultan Alaeddin
Keykubat, I order you to
stop the execution.
We want Noyan's head!
-We want his head!
-Kill him!
-Nobody can take him from us!
Kill him! Kill him!
-We want justice!
-Kill him!
We want justice!
Kill him!
Kill him! Kill him!
We announced peace with
Ulu Khan Ogeday.
This bloody war we fought
for years is finally over.
From now on, no more Seljukian
and Mongolian blood will be spilled!
Khan Highness!
If you let me, I have a question.
What is the cost of this peace?
I know well how you defeated the vanguards
of this dishonest man...
with your brother, Ertugrul.
I have endless respect for your bravery.
You asked me abour the cost!
The cost of this peace
is paid with the blood of our martyrs.
Prisoners of both sides will be replaced
and peace will be provided.
Noyan also takes place within
these prisoners...
...who are going to be replaced.
We want his head! We want Noyan's head!
Kill him! Kill him!
Commander.
Those are men of that Turk.
Do not approach, if not, girl dies!
Dear God, you give plenty at one time.
Kill them all!
Kill them all! All of them!
Halime, daughter...
...I say it as last time.
You came to my marquee.
I understand it.
You are from ancestry of Seljukian.
Bride of Suleyman Shah.
But how did you enter to my intimate,
tell me?
I came to talk with Aytolun Hatun, Bey.
This is the reason why I am here.
Bey.
Sadettin Kobek came to nomad tent
with his soldiers, Bey.
What?
Halime Sultan. Rest for a while.
Aytolun Hatun will come and see you soon.
Banu Cicek, look after Halime Sultan.
Leave marquee of Bey right now!
Why did you help me?
Halime Sultan, I show respect to you.
Do not make me lost it.
Go away.
I had to lie Bey, all because of you!
Why?
Why you lied to Bey because of me?
What is the thing you know and
not sharing, Banu Cicek?
I said go Halime Sultan!
Go, if not things will come to a bad end
for you!
Now, Noyan is gone!
There is only victory!
There is your brother Tangut will take you
to victory!
Is there anyone makes an objection...
...to things I say, if there is
show yourself up like a man!
Kill him!
Give his head to us! Kill him!
Give his head to us!
Beys!
People of Kayi, Dodurga.
Thanks to God, we made peace between
two states.
Today is such a holly day!
But Ameer Excellency...
...we know that exchange of prisoners
are made between honorable...
...soldiers and valiants.
But this Mongolian cur...
...is a murderer, killed our brothers,
mothers and sisters!
His punishment will be conducted
right now in this pitch!
Live long Bey!
Our Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat...
...always thinks that
mutinous of Turkmen Tribe comes...
...from their nature,
as their valiantness.
He plugged his ears to statesmen and...
...people that complains of
migrant families...
...accompanies brother and
he always stand...
...ancestry of Oghuz family.
Be sure that I know this ignoble and
his numbers better than you do.
How cruel he is and...
...how he murdered many
women and children.
But know it, we need peace
so that ignoble people...
...like him will not come again
to lands of our state.
We need to exchange him with three
of our precious commanders.
For this dishonest that is not be
a patch of one of our commanders...
...I cannot let anyone to reject
peace strictly.
We want justice!
-We want justice!
-Bey.
Do not you see?
We cannot give Noyan to you.
We want justice!
Dear Ameer, Sadettin Kobek.
Korkut Bey.
Hayme Hatun.
Noyan took too many lives from us.
But talking about this matter
in front of angry Alps,...
...furious people is not right.
I have always trusted to your mind and
common sense, Korkut Bey.
So, stop the execution.
Discuss this matter in a calm environment.
Sister, stand up sister, are you alright?
Get up sister, get up.
Because of peace condition...
...I have to give Noyan and take
my prisoner commanders, Korkut Bey.
Unlike, more valiant will be...
...murdered and destroyed.
Peace will be a dream in these lands.
We will think about this matter out.
What will you think out, Korkut Bey?
This murdered will not get out
of my nomad group freely.
We will not let it happen.
Will we revolt against the state
we fight for?
Hayme, we should discuss on this matter
in your marquee.
I will accommodate with...
...my soldiers in caravansary.
I will wait for your propitious news.
If God permits, you will be...
...in the side of peace and mind.
Gundogdu Bey.
Take this ignoble to trussed tent.
We want justice!
We want justice! Kill him!
What did I tell you, smart boy?
Did I tell you, you are unable
to kill me or not?
Your corpse will leave from this
nomad tent, Noyan.
You so furious boy, you are so colt...
...and fool.
Kill him! We want justice!
-Kill him!
-We want justice!
Noyan knows about us.
Everything about us.
More he breathes, more danger will be
our intention of taking margrave...
...that we've been working for years.
-Noyan is not a risk for anyone.
I will not jump on a risky path.
Do not you still understand it?
Do not forget about your duty.
Do what is necessary for peace.
Salve trouble of people so that...
...I can take Noyan and leave.
I will be waiting for you in
caravansary at night.
Bring the seal with you when you come.
Do not tell me that you have not taken
the seal from Sungurtekin.
I will come to caravansary at night.
The reason of vulgar expression
on your face was this, right.
-What are you trying to say, Sungur?
Did not you understand why he was so sure
that he will not die, brother?
He knew about peace.
Smart boy.
Even if you knew about peace and...
...Ameer Excellency Sadettin Kobek
would come here...
...you kidnapped my wife.
You set me up.
Such a damn man you are!
If you think by hiding behind of peace...
...you can save your people,
you are wrong.
My battle just began.
Sungur!
Wait outside, brother.
Ameer Sadettin Kobek waits for you
in caravansary, Sungutekin Bey.
Souls always support the strong one,
smart boy.
Peace is for cowards.
The one who settles peace lose courage
and spirit.
Peace is...
... a game to cheat weak ones.
Eventually, one day it will be over.
You will find me standing
against you then.
I will do everything I can...
...not to let you go from this nomad tent,
Noyan!
Do your best!
I will cause to your extinction!
I will not die before I take child of
Ertugrul from womb of his mother!
We killed crusaders and saved people, Bey.
Thank you.
God bless you.
-Amen.
-As you see Ertugrul Bey.
These fertile lands and people
under cruelty...
...waits for a Bey that can save them.
A Bey that can conquer heart of these
people and lands.
If God permits, when the time comes...
...you come and settle here with
your glorious...
...Kayi nomad group and with
your valiant men.
If God permits, Dervish Mahmut.
Bey...
...your hand.
Thanks to God, it healed, Turgut.
Praise be!
Air and water of this place
came good to us, Bey.
Everything about here is fertile, Bey.
Crusaders comes here like a rain.
As Dervish Mahmut brother said,
I am begging you...
...we should not be late to come back
to these lands.
If God permits, we will be here soon,
Bamsi.
Dervish Mahmut.
Yes, my Bey.
What will happen to these people?
Bad smell disperses quickly, Bey.
From now on, their lives are in danger.
Welcome, Sungurtekin Bey.
Finally I had honor of seeing you
before I die.
Come and sit.
I was always curious about spy that...
...Sultan Aleaddin Keykubat has
eves only for.
Who can think that spy is son of...
...Suleyman Shah which known as dead?
It is true that Sultan has only
eyes for me.
But someone from palace learned who I am.
If he would not inform Ogeday about me...
...I would be still on my duty.
Duty.
I cannot describe the passion
you feel for your duty.
But I want you to know that...
...after you came to palace and
told what happened...
...you cannot imagine
how many lost their lives.
Palace is a fertile place for traitors
so that they materialize.
If God permits, you got rid of traitors!
Even my family believed that
I was dead for years.
My mother, father, brothers
endured with it.
Except Sultan, no one knew about
me at all.
Until someone denounced me in palace.
All lingered.
With the information you shared about
Mongolians, we made peace, know it.
I want you to know that...
...I am grateful with...
...the name of our people and state.
Thank you.
Because of being a denounced spy
your duty is over.
I want you to live in your nomad group
as a valiant Alp.
You deserved it.
But there is a fall on your
shoulder with...
...the name of our state for peace.
Be careful about Beys of
both nomad groups.
Do not make them change their mind
about being in the way of peace.
Conclusions of it will be bad
for everybody!
It will be unpredictably bad
no one can foresee it!
For the benefit of state,...
...I will do whatever it takes,
Ameer Sadettin Kobek.
With your permission.
May God help you, son.
Genghis Khan never left anyone
behind before!
Noyan did not as well.
You cannot be a patch of Noyan.
Tangut.
Sadettin Kobek waits for you in
caravansary.
We will have a break in here.
Halt!
With you help, poor people got joyful,
Bey.
I hope same will come to
other oppressed people.
Amen.
Brother, when I have a look on how poor...
...these people are I justify
prophet Kirmani.
Thank you brother.
Brother, do you know what I say?
Can we do trading at odd moments?
Trading is not like using a weapon,
brother.
Why do you think in this way, brother?
We can hold money with the hands
we hold weapon.
Eventually, there is no killing or dying.
What kind of things you are capable of?
What will you sell to people?
Do not say it brother.
I can clean around,
I can kill non-Muslims and...
...I can inculcate as last option.
None of them makes money.
In order to make money,
you need to know about goods...
...and what clients want, brother.
And also bunch of capabilities are needed.
Brother...
...if I knew being a trader is so detailed
I would practice on it in our free times.
Yes, we do not know about trading,...
...we do not know how to plant as well.
But, we know one thing very well.
Give the work to its expert.
If we become an ocean,
all rivers will flow to us.
If we have a home, we will take
best craftsman...
...artisan, traders and poets with us.
We will make these lands as center of
halal income.
The main purpose is not to earn lucre,
brother.
It is earning in halal way and sharing
what is earned.
Lucre gets fertile when it is shared.
Now, so witness me God...
...we will destroy this savage system.
There will be justice and order
in these lands.
Thank you, Bey.
If we release cur Noyan,
he will win the war.
It means we lose the peace. It is obvious.
There is nothing else I can say.
Gundogdu Bey is right.
Our tradition says to be with justice,
is not it?
Will Noyan's leave freely
suite to our justice, father?
I am sorry.
It is possible that tradition, justice and
peace may come together.
But for this, execution of Noyan is
a must!
We suffered a lot, because of Noyan.
We lost many lives.
We cannot let him go
like an innocent pigeon...
...while we captured him by our own hands.
Even this idea makes me out of control.
What about our Alps?
In many battles, many Alps became martyr.
Is not it being disrespectful to wives,
sons...
...fathers to people left behind
by our martyr?
Many Alps became veteran
in numerous battles with us.
How can we release this ignoble
while we look to eyes of our veterans?
Obedience to state.
This is the only way out.
What are you saying, father?
Korkut Bey is right, Tugtekin Bey.
We need to think with logic,
not with anger.
What are you saying, brother?
Do not you know what he has done to you...
...your brothers and mother in
migration caravan?
What do you suggest?
We should let this ignoble leave?
I cannot believe we sit in here and
talk on these.
Are you aware of what you are saying?
Gumustekin Bey.
Do not you have anything to say?
I am ready to give my life in order
to take Noyan's.
But...
...we need to deal with this matter
with brotherhood and facility.
Road of facility and brotherhood
passes by peace.
For peace, we need to clean dirt and
dust from our hearts.
Dirt and dust are these, Sungurtekin Bey!
They burned my daughter
in front of my eyes.
They murdered our brothers and sisters.
If we do not take revenge of them...
...neither their souls will
rest in peace...
...nor these dirt and dust
will be purified.
You talk about not obeying
order of state.
Do you hear what you are saying?
What a shame!
I thought you will come and be
in the side of tradition and justice.
But I see that fear filled your veins.
What a shame!
Tugtekin!
Tomorrow morning, we will run headquarter
and decide on it.
Yes...
...we should leave justice to Beys
of headquarter so that it is spoiled!
When you changed like this, brother?
I say Ameer Sadettin Kobek should
also join to headquarter.
So that he can see the suffer within us.
Whatever our decision is he hears it
with his own ears.
Bey.
I saw you are so furious...
More he got aged, more afraid
and lost his dreams.
Now he tramples on his honor.
Do not say it...
...he is your father.
All he says is to give Noyan back
nothing else, Gokce.
Nothing else.
After my mother died, my father
changed a lot.
He is an old man what I cannot
recognize anymore.
Now, he is on tail of Sungurtekin.
Gundogdu brother made a mistake with
bringing him back to nomad tent.
If you would be head of Alps...
...you would bring his head, not himself.
If you would be Bey...
...you would not give him to anybody.
Everything comes with time, Bey.
Everything comes with time.
What are you saying, brother?
Do not you know what
he has done to you and your family?
What about the things he done to Ertugrul?
Of course I know, brother.
But state needs to dress the wounds
like we did.
This peace will empower our state.
What peace you are talking about, brother?
Mongolians do not want peace at all!
Do not you see it?
They will attack again.
They will attack after they gain strength.
Brother, neither Mongolians want peace...
...nor we can get rid of this
Mongolian trouble.
Bu sure that I am not that blind.
I know the truth!
I know the truth...
...but I will not be a prisoner by
surrounding anger.
If Ertugrul Bey would be here he would not
let this cur live.
Whoever lives under shadow of
this marquee...
...knows that Noyan will not stop of
killing.
He even knows the baby
inside of womb of Halime.
His impudent, ominous, shameless pack...
...know about our weak sides.
They know about our love and
respect to each other...
...and makes trap to us based
on these weaknesses.
There is also possibility of losing
the purpose...
...like grasses smashed
under cavorting of bulls.
You are right, father.
Who faced up to what for this seal?
You will get what you wanted from
Sadettin Kobek.
There is no obstacle remained
for being margrave, brother.
He is henchman of Sultan Aleaddin...
...most reliable man in palace, Aytolun.
If we consider he rushed his horse
to take Noyan from nomad group.
What are you trying to say, Brother?
Obviously there is purpose behind
purpose, Aytolun.
Our part is not to be smashed like grass.
Bring me the seal!
I will take it with me and I go to
see Kobek.
So Noyan? What about him?
It serves to my purpose if he dies.
I know that he knows most private secrets.
You, me, daughter my connections
in palace, everything.
I can understand it from his eyes.
What else a man know that knows
things between me and Sadettin Kobek.
Bring me seal in the evening.
Stop poisoning Korkut.
After I talk to Kobek, I will make
my decision.
What if Banu Cicek would not come?
What Korkut Bey would do to you?
From now on, I will keep you
out of this matter, Halime.
You are pregnant matters like that
are not for you.
I am inside of it as much as you are,
Selcan.
I will not give up!
I am begging you sister.
Do not make me regret because of
telling it to you.
There is something with Banu Cicek,
Selcan.
She knows some things, but she hides.
She is stuck in loyalty she feels for Bey
and suspicion that oppress on her.
Our part is not to let it go, Selcan.
Halime!
Korkut Bey went to Artuk Bey.
He is giving blood.
Do you have any other commands
Aytolun Hatun?
I do not, Banu Cicek. You can leave.
People can pay their taxes
with this gold.
People who are in trouble
can go to Seljukian lands...
...and can build a new life there.
If God permits
they will come back to their land.
God bless you, Bey.
Thank you, Mahmut Dervish.
We will leave early in the morning
and return to our nomad group.
We did very well by coming here.
As I said, Ertugrul Bey, the person
who will conquer this land...
...will also conquer
the hearts of the oppressed non–Muslims.
He will not only rescue people from
the Crusaders and non-Muslims...
...as long as this valiant Bey comes with
his Alps and enlivens this land.
-Amen.
Amen.
Why do you not tell me clearly
what is going on, Ameer Sadettin Kobek?
Do you not rely on me?
First Sungurtekin, then
the seal of Oghuz Khan and now Noyan.
You got what you want.
As I stated in my latter
there is no obstacle left for a margrave.
What about Noyan?
How does he know everything about us?
I removed the Mongolian spies
from the palace, Gumustekin.
The biggest trouble is that bastard
Noyan. Do you not know that?
He will do anything to use
what he knows against me when he is free.
Noyan will not be free
for himself, Gumustekin.
He will be free for the sake of peace.
You will do best you can do
in the Headquarters.
Leave the rest to me.
Did you bring the seal?
How can you be so sure that Noyan
will not cause any trouble to me?
We all saw what he could do for this seal.
He kidnapped Selcan and was captured.
He almost died.
Noyan will not be able to cause
any trouble to anybody.
This gold is for your margrave.
If anybody is against your margrave
you will bring them to heel with gold.
If anybody is stubborn, then you will
bring them to heel with poison and...
...if it is not enough
then you will use your sword.
As for the seal,
this seal will open so many locks...
...and guide us.
Now, give me that seal.
Now go and do not let
the Beys of the nomad groups...
...break the peace in the Headquarters.
Do not forget!
If there is no state,
then there is no margrave either.
If you show mercy to your enemy
one day he makes you sole to his boots.
If we release that bastard, you know what
will happen as much as we do, brother.
I met with Ameer Sadettin Kobek
in caravansary today.
Do not expect that I will endanger
my nomad group and marquee on purpose.
Especially for that palace bastard
Sadettin Kobek.
Mother...
Our state wanted peace...
...and Ameer Sadettin Kobek came to the
nomad tent to do what is necessary.
The command of the state
will be executed.
No one can stop it now.
When it comes to that bastard Noyan,
our state will not give rein to him.
You can trust my words.
He will get what he deserves
when the time comes.
Trader Abdullah is here
and he wants to see you.
Send him in.
You wanted to see me
Ameer Sadettin Kobek?
Something happens to you soldiers
when the war ends.
You became like fish out of water.
Do you not know that
there is not peace for a Mongolian?
How should I not know that?
That is why I asked for you.
What do you want?
I will take Noyan from Kayis.
You would be more pleased
if I did not, did you?
-What did you say?
-Put that dagger back.
Do not play the loyal soldier to me.
We know very well that Noyan
is a trouble maker and needs to be killed.
Do not play with me.
It will end badly.
Do you know what I see
when I look at you?
A loyal soldier of Ogeday.
Not a swag
and undisciplined man like Noyan.
Even if he knows that the peace is
very close...
...he put himself in so much trouble.
He went there
and gave his head to Gundogdu.
If there was not
a peace contract in question...
...I would have been
happier than you for his execution.
Unfortunately, I have to take him from
Kayis' hands because of the peace.
But I would like to work with you
instead of him
while a new system is being established.
We will both make profit
for the war tax paid to Ogeday.
If Noyan lives, we both lose.
What do you want from me?
Kill Noyan
and replace him as the commander.
It will be a good negotiation.
Kind of.
There is no negotiation.
Kill Noyan and replace him
as the commander. It is that easy.
Why wouldl Ogeday
make me the commander?
I like smart men.
Clearly, our partnership will be good.
You did not answer my question.
Because I have what Ogeday want.
If I give it to you,
you become the commander.
What is that?
The seal of Oghuz Khan.
Do you have the seal
whih is the death warrant of Noyan?
What do you want in return?
If you accept my conditions
I give the seal to you but only...
...if you accept my conditions.
What are your conditions?
How is that even possible, Artuk Bey?
He talks about releasing that bastard
who harmed his mother, sister...
...wife and brother.
Why does Sungurtekin Bey do that?
The mind of people and the mind of
the state do not work the same way.
Wild Demir!
I have no more words to say to you.
And the warmth of my heart
withered off.
Forgive me, Bey.
If God permits, other Beys will not listen
to you in the Headquarters meeting...
...and Gundogdu Bey
takes that bastard Noyan's head.
He still suffers because of his daughter.
I know that
and it upsets me a lot Artuk Bey.
Sometimes the price of truth is
heavier than the price of wrong, Bey.
He will
stand behind his words, though.
Thank you.
I talked to Ameer Sadettin Kobek today.
There is no solution other than peace.
And we have to release Noyan for that.
What about Noyan?
You know that Noyan will wiggle.
Of course, I know.
That is why me and Ertugrul's duty is
to take precautions.
I will do all I can, Bey.
May God accept it, my daughter.
Amen. Thank you, mother.
I spent a lifetime waiting.
I waited for Suleyman Shah's return...
...from so many wars and my sons
to get out of so many troubles.
Waiting...
You have said that
the fate of the woman of Kayi is this.
And I came to this marquee
lovingly as a bride.
As long as God speed Ertugrul Bey.
As long as I see that he returns to
his child and nomad tent.
I will experience the grief of waiting
and the beauty of coming together...
...with you until I die, mother.
My beautiful daughter.
Suleyman Shah told me
when I saw him in my dream.
Hayme, we will all die one day.
But people living in this marquee
will have more than that.
-Ertugrul!
-Father!
Father!
Ertugrul!
Come on, sit down next to me.
You went to various places,
from the Caspian Sea...
...to Ahlat, from Ahlat to Aleppo...
...from Aleppo to Erzurum.
In these places you go, you became
the honor of Kayi tribe...
...the pride of our tribe,
and the flag of Islam.
I just followed your way father,
and I will do the same hereafter.
The roads that Kayi tribe, you...
...and Oghuz was on exile
showed its light to you son.
Be a follower of that light.
Thus you can be a new hope...
...and you can open the doors of
a new world state for your descendants.
The ones with you...
...and behind you
will be happy with the honor of this.
From the North to the South.
From the East to the West.
A big oak tree with branches...
...will be raised in these lands.
Your son, Osman.
He will change our fate.
He will take root of Oghuz in these lands.
May your generation follow
God's order and make war.
Do not forget, son.
Child is the essence of a father.
May God be his helper, son.
Father!
Osman.
How could you fall into carelessness...
...and bring together the Headquarters
for that bastard Mongolian?
Is this fair?
Everybody wants justice, son.
But it is not wise to act with anger.
You need to think.
We brought
the Headquarter together for this.
The Headquarters?
The Headquarters!
You will hand that cruel man who killed
so many people out with your own hands.
Sadettin Kobek will bridle you and
make you do what he wants.
But I will not share your sin, father.
I do not care about
neither the Headquarters nor your verdict.
Ameer Sadettin Kobek...
...wants to be our guest
and see what our Beys think.
May I have your permission?
-He is welcome.
He is welcome.
He is welcome. He can come and
see our pain and anger with his own eyes.
He is welcome.
He can come and see.
He still did not understand our pain.
-Peace be upon you.
-And peace be upon you.
May God help us give a right verdict.
-Amen.
Thank you.
Go ahead!
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim.
By the 99 names
of the gracious and merciful God...
...I start the Headquarters.
The furious boy caught fire again.
He climbs the walls.
He rubs salt in the wound
that I made on his chest.
It is not possible
to forgive a killer like Noyan!
-Yes, we will not forgive him!
-Yes!
-We will not forgive.
-We will not accept.
It is betrayal. It means to object
our tradition and our religion.
-You are right.
-He is right.
It is unacceptable to bring
the Headquarters together for this.
We elected you as the Bey
so you can administer justice.
Not to release murderers
by bending the justice.
My Beys!
First they took my two sons
and then my daughter from me.
Do you want me to forgive this cruel
murderer before my gravid daughter...
...and my unborn grandchild's body
mixes with the soil?
No.
Neither will I forgive him
nor leave him alive.
-You are right.
-He is right.
Are you not ashamed?
We had so many martyrs.
-He is right.
-You are right.
Shame on you!
-Our martyrs' blood are shed for a reason!
-Shame on you!
God Almighty ordered in the Quran:
"O you who have believed, enter the state
of submission collectively
and do not follow the steps of devil
for he is clearly your enemy."
Artuk Bey is right.
Peace is our state's way.
The way of the Mongolians
is the devil's way.
If we enter this way
there will be no return from that.
It is obvious that
the devil makes you talk.
He makes you talk
and you do not hear what you are saying.
Wild Demir!
Nobody wants Noyan
to leave here freely.
This is not the matter.
My Beys!
I did not tell you the truth
when I came back to the tent.
It is not true that
I was captured by the Mongolians...
...and took care of the horses of the
Ogeday family.
I succeeded to become the best man of
Ogeday due to my friendship with Noyan.
As a spy of our sultan
I lived within these devils for years.
None of you can know Noyan,
Genghis Khan and his sons better than me.
All of your words are true.
Not only to kill Noyan but kill them
all is halal to us like our mother's milk.
But it is not about getting what
we deserve. It is about surviving
and protecting the unity and
the solidarity of our state.
Did you think that
you can get away with attacking...
...my nomad group and taking
so many lives? Tell me, Noyan.
Go to the ends of the earth, Furious Boy.
Do that so you can sleep
in your bed comfortably.
Hit me, come on.
Hit me so you can get rid of the worms
that nibble you.
Bring me to account for your body
that I knifed like a goat.
Right?
If our state wants peace
and it convinced our enemy to it...
...it is for us and
our state to live forever.
That is why we have to follow...
...our state's command
without being overwhelmed by our anger.
It is our duty to be with our state
in peace just like we did in war.
I believe it is time
to take the Beys' opinions...
...to solve this problem.
On this way that is thinner
than hair and sharper than sword...
...we will raise hands for our
desperation, though.
For the peace of our
captured commanders...
...those who accept
the release of Noyan...
...raise your hands.
I see that
our Beys want the execution of Noyan.
Either victory or raven to death.
I wish my arm was broken and
I could not raise it.
Raven is already here for the carcasses.
From now on, nobody should wait for me
in this headquarter.
God is greatest!
God hears all the prayers.
May God's peace and mercy be upon you.
My God, the light of heaven and earth.
You are guideline.
You are powerful.
We snuggle up to you with
all our helplessness.
We appeal for aid from you
and expect your mercy.
God!
The situation of Islam is very bad.
Sedition and dissension
captured all hearts.
We forgot our brotherhood.
We lost our sincerity.
We became overwhelmed by our soul.
We became partners with cruel.
God! Forgive us.
Clean our hearts with light of faith.
God! Increase our sensation.
Reinforce our sincerity.
Reunite us against the cruel and enemies.
Make us powerful. Make us resourceful.
God!
You gave us the opportunity to be
people of Prophet Muhammed.
Destine us to be martyr for this cause.
Do not return us from your way.
Do not leave us uncompassionate.
For your name's sake
destine resurrection again.
Amen. Amen.
Amen.
I shahada...
I shahada that the God is the only One
and Prophet Mohammad is his servant
and his messenger.
May God speed you, Bey.
Thank you, Dervish Mahmud.
May God bless you and your son.
You helped us very much.
-Thank you.
Will you come again, right, Ertugrul Bey?
If God permits, I will come
as soon as possible Edebali.
If God permits, you will come, Bey.
-Thank you.
-Thank you. May God speed you.
-May God speed you.
In the name of God.
Let us go to our marquee
as soon as possible, Alps!
Come on!
Almighty Khan.
We give this non-Muslim entered
in our marquee with our own hands.
But if something happens to one of
my brothers marquee it is on you.
You know that.
Gundogdu Bey.
You know very well that our state
never forgets those who serve.
Our state does not behave unjustly
especially toward Kayis.
Tugtekin!
Stop!
How can you treat a prisoner like this?
Does it suit a Bey of Dodurga in future
to behave like this?
To be a Bey requires destroying those
who intent to kill our people.
Not to deliver to their owner.
-Tugtekin.
Headquarter gave a decision.
We do not have any other solution
than to follow that.
I told you to kill me when you had chance,
did not I, smart boy?
Soldier!
I told you, did not I?
This is not over, Noyan.
This is not over.
Sons of Suleyman Shah will make you
pay it sooner or later.
Take him. Take.
What did we do, brother?
Tell me, Sungur? What did we do?
We released the non-Muslim
who set his eye on our bread
mother and sister with our own hands.
I will kill Noyan, brother.
If I kill him before prisoner chance
then the peace will be excused.
Our commanders' token as prisoner
will die in hands of Mongolians.
So, I will kill Noyan after Kobek
took and brought our commanders
token as prisoner.
I cannot let that happen, brother.
I cannot send you alone after Noyan.
I have to go, brother.
You know very well what will happen
if Noyan lives.
Then I will come with you, brother.
This is such a way and I do not know
when I will return
or I will ever return or not.
You are the head of Alps
of both nomad groups.
In your existence nomad group
will fall into weakness.
You cannot come, brother.
What about my mother?
My mother is a smart woman to know
why I returned and why I went.
Do not spare your prayers for me, brother.
Kill him!
Killer!
Give him to us and we will kill him!
Kill him!
Killer!
Give him to us and we will kill him!
Killer! Kill him!
Death for the killer!
We want justice!
Killer!
Noyan, the child killer!
We want justice!
We want justice! Kill him!
Kill him!
We want justice!
Killer!
Kill him!
My son...
...from now on the nomad tent
is entrusted you.
Wild Demir?
Wait for me, Aykiz.
I am coming to you.
Kill him!
Killer!
Wild Demir!
Kill him!
We want justice!
My great God.
I know, you destine me another child.
Destine me to grow him in my belly
and raise him as a good boy
for Gundogdu Bey.
May God accept, Selcan.
Thank you, sister.
Halime.
The night when Gundogdu Bey stayed here
I had a feeling that I was pregnant.
Selcan!
If God permits.
From now on, I will fight for my son
not only for me.
So the hope inside me can burgeon.
Noyan went, son.
From now on, my children are in danger
than ever before.
We have to find a solution for that.
Where is Sungur?
Call him. I want to talk to you.
Where is Sungur, son?
He left, mother.
Did he leave?
Where did he go?
How did you let him go?
How can he kill Noyan by going after
so powerful Mongolian army?
-Mother!
-How could you let such a thing
happen, Gundogdu?
-Mother!
You know that Noyan will not leave
neither me, you, Halime
or her baby alive.
Sungur did everything he can do
so we can release him for peace.
He did this for our state and Alps.
Since the very beginning
he determined to kill him.
So, he did everything
he can do to release him.
Come along, brothers.
God!
Let this plane tree embrace
whole world with its branches.
Let it take roots.
Let it take roots so our generation
can spread your justice and name
to whole world.
Let the fate of this plane tree
be our fate for this cause.
Amen.
We will make the sun our flag
and the sky our tent.
We will ride our horses
to endless marquees.
We will make our swords our lovers
and army our roses.
Our stamp will flap as the flag of
justice in seven climates.
We will carry our omniscient over
to the mountains and seas.
God is greatest!